GORGEOUS
Attention, please!
We have a special message
for all our dear, faithful listeners!
Fathers, mothers, relatives!
Stella Film has organized
a great contest
to find a little girl,
a child from 6 to 8 years of age,
a pretty little Italian girl.
Bring your daughter to Stella Film,
to Cinecittà offices,
Via Tuscolana, km 9.
It could turn your luck
and hers around!
All the girls from 6 to 8 years,
can enter the theatre,
quietly and calmly
to be seen by
the film director Blasetti!
Now, go along inside!
Hurry! Hurry! Move along there!
Vito!
Where is this little girl?
- What's her name?
- Maria Cecconi.
Maria Cecconi!
Quiet, please! Quiet!
There! Good manners will get you far.
You will get your daughters
tested by us,
as you'd like, quietly and calmly.
We'll be able to see them better.
Right? Fine!
- Ready?
- Ready!
Glori, send over the first child.
Let's see the first child. Come on!
What can you do?
I can do an imitation
of Betty Grable.
Good! Go on!
Very good!
Well done! You're starting early,
how old are you?
- Eleven.
- Eleven! Give her a number.
Next!
Another child, hurry!
Be quiet over there!
Fine... Keep that child quiet!
- What can you do?
- "Arrivano I nostri".
Perfect!
Sing "Arrivano I nostri". Go!
Fine!
- Very good!
- Her voice is a little low!
- We need a louder voice.
- Louder!
Very good! Give her the number.
Next!
Please, be quiet over there!
Good, you with the Chinese hat!
Quiet!
Incredible! I've been looking
for you for three hours!
How could I go home without you?
Look what a mess you're in!
Just look what a mess you're in!
Stand up!
You deserve a good smack!
Now you're crying?
Look at you! Damn!
You're all dirty. You drive me crazy!
- They called you over the megaphone!
- Mummy!
What do you want from Mummy?
What did she do wrong?
She nearly gave me a heart attack.
I've been looking for her
all over Cinecittà!
They won't let us back in.
Are you happy?
- Are you here for the contest?
- Yes! Look what a mess she's in.
She looks like St. Lazarus!
Come here!
If I had to take a child to the
contest, I'd leave her like that.
All dirty? Beautiful!
They're prettier grubby and with
their hair tossed. They look nicer.
It's you who's nice.
She has a pretty face.
She's photogenic.
And she has lovely eyes.
Let me see!
Really lovely eyes!
Good thing! Let's hope they pick you.
Come on!
- Goodness! I'm lost now.
- I think they're at n. 5.
- What's that?
- Studio n. 5.
How do I get there?
I'm completely lost!
- I'll take you there.
- You will?
- Sure.
- How kind! Thanks. Let's go!
Wait till we get home!
This is the little girl who got lost!
- The lady can go in through here.
- If you say so!
I brought some photos of her.
Did I do the right thing?
- She really is a pretty child!
- At this age, they're all pretty!
Right. They're all pretty,
but I prefer their mothers!
Listen, allow me to give you
a piece of advice:
the second time
the test will be a bit harder
and these photos
won't help you much.
- They're not very good.
- Yes.
You need to get them re-done larger
and better by a professional.
- I will.
- I can give you an address.
- That'd be great!
- Tell him I sent you.
I'm Alberto Annovazzi.
The photographer
is at 14, Via Quattro Fontane.
Go to him. He's a real artist.
I'll go there! Thank you so much.
- Not at all.
- I don't know how to thank you.
- Can I go in?
- It leads straight to the studio.
- If I hadn't run into you...
- Best of luck!
- Say bye-bye!
- Bye! Don't run off again.
- I'll hold onto her tight!
- That's best.
- Goodbye!
Good. Well done, little one!
What's your name?
Mario! Give her a number.
Now, the other little girl
who is waiting her turn.
Come forward.
Madam, we're not at the races!
The incident's over!
Go back to your places! Enough!
Back to your places!
The incident is over!
This is the child who got lost!
- Ah, that one!
- I lost sight of her!
- Where?
- I don't know!
- It's a village, you can get lost.
- Where was she?
- Near the pool!
- Silence, please!
For goodness' sake! Quiet!
Where did you find her?
- Near the pool, fishing!
- She got dirty.
Yes. I struggle to iron her dress!
- Cute! What's your name?
- Maria!
- He didn't catch that.
Nice! Maria what?
- Maria...
- Zecconi!
- No. She lisps slightly.
- So, what's her surname?
- Cecconi.
Cecconi.
Repeat: "Maria Cecconi".
Okay, maybe she likes that way.
When I made the announcement
you were looking for your girl,
but I said the child has to be
6-7 years old and no younger!
- Mr. Blasetti, she's 7.
- She's a little...
You find her small?
The dress makes her look small.
To tell the truth,
she hasn't grown much this year!
She will. For sure!
What are you going to do for us?
Do you dance? Sing? Or what?
- Venice.
- You're doing Venice!
Mr. Blasetti won't understand!
- The poem on Venice!
- Fine! Off you go!
- Do you want to hear it?
- Of course!
Venice, your final hour has come
Illustrious martyr, you are lost
The plague is spreading,
we are starving,
A white flag
is fluttering on the bridge
Did you teach her that?
She's a star!
She didn't recite it that well
even at Christmas!
Come on, don't waste time. It's 2pm.
If we get to the stadium late,
it'll be full,
we'll be standing like idiots!
Hurry up!
I've had enough,
I don't feel like coming.
What?
You're not coming to the match?
Bruno, did you hear him?
There's nothing odd about it.
I'm worried.
She's been out since this morning
and she has the child with her.
Why hasn't she turned up?
I'm not coming, don't insist!
She said: "I'm going to give
an injection in Monteverde".
Where do you expect her to go?
What's the point of going
as far as Monteverde to give shots?
It's Sunday and the tram
costs 20 cents each way,
and the child pays full fare.
Your wife is nuts!
Come on, Franco, drink your coffee.
See what you've done?
This idiot's always laughing!
- Drink your coffee!
- Can't you see it's boiling?
Mum, it's best not to fret over her.
- She does as she likes anyway.
- Make her respect you!
Right! Make her respect you!
Once and for all!
Do you know what I think?
She didn't go to Monteverde!
What are you saying?
She has your daughter with her.
That's the reason!
Because she has the child with her!
Come on! Let's go! It's 3pm
and we're still chatting! It's late!
Let's go, Spartaco! Hurry!
Give her another kiss!
Mum, you're always the same!
- I dropped food on myself.
- I'll clean you up. Bye!
- Won't you kiss my forehead?
- Bye! Don't catch too much sun!
- Don't worry!
- When you see Maddalena...
I'll tell her not to bring
the child with her any more.
- She hasn't eaten yet!
- Don't take it out on her.
I won't, don't worry.
Bye-bye. See you soon.
- Have a good time!
- Come on!
Spartaco! Your wife's there!
There she is!
- I want to know where you've been!
- Spartaco!
Slow down!
You're in such a hurry now.
- I did go!
- Where?
To Cinecittà,
for the film role contest!
- Are you crazy?
- Crazy or not, they picked her!
- Who?
- Our daughter, not me! If only!
Don't tell lies.
You're always telling fibs!
Leave her be, she always does what
she wants. And she's always talking!
Let's go, the match is starting.
Why don't you mind
your own business?
Don't you talk
to my brother like that.
I'm coming with you.
No, you go home
and feed the child.
- Your mother can do it.
- You feed her!
- Take me to the movies tonight!
- I'll give you the movies!
We'll discuss tonight.
Let's go, Franco!
- What needs discussing?
- She's always talking!
- Cut it out!
- Bye, Maddalena.
We're going to the movies, right?
Be serious and take the child home
to feed her!
You grouch! Come on! Bye!
Two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
Mrs. Molteni!
What do you want, Maria?
I can't hear you! Shout louder!
They start waking people up
very early in the morning, dammit!
What do you want, Maria?
- Is my mother up there?
- No, she's not here, Maria!
She's at Margherita's giving her
an injection. I'll call her.
Mrs. Maddalena!
- What's up?
- Maria's looking for you!
- Who?
- Your daughter's looking for you!
What do you want?
Mummy, there is a lady
who wants coffee!
- I can't understand you! What?
- A lady wants coffee!
You're holding me up. I'm giving
an injection. I'll be right down.
Be good, now!
Thank you so much, Madam.
Mummy's on her way.
She's giving a lady an injection.
You see this egg?
God sees and provides.
- Your daughter's been calling you.
- I know!
Is she ill?
She's fine, she was picked!
We're going to the photographer.
When are you going to have
this baby? Hurry up!
You're always on the stairs.
Go home!
Mrs. Gisella, please, ask your
daughter to do Maria's homework.
We're going to the photographer's.
She was picked! Bye-bye!
She's mad! That fanatic!
For heaven's sake, don't choke!
Is this the lady
who wanted some coffee?
Do excuse me. I had
a sort of cramp in my stomach.
I asked for a drop of coffee.
We don't have any. We do have
some eggs, but I see that...
- They're better.
- Yes, I know they're better.
- Excuse me, but who are you?
- How silly of me, you don't know me.
I'm Tilde Spernanzoni.
The actress.
- What?
- The actress.
I've given up the stage now,
I'm tired.
When you get to a certain age,
you have to rest.
Anyway, you have to make way
for the young.
I do a little film work.
Mummy!
- The lady drank an egg.
- It doesn't matter. Don't worry.
Little blabbermouth!
This is the child who was chosen
for the second test?
Dear lady, who sent you here?
Cinecittà? Stella Film? Who?
No one.
Someone must have sent you.
You're wasting my time!
An acquaintance gave me the names
of the ones who were chosen.
She's pretty, very pretty.
Take my hand, dear.
Give me your hand. Good girl!
While Mummy's making some coffee
with lots of sugar,
you'll recite something for me.
It's nice here! You have a garden!
Wonderful! Will you come with me?
- Let's go into the garden.
- Yes, it's a real palace!
Thank goodness we're moving.
Where are you going?
I've already asked
and she doesn't need lessons.
They want her just as she is,
provided she's bright
and intelligent. Look at her face.
My daughter doesn't need coaching.
Anyway, we can't afford it.
I see, but for our children
we can make sacrifices.
- But...
- Our children are our children!
Come here, dear, come here!
Have you turned up to teach me
how to bring up children?
You're holding us up.
We're going to the photographer.
How else can I put it to you?
Be reasonable!
- You'll go there later.
- What?
Where are you going?
Maria, recite
"The final hour of Venice".
She'll be satisfied and we can go!
What a clever girl!
Say "The final hour of Venice".
- I want to hear that poem.
- Who ever sent her here?
Who ever sent that mad woman
to my house?
You come home happy and
you find a mad woman in the house.
"I'm an actress..." She tells you
her life history. "I'm retired..."
I've so many problems of my own,
I'll give her coffee so she'll go.
How much time we're wasting here!
"I'm tired", "Now I'm teaching"...
But she's far from being mad!
You're tired,
but you drank three eggs!
What bad manners! How uncouth!
I'd best lock the meat up.
Now, we're wasting half an hour
to let her hear a poem?
It's simply incredible!
We'll miss our appointment
with the photographer!
Have you nothing better to do?
In this heat!
It's nice and cool at the park!
Instead of drinking others' eggs!
This really bothers me!
I can't accept it!
- Excuse me! Listen!
- Is the coffee ready?
I'm making it. Do you want it sweet?
With lots of sugar?
The little girl is talented.
But she'll get to poetry later!
Now, it's too soon.
It's tiring for her.
I'll teach her something myself.
We'll find a suitable,
quiet spot. Let's see.
Here we are! Take my hand, dear.
Come with me.
Come with me, here we are!
You'll see what I have to teach you.
This is an ideal spot.
Come with me. Good girl!
Imagine you're in a meadow,
a large, green meadow
that's cool, like here.
You're here to pick strawberries.
Excuse me! Excuse me!
She's even deaf.
The first exercise is
in role-playing.
Imagining yourself in a situation.
Do you like strawberries?
So you're happy
to pick strawberries.
Oh! Look how many strawberries
there are under that oak!
She's mad!
Where can she see an oak?
Run, run! Pick them! Go on!
Bend down, there's a good girl.
Pick them! There are so many!
Look how many there are!
And that silly girl listens to her.
Excuse me,
but you're sapping her brain.
Maria, what are you up to?
What are you doing?
She's picking strawberries,
isn't she?
Can't you see
she's picking strawberries?
Give it to me. What a lovely one!
Bend down and pick it, dear.
You see?
- They don't understand anything.
- If she doesn't leave...
Maria, hurry!
How long does it take you
to come here, sweetheart? Hurry!
Come on, you're making me late.
She drove us both crazy.
Who is that woman?
You must only listen to Mummy.
You're making me late! Come on!
Goodness me...
Wash your hands.
Wait! Let Mummy pour the water.
Pick up the soap! Be quick!
Look what a state you're in.
Where did you go, in the coal shed?
Oh, what a slowcoach!
Can't you go any faster?
Now, rinse your hands properly.
Give your face a wash too.
Look what a state you're in.
Hurry, while Mummy gets ready.
How odd that woman is!
"Honey, pick the strawberries".
She was just pretending!
She was teaching you to act.
Yes, right, to act.
What is there to acting?
If I thought I was someone else,
if I pretended
to be someone else,
I'd be acting.
You're not interested, are you?
It's like when you say that poem,
the one about the butterfly.
"I'm a butterfly,
half white and half yellow."
The one you recite with
your hands like that! Show me!
I'm a butterfly,
half white and half yellow.
How do you move your hands?
My goodness!
You see that you can act!
You see you can act too?
But don't stutter, sweetheart,
otherwise they won't pick you?
You must speak without stuttering.
Do you understand?
Picking strawberries...
Listen to your Mummy.
All the mothers in this block
make me laugh:
"My daughter, my daughter..."
They don't have what it takes!
You're my daughter,
you certainly can be an actress!
You can be an actress, you know?
I could have, if I'd wanted to.
Come here and let me fix your hair.
What a mess you're in!
How would you look
with a centre parting?
Oh, Lord! You look ugly like that!
No, let's leave it.
All combed back, like Mummy!
Let's see.
Let's see how you look.
My beautiful potato!
Let's fix your plaits.
Let me see.
These plaits!
But... But you're cute!
You look pretty like that!
You look simpler and more natural.
Today, we'll just do the photo.
We can't afford anything else.
Understood? Understood?
Mummy, am I going back
to school tomorrow?
Oh, my Goodness! You're stuttering
and lisping. What are we to do?
Repeat it.
Louder!
What are you up to?
Are you doing it on purpose?
You never stuttered before.
You never lisped.
Pronounce it properly.
You can't speak Roman dialect
if you want to be an actress!
What's happening here?
Come here, next to Mummy.
This is a problem a real problem.
No, no, without lisping!
You're making me lisp too!
What's going on?
Here! Take your shoes
and go and get dress in there.
Put on your socks and shoes.
Then put on the dress
that's on the coffee table.
Don't toss your hair!
Do you have to stand there every
time I open the window? Scram!
What a brazen boy! At his age!
What a house this is! It's crazy!
They come right into your flat!
I'm lisping too! Really!
What's going on here?
Are you ready?
Don't toss your hair putting on
your dress, or you'll get a smack!
That's too high a pitch! Ready?
We have to do everything
in a hurry...
You're still there!
You're bothering me.
Supposing that mad woman's right?
Maybe you do need to study...
Is lisping a family trait?
Are you ready?
What's she like?
Show me.
There she is! Just a moment.
- What pose are you putting her in?
- This one. How's that?
That's not suitable!
- Put her in the tomboy one.
- Don't interfere!
Sorry. My wife's been an invalid
so long, she likes to get involved.
Let's hurry, now!
Would you like to choose a pose?
- Now, poppet, sit up straight!
- Put her in the pose I suggested!
I thought you knew each other.
That would be normal,
both here for the contest
and acquaintances of Annovazzi.
Me? I hardly know him.
Lift up your chin, won't you?
Come on!
Lift up your chin!
Keep your head straight!
I met him at Cinecittà
and he was interested in my girl.
Look over there, over there.
Don't cry!
Mummy's sweetheart!
Let's take a nice picture.
It was he who advised me
to come to you.
Because he particularly liked
her eyes.
Why are you crying, sweetheart?
Poor thing, she's not used to this
and she's a little scared!
Smile, come on! Smile!
Your daughter takes ballet classes.
They have to dance in the film.
- Not at all! Who said it?
- I thought they did!
Because one of the little girls
I photographed
was from the Opera school.
- The Ruskaja School.
- No, the Opera school!
- The Ruskaja School!
- That woman!
Excuse me, but are you sure
they have to dance?
In the novel the film is based on
the little girl dances.
I've read it!
That's exactly how it starts!
I do believe you're mistaken.
I don't want to insist.
It starts with her saying
she can't stand it any more.
Yes, it starts like that,
then the girl dances around
the table on her birthday.
No. She tells him she's leaving him.
He wants to kill her.
The girl is very happy
because it's her birthday.
She's cheerful and dances and hops,
there's a cake on the table!
In the book, the girl dances!
Excuse me.
Anyhow, if they can dance,
it'll be for the better, won't it?
No, she doesn't have to dance!
- Ready?
- Wait! I just need to settle her!
- A big smile!
- Please step aside!
A big smile! Look at the camera,
he'll take a nice photo of you!
There we are!
- You nearly set me on fire!
- It all went fine!
The bang will have frightened her
and she'll have closed her eyes!
No, they were wide open!
- Did you watch them carefully?
- Don't worry!
- They're what I'm worried about!
- I'm busy now.
- I'm the photographer!
- No need to lose your patience!
Now it's the turn of the pretty girl.
- How did you have your eyes?
- Open.
You tell so many lies.
Were you feeling afraid?
We risk wasting time
and money here. Excuse me...
When shall I come
for the negatives?
- This evening. Tomorrow, rather.
- This evening, please!
Why not yesterday?
I can't do them for this evening!
- Come tomorrow, they'll be ready.
- You're so kind!
Do you want to take it home?
Mummy will get you one like it!
It's really late, now.
Daddy will be starving!
- Goodbye! Thank you.
- Goodbye.
You know what the photos are for.
I'm in your hands!
Don't worry.
- Don't worry about a thing.
- Say goodbye to the gentleman!
Are you ready for your shot?
- Yes I am!
- So am I, I'm almost ready.
- Thank goodness.
- Decide where you want to have it.
I have. On the right again.
Always on the right!
You're full of holes there!
It hurts on the other side!
Very well. The right side it is!
But if it hurts, don't complain!
- What is it? Penicillin?
- No, we've finished with that.
You've had 8 million shots.
- So what are you giving me?
- We're back on Balerofosforo!
- I've had a whole box of that!
- You need another. You're run-down!
Look at the white of your eyes!
You're heavy,
but you have no strength!
Let's hope it helps!
What a chatterbox! I'm wasting time
here and I've so much to do!
Are you ready?
I must ask you for a favour.
- May I make a phone call?
- Of course! Naturally!
You're still lying there?
Come on! Show me where you want it!
I must phone my daughter.
We had the photos done!
They came out very well.
Don't hold me up, now!
Come on! Turn over!
Careful with that
or you'll set fire to the bed!
Hurry up! Turn over!
- Come on, skinny!
- Don't hurt me!
You're nice and plump!
Who enjoys all this abundance?
- Relax your leg.
- Don't hurt me!
Don't delay me. I must stop in on
the Commendatore.
- What's he got?
- Diabetes.
- He's worse off than you.
- That's life!
You'll get it too if you go on
eating, smoking, drinking...
They're vices.
I can't give them up.
- You're mad! Relax this leg.
- All right, but don't hurt me!
You hurt me!
You make me break out in a sweat
every time I give you a shot!
You didn't even feel the needle!
I have a very light hand!
The Commendatore, the diabetic,
says he only has his shots from me.
- He's in love with you!
- What do I care?
As long as he has his injections.
There you are, as good as new!
Rub the spot yourself.
I need to make that phone call.
- Go on, then!
- Thanks.
If you don't mind,
I'll move the phone over there.
All this stuff is open.
I don't want to spill anything!
- Come in!
- Are you expecting company?
It's my breakfast.
- Lord! You're having four eggs?
- I have to keep my strength up!
Your liver must be bombproof!
- What's she got to complain about?
- Who knows!
- Do you want an injection as well?
- No, I don't need one, do I?
- You do! You do!
- I don't need any injections.
You do! Can't you see how fat
you are? I'll help you slim down!
- She's huge! Where did you find her?
- Who knows?
Hello! Mrs. Gisella?
Listen, this is Mrs. Cecconi.
Would you do me a favour?
Thanks. My little girl
is in the courtyard.
Would you please tell her...
No, don't bother to go down.
Call down from your balcony
and tell her
that I'm not coming and
she is to carry on with her lesson.
What do you mean, what lesson?
Acting! She's with her teacher.
Right! And tell her we'll collect
those things tomorrow.
We've even crossed paths
with a black cat!
Has he died by any chance?
- Who is it?
- Oh, you've answered at last!
- It's me, Mrs. Cecconi!
- Oh, right! Sorry!
She's locked herself in.
- Do come in!
- Another black cat!
- Don't be afraid. Come in.
- No. How is the attorney?
- Oh Lord, another one!
- Well, actually...
He's not well.
He has a fever again.
The doctor says he has
to go back to taking
the streptomycin every 12 hours.
And not to stop
even if his fever goes down!
- Of course he shouldn't!
- This was to be your last visit.
But you'll have to come back,
my dear.
- Thank goodness for that!
- What do you mean?
No, I meant for him, poor man!
I'll be right there. Just a moment.
I'll get my syringe and go through.
- Quietly, please.
- I'll walk on tip toe!
How could I do otherwise?
He's unwell, fortunately!
In five days, I'll pay for her dress.
Thank you, St. Joseph!
You're so kind to me!
I'll light a candle to you, later.
Eleonora!
What are you up to? We've been
waiting for you for an hour!
- Just a moment! Here I am!
- Don't keep the lady waiting!
This is all the tulle I've found!
But the storerooms are full of it!
You're making me look bad!
- That's all there is!
- Nonsense!
Look, Madam.
- Do you like it, Madam?
- Lovely! Just like a cloud!
- Let me feel it, Miss!
- Here!
A little hard, isn't it?
It's a pre-war fabric.
I'll sell it to you cheap.
- This is better.
- At cost price!
- This is nice and soft.
- You see?
This is the pattern
with a fluffy tulle skirt!
It's a classical tutu with
a sleeveless satin bodice.
- I see.
- Have you seen "The Red Shoes"?
I'll make it identical to that one.
Don't worry! You'll love it!
How pretty you'll look!
Here! Do you like it?
It's the price that worries me.
Don't worry! I'll ask a fair price!
Since I'm a little short after
all I've had to spend on her,
at times, you never know,
one can think that...
I'm a nurse,
should you ever need shots!
Dear lady, are you joking?
If there's one thing I enjoy,
it's really good health!
You don't have shots
only when you're at death's door!
You have them when you're well,
as a tonic, to give you a boost!
- Are you here to bring me bad luck?
- You've misunderstood.
Maybe at home you've a relative
who needs a course of treatment.
What? I'm fine as I am
without you making holes in me.
And my family too. Right, girls?
Tell her we're bursting with health!
You can't get round me, you know?
Come here, dear. I'll measure you.
Come on!
She's cute!
She's about my daughter's age.
- Yes, she's very young.
- Right!
Oh, goodness!
Excuse me, but must she always
stay so close to the wall?
She'll hurt herself like that!
Don't worry! She won't hurt herself!
It takes time.
We're in a hurry! Why doesn't she
put her with the others?
Aren't I right?
Always stuck to the wall?
Excuse me, does my daughter always
have to stay stuck to the wall?
It's been three hours.
Put her with the others!
But they've been studying
for two or three years.
You marched in here saying:
"Make her dance like a butterfly".
Where's your common sense?
You're asking for a lot!
That child is very small!
She isn't old enough for ballet!
- How old does she need to be?
- Eight!
Am I supposed to wait three years?
Do as you think best!
Anyway, her little legs...
Her legs? Look at them closely!
Her legs are as straight as a dart!
Straight legs are not enough!
You need other things.
You need intelligence. You dance
with your brain, not your feet!
What?
You dance with your brain,
not your feet!
She has a good brain. She was born
healthy, she wasn't born backward!
That's your opinion!
You're getting on my nerves!
We're the teachers! We decide
if a child is intelligent or not.
I decide because I'm her mother!
I assure you
my daughter is not stupid!
Sweetheart,
why are you crying like that?
They're not going to hurt you.
You too will become a good dancer.
Look at that girl!
How good she is!
Look! Can you see her?
Do you want to become like them?
You'll learn to be good too!
Did you have to make her cry?
How rude you are!
We're going home now.
Give Mummy a nice smile!
Don't let Daddy see you crying!
Let's go home! Come on!
Naturally, the child is rather
disheartened now,
but I must make it clear that
here, we study, study, study.
I've been dancing for 40 years,
but if I didn't practice daily,
these arabesques,
these temps levés...
You see these steps?
I couldn't do them!
You tell her, Placida!
Unfortunately, it's the truth,
you have to study
and sweat, sweat, sweat!
That's the way it is!
Hello, Spartaco.
Now you go out after dinner?
And you take the child with you?
What could I do? You weren't here.
Was I to leave her on her own?
- Where have you been?
- Giving injections.
- Say hello to Daddy, won't you?
- Hello, Daddy.
Daddy's little darling!
Give Daddy a kiss!
- Maddalena!
- Yes?
The instalments aren't
60,000 lire, but 65,000.
How come?
The lift has to be paid for.
We didn't include it.
Everyone's paid for it,
and so will we.
What happened to you, poppet?
- Tell Daddy what happened.
- I'm tired.
Daddy's little sweetheart!
This is the new house
that Daddy has bought you.
We're putting your bed here.
And Daddy will buy you a Pinocchio.
Do you know the story of Pinocchio?
The boy whose nose grew longer
because of all the lies he told.
He lied to his father,
an old man who...
There's only 60,000 lire here.
I don't have another cent.
How will we manage?
Spartaco, do we absolutely have
to pay the instalment on Monday?
Yes, on Monday.
We're only 5,000 short.
You'll just have to ask
for some arrears!
Didn't you feed the little one?
So now I'm starving her!
That's all we need!
She had a cup of coffee and milk
and two buns. Tell him!
- That wasn't much!
- Tell him!
- Leave it!
- Mummy will undress you.
- I'll do it!
- You'll tear her dress!
There! You undress her.
Daddy will put you to bed.
Tomorrow, I'll take her out
and buy her a big ice cream.
Ice cream's bad for her tummy.
- Maddalena, go away!
- You know I do whatever you say.
See how tired the child seems!
Look!
What do you want from me?
How pretty you are.
The baby of the family!
Do you love your Daddy?
Give me a kiss and a pinch.
Tomorrow Daddy's taking you
for an ice cream all the same.
Are you happy?
- So, are you coming?
- I have a lesson tomorrow!
No, you're coming with Daddy.
No lessons!
Give Daddy a kiss.
Be good! Go to sleep now.
I'm turning off the light.
You see? It's Montgomery Clift.
He's nice, isn't he?
Maddalena,
forget about the cinema!
Spartaco, you don't understand me!
Look what lovely places!
Look where we're living.
When I see those things, I...
- Maddalena, it's all make-believe.
- It's not make-believe!
Oh! Look!
They're taking the wagon across!