SHAW BROTHERS (HK) LTD.
A SHAW STUDIOS PRODUCTION
TIANDAO MANOR
You really heard
Du Tiandao wasn't home?
I'm certain of it.
Who dares break into Master Du
the Black Tiger's manor?
The Three Tigers of the South.
We are here for Du Tiandao.
- Let's go!
"The chirping of songbirds fills the air
after a night of roaring wind and rain..."
This is Du Tiandao's wife.
And that's his son.
- Seize them.
- No, stop! Stop!
- No!
- Should we kill them?
I heard that Du Tiandao has a steward
called Wan skilled in martial arts.
- Why hasn't he shown himself?
- Perhaps he left with Du Tiandao.
Since we are here,
let's get it over with.
However, killing a defenseless woman
and child seems...
Du Tiandao thinks he's a great hero.
Let's use his wife and his precious son
to leave him a surprise.
Yes! Let's chop off his wife's legs
and his son's arms.
Very well.
Mother! Mother!
Father!
CHEN KUAN-TAI
- Du Tiandao?
- Are you the Three Tigers of the South?
You threaten women and children.
You don't deserve that name.
Each of you will die from one
of my Black Tiger's Three Styles.
Watch carefully,
this is "Black Tiger Emerges"!
Winged Tiger!
Windmill Style!
Steward Wan?
Father, Mother is dead.
Father, they cut off my arms,
but I did not beg them for mercy.
Good.
I will spare no expense
to hire skilled craftsmen
to build a pair of iron arms for you.
You will train in martial arts again
and become invincible.
LU FENG
(AS AN ADULT)
See? I did not lie to you.
I finally found an expert craftsman
to create a pair of iron arms
that can be controlled at will.
Yes, seven pairs in total
have been made,
but this pair works the best
and can even shoot concealed weapons.
I am known for my Black Tiger Fist Style.
- Practice it diligently.
- Yes.
Do you remember that I used each
of the Black Tiger's Three Styles
to kill the Three Tigers of the South?
The Black Tiger's Three Styles
is the essence of the Black Tiger Fist.
Let us see if you can unlock its power.
Black Tiger Emerges!
Winged Tiger!
Windmill Style!
These are the descendants
of the Three Tigers of the South.
I allowed them to grow up
and practice martial arts
before I captured them.
This is my son, Du Chang.
Your fathers cut off his arms
many years ago.
All of you are martial artists.
I will set you free
if you can defeat him.
I will not hunt you down.
I will not interfere in the fight.
Du Chang, I have already
avenged your mother
by killing the Three Tigers of the South.
They spared your life.
Therefore, you must just cripple
their descendants.
Yes.
- Now, untie them.
- Yes, sir.
Untie them.
The Three Tigers of the South
cut off my son's arms.
I will have each of their descendants
become cripples as well!
Although my son doesn't have arms,
he is still skilled at martial arts.
He's a natural.
There are plenty of people who deserve
to be crippled more than him!
LILU'S INN
Bring the meat over, quickly.
Please enjoy.
- This way, sir. Come this way.
- All right.
Have a seat.
PHILIP KWOK
What would you like?
- Some wine first.
- Yes, sir.
Master Du is here.
Sir, stand up. Quick, stand up.
Who is he?
The famous master of Tiandao Manor,
Master Du the Black Tiger.
And that is the young master.
And his steward Wan.
Master Du...
- Young Master Du.
What is the matter with your hands?
Are you mocking him for having no arms?
What?
Calm down!
LO MENG
Hey, what's going on?
Why is that man so full of himself?
Do you have a death wish?
Those two are very lucky.
If Master Du had acted,
the result would've been much worse.
- Sir, have a seat.
- All right.
Master Du, we are sorry!
Hey! What has this world come to?
It's like people have seen a ghost
when they see those two!
Sir, sit down. Don't be angry.
Don't be angry.
Sit down.
Such tyrannical behavior
will be punished by Heaven!
Let's leave.
His wife was murdered
and his son's arms were chopped off.
So just because he knows martial arts,
he takes out his anger on other people!
What kind of man does that?
Others might fear you,
but I, Wei Datie, do not!
Innkeeper, bring me two jars of liquor!
Master, Young Master,
no need to be angry.
That lad's a blacksmith.
I know where his smithy is.
- We know where to find him.
- Heaven isn't blind after all.
That man delivered
a very satisfactory tongue-lashing.
Heaven is blind.
Master Du, that fellow is also blind.
Yes, you too are blind.
Master Du, he is a trader
from another town.
He doesn't understand...
- Your hands...
- I have no hands, and you have no eyes.
- So we're even.
- How do I not have eyes? I...
WEI DATIE'S SMITHY
A hit here and there,
and they were all down.
What is there to be afraid of, right?
Then what? What happened next?
Hey, I gave Du Tiandao and his son
a piece of my mind earlier.
- Aren't you afraid he'll give you trouble?
- I'm not afraid!
The worst that can happen
is that he'll kill me.
If nobody is afraid of him,
will he kill everyone?
- Steward Wan.
Wei Datie,
Master Du has invited you over.
What for? Does he like
hearing me tell him off?
Will you accept or not?
I will if you ask me nicely.
Otherwise, no chance!
Wei Datie, do you think
you can win against Master Du?
- I'll fight him with all my might!
- Master Du won't fight you.
He is inviting you over for a drink.
- Didn't you say you aren't afraid of him?
- Of course I'm not afraid.
Let's go, then!
Datie is an honest fellow.
Steward Wan, please just spare him.
I'm not afraid of them.
It's no use begging them anyway.
Let's go.
I can walk on my own.
You'll regret it if you push me again.
I'm here. What do you want?
Do you like insulting others?
I don't insult people
unless they're tyrannical lowlifes.
Master Du is offering you a cup of wine.
- What's in the wine?
- A drug that will turn you mute.
You'll never be able
to curse others again. Drink it!
I refuse!
Du Tiandao, you have no morals!
Throw him out!
Du Tiandao, you are a cowardly bastard!
You will meet a tragic end!
Heaven will punish you!
Are you still talking?
THE WHOLE WORLD
WILL CURSE YOU
Very well.
The whole world can curse me.
You would love that.
Too bad you won't be able to hear it!
WEI DATIE'S SMITHY
- Wei Datie!
- Wei Datie, what happened?
- Tell us!
- Say something.
- Can you hear me?
- What's the matter?
- What happened?
- Why aren't you saying anything?
- Say something!
- Wei Datie?
Be careful.
Sir, I would let you stay,
but you have offended Master Du.
I am old and weak. I wouldn't dare...
I understand.
Oh, by the way, where does
that outspoken blacksmith live?
You had better leave.
They have turned Wei Datie
deaf and mute.
- You take care.
- Thank you, thank you.
Take care.
Careful!
Go slowly.
Thank you, thank you.
Be careful.
You... I am blind.
Are you also blind?
Are you mute?
You are also deaf?
You are Wei Datie!
Get lost! Leave now!
- I will hire another assistant!
- Fine, I will leave!
SUN CHIEN
Someone as harsh as you
will die a horrible death!
Someone as poor as you
deserves to starve to death!
I am an able-bodied man!
You will starve to death before I do!
Does being able-bodied mean you don't
have to look where you are going?
I was talking about myself, not you.
I didn't know you were behind me.
You weren't looking...
Du Chang, he isn't worth it.
Killing someone like him
is like killing a dog.
All right, I will let you vent your anger.
Tell me what you want from him.
He bumped into me.
He walks without taking care.
So chop off his legs.
Do it.
WEI DATIE'S SMITHY
Datie says not to be afraid.
He can support us.
We are all disabled.
What other option do we have?
So? How do you like life
as a deaf-mute?
Listen.
Whoever makes a purchase
from Wei Datie's shop
should fear for their life!
CHIANG SHANG
The blacksmith just went out of business.
I need a blade made.
Is there another blacksmith in town?
No.
Why did the blacksmith close?
This is strange.
I asked for directions
to the smithy on my way here.
How come everyone acted
as oddly as you're doing now?
Sir, you aren't from around here.
You don't understand the situation here.
The poor blacksmith...
Go away!
Which one of you is Wei Datie?
Run!
- I can't believe such a thing could happen.
- Thank you, sir.
You must not be from around here
since you helped us.
Is he the blacksmith?
Don't worry. I will avenge you,
and rid the world of this evil.
LILU'S INN
TIANDAO MANOR
Come out, Du Tiandao!
Are you Du Tiandao?
How dare you call Master Du
by his full name!
I am Du Tiandao.
How are you related
to the Three Tigers of the South?
The Three Tigers of the South?
My name is Wang Yi.
I've heard of your atrocities,
how you crippled innocent men.
I have come to rid the world of you!
Where did this insolent fool come from?
- Get him!
- Yes, sir!
Father, allow me.
Kill me if you must.
Someone will avenge me if I die.
Whatever torture you subject me to,
I won't so much as furrow my brow!
Du Tiandao, you terrorize innocent people
because your son lost his arms.
Heaven will punish you!
- What is your name?
- I already told you. My name is Wang Yi.
You remember your own name.
I'm not an idiot. Why wouldn't I
remember my own name?
Father, he said he wasn't an idiot.
- For now, he isn't.
- What? You...
Du Tiandao, you...
Sir, are you all right?
Hu Agui, what happened to him?
- Is he injured?
- I don't know.
Sir, are you...
"Sir, are you..."
WEI DATIE'S SMITHY
This is rather fun!
Sir, what is your name?
"Sir, what is your name?"
Hu Agui, this person is an idiot.
Do you have the wrong person?
You should recognize his voice.
- What is your name?
- This hero tried to avenge us.
He fell victim to Du Tiandao
and his son's cruelty.
This is fun!
I wonder what they did
to turn him into this.
This is boring.
Hey, what are you doing?
I'm searching him for anything
that can tell us who he is.
We are the reason
he's in this state now.
We should at least find a way
to notify his family.
TO THE MASTER OF YING MANOR
There's a letter addressed
to the master of Ying Manor.
The letter is for this man's master.
Hey, let me push it.
Master Wang, we are taking you
to your master.
- Will you stop playing around?
- Are you talking to me?
Come on. Let's get going.
What happened?
Master Wang still knows martial arts.
Datie was beaten.
It will take at least a week
to reach his master.
What... What will we do?
Let's get going!
WINE
- Attend to the customers.
- All right.
What would you like to order?
- What would you like?
- Anything will do. He's blind.
- Be quick.
- All right.
Throw it at him.
Let's go!
This is bad. We should leave.
There'll be trouble if their parents come.
Hey!
Hey! Who hurt my son?
- It was him!
- Show me!
- He hurt us!
- Let's have a look!
YING MANOR
I've been here before.
Come on.
Thank you for escorting
my apprentice here.
We are the reason why Master Wang
has ended up like this.
Fortunately, we found
a letter on him addressed to you.
That is how we found our way here.
Du Tiandao the Black Tiger rose to fame
with his Black Tiger Fist.
He is considered a great hero
in the martial arts world.
I cannot believe he could be so cruel.
Get up.
I know what you want.
However, it is hard enough
for ordinary people to learn martial arts.
The three of you are...
No matter how difficult it may be,
I will turn you all into martial artists!
Since you are blind,
you must see with your ears.
You will have to practice
the art of hearing,
until you can detect
the subtlest of sounds.
Listen carefully now.
Wei Datie is deaf.
I am writing on his palm
and teaching him how to train his eyes.
You can use this method
to communicate with him from now on.
Do not let him push you around.
Kick him.
- But I am indebted to Master Wang.
- Do not worry.
He may be out of his mind,
but he still knows martial arts.
You might not be able
to land a kick on him.
Come on, push me.
Be quick to lift your leg. Use your hips.
Do not let your upper body sway.
Chen Shun...
Your hearing has greatly improved.
The technique I am teaching you now
will help you react more quickly to sounds
and allow you to be victorious,
so let's begin.
I quit. You are pretending to be blind.
You're pretending.
Come.
Come here.
Go.
Hu Agui, you seem to have taught
Wang Yi a lesson.
I'm sorry about landing
three kicks on him yesterday.
Now he runs away at the sight of me.
Hey, are you really blind?
Hey, train with me tonight.
No! It really hurts when you kick me
with your iron legs.
- He's here.
- Let's go.
This footwork technique
is most useful as a contingency
against a powerful opponent
such as Du Tiandao.
You are deaf and can't hear a thing.
You can defend yourself
in all directions with this technique.
You're the most fun!
The other two
either kick me or hit me.
You've been here for three years.
During these three years, our bodies
were broken, but our spirits were not.
- Thank you for teaching us, Master.
- You are right...
A broken body can be fixed,
but a broken spirit cannot be fixed.
Du Tiandao may have all his limbs,
but his spirit is already
damaged beyond repair.
Master, do you think the three of us
can rid the world of that scourge?
Over three years, the three of you
have shown great perseverance.
You are ready.
Stand.
From what I have heard,
Du Tiandao and his son have become
even more vicious in recent years.
They have gathered many strong men
and committed many atrocious acts.
For you, victory is not assured.
You must be careful.
The Black Tiger's Three Styles are
the most lethal martial arts techniques.
You must first understand
Du's fighting style
before devising a plan of attack.
Only then, will you stand
a chance of winning.
- Yes.
That is what I have heard,
but you will have to see
whether it is true.
Although he has crippled you,
he did not take your lives.
You can go there separately
to reconnoiter the situation
before deciding what to do.
I have also heard that
he will invite many martial artists
to celebrate his 45th birthday.
It will be a good opportunity
for you to observe him.
However, do not harm anyone
unless you are in danger.
- Yes.
YING MANOR
I will pretend to be a fortune-teller
and go first.
Wei Datie will be second.
Hu Agui will then come with Wang Yi.
Hu Agui and Wei Datie
will meet up at the smithy.
Wei Datie and I will meet up at the inn.
I will hang this banner
outside my room as a sign.
If I go out,
I will turn the banner around.
Everyone must arrive there
before Du Tiandao's birthday.
TIANDAO MANOR
DU
LONGEVITY
- Master Du.
- Where is Steward Wan?
He's gone to purchase some things
for your birthday from Fang the innkeeper.
LILU'S INN
Master Wan, these are all the items
you asked for.
Please have a seat.
Everyone, please have a seat.
Waiter, brew some fresh tea!
Have a seat.
- Use high-quality tea.
- Yes, sir.
FORTUNE-TELLING
- Hurry up, waiter!
- What would you like to order?
Why are you staring at me?
How did you know
I was staring at you?
Innkeeper, don't you think
that blind man looks familiar?
- That blind man over there?
- Yes.
He looks like the trader
who was blinded here three years ago.
- Yes.
- Go and warn him.
- Don't go dicing with death.
- All right.
Be careful.
Steward Wan of Tiandao Manor
is sitting over there with his men.
Gentlemen, would you like
to have your fortunes told?
Come here and tell me my fortune.
Blind man, sit down first.
All right.
Blind man, have some wine first.
There's no need to get up,
you'll be flat on your back soon.
Blind man,
where have I seen you before?
A noble man like Steward Wan
need not remember names.
Do you recollect what you said
three years ago?
"That fellow is also blind."
Yes, you are that trader!
You have a good memory, Steward Wan.
You weren't a noble to begin with anyway.
You are merely the head servant
at Tiandao Manor.
You must have a death wish!
Amazing. He's highly skilled.
Let's go!
There'll be trouble.
FORTUNE-TELLING
Master Luo, your skill is second to none
in the martial arts world.
You're too kind, Steward Wan.
These men have greatly improved
after training with you.
I would like to ask you
to take them with you
to deal with a certain matter.
Can you do that?
- Steward Wan, tell me what you need.
- Thank you.
A former enemy of Master Du
is staying at the inn now.
He is a blind man
and relies solely on his hearing.
Given your skill, you will surely
be able to capture him easily.
- Sure. When should I go?
- I think tomorrow would be good.
- Come on.
- Here, look.
- Well done!
- Amazing!
- Bullseye!
- Good job!
Steward Wan, even if the blind man
is a skilled martial artist,
he's no match for either of us.
Why don't you just teach him a lesson?
I am aware of that.
Even if he were up against you alone,
he would not necessarily win.
However, he would manage
to injure our men.
Then Master Du would find out.
The day after tomorrow is his birthday,
and I don't want to displease him.
So what are you planning?
It would be best
to take care of this quietly.
I believe that
with your martial arts skills,
combined with Master Lin
and his skill with projectile weapons,
dealing with the blind man will be easy.
Isn't that a better plan?
But is Master Lin willing?
Of course I am.
LILU'S INN
- Over here.
- Yes, sir.
Here, enjoy.
Cheers!
Innkeeper!
- Is that Wei Datie?
- Yes.
Wei Datie, are you looking
for the blind man?
He is staying here,
but he is out at the moment.
Wei Datie can't hear anything.
This way.
- Waiter, bring the bill!
- Coming!
- Steward Wan.
- Everybody out.
- And do not return for four hours.
- But Steward Wan...
- Leave!
- Get out!
Everybody, listen carefully.
When the blind man comes in,
do not move a muscle
or make a single sound.
He cannot see,
but his hearing is incredibly sharp.
He will surely return to his room.
When he reaches this spot,
Master Lin will first shoot him
from outside the window.
It would be best
if a single attack kills him.
But in case he manages to dodge it,
we all attack him at the same time.
If we catch him unawares,
we will surely succeed.
- Does everyone understand?
- Yes, sir.
Master Lin, please.
Master Du, there's a fighter
by the name of Ju outside.
Ah, very well.
He is my fellow apprentice.
This is his first visit.
Let's greet him.
Ju Gaofeng was my master's
last disciple.
He is skilled in martial arts
and gifted with astounding strength.
Go away.
Don't you see where you are? Get lost!
He's blind. How can he see?
Let him be.
Take pity on the crippled.
Ju Gaofeng!
Du Tiandao.
Go away.
- What's the matter?
- He's just a beggar.
Give him some money
and send him away.
Yes, sir.
This is my son.
His name is Du Chang.
- Greet Master Ju.
- Master Ju.
I came to wish you a happy birthday.
Thank you. Let's talk inside.
This is your first visit.
You must stay for a few days.
Withdraw!
That's very thoughtful of you.
Master Ju. He is Master Du's
fellow apprentice.
- Master Ju.
- This is Master Lin.
He is a renowned sharpshooter.
So you use concealed weapons.
With such a robust physique,
you must be incredibly strong.
You have no need
for projectile weapons.
A real man is open and above board.
I use physical martial arts.
Do you mind showing me
a few moves to enlighten me?
Very well. You shoot pellets.
What other weapons do you use?
The two of you are guests.
If you want to show off your skills,
I shall be your sparring partner.
Fine.
What weapon will you use,
Steward Wan?
This meteor hammer.
I hope I don't make a fool of myself.
Your meteor hammer is one of a kind.
That chain is long and thick.
You must have a special technique.
Feel free to demonstrate
and don't hold back.
Just hit me.
All right. Master Ju, it is an honor.
He's so strong!
My apologies.
He's very condescending,
just because he knows some martial arts.
He'll be taught a lesson one day.
He is Master Du's friend.
Out of respect for Master Du,
we cannot touch him.
Huh? Where's Luo Bao?
When you held him back
from fighting those two earlier,
he seemed displeased.
He might've gone after them
by himself.
Find Master Luo and ask him to return.
- Tell him I need to speak with him.
- Yes, sir.
Tomorrow is Master Du's birthday.
I don't want any trouble.
- I want to play.
- I want this one.
- Give it to me.
- I win!
- I got it!
- Come and play marbles with me!
- I'm done playing!
- Don't leave! Play marbles with me!
Don't run off!
LILU'S INN
WEI DATIE'S SMITHY
You... you...
Steward Wan, it's Master Luo...
- Who did it?
- Wei Datie.
Master Luo tried to ambush him,
but Wei Datie was wearing a mirror
around his neck and saw him.
He is deaf and can't hear someone
sneaking up on him.
That is why he wears a mirror.
- Very clever.
- What do we do now?
I'd held Luo Bao back.
I wanted to get this done quietly.
I didn't want to make a big deal of this
with Master Du's birthday coming up.
- Little did I know...
- So...
Now this has happened to Luo Bao,
we won't be able to keep it
from Master Du.
We will have to get rid of those two
before Master Du's birthday tomorrow.
- Then we can report to him.
- Let's hurry back and gather some men.
We'll get rid of these two men tonight.
We can't play it safe again this time.
Unfortunately, Ju Gaofeng snapped
the chain of my meteor hammer.
I wonder if he's fixed it yet.
- Where's Wei Datie?
- He returned to the inn.
That's what we will do...
LILU'S INN
- Master Ju.
- What's going on?
Is Steward Wan angry
that I broke his meteor hammer?
Of course not.
Two of Master Du's former enemies
are at the town's inn.
Steward Wan wanted to use this,
but we've been busy the past few days
and forgot to fix it.
- And where is this inn?
- It's the only one in town.
When you reach the main street,
you can't miss it.
Put out the candles.
Stop!
The deaf man won't be able to see
without candles,
but did it occur to you that
you won't be able to see either?
You wanted to attack
under the cover of darkness,
but you forgot one thing:
blind men aren't afraid of the dark.
Get out, you useless bunch.
You'll only get in the way.
Watch me deal
with these two cripples by myself.
Just make sure nobody escapes.
They gathered so many men
to deal with two cripples.
What an embarrassment!
I can give you an advantage
so people won't say
that I bullied two cripples.
I won't move from this spot.
I will allow each of you
three punches and three kicks.
Then I will counter
If you manage to make me fall over,
then you have my word that
Master Du will not bother you again.
But if you fail to make me fall over
and do not survive
my three punches and three kicks...
...then consider yourself out of luck.
- What do you say?
- You have a deal.
Now it is my turn.
Who will take my three punches first?
Wait!
The three of us are friends
who will live and die together.
Will you take my three punches
and three kicks before fighting back?
Very well.
Hey, big guy, don't fall for it.
His legs are made of iron!
Yes. He just took
Wei Datie's iron fists.
Now it's time for him
to experience iron legs.
Many people in the martial arts world
claim to have iron fists and iron legs.
But they are nothing special.
Come on.
Aren't you embarrassed,
delivering punches like that?
- Come on. Try with your iron legs.
- His legs really are...
Your legs really are made of iron?
A worthy opponent!
He truly was a formidable martial artist.
If he had known your legs really were
made of iron, I fear we would have...
The boy nearly let the cat out of the bag.
Luckily, your comment fooled him.
By the way, you and the boy
should hide in the room.
Nobody knows that you have iron legs.
It will be a useful advantage.
Get inside.
He's dead.
He was a good man.
Pity that he made friends with bullies
like you and met this end.
Out of respect to him,
I will let you take his body.
Be quick about it and leave.
After years with me, you should know
how to handle such difficult situations.
How did you let things end up like this?
Since your birthday is coming up,
I wanted to handle things quietly
without bothering you.
- I thought...
- Forget it.
What is done is done.
There's no point in discussing it further.
I will personally deal
with those two tomorrow.
- But tomorrow is...
- I know what tomorrow is.
I will kill those two first,
then return to entertain my guests.
Wei Datie saw Du Tiandao and Du Chang
heading here with a gang of men.
Take Wang Yi and leave out the back.
Don't let them see you.
- We'll meet up at the smithy.
- We should leave together.
We didn't know any martial arts
in our past.
We know nothing about Du Tiandao's
and his son's martial arts skills.
Wei Datie is only
testing the waters today.
We're not ready for the final attack.
It's best not to let them know
about your iron legs just yet.
- Come with me!
- I'm not leaving.
If you're not going,
we'll leave you here.
Hurry and go. Just leave him.
Who are you?
Where are the blind man
and the mute?
The blind man and the mute?
I'm not telling you!
Father, he's the one who came
to avenge them three years ago.
We injured his head.
He's probably...
Capture him first.
Come on.
He acts like an idiot,
but he still knows martial arts.
Be careful.
Du Chang...
He seems to be retarded,
there's no need to kill him.
What's with your hands?
Are those iron hands?
They hurt!
They're just like Hu Agui's...
He has iron hands.
Don't go head-to-head with him.
I have heard
of Master Du the Black Tiger.
We knew no martial arts before,
and didn't know who we were up against.
Today, we would like to experience
Master Du's Black Tiger's Three Styles.
- You two aren't qualified.
- Our master's name is Li Zhengying.
We are his humble disciples.
Wang Yi, our fellow disciple,
was injured by you three years ago.
Today, we ask to duel with you
to test whether
we have learned any skills.
Very well. So the idiot
is Li Zhengying's disciple?
You are all his disciples?
Then let's see how powerful
his martial arts are.
Watch out.
This is "Black Tiger Emerges".
Winged Tiger!
Windmill Style!
Hey, wait for me!
Let them go!
Our guests will be arriving,
we must return to the manor
to receive them.
Since they seek revenge,
they won't be going anywhere.
You are right, Master Du.
Today is your birthday.
Even if they don't come to us,
we'll be able to find them
as long as they're in town.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Boarding up the door.
Hey! Are you leaving me outside?
You can't!
Stop fooling around.
Even if we board up the door,
it makes no difference.
Du Tiandao knows we will be here
because we have nowhere else to go.
Then we should...
I don't think he'll come
looking for us right now.
Why is that?
Du Tiandao is ambitious and wants
to dominate the martial arts world.
He has invited guests from far and wide
to his birthday celebration.
His reputation is important to him.
He wouldn't miss the party
to go after a few insignificant cripples.
His guests would mock him.
He's probably guessed that
we can't escape. Nor shall we.
- He can still come after us later.
- So how do we deal with him?
Of course, there'll be a way.
Rather than wait for them
to come after us,
we should ambush them early in the morning
after they've had a long night.
LONGEVITY
- Cheers!
- Happy birthday!
- Thank you! Have a seat.
- Let's go.
- All right. I'll be right behind you.
Steward Wan, they've left the smithy
and are on their way here!
They're here.
Everybody, get ready!
Open the door.
Run!
Good! Very good!
Amazing!
Wang Yi didn't follow us here.
Remember,
keep Du Tiandao occupied.
Use what our Master taught you.
Do not fight him head-to-head.
Once we have eliminated Du Chang,
we will fight him together.
Playing alone is no fun.
Hey, I should find Chen Shun!
Chen Shun! Chen Shun!
Chen Shun!
Play with me too!
Come on.
His iron hands hurt me really badly!
Your legs are...
- Du Tiandao?
- Dead.