Venice
- Spring 1866
The last months of
Austrian rule in Venetia.
The ltalian government has
allied itself to Prussia
and the war of
liberation is imminent.
Foreigners out of Venice!
General La Marmora has
mobilised the army!
Long live La Marmora! Viva ltalia!
Viva ltalia!
Where are the
stewards? This is a disgrace!
Please go and see, General.
lf this continues, we'll have no
choice but to evacuate the theatre.
Please go and see, General!
How amusing. This is the kind
of war the ltalians prefer.
A shower of confetti to an
accompaniment of mandolins.
Coward! You're a coward!
l'm ready to prove that the
ltalians want to fight!
And if you are a gentleman...
Let me go! You have no
right to lay hands on me!
Viva ltalia! Power
to the ltalian Army!
- Where are you going?
- To the foyer. lt's terribly hot here.
l don't think this is the best time.
Leave me alone. You know
l always do as l please.
Even so, l won't allow
you to wear these flowers.
lt all began that evening.
lt was the 27th of May.
My cousin, Roberto Ussoni,
who'd been among the
organisers of this demonstration,
was also an important figure in the
Venetian underground movement.
l was terribly worried
he'd endangered himself
by challenging that officer.
l was already thinking
of ways to help him.
Roberto.
Livia.
lt was madness to expose
yourself like this.
You shouldn't have done it.
All l know is that l lost my
head. When that cad said those words...
- What will you do now?
- He has accepted my challenge.
At least, so it seems.
- We'll fight a duel.
- No, you mustn't!
To take on an
officer, in your position...
the consequences would be so...
Something must be done. Leave!
You must get out of
this theatre right away.
Go home.
Go there or to
Marsenza's, wherever you want...
Wait for me to get word to you.
l beg of you, Roberto, you must
be careful for everyone's sake!
l know. Don't worry.
But did you see?
They rose up tonight.
There's still a lot to
do, but they're stirring.
Let's go, Roberto. We'll
go by way of the pier.
- Farewell, Roberto. Go!
- Farewell, Livia.
- Go!
- See you soon.
This is La Marmora's statement. We
haven't published it in the newspapers.
lt's utter nonsense.
And it would only further
agitate the Venetians.
There are still people here who don't
think much of him and his provocations.
We are truly sorry to have
halted the performance, dear Count,
but we cannot allow La Fenice
to become a hotbed of sedition.
l wholeheartedly agree.
But please believe me, this must
be the work of some agent provocateur.
- There can be no doubt about that.
- Of course. lt has been a delightful evening.
Ah, Countess Serpieri.
There is going to
be a duel. l mean it.
They've challenged Franz Mahler.
Maybe they wish to recreate the
battle between the Horatii and Curiatii.
You are very close to the man who
made the challenge, Countess.
Please, Your Excellency, let us not
dwell on this unfortunate incident.
That young man is a distant
relative, but we never see him.
Aren't relatives the
people we all know least?
l know him very well.
This will be no battle between
the Horatii and Curiatii.
My cousin isn't
interested in politics.
He is completely apathetic...
when it comes to this
kind of thing, l mean.
He must have had other reasons.
That Lieutenant Mahler...
l have heard a lot about him.
This doesn't surprise me.
All the ladies in
Venice are talking about him.
There you are, the ladies
must have spoken of him.
That's how so many stories
are made up. lsn't that right?
ls this an officer under
your command, Your Excellency?
- Mahler? Of course.
- Yes, he is.
l would love to meet him.
Given that all the Venetian
ladies are talking about him,
l'd love to be able
to speak with him too.
Countess, this is a favour you
shouldn't request from one of your admirers.
Lieutenant Mahler is far
too dangerous a rival.
- Would you care to sit down?
- No, thank you, Your Excellency.
This isn't the first
time l've seen ll Trovatore.
Besides, Austrians love music.
We ltalians, on the other hand, come
to the theatre for very different reasons.
We have arrived;
There's the tower where the
State's prisoners languish.
Ah, the hapless man
was brought here!
Go...leave me,
and don't fear for me.
l can save him, perhaps
Fear for me?
Sure and ready is my protection.
- Shrouded in this dark night...
- Countess, Lieutenant Mahler.
Countess Serpieri.
l'm near you, and you don't know it.
- Would you care to sit down?
- Thank you.
Moaning wind,
you who blow here.
- Do you have a good view?
- lt's fine, thank you.
Do you like opera,
Lieutenant Mahler?
l am very fond of
opera, Countess Serpieri,
as long as l am fond of
that particular opera.
And you?
l'm very fond of it.
l simply dislike it taking
place off the stage.
l dislike it when
people act melodramatically
without considering
the serious consequences
of an impulsive action,
or of an action dictated by
unforgivable thoughtlessness.
May l speak to you very truthfully?
Please.
Honesty is the one
thing l appreciate.
lf l've heard aright...
a duel should take place
tomorrow. lsn't that so?
And it's up to you to accept or to
refuse this challenge - isn't that so?
l wish to know.
l wish to know as well.
Don't accept the challenge.
lt isn't right to
risk one's life for...
Why are you so
concerned about my life?
lt's a matter of principle.
Don't worry.
Neither my life nor your
principles are at any risk.
This foolish incident will
soon be dealt with by an arrest.
What do you mean?
..waken in him the memories...
What wonderful music.
Will you return tomorrow evening?
lf you'd allow me to...
l don't feel well.
l must go.
Please, don't move.
Good night, Your Excellency.
- Are you depriving us of you company?
- l don't feel well.
l'm so sorry.
Good night.
- Let's go.
- lf you don't feel well, we should wait a while.
- l said, let's go.
- As you wish.
Good bye! Why so soon?
Won't you come with us?
Your Excellency. Colonel.
They arrested Roberto as
soon as he left La Fenice.
That's impossible!
He was with Don? and
Meneghini. All three have been arrested.
We must do something, immediately.
Why don't you tell your
husband about it?
- lf he'll only look into it...
- Leave it up to me.
Go to Marsenza's.
l'll send you word.
But leave now. Don't take any risks.
- Good night.
Did you hear? They've
arrested Roberto.
Listen, l've never
asked anything from you,
but this time you have to
do something to free Roberto.
You can do this. You have
influence, you know people.
l'm sure that
lieutenant must have reported him.
- He didn't want to fight.
- Fair enough.
Why would an Austrian
officer fight an ltalian civilian?
lt would be absurd.
lf your cousin had a
modicum of good sense...
Can't you see what
the outcome might be?
Yes, l do. And l want nothing
to do with this matter.
They were right to arrest him.
And you'd like to involve me in
matters that don't concern me in the least?
l've had it. Don't mention
this to me again, do you understand?
lt's childish tomfoolery! What do you
all think you'll achieve, anyway?
Roberto was sent into exile for
a year, along with many others.
l had a strange foreboding about
what his departure would mean...for me.
Farewell.
l hope to see you
soon, my guardian angel.
Go to Aldeno as soon as you
can. Please tell Cavalletto.
We need secure lines
of communication.
l hope to come back soon.
Garibaldi is in Desenzano. Just
think, Livia, the time is nigh.
May we meet again as ltalians!
Roberto, take care.
But when l saw that officer again,
l understood that he was at
the root of all my fears,
and that for many days l'd been
apprehending a possible meeting.
Countess Serpieri.
What do you want?
- May l escort you?
- No, thank you, Lieutenant Mahler.
But there's a curfew
and it's already late.
Would you have me arrested because
l'm still walking about?
l've never had anyone
arrested over so little.
What do you think about
Roberto Ussoni's arrest?
Oh, so he's been arrested? l thought he was only
asked to go for a change of air for a while.
They sent him into exile,
as you know perfectly well.
You believe it's my
fault, but you're wrong.
l hope you believe me.
Besides, Ussoni will be pleased.
He was born to sacrifice
himself for a noble cause.
- And what were you born to do?
- To be what l am.
To be what you are... Good night.
Wouldn't it have been better if
you'd told me that first evening
that Ussoni was your lover,
and that you hoped l'd do
anything to keep him in Venice?
A true gentleman.
would not take advantage of the
fact that l'm alone to insult me.
- l have asked you not to follow me.
- But l'm not following you.
- So you're not following me?
- Consider me your shadow.
- Thank you, but mine will be enough.
- Mine will protect you much better.
Look, don't follow me!
- ls he dead?
- Yes.
How did it happen?
Come, quickly.
- What's this?
- Go and look.
He's dead! Quick, take him
away. Two men over here.
These damned Venetians. Every
night, they kill someone.
Go! Take him away! One either end.
Quick, quick!
Poor wretch. l knew him. He hadn't
been long in the Eighth Company.
Thank you.
You see,
it isn't very pleasant to be
part of an army of occupation.
You have to live among
men who hate you.
And since we're young, far
away from home, alone...
we end up courting their
wives, their girlfriends, and...
Yes, l understand.
Good night, Lieutenant.
l'm not afraid any more.
Please don't bother to walk me home.
Good night.
But there's
something l'd like you to know.
Roberto Ussoni is not my lover.
He's my cousin.
And he's the man l
admire most in the world.
Do you admire him more
than your husband?
My husband and l
have very different views
regarding the Austrians.
He's prepared to accept them, and
is willing to accept favours from them.
l'm like my cousin,
a true ltalian.
Good night.
Countess Serpieri.
We walked for a long time, together,
through the deserted streets.
My preconceptions had vanished.
Time stood still.
All that remained was
the hidden pleasure
of hearing him talk,
of hearing him laugh.
of listening to the sound of
our steps, in that silent city.
- Where are we going?
- Wherever you'd like.
l don't even know where we are.
- We've arrived somewhere.
- That's my house.
That's where l live.
Alone?
No, not alone, with other officers.
We often sit around in our
shirtsleeves, drinking beer, talking about women.
- But everything's about to change.
- Why?
Because l've met you.
- What have you found?
- A piece of broken mirror.
Why are you looking
at yourself so closely?
Are you that taken with yourself?
Yes. l never pass before a
mirror without looking at myself.
Why is that?
l like to look at
myself to make sure l am...
me!
ls that the only
way you can be sure?
Also when l see a woman
who is looking at me the way you're
looking at me right now.
''lt is Judgement Day
''the dead rise again...
''to eternal joy...
''or eternal suffering.
''And we remain in an embrace
''and nothing matters to
us, neither Heaven, nor Hell.''
- Do you like these verses by Heine?
- No.
- Why not?
- l don't like their meaning.
What a shame.
But with war about to break out...
You think there will be a war?
Yes. However strange it may be
that people will die over
matters that don't concern them.
Do you believe in war?
l believe that a country's
freedom should be defended
even if it costs you
your freedom or your life.
And so we shall be enemies?
l don't believe that.
l suppose it is a failing of mine
that l've never been
interested in war, in politics,
in the loss or gain of territory,
in all those terribly serious matters
for which men ought to be ready to die.
You see, l believe that even if one
man was born on this side of a river
and another man on the
other side of a mountain,
it doesn't mean God put the rivers and
mountains there to keep them apart.
You talk like a child.
How can you be a military
man when you hold such opinions?
lt seems absurd that
you're an officer.
Yes, l agree with you.
Everything's quite absurd.
l must go now. lt's almost dawn.
- Livia, that's your name, isn't it?
- Yes.
When can l see you again? Tomorrow?
No, that's impossible.
l'll wait for you.
By now it was dawn. The city
was coming to life again.
And l was beginning
to feel almost ashamed.
How could l have spent the
whole night with a stranger,
an Austrian officer?
l was an ltalian
woman, a married woman,
a woman who had never behaved
frivolously in her life.
And yet, four days later,
four days spent in the
vain hope of meeting him,
I was going to him.
l had managed to persuade myself
that he alone could help Roberto.
lt was my duty to ask him.
Not bad, eh?
Do you want a game?
l've been waiting for days...
and you've finally come.
Let us not bother
with heaven and hell.
From that day on, we often met.
We would go to a rented room that
Franz had found in the Fondamenta Nuove.
You see,
in these rooms, there is
always some little noise.
The swish of a curtain, a fly
banging against the window..
Had you ever noticed that?
No, Franz.
One notices it only
later, as a memory.
Only then does one remember having
heard it while in an embrace.
ls that so, Franz?
Later, you realise that
you'd heard it all along,
without paying attention.
But later...
this tiny detail becomes important.
Can a detail be that important?
lt's the sense of
adventure. lt's as important as...
As what?
The colour,
the scent of your soft
hair on the pillow.
Had you never noticed this, my love?
No, Franz, not until now.
l keep forgetting...
What?
l keep forgetting that the past doesn't
exist for Countess Serpieri.
There is only the
present, and the future.
Only the present, Franz.
Only today? Not tomorrow?
- Will you hand me that hairbrush?
- Yes.
You see, if they told me that
there would be no tomorrow for me,
that tomorrow would never
come... after a moment like this...
l would feel as if
a doctor had told me,
''You are about to die.
''You only have a few hours left.''
And now l know it's true.
lt is just now, just now,
Franz. There is no tomorrow.
Every time you leave, you say,
''Farewell, Franz, 'we
will never meet again''.
But each time, l wait for you with the
same confidence that you'll return.
You may think you will never see me again,
but l'll keep waiting for you.!
Maybe you will.
But you've had so many love affairs,
during which the room
was filled with sounds,
with the noise of a fly
banging against a window,
which you only noticed later on.
So you got up
and you gave that poor
insect its freedom,
with the same elegance with which you
freed yourself from the woman's heart.
But don't worry,
when it comes to us
you won't even have to
make that small effort.
l'll do it for you, Franz.
l'll get up, l'll open the window,
and l'll let your heart fly
out, as free as a butterfly.
Would you give me
those hairpins, please?
l will no longer be
acting as your maid.
You will have to get
your own hairpins.
Franz, remember me by this.
What a splendid medallion.
Keep it by your heart.
l'm leaving now.
l'm leaving.
Farewell.
Franz...
- Would you let me leave like this?
- No, my love...
l knew you wouldn't go.
One afternoon,
while l waited for him
in vain in that room,
l realised for the first time
that l wasn't in control of my
feelings, as l'd always believed.
l must go out, and
no one else is home.
Shall l leave the door
ajar or will you answer it?
Are you sure the lieutenant
hasn't left a message for me?
- A message?
- l'm sure, ma'am.
But perhaps you'd gone
out and no one was home.
What can l say? Maybe he's left.
There was a captain
who came here a lot
and he was suddenly transferred.
ln fact, you wouldn't happen to
know anyone who could help me?
They want to turn my house
into military accommodation.
Don't they have barracks for that?
Ma'am, see if you can help me. lt
would be in your interests, too.
l know you can do
anything, Countess.
l know you very well, you see.
One of my sisters spent
years working for...
You're leaving? But what if
the lieutenant should arrive?
Besides, Countess...
what if the lieutenant
has really left?
Who will settle his bill?
l've never said anything, because
l know him well, but...
think of all the
laundry l have to do.
Thank you, ma'am. That's better.
Excuse me, is
Lieutenant Mahler around?
ls he in Venice?
Yes, he's still in Venice..
- Do you know when he'll be back?
- l don't know, ma'am.
- l'll wait for him.
- Please do.
Do sit down.
Do you like our dwelling?
She won't say whether she likes
it, but she comes here anyway.
Two pairs of underpants,,
three shirts,
two smart shirts,
and two sheets.
Here you are! The gentleman
will come by tomorrow to pay his bill
But the lieutenant, didn't
he say where he was going?
How should l know?
- He didn't come back last night.
- He stayed out?
- All night?
- Probably not all night.
But he didn't come
back? You didn't see him?
How should l know? Perhaps
he was with Kati or with Nena.
Don't lie to me.
Well, if you want to
wait for him, please do.
Are you sure he's not nearby?
- Or in the barracks?
- Nothing's certain.
l can assure you of that.
ln fact, it's the one
assurance l can make.
But if you're patient... And since you're
a friend of Franz's, you must be.
Ludwig said he left
Franz an hour ago.
They were playing billiards together.
We don't know where he went after that.
Why can't you keep your mouth shut?
Pay no attention to him. He doesn't
know what he's talking about.
Why don't you sit down?
Franz will be here in a few minutes.
We never know what he's
up to, or where he is.
He's always out
somewhere. He's hard to pin down.
That's just the way he is.
We lived in the same
apartment for three months, once,
in lnnsbruck.
Girls were always coming
around to see him.
And even if he was
home, he refused to see them.
- Countess! We're leaving.
- What is it?
The count has ordered us to pack.
You must have misunderstood him.
What's happening here?
You could have told me about
this. Don't l matter at all?
The Prussians have invaded Holstein.
This means the war has begun.
- l think it would be wiser...
- No, it can't be!
This is so sudden.
- What do you want?
- lnstructions from the countess.
There's no hurry, Laura.
l was dismayed by my
husband's decision.
But l managed to convince him
to delay our departure by
at least twenty-four hours.
Lieutenant Mahler,
please, from the Eighth Company.
The Eighth Company is
no longer here, ma'am.
They're at the
Misericordia barracks.
Oh, Countess! l was
bringing you an umbrella.
The count told me to.
But l didn't know
where to look for you.
l thought l'd start out at
Countess Marcello's, or...
But you're all wet. What
terrible weather!
Even the sky has gone mad.
lt's the war's fault.
l remember as if it
were today that in '59...
The count was worried.
l said you must have had things
to do before the departure.
A man came looking for you.
l had never seen him before.
l didn't tell the count.
He said it was urgent, that
you had to go see him.
You have to go to Campo
San Gerem?a 349
and ring three times.
- When did he come? Who was he?
- l don't know him. You'd just gone out.
He wanted to go looking for you.
l'll be back later.
Give me the umbrella.
What shall l tell the count?
Whatever you want! l don't care!
l really don't
care! Tell him everything!
Tell him!
There was no call
for you to spy on me.
l'd have told you
myself. l'm tired of lying.
lt's true, l have a lover.
l love him. l want to be with him!
Livia, At last! We were
waiting for you. Come in.
Livia!
Livia, how wonderful. At last!
Oh, it's you. l didn't
know you were back.
You could have told me.
Livia, we were able to cross
the border last night.
l must get in touch with
our friends in Venice.
- There's no time to lose.
- Why didn't you trust me?
- She wanted me to believe that...
- You can't understand.
You can't understand.
l've already been
very clear with Livia.
Now l should tell you
what l said to her.
l have absolutely no
intention of accepting the position
the Austrian government has recently
insisted on offering me.
Livia, how are you?
l was born in Venice,
l was brought up here.
My business affairs are tied to
this city. My loved ones are here.
Now, it's clear that whatever
the outcome of this war,
Venice will go to the
ltalian government.
The French Emperor has
vouched for this.
As a result of all
this, l wish to help you.
You can trust me.
As you can see, mine
is a practical offer.
lt isn't dictated by enthusiasm or
by ideals and beliefs l don't share.
l understand.
And what do want in return?
l told you, l want to be
able to stay in my country
without being harassed.
- l can't promise you anything.
- l see.
But, one day, you could
testify in my favour.
...and a ruby ring.
A gold chain with a watch...
Livia, would you be prepared
to leave for Aldeno tomorrow?
Nothing would please me more. For
days, l've been telling Livia...
l know, it was my fault.
l wanted to wait for you.
l was sure that you would come back.
That's fine, Livia,
but now there's no time to lose.
l'll be leaving Venice tomorrow.
l must reach the
headquarters of the ltalian Army.
They'll instruct me on
the role of the volunteers.
We've set up a good communication
network. Luca is already in Aldeno.
l'll be there in four or five
days, if everything goes well.
You must take charge of
the money we've raised.
Give it to me,
Andrea. They need it urgently.
Our volunteers are living
off charity, like hermits.
lt's a decent sum.
You must have contributed as well.
No.
We've been waiting for
this moment for a long time.
And now it has arrived, it feels
like a surprise, doesn't it?
lt comes as a shock.
We must all behave as if the lives of
our fighters depend upon our actions.
We no longer have any
rights, Livia, only duties.
We must learn to forget ourselves.
l don't care if l sound
bombastic. ltaly is at war.
lt is our war!
Our revolution!
Roberto's words,
his trust in me,
had given me the courage to leave.
The first days spent in the
peaceful surroundings of our villa at Aldeno
reminded me of the
periods of convalescence
that follow a serious
childhood illness.
- Laura! Laura!
- Yes, l'm coming. Just a minute.
When the dogs started barking, l
noticed someone on the balcony.
l noticed someone on the balcony.
- l didn't hear a thing.
- Now be quiet. The countess is asleep.
- Who is it?
- lt's me. Laura.
- What is it?
- Countess, you must forgive me.
But the gatekeeper...
Yes?
...has seen someone on the balcony.
Countess!
He's sure he saw
someone on the balcony.
Yes, it was me.
- Have you lost your mind?
- Yes, in Venice, when you left.
- ls the door locked?
- The door...
- Laura?
- Yes, Countess.
lt was me.
- Go to bed.
- You see, you fool?
- Did they see me?
- What were you thinking?
How could you?
Why do you keep all those dogs? To keep
away your enemies or your lovers?
Why did you decide
to come here, Franz?
l didn't decide
anything. l just came.
l suddenly felt l had to
see you again, so l came.
Livia!
So you'd have me get torn
to pieces by your dogs?
No! No! No!
Go and hide over there.
Go, over there.
l... l don't believe you risked
your life just to see me again.
There was a time when l
would have believed you,
before you began to
miss our rendezvous,
before those agonising days
when l couldn't find you anywhere.
l am younger than
you, Countess Serpieri,
and not as smart as
l'd like to think.
When l began to realise that
l'd fallen in love with a woman
who would never be able to love me,
my first reaction was to disappear.
That's why you didn't see me again.
But it made no difference.
When l realised that you were
the one slipping away from me,
that you'd left Venice,
all l could think of
was to find you again.
You must have some other
reason l don't understand.
For what other reason would a
man risk his life to come here?
But can't you see? We're at war now!
War...
l'm so tired.
All l want is to look
at you, to be with you.
That's why l came, that's
all l can think about.
l would have believed you, once.
lf you don't believe
me, l'd better go now.
No, wait!
Wait.
Franz?
Come here, Franz.
Franz.
- Stay here.
- Here?
- All right.
- Please.
Don't make any noise.
Wait.
Countess, what's going on?
Be quiet, you fool.
Ah! Countess. What a scare! l
knew something would happen.
l was fretful all
night. l couldn't sleep.
- Was it really you on that balcony?
- Simone!
Look everywhere! See if
you can find any footprints!
Make sure no one is
hidden in the garden!
That's good, Simone! Keep
looking around with the dogs.
Do you need me, Countess?
No. l don't need
anything. Go on, go to sleep.
Keep looking.
He must have fled when
he heard the dogs barking.
- l'm going back to bed.
- Good night, Count.
Giuseppe, look behind the
stairs! Be sure to have a good look!
l'm sorry. You must forgive me.
We're no longer in Venice.
l've changed.
l can think straight
again. My mind is clear.
- Livia, listen to me...
- No! We're no longer in Venice.
You made me lose my sense
of shame, my dignity.
- But why?
- lt's true, l lost all my dignity,
for a wretched, illicit love,
a shameful love.
Livia, my love.
We're no longer in Venice.
Fine, we're no longer in Venice.
We're agreed on that.
- We're agreed on that.
- May l sit down?
Yes, seeing as you can't leave
until they've tied up the dogs.
Thank you.
l'm so sleepy.
l haven't slept for three nights.
l love the smell of summer.
l love the smell of ripe wheat.
This place is full of that scent.
l'm so tired.
There's a gentle
laziness in the air.
What did you say?
The dogs have gone away.
You speak so quietly,
that l can't hear
what you're saying.
Did l mishear you?
l thought that you were saying...
that you were saying...
Franz...
Dear Franz...
l'm so alone...
please...
stay with me.
You misheard.
Forgive me.
l misheard.
l said you had to leave now.
You must leave. You must leave.
What did you say?
l said that the danger was past.
You can go now.
How long...
How long has it been since we
last saw each other, my love?
That's what l was
dreaming you would say.
l told you to leave.
Leave. Leave. Leave...
ls that it?
ls that what you really want?
l was hoping you'd ask me to stay.
Oh, Franz...
Franz...
Yes, Franz.
Please stay.
Franz...
Franz, wake up, my love.
lt is almost dawn,
and you told me you had to
be in Verona before nightfall.
Who is it?
It's me, Livia.
Franz, wake up. lt's daylight.
- What did you say?
- You must go away now.
The sun will be high soon.
And if they see you...
Close your eyes.
- l didn't close them all night.
- Why?
l was watching you sleep.
That's why l slept so well.
l dreamt l was home.
l was a child, and l played at
being a soldier with a wooden sword.
- l must go.
- l wish you could stay!
- l wish l could...
- What do you wish you could do?
l wish l could stay in your
arms, just as l did tonight,
for the rest of my life.
Farewell, l must go.
- l must go. l must go.
- No!
The sun's coming up.
lt's already late.
You wouldn't want them to see
me climbing down your window?
No, no!
Don't go yet.
l'll hide you.
l'll have you with
me for another day.
With me. Wait. Wait!
Let's hurry!
Come along, hurry.
Livia!
Come, stay with me a while.
No, the maid must
find me in my room.
- But it's still early. There's time.
- Don't speak so loud.
l won't say another word.
You know, it's not bad here.
l could stay here my whole life.
Then why don't you stay?
Have you forgotten that l must
go to war and become a hero?
Oh, no. No.
Try to forget that.
lf only one could forget.
lf only.
One of my friends did
an incredible thing.
Which one?
A companion. An officer.
What did he do?
He managed to bribe a doctor,
and got himself declared unfit
for military service.
He went for a check-up, you see?
The doctor pretended to
find him a heart defect,
which required a quiet,
restful existence.
So they sent him home, free
from any further obligations.
- But how can this be?
- l told you. He bribed a doctor!
A huge sum.
l didn't think such
things could happen.
But, after all, those of our
generation were spoiled like children.
We like elegant
uniforms because they suit us.
The gold braid, the tabs,
the sound of the marching band that
accompanies our heroic parade.
But then here's the
other side of the coin -
being far from our women,
being hungry, cold, tired.
When it comes to raising a glass to
future victories, we're all there.
But we're not willing to pay the
price of the victory we're toasting.
- The loss of an arm, an amputated leg.
- That's enough!
A face so disfigured that it
causes others to recoil in horror.
No, Franz! No!
And why? War.
Tens of thousands of men
ready to kill each other,
for no reason, no purpose.
Reason has nothing to do with war.
What is war, after all, if
not the most convenient means
to force men to think and act in the
way that most suits their leaders?
Why are you silent, dear?
What are you thinking about?
That war is horrible. Horrible.
l'll be back as soon as l can.
So many troops went past last night.
Even the heavy artillery. The
whole house was shaking.
They're going from
lnnsbruck to Verona.
- Ah, they're going to Verona...
- Count!
Count, should l
report last night's incident?
No, better not.
l bet someone found out about the
wheat and is trying to get us into trouble.
None of the men can have spoken.
Still, let's have some
men keep watch at night.
But...look over
there! lsn't that Le Ronghe?
- Yes, it is! That fire is at Le Ronghe!
- That's one hell of a blaze!
Let's go and see!
Look, Count, look at that
dense, dark cloud over there!
lt looks like a
barn is burning down!
We must send someone
over there right away!
To Le Ronghe! To Le
Ronghe! Look, sir.
lt's coming from Mangini's house!
lt can't be! His house
is behind the hill!
lt's further away! lt must
be the stables at Piovene.
Come on! Let's go to
the granary to look.
lt's just some slag piles, l expect.
Can't you see all
the smoke, Countess?
That's Mancini's house!
No, it's very clear from here.
Perhaps it's a military camp.
lt's best to be sure.
You two, come with me.
This is not good... Let's
look out the windows!
Let's hope no wind will
rise All that wheat...
Listen, the bells!
What are they waiting for? For
the whole country to burn?
Sir, we can't see a thing
here. Let's go to the other side.
What's happening here? The door is
locked with a key. Let's move it!
Look! The view is
much better from here.
Romagnano's patriots.
They will challenge the Austrians.
Have they lined up
close to the houses?
These idiots are endangering us all!
And that's why they are
setting fire to our farms?
Antonio! Call Giuseppe!
Antonio!
Tell him to prepare
the carriage! Hurry!
- Countess?
- What happened?
That gentleman is there.
- And Luca has returned from Romagnano.
- Countess!
Good news.
Marchese Ussoni has
arrived at our headquarters.
It's will just be a few hours now...
We are waiting for further
orders. Garibaldi is in Salo!
Two of our representatives met with a
spokesman of the General in Trento yesterday.
Garibaldi congratulated
the patriots.
He didn't think there
were so many of us.
His troups arrived and they
saw the work had been done already!
We don't need help to
protect our country!
Sure. Tell me more.
- Come back later. This evening!
- Countess!
Ussoni told me, you have to
give me the money
collected in Venice.
There should be more
than 3000 florins!
I don't know. I haven't counted it.
I'm sure you're right.
This evening! Come
back this evening, OK?
- That can't grow to such
proportions in such short time!
They haven't told me anything.
Nothing! They must
take me for an idiot...
- Count, the carriage is ready.
- Good.
- I'm going there.
- Yes, and hurry!
- Good day, Count
- Good day..
Antonio, my hat! Quick!
- Take Luca outside.
- Good day, Countess.
- Until tonight.
- Very well, Countess.
How did you get here? How?
Laura! lsn't that
her name? The maid.
l thought it was you who'd sent her.
How extraordinary! She
came to collect me,
brought me here and
gave me breakfast.
My God!
- She knows you're here!
- What harm can it do?
This is what ladies' maids are for!
Countess! The count
is looking for you.
We're leaving. l won't
be back for lunch.
Very well.
- What?
- l said, very well!
At your service, Countess.
Goodbye.
What are you thinking?
l was thinking...of something.
Tell me what.
This morning, in the granary...
you told me of that
friend of yours...
who they sent home...
because a doctor had
said he had a bad heart.
So?
Couldn't you do the same?
Me?
Yes, Franz, you.
You want me to play the cripple,
bribing some crook to
pass me off as unfit?
Yes.
You think me...
capable... of something
so contemptible?
And even if l was...
it comes at a price.
How much?
2000 florins.
2000 florins! Impossible.
- More than l'm worth, is it?
- lf you could...
lf you found a way...
You could stay close to me...
- At Trento, couldn't you?
- No... No.
Regulations state that
the discharged soldier
must remain close to his regiment.
- lf only you could!
- l have to leave, lt's late.
lf l'm not in Verona by tomorrow
morning l'll be declared a deserter.
- No!
- l could be shot.
That would solve all our problems.
- We have no time!
- Wait! Wait, Franz!
Wait.
Close the door!
Quickly! Come here!
My love! ls it yours?
Your husband's? Whose then?
l can't tell you! You'll
think l'm insane!
l am! l am insane!
Oh, my love! My love!
My darling...
My poor, sweet love!
My poor, poor darling.
- Who is it?
- lt's me. Countess. May l come in?
Don't come in!
- Don't come in!
- lt's me, Countess...
l said no!
Have you counted it? ls it enough?
l know you have
given me your heart...
and not only your heart.
l don't feel guilty
accepting the money.
l'd feel guilty not accepting it.
Do you believe me?
Countess! Countess!
- The count will be back any minute
- Yes, l realise!
Tonio saw him down in the
village and he told him...
l told Tonio to wait in the kitchen. l
had the gardener called too, with an excuse.
You need to avoid the terrace...
Ada's putting the washing out. l tried
to call her into the house, but...
Luca's here, too.
l showed him into the sitting room.
- He's waiting.
- Very well!
Write to me as soon
as you can, l beg you.
l have written the address here.
Give the letter to a civilian
and have them take it to Luca,
and l shall receive it directly.
- l must hear from you!
- l'll write.
Don't forget. As soon as possible
Go now!
Send word when all is settled,
and l will come to you at once.
l cannot live like this.
You shouldn't love me.
No one should.
l was irrevocably tied to him.
For him, l had forgotten...
and betrayed all of
those who were fighting,
in an attempt to realise
my long unfulfilled dreams.
Marchese Ussoni.
You should take a
route around our left wing,
just outside of Valeggio...
But there will be serious
obstacles. lt will not be easy.
- Thank you!
- Good luck, Marchese Ussoni!
Stop!
Can you take me to
Oliosi near Montevento?
- lt's dangerous...
- Don't worry, we can find a different route.
Here. There we go!
Which way should l
go to get to Oliosi?
Oliosi... The roads to
Montevento are blocked.
There are battles going on.
Try to reach that hill, turn left,
you'll come to a large,
square farmstead called Ca' Pasquale.
- Here.
- That's it.
From there, continue
going left, maybe...
Take the road to
Maragnote and on to Menso.
We can still get to
Sant'Ambrogio avoiding Oliosi.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
- Are you from the south?
- Naples.
Good luck, Lieutenant!
- l'll take the reins.
- She goes slowly, mind.
l have to get over the
hill. lt's absolutely imperative!
l have safe conduct signed
by General La Marmora in person.
To arms!
l had received a letter from Franz.
He had been
discharged, and was in Verona.
But he urged me to stay where l was.
The journey was dangerous and
he feared for my safety.
Battle had
commenced on all fronts...
and the news that reached Aldeno
confirmed hopes of
an ltalian victory.
You can see the canons
firing from Sant'Ambrogio!
- He said the Austrians are leaving Verona!
- No, they left yesterday!
Luca's here!
Let's hear what he has to say!
Here he is.
What did he say?
The Austrians have fled Verona!
We'll get the lot of them!
Viva ltalia!
Good day, Countess.
Are the Austrians leaving Verona?
Yes, Countess. We're
advancing all along the front..
They've called for reinforcements
at Trento,
and they're leaving Verona!
And this time they'll
be gone for good!
Viva Italia!
And we have no part to play?
The time has come to act for us
as well...and Marchese Ussoni.
We've heard nothing of Marchese
Ussoni. No news...nothing.
We can do nothing.
We must await orders.
But Countess, we
can't wait any longer.
Even having heard nothing,
our troops must move
in and occupy the area.
There's no more time to lose!
We will not participate.
Garibaldi will be coming here!
Countess, just think,
Garibaldi! Bloody hell!
What's going on? What are you doing?
Officer, what's
happening? Where are you all going?
We've been ordered to retreat.
Come on! You can do it!
Who are you? Are you injured??
Everyone is retreating,
Lieutenant. Yes it's true. lt's a disaster.
Not us. Eh, lads?
Everyone here's
staying put, Lieutenant!
Lieutenant! Orders to retreat!
- Everyone out!
- Understood, Lieutenant!
Always last to know,
eh? Come on, lads!
Come on, lads!
l decided to leave. At dawn.
Before patriots could take
over the surrounding area,
and before the ltalian
troops could reach Verona.
l knew l would never
return to my house, my people.
And yet, l felt neither
regret nor emotion.
The walls of the
carriage were burning,
and the sultry air suffocated me.
l had Franz's letter with me.
And l re-read it over and over
again, even though l knew it by heart.
''My darling Livia...
''You have saved my life.
''The money was
sufficient, for now at least
''to satisfy the rapacious doctors.
''l have been discharged and
they are keeping me in Verona.
''l have a beautiful room overlooking
the river Adige,
''on Via Santo Stefano, number 149.
''l miss you day and night.
''But don't come just
yet. Stay where you are.
''The journey would
be too dangerous.
''Love me always...
''as l love you.''
- .From there take the road to Ala.
- Drive on! Make way!
Do you have safe conduct to
enter Verona at this hour?
No, but l am Countess Serpieri.
My husband is an Austrian officer.
l am here to meet relatives in town.
Very good, Countess. You may pass.
But l must warn you,
tonight the streets of Verona
won't be safe for a lady.
Thank you.
- Quickly! Via Santo Stefano 149.
- Yes, Countess.
Well, what a lovely surprise.
Oh, Franz!
What?
l am here.
Has something happened?
l am here, Franz.
l told you in my letter not to come.
- Did you not receive it?
- Yes, but l came all the same.
- l couldn't bear the anxiety any longer.
- What anxiety?
- Anxiety over what?
- What might happen to you.
You knew l was safe.
You knew how...
with your money.
You know it bought me safe passage,
calm, wellbeing,
peace and amusement.
But l wanted to be sure...
to see it with my own eyes.
Fine! Now you have.
You shouldn't have come.
lt was a bad decision,
and now you'll be sorry.
You see?
l am no longer an officer,
or a gentleman.
l'm a drunken deserter..
who reeks to high heaven
of cowardice and vice.
But now l'm here, Franz.
l will stay with you always..
l have left everything for you.
Take me in your arms, Franz.
l haven't washed or
shaved in a few days.
l wouldn't want to disgust
you by coming too close!
You'd get dirty.
Franz!
- You're not alone?.
- Don't worry about her.
She comes for a couple of
hours each night to keep me company.
Do you want to meet her?
Don't be shy.
After all, she belongs to you.
l pay for her with your money.
Clara! Come here.
l'd like you to meet a great lady.
The Countess Livia Serpieri.
She has made a long journey.
As you see, she is exhausted.
She's travelled amid the
soldiers returning from battle.
Men who haven't been lucky enough
to have what l have...
a rich benefactor.
Clara,
Get her something to drink.
Wash it first!
Stupid girl.
lt's for a lady.
Ladies don't drink from
unwashed glasses.
Didn't you know?
Guests must be treated with respect.
You don't want it?
Are you unwell?
What are you waiting
for? Help her you fool!
Lift her veil! Take
off her hat, her gloves!
Countess Serpieri is a lady! A
high-class lady, and important lady!
Can't you see?
An Italian aristocrat.
- Haven't l told you about her?
- No!
You don't remember?
You didn't listen because you
thought l was just crowing.
You didn't believe me when
l said that a real lady
like the Countess Serpieri
was in love with me.
lt's true!
She said to me,
that she didn't know what love was
before she met me.
Why are you saying these things?
To hurt me or to hurt yourself?
l beg your pardon, but
l didn't hear you,
you're speaking so quietly.
Did you hear what she said, Clara?
No, l didn't hear
anything, and l don't want to either.
- l'm going.
- You're insane!
Livia,
you must forbid her to
leave at this hour.
lnvite her to sit
down to table with us.
Ask her.
Please, stay.
Don't mind him. He's drunk.
Who exactly do you think you are?
Do you have such a
high opinion of yourself
that you can't sit at
the same table as a whore?
What difference is
there between the two of you?
l'll tell you myself.
She is young, and beautiful,
and men have to pay for her.
You, on the other hand...
What? Why are you
looking at me like that?
l don't like being looked
at like that, understand?
Do you think l've gone mad?
No! l'm not mad!
l've never been as
lucid in my entire life.
Listen, and try to understand.
Try to see me as l really am.
Not as you imagine me to be!
The image you have created
of me is mere fantasy.!
lt's all in your head!
lt has nothing to do
with who l really am.
So, who am l?
How do l live? By what means?
With money l procure in two ways.
Money l get from women,
and money l steal,
cheating at cards.
l am a master of both arts.
That's how l make my living.
l have other charms, too.
l am a deserter because
l'm a coward.
And l don't mind being either!
What matters to me is that my
compatriots won a battle today
in a place called Custoza,
when l know that they are
going to lose the war.
And not just the war.
And that Austria, in a few years,
will be finished,
and a whole world will disappear,
the world to which we both belong.
The new world your cousin speaks
of holds no interest for me.
l think it's much
better not to be involved,
and to take your
pleasure however you can.
And, for that matter, so do you.
Otherwise you wouldn't
have given me money
to buy yourself an
hour's worth of love.
- No!
- That's enough!
lt's too late. lt's over.
l'm not your knight
in shining armour!
And l don't love you anymore.
l wanted money, l
got it. That's all.
Oh! And l forgot. l'm
also an informant.
lt was me who betrayed your
cousin to the police.
Of course, you knew
this, but pretended not to
to save our love affair!
No!
Go on! Go on, my lady!
Run! Run away, you whore!
Run! Run away!
Break your neck! Don't look back!
..with devastating precision.
Afternoon report
of the Fifth Corps -
After heavy fighting,
Santa Lucia was taken.
At 7 pm, Custoza was won.
The enemy has certainly put
up an admirable fight.
The first of the
offensives were particularly forceful.
Officers set their
men a fine example.
l've come to fulfil my duty
as a loyal subject.
The countess is Austrian?
Venetian.
Here.
l don't understand. ls
it addressed to you?
Right then, l don't have
much time, let's see to this.
The letter is from...
Franz Mahler, of the
Third Artillery Regiment.
And, so?
lt's quite clear.
He bribed doctors into
saying that he's ill.
He is a deserter.
Ah, l see..
The officer was your lover,
and now you're taking
revenge by getting him shot.
Think carefully, Countess. To
inform is a vile treachery,
and your actions
will see a man killed.
Lieutenant Schneider!
General...
carry out your duty!
Show the lady out.
Arrange this order to be executed!!
Highest priority!
Do you understand? Highest priority!
lmmediate execution.
Order
- arrest immediately.
First Lieutenant Franz Mahler.
Residing in Stefanstrasse 147.
Franz!