Push! Push guys, harder!
Mercenaire has arrived.
My greetings, ladies!
Mother Collé! Mother Collé!
God! What is it?
Mother, what is it?
Do not beat them. Look at their clothes,
they've deserted the excision.
Quick, call your mother Adjaratou.
Mother Diattou. Mother Diattou.
- What is it?
- My mom's asking for you.
What's going on?
- They've run away from purification.
- My god!
What is this early morning drum
announcing?
- Bathily.
- Traoré.
- Good morning.
- Bathily.
We were also wondering about the drum.
They are looking for something.
It sounds rather serious.
They are looking for human beings.
Not one or two people.
Six people are missing.
- Greetings, ladies.
- Did you have a good night?
- Ciré, ready?
- Yes, all set.
First wife, we are ready to depart.
- May you have a safe journey.
- Amen.
- May you return safely to us.
- Let's go.
Stand up.
Mother Collé,
we are requesting your protection.
We do not wish to be cut.
My elder, if you grant them protection,
it will be said you inspired them.
Mother, do not deny them.
One cannot deny someone protection.
Allah willing, tomorrow,
I will make their case public.
Tomorrow?
The moolaade will have started.
Amsatou, have them change clothes.
- Follow me.
- I am going to the well.
Mercenaire. Mercenaire.
Hey, Sanata.
Good morning, Mercenaire!
Greetings, ladies!
Come and see my inventory.
Hey, Sanata, I brought beautiful things.
Nice clothes for the purified girls.
I also have bread.
Greetings, Mercenaire.
- Hey, Collé, good morning.
- Morning.
Mercenaire,
keep three kilos of bread for me.
It is as if you already
have them in your belly.
- You do smell great, don't you?
- You naughty.
You are troubling for the mind.
Mercenaire, you are a womaniser.
Can I help you?
How much bread?
One and a half kilos.
A kilo...
and a half.
Patience.
Sweet for the kids.
Goodbye, fellow.
Thanks, sister.
Here, some sweets.
Next in line.
Woman, candies for your kids.
Thanks.
- Amsatou.
- Yes.
Mercenaire is in town.
Go buy 5kg of bread
and batteries for the radio.
I am on my way.
Oumy.
Awa.
Nafissatou.
Do not step out. Wait.
Come closer.
See this rope? You will only cross it
with my permission.
Neither can I dismiss you from the house
before the end of the moolaade.
This -
whoever breaks that law
will be killed by the moolaade.
- Hear me?
- We do.
Now, let's go back in.
- So, Amsatou.
- Mercenaire.
You don't stop growing.
Anything you desire?
Five kilos of bread and radio batteries.
Coming up. Come see.
Two.
Five kilos.
Let me do the wrapping.
- Voilá.
- Mercenaire, good morning.
Amsatou, do not move.
Wait.
Anything, beautiful?
A razor blade.
Here.
State of the art.
Very flexible.
- Your money.
- Please, allow me to do the giving. Here.
Say, could you come see me tonight?
God, someone is lucky.
You people my dreams.
I am out of here, you womaniser.
Amsatou, seen anything you like?
Like this one?
Look. The latest fashion,
and a perfect fit. Buy it.
I am penniless.
Not to worry, come back tonight.
The money I don't have now,
how can I have it tonight?
Amsatou, I'll ask to have you as wife.
Marriage?
I am already taken.
I'll triple your bride price.
My fiancé is richer than you are.
He works in Paris, France.
You are nothing but a mercenary.
Do you know that word means?
Mercenaries are people
who kill women, children,
and they also do coup d'états.
See, I too do listen to the radio.
You sure are a smart cookie.
So long,
Mercenaire.
Doucouré. Doucouré.
- Bathily.
- Good morning.
Amsatou, your future husband
should arrive soon.
You will hand him the welcoming water.
Look your best, and see you soon.
Dougoutigui.
Doucouré. Welcome.
- What can I do for you?
- We want batteries.
- It is for a radio?
- Indeed.
I have both local
and French-made batteries.
The French are more durable,
but they also cost more.
Go for the French. We want to listen
to the recital of the Koran.
I also have children's clothing,
kitchen utensils, and much more.
What about you, Dougoutigui?
I want batteries and 30 kilos of bread.
My son arrives soon from France,
he'll pay you.
- I'll send someone to pick them up.
- Very well, Dougoutigui.
I heard the drum this dawn.
- It's about the girls' purification.
- Allah be praised, a minor domestic issue.
This one is good.
Hand me another one.
Worthless.
Good.
Some music now, shall we?
Mother, the bread and the batteries.
Mother, Mercenaire brought
beautiful clothes.
They are very expensive, Amsatou.
It's my duty to welcome the guest.
I am penniless.
Wait for your father's return.
- What if someone buys what I want?
- What if Mercenaire had not arrived?
I saw beautiful things at Mercenaire's, and I
have been assigned to welcome the guest.
Good news.
Let's go.
- Collé.
- Yes.
We are going to Mercenaire's.
Her fiancé is on his way.
She is to present him the welcoming water.
Coming back from France.
Besides, marriage is a serious issue.
Why did you choose
to come to me for protection?
Nafi?
Six of us wanted to go to the city,
but we do not have any connection.
You are our last resort.
The two others went a different way.
You mean six of you
deserted the purification?
How did you get the idea?
Oumy?
We were told you refused
to have your daughter cut.
Now you are our only lifeline.
Oumy, there is too much gossip
at the well.
You should know that
purification is one thing,
and moolaade a different thing.
Diattou, what about you?
My older sister died of the purification.
That's why I don't want to get cut.
Awa?
Mother, you did not have Amsatou cut.
Her fiancé in France
is the son of the Dougoutigui.
He is bringing back a lot of money
and he is going to marry her.
Diattou?
Is it true that a bilakoro
cannot have children?
That is not true.
Collé, we went and took the things,
on credit.
Her fiancé will pay when he gets here.
When he arrives from France, he'll pay.
Kids, take these things inside.
Take all of it.
Go with them.
Collé, you've started the moolaade.
Are you aware of the responsibilities?
Elder, it is a question of life and death.
I won't add a word.
Mother, the salindana are here, mother.
Mother Diattou, they are on us, dear.
You take this.
Collé Ardo, seven years ago,
you refused to have your daughter purified.
I purified you,
along with Seynabou, Binetou,
Salba, Coumba and Binetou.
Why do you oppose
the purification of these children?
Truth be told,
you cut me and stitched me twice.
Twice,
and you also buried my two children.
When my Amsatou was being born,
the woman doctor opened me up to here
to let her out.
These children requested protection.
They'll get it.
What are you talking about?
Who put them under your care?
You want our daughters to remain
a bilakoro like your Amsatou.
Hey, Collé!
During our purification you were
the only disgraced girl to cry. You peed too.
Whoever crosses this rope
will be punished by the moolaade.
Oumy, Diattou, Awa, Nafi,
if you want to be cut
cross this rope.
- Diattou, Diattou come here.
- I don't want to.
Do come, you won't be purified.
Diattou, come here, bastard.
You will never get a husband.
Collé, it's you who manipulates them.
I do not wish to be cut.
- Me neither.
- We don't want to.
Collé, have you seen my child?
I only know of these four.
Mom, let's go find our children.
For each child you received 10,000 CFA
and imported bar soap.
Ardo, you are too subversive.
I will have to neutralise your powers.
Niassi, Salba, Binetou, Senebou,
under my protection
your children will be safe.
Now, let's go find the two missing children.
- Good morning, Mother.
- Bathily.
- How is the farm?
- I praise Allah.
Nothing serious.
The salindana did complain.
- Send them back the children.
- Never!
They have not committed any crime.
Mother, the salindana
will cast a spell on them.
Go tell your mother Collé,
the children are under her care.
You know she's a mad woman.
She manipulates them.
She refused to have Amsatou purified.
- Good morning.
Thank you.
Didn't she refuse?
End of conversation.
- Why is she crying?
- She is not able to pee.
With your pinkie covered with Karite butter,
remove the clot.
Do not drive in your finger.
Take off their loincloth.
Quick on your feet.
Quick. Follow me.
Form a circle.
Spread your legs.
You have to open up.
Now jump. Jump. Now jump. Jump.
Hand me my bag.
Thank you.
Now this has become
a contentious issue.
The two missing girls
escaped to the city.
Seven years ago,
Collé Ardo refused
to have her daughter purified.
Now she is harbouring four girls in
her house to keep them from purification.
She things her powers greater than ours.
She wants us to give up our knives.
Should we give in?
Let's request
a meeting with the Dougoutigui.
Collé is challenging us.
I will destroy her powers.
- Balla is rather early today.
- What was he saying about the girls?
What does he intend?
Is he about to snatch them from me?
My conversation with my son
is none of your business.
And don't you ever raise your voice when
talking to me. Be back to your quarters.
Welcome, all.
You the noteworthy, welcome.
Hail, Doucouré. Bathily.
You, Kémo, I salute you.
You dignitaries, I welcome you.
Women give birth to kings.
They give birth to the poor.
They also give birth to the valiant.
I salute you, women.
Like a man, a valiant woman
deserves to wear the pants.
Dougoutigui, Kémo, dignitaries.
The salindana wish to be heard.
We shall hear them.
Purification is a tradition
none ever questioned.
Seven years ago,
Collé Ardo had refused
to have her daughter purified.
- Say who?
- Collé Ardo Gallo Sy.
Your younger brother's second wife.
My brother is out of town.
I give you permission
to get the girls and to purify them.
Dougoutigui, may I speak?
You may.
Dean of the salindana,
did you have some girls escape?
We are still looking for them.
Haven't you heard what Amath just said?
His younger brother is not here.
He gives you permission
to get hold of the girls.
No one ever married a bilakoro.
Never, ever.
We cannot get hold of them.
Collé Ardo granted them the moolaade.
Oh, Lord!
Kawako!
Moolaade, you are in this anthill...
that embodies our first king,
Yérim Dethié Kodé Ndiak.
His people rebelled
and he was transformed into this anthill.
He had offended the moolaade.
Kalfa!
His rebellious subjects killed him.
After he was buried here,
his body was swollen and...
transformed into his anthill.
Years later,
our ancestors converted to Islam.
To Allah they erected this mosque
next to the tomb of the first king.
None can transgress the moolaade.
Its sprit is formidable.
To calm its spirit
one needs to shed blood.
Eskey. Eskey.
That's all I had to say.
Collé Ardo is challenging our traditions.
Seven years ago,
she refused to have her daughter purified.
Will you men then marry bilakoro women?
- Never!
- Hell no.
- Amath Bathily.
- Yes.
Hear this.
My son is not going to marry a bilakoro.
Dougoutigui, take it easy.
There still is a way
to purify all these girls.
Isn't your son arriving in two days?
If we purify then, including Amsatou,
your son will have to wait only 15 days.
15 days?
That's too long to keep an erection!
Silence, please.
As long as Collé Ardo
has not uttered the word,
no one will be able to take the girls
away from her quarters.
- Kémo Tiécoura.
- Yes.
Our ancestors offer a way out.
A husband has unlimited powers.
He may demand his wife
to utter the redemptive word.
This has to be done publicly
to bring an end to the moolaade.
Kémo Ansoumana,
thank you for your wisdom.
I understand what you are suggesting.
Ladies, you may leave.
The Dougoutigui excuses you.
You'll be informed of his decision.
Mama Collé, help!
Kawako, they are like
vultures that smell blood.
They took their case to the Dougoutigui.
Elder, I am scared of their curse.
The girls are not under your care.
Shut up or I'll kick your ass!
Do not touch her.
She has my protection.
You are not crazy after all.
She still has respect for me.
- Good morning, brother-in-law.
- Good morning.
- Bathily.
- Traoré.
- Bah.
Our husband has been away
for a long time.
Not to worry.
You know how meticulous he is.
In his absence, Collé...
Hold on.
Wait for her to be here.
Wait here.
On my way.
Let's go in.
- Your co-wife has bad manners.
- Uncle is right.
Purification dates back long ago,
and she wants to challenge it.
No, over my dead body.
Elder, I do not want to be burnt
by the fire Collé has started.
Shut up and go back to your quarters.
Here he is.
He has arrived.
- Alima, are you ready?
- Let's go.
You are not coming to be welcome party?
Sorry, I am too busy.
Go in peace.
People, admire the valiant.
Admire the son of the lion.
Doucouré, proud heir to your ancestors.
Heir to the throne,
the people salute you.
Doucouré, Doucouré, the generous.
Doucouré, here is your brave son.
He arrives from France.
He's coming to get married.
Doucouré, they also hail you as Cissé,
Sylla, Touncara.
Doucouré, descendent of Segou.
Your origins are in nine Soninke villages.
Women, the heir to Alpha Doucouré
is back with us.
He is tall, strong,
and as handsome as the rising sun.
- Good morning, Mother.
- Good morning, son.
Thank you.
Folks of Djerisso.
Our good Dougoutigui's son
is back from France.
Come all and welcome him.
The blessed son is back from France.
Let us be reminded that
everything has its time and place.
Mother.
Why didn't you have me purified?
I would have given Ibrahima Doucouré.
The welcoming water.
Allah is great.
Feel no shame in being bilakoro.
Hear me?
Nafissatou, I am speaking for you too.
Your two older sisters died before birth.
You owe your life to your doctor namesake.
She tore me apart to deliver you.
Genital mutilation is a bad thing.
A bilakoro is a good wife,
a good mother.
Look at all these goodies. He must've
brought back all the wealth of France.
What a worthy man.
Rich.
- Bad, we are already old.
- I would be stalking him.
- Doucouré.
- Greetings.
- You are Aunt Khardjatou?
- Yes, I am.
I cannot forget you.
As a child,
I used to steal from your cornfield.
What a good memory!
Meet my husband's third wife.
- What about Auntie Collé Ardo?
- Amsatou and her mother send greetings.
I'll come and visit them.
Welcome back.
What's happening?
The two missing girls
threw themselves in the well.
- Ibrahima, go have a rest.
- Yes, Mom.
Dougoutigui,
the girls threw themselves in the well.
- Oh, my God.
- Allah is great.
Tomorrow we'll fill it in.
Our emissaries are back.
The women should not be allowed
to listen to the radio.
All their radios should be confiscated.
What to do now?
Amath, speak to Ciré, your brother.
Collé is at the roots of the moolaade
and of the two girls' suicide.
I do understand.
Ciré, welcome back.
Bathily, did you have a nice trip?
Welcome back both.
Ciré, in your absence,
Collé gave asylum to four girls in your
house to shield them from purification.
I witnessed it.
Ciré, Dougoutigui wants you to know,
his son cannot marry your daughter.
- And why?
- Because she is a bilakoro.
She has to be purified.
Collé's radio should be confiscated.
- Confiscate her radio?
- Absolutely.
Hamsatou, her daughter's namesake,
gave it to her.
What about your authority?
Tell Dougoutigui
we brought back good crops.
We are listening to you,
our children's father.
You may listen,
but then you do what you please.
How come as a first wife
you allowed Collé to keep the children?
You went against my authority.
We did not mean to.
If, in your absence,
I'd told Collé to give up the girls,
it would be said in your absence
I denied young girls a needed protection.
You should've expelled them.
Out of here!
- Collé.
- Yes.
Do come back.
Down to the floor.
Collé,
18 years of marriage,
only one daughter.
You are my favourite wife.
You refused to have our daughter purified.
I did not object.
Now you want all girls to remain bilakoro.
You have climbed over my head,
I did not object,
and now you want to shit on my head.
Collé,
tomorrow morning,
you will utter the word
that ends the moolaade.
Amsatou and all the other girls
shall be purified.
And one more thing.
This radio, this damned radio,
I no longer want to hear it in my house.
Hear me?
May I be excused?
The village is silent.
Like a graveyard.
I heard the men confiscated
all the women's radios.
All this was cooked up by Amath.
I never liked him.
I am really worried about Amsatou.
She asked me why I did not have her cut.
Since she learned that Doucouré's son
is not going to marry her,
she has been disappointed.
Now she hangs a lot around Mercenaire.
I do not like that guy.
You do not know that fellow.
He's worst than a goat,
always around women.
Womanising all the time.
I know a magic potion
that will reduce his craving.
Elder, hand some to Amsatou's father.
Yes, he needs it.
Amsatou's father has decided
to make me say the redemptive word
to ward off the spell.
Do not utter it.
It is dangerous.
The moolaade is unforgiving.
Years ago two wives died from it.
Keep the girls here.
Elder, I do not understand you.
You do not, do you?
But I am on your side.
I often lie to protect you.
You can trust me.
- I too do not like excision.
- You don't?
- No.
- Liar!
Why did you have your daughters cut?
It did it against my will.
I got it.
I am taken as the sacrificial lamb.
Elders, it's getting late.
I am going to bed.
- Good night.
- Amen.
The four girls will sleep in my quarters.
Keep Amsatou with you.
- Good night.
I don't want to!
Mercy. Mercy!
Please, don't!
I beg you!
Mother, I'll handle it.
- Good morning.
Morning, elder.
Morning, Collé.
Ibrahima, turn off your radio.
The elders are blessing you
for your generosity.
Amen!
You've honoured your family.
You paid for a whole building.
You provided food during hard times.
- The women too send their blessings.
- Amen.
You gave them a water pump
that improved their daily lives.
Ibrahima, we are happy to have you back.
May Allah reward you.
Before your arrival,
things happened.
The elders confiscated
all the women's radios.
You can't turn on your TV set around here.
Its influence is even worst
than that of the radio.
Why deny them radios and TVs?
Uncle,
you can no longer silence these media.
Today, everywhere in the world
radio and TV are parts of life.
We cannot cut ourselves off
from the progress of the world.
Before your return,
two girls chose to drown themselves in
a well rather than submit to purification.
It's Collé who sets the women
against purification.
I opposed your marriage
because Amsatou is a bilakoro.
- Fily.
- Yes.
- Good morning.
You are cousins.
Yesterday the elders blessed your union
in front of Allah, at the mosque.
Father,
I still do honour and respect you,
but my marriage is my own business.
Say what?
You damned son!
Kawako, I am your father!
You shall marry whom I want.
If you don't submit,
I disinherit you.
Take your TV out of here.
Nephew, this is not a way
to talk to one's father.
Fily, you are excused.
Mother, I am going to visit families
and deliver them their money.
- May Allah bless you.
- Amen.
- Ibrahima.
- Father?
- Go see Mercenaire and pay my debts.
- I shall.
I've never spoken to my father like this.
I bought this radio with my toil.
I'll take it anyway. Since when
does a woman challenge her husband?
- Balla.
- Father.
Come here.
- Here, this one too.
- Father, this is my radio!
Amsatou, you shall be purified.
Yes, it will be done,
and I'll deliver you to the first
who requests you for marriage.
Let's go!
- You like them?
- I do.
He is my son.
Rewarding him with his first pair.
- He worked well.
- Well, what do you want?
A kettle.
You should not torture bank notes like this.
Here, candies.
Thank you.
Put on your shoes and go show them off to
your grandma before the purification party.
Doucouré! Konaté.
Greet the Dougoutigui's son.
He returned from France.
- How are you?
- Fine.
When you grow up, you too will go
to France where money is printed.
- May Allah protect you.
- Amen.
Francenabé.
How is the return to the native land?
>Aimé Césaire,
Notebook of my Return to my Native Land.
- Exactly.
- It is going well.
Did you know this ostrich egg
has been up there for 150 years,
when this shrine to Allah was built?
- Collé.
- Yes.
Look at this radio.
It only needs batteries.
Pati.
It must be older than my grandmother.
Now, be aware.
If Balla or his dad catch you with it,
I don't know you.
There is a grave behind the mosque.
You know what is it?
No.
It is the moolaade.
- I came to pay my dad's debt.
- Well!
Dougoutigui.
30 kilos of bread,
at 150 Francs per kilo.
Six new alkaline batteries.
- Here's what he owes me.
- This is cheating.
One kilo of dry bread
at 140 Francs per kilo.
In the city, fresh bread costs
135 Francs per kilo.
When unsold, the next day
you have it for 65-70 Francs per kilo.
You are cheating people.
What do you think?
I too have to pay for
transportation and conservation.
Besides, this dry bread
is cheaper than rice or millet.
You visited Europe, and you know what
globalisation and free market mean.
Will I have to tell your dad
you refused to pay his debt?
What a bullshitter, this guy.
You are a true mercenary.
New bank notes!
That is not all.
You have a bill.
Your fiancé's, that is.
- My fiancé?
- Yes, Amsatou Ardo Bathily.
She came and took goods
for your wedding.
You unloaded your junk on to this girl
and I don't have to pay.
Francenabé,
you'll settle that with Khardjatou.
Good morning.
- Greetings.
- Is Auntie Khardjatou in?
- Here she is.
Ibrahima Doucouré, how are you?
- Doing fine.
- Traoré!
- Collé. Collé.
- Yes.
Bring in the chair.
A distinguished guest.
Doucouré. Doucouré.
- Sy-Doucouré.
- Have a seat.
Amsatou, bring your husband
the welcoming water.
- I heard it's very cold in France.
- Cold, with snow.
No sun, girls with their hair
down to their buttocks.
You are right.
- Amsatou.
- Coming.
Is it you who refused to be purified?
You will never have husbands.
Won't you marry a woman bilakoro?
A woman bilakoro!
- You do have a sharp tongue.
- We listen to the radio.
The radio! The elders prohibited all
the women from listening to the radio.
How come?
- Thank you.
- You welcome.
Amsatou. Come back.
- The youngest, what's your name?
- Diattou Coulibaly.
Some candies to share.
But don't let them cheat you. Candies.
Merci.
Ibrahima.
You are about to steal our girl.
- Aren't you?
- Yes, I am.
Since marriage is such a serious matter,
we visited Mercenaire,
took things for credit,
with the promise you will pay.
- I hope I did the right thing.
- You sure did. I'll pay.
- I have to leave now.
- Doucouré.
- Greetings to your parents.
- Thank you.
- Traoré.
- So long.
- Ibrahima, do not forget to see Mercenaire.
- No, I won't.
- Our radios, we want our radios.
- Out of here. Go back home.
Fast.
You bastard.
- Sanata. Sanata.
- Yes.
Since you hang a lot around men, do you
know why they confiscate our radios?
Our men want to lock up our minds.
But how do you lock up
something invisible?
We are all ignorant.
I am telling you.
Binetou, let's go.
Ah! Without my radio
I can no longer sleep.
Me neither.
Without these programmes,
no more sleep.
Sisters, my sisters,
why this vigil at this well?
We bought these radios, didn't we?
Who should dictate what we listen to?
- Let's have a shower.
- Are you sleepy?
I am outraged.
It's intolerable.
- Hi, Francenabé.
- Mercenaire.
Came to pay your bills?
Yes.
I told you,
Khardjatou is a bully.
So, let's see for Amsatou.
Here, what you owe me.
All this?
This is perverse!
Your junk is not worth even half of this!
Francenabé, watch out.
I could tell Khardjatou.
Don't let it annoy you.
Here, a rubber, your first wedding present.
From me.
Thanks.
New bank notes!
It is expensive to have a wedding.
I know you are loaded.
You can be a friend.
Listen, I would like
to help with your marriage.
My marriage to Hamsatou won't happen.
My father is opposing it on
the ground that she is a bilakoro.
From a nearby village he summoned
my uncle and Fily, his daughter.
The elders celebrated and blessed
the marriage at the mosque.
- He doesn't know you already laid her.
- I didn't, she's eleven.
- No shit, eleven!
- Yes, but purified.
Francenabé, Fily is still being breast-fed!
You, your father,
and your uncle are paedophiles.
Did you say paedophiles?
Fuck you!
Now, let's talk about you.
Why were you kicked out of the military?
That's ancient history.
I participated in many UN military's peace
expeditions in the Middle East and Africa.
At a point,
we, the junior officers,
noticed that the senior officers
were stealing from our earnings.
I became our spokesman.
We made so much noise that
they hurriedly returned our money.
But it was not to end there.
I was especially targeted.
Five years in the jug,
and dishonourable discharge.
In the media I was nicknamed Mercenaire!
It suits you well.
Let's come back to you.
I have to speak to your father.
No, I can speak for myself.
You shitty little fellow, your dad and uncle
should be jailed for being paedophiles.
Africa is a real bitch!
Good morning, brother-in-law.
Balla! Come here.
- Collé!
- Yes.
You sit here.
I wouldn't have married you
if you were a bilakoro. Never!
We do not need to have a witness
to have this kind of conversation.
Younger brother,
your wife just kicked me out.
Not so fast. Calm down.
Sit down, older brother.
Collé, have you gone mad? How dare
you expel my elder from my house?
Young brother, have you given up
your authority as a husband?
Purification dates way back.
It is required by Islam,
and you woman want
to put an end to it.
Why are you dishonouring us?
Why are you opposing purification?
Amsatou is going to be purified.
- Mother.
- Yes.
You have visitors.
Father, the salindana want
to speak to my mother.
You may go.
Young brother,
Collé is holding you up to ridicule.
To put an end to it,
I had you take Alima as a third wife.
A very docile girl.
You have become
the laughing stock of the village.
To restore your authority,
you have to repudiate Collé,
kick out the four girls,
and have Amsatou purified.
Take this!
You have to flog her to have her utter
the word that exorcises the moolaade.
Here. Take it.
I have never beaten a woman before.
- Not even my daughter.
- Say what?
On your feet.
I am your elder.
Do as I say!
Mah, take care of the kids.
The moolaade is still in effect.
Alima, follow me.
Collé Ardo,
there is still time to purify the girls.
You only need to say the word.
- Collé.
- Yes.
Utter the word!
- My Amsatou's father...
- Say the word!
Say it!
Say it! Say it! Say it!
Utter the word!
Tame her! Tame her! Harder!
Collé, the word.
The word!
Collé, say it! Say it!
Do not say it. Do not utter it.
Do not. Resist, Collé!
Collé, what are you waiting for?
No shit, say it!
Say it, damn it!
Tame her. Break her.
Say nothing. Nothing.
Do not fall. Do not fall!
Why are you meddling with this?
She is his wife!
Kémo Amsoumana,
she did not say the word.
She did not say it.
After all this beating,
not a word!
- Unprecedented.
- That's the end of it.
The kalfa is with Mercenaire.
- What a failure.
- A real blow.
Tell me,
have you ever laid a bilakoro?
Allah forbid.
Kémo Tiécoura, I have never done that.
Never!
- What about you?
- That's blasphemy!
I'll never do that!
Mercenaire!
What have you just done?
Stop a husband from beating his wife?
- Who do you think you are?
- I cannot bear the violence!
Motherfucker, you are perverting
our wives and daughters.
Get hold of this motherfucker.
Once out of the village,
make him disappear!
Hurry up! Quick!
- Elder, it hurts!
- Be strong.
I regret having my girls cut.
Allah is my witness,
no other girl will ever be cut.
Alima, I swear!
- Easy, I am in pain!
- Don't move.
I felt the blows in my flesh.
Amath orchestrated it all
to publicly humiliate Collé.
I hate that man!
Where are my girls?
During your flogging,
Salba stole Diattou.
She had her cut and she died from it.
My poor Diattou.
May Allah protect her!
Mercenaire has also been murdered.
- What?
- Yes, and all his money was stolen.
Poor fellow!
Don't cover your wounds.
Elder, the moolaade has ended.
Alima, go undo the symbol.
Right away.
Greetings.
- Mah, bring the mats.
- All in peace?
- Peace.
- Thanks.
Be seated.
- Collé.
- Yes.
- Salba, our condolences.
- Amen.
- Greetings, ladies.
- Bathily. Bathily.
- I am heading for the mosque.
- Well.
- Pray for us.
- Allah willing.
Elder, your husband looks pained.
He is remorseful.
It is Amath who manipulates him.
We are being told everyday
that a woman bilakoro smells bad,
and yet nothing can smell worst
than a man who does not shower.
Sisters, I am pleased with your visit.
- Nafissatou.
- Yes.
Come reunite with your mothers.
From now on, the moolaade has ended.
- Amsatou.
- Yes.
Bring water.
- Mah.
- Yes.
Bring the girls' loincloths.
My Diattou died in my arms.
Collé, we too felt the blows.
I was so choked up
that I peed in my pants.
Collé, we honour your resistance.
Any other mother
would have done what I did.
Salba, dry your tears.
Coumba, Ibatou, my condolences.
Diattou's blood was dripping on my arms.
Diattou shouted her hate for purification.
My Diattou, my Diattou.
Collé, purification
robbed me of my daughter.
Oh, my Diattou!
- Oumy.
- Yes.
Your loincloth.
Nafissatou. Yours.
Awa. Your loincloth.
Salba.
I can hear her screams.
I want to follow my daughter.
Diattou.
Diattou, come here, here.
Diattou, here.
No, no, I don't want to!
I don't want to get cut.
No, don't cut me!
I don't want to.
Mothers,
be my witnesses.
Salba.
Here is your goddaughter,
have her for life.
This one will not be cut.
No girl will ever get cut.
Why are these females still bitching?
They are aroused by Collé's resistance.
Do what they please
but no one will marry a bilakoro.
- Never.
Our radios.
Our radios ablaze.
This one will not get cut.
- No girl will ever get cut again.
- Never ever again.
Our radios.
Allah!
Our radios blazing.
Some give birth, others kill!
The child killers are here.
- They will no longer cut anyone.
- Let's end our genital mutilations!
Calm down.
- No girl will get cut.
- Forever!
Throw your knife, quick.
Are you deaf?
Throw your knife.
Your knife.
Now yours.
No girl will ever get cut again.
I am going to confront the men.
Give it to them. Now or never, let's put
an end to female genital mutilations.
But don't forget the knives.
This day will see the end of our ordeal.
I am coming too.
Hope gives birth to courage.
Women's hope.
What is this?
Brother, if you don't subdue your wife,
I'll do it.
Elder, Collé is not a newborn.
If you touch her, I'll deal with you!
- He lost it.
- Brother-in-law.
You already burnt our radios.
But if you raise your hand on me,
I, Collé Ardo, will set the village on fire
and drown it in blood.
My warrior has spoken.
Admire my noble warrior.
Collé Ardo Gallo Sy has spoken
Collé from Niani has spoken
Djerisso women, fasten your belts
You are more valiant than men
Sanata, shut the fuck up!
You are but from a lower caste.
You are scared of the radios.
Fear also lead you to murder Mercenaire.
Collé Ardo, take away this filth.
Collé Ardo, be reminded that purification
is a legacy decreed by Islam.
Here are the knives
the salindana use to mutilate us.
Purification is not required by Islam.
The Grand Imam said it on the radio.
Each year millions of women
go for pilgrimage to Mecca.
- All have not been cut.
- Astarfirou Allah.
You are Satan.
Satan himself!
Balla, let's get out of here.
Ciré, you are betraying your menfolk!
It takes more than a pair of balls
to make a man.
- Ibrahima!
- Father.
You will not marry this bilakoro.
Father, my marriage is my own business.
Cursed son, challenge me
and I shall disinherit you.
You will have a bad ending.
Father, it is easy to hit a son,
but the era of little tyrants is over.
Forever and ever.
From now on I'll have the TV on.
Son of a bitch!
I am and shall remain a bilakoro!
Visiontext Subtitles by: Adrian Isaac