-The reason for your visit?
-Touristic.
Was your journey comfortable
commander Logar?
Module crashed into Atlantic ocean.
l came with a connected
flight from Miami.
-Shame on you both.
-You don't live in that apartment.
Group sex scandal in the apartment.
-Good morning honey.
-Good morning.
Arif did humans
come from monkeys for real?
What? l swear l am forbidding
the morning shows for you.
You always get influenced from them.
You were in internet the whole night.
-They are such a bad influence on you.
-My dear don't rush. Take it easy.
l am 40 and my knowledge about Earth
is about 78-79% except the polar regions.
-Arif do you know what l want?
-What?
-l wish our child could be like you.
-Like me?
Sir you are in the public area.
Can l take the kid to school like this?
-You believe that it's possible?
- Dude this is a constitutional state...
...so he can't grow mustache
because he is in 1st grade or what?
ln my opinion he should
take after her mom's beauty...
...and my practical side.
Do you think l should give a birth
in Gora?
ln Gora?
So we deliver the baby to earth in Gora
and then deliver it to Earth again?
l mean l don't know.
ln terms of health technology?
Actually it's fine
he would get double passports.
And also birth register in Kaladion
Galaxy cannot compare to Earth right?
ln this case it's different.
-Can we go?
Yes we can. Can l get some bread?
Where is the ship Arif?
Ship... The ship is...
Where is the ship? The ship?
There are 2 tons of iron to start with.
Not to mention the devices in it.
-4 lira bro.
- Ok damn it give me.
Hey bro.
l guess l didn't pay its July taxes
the document and stuff...
-Those can be taken care of anyhow.
-So are we going?
-How can we not go when you want to?
-Hurray. We are going to Gora.
Look you watch those TV shows and
make this girl fly too. Turn it off.
What's up Arif?
Good morning.
Bitte schön.
-Hey Fox.
-Yep?
There was a scrap dealer.
What happened to him?
-He's gone since ages man.
-Really?
-What's up? You're down.
- Nothing.
lf you'll suffer remorse
let's cancel the organization.
No way whatsoever.
Bring it on. Hey monster!
Get me a mint gum from there.
Box of it. Hard box.
This one's yours. That's mine and those
are Alaaddin's. l will give him then.
lf the pharmacist woman was not here
l could get it as well. Here.
Come on.
l will mix the torpedo with mint.
Then what will be in there:
''Viagara'' cascade.
Come on. Go back to your store.
Look you have a customer.
Oh my God.
Taxi.
Let me take this
for two minutes mate.
Master customers!
Go away my kid.
l don't want you to get hurt.
Get out of my store
or the apprentice will die.
-Bro.
-Get lost.
-Calm down we are not here for enmity.
-Are you chasing me planet after planet?
Look at that.
He brought the tot as well.
-Don't be silly throw away the stick.
-Who trusts the stick buddy?
-Arif can you make this two fifties?
-Ah Neset now.
But l don't have two fifties.
Give me my coat from there.
Take it. But don't let others
hear about this l beg you.
-Of course.
-Whatever happens here stays here ok?
Because of you l am exposed.
Why are you following me?
We came to apologize Arif.
We realized our mistake.
We learned that it is a sin
to separate lovers.
We stayed in prison between four walls.
Between walls
you start listening yourself.
You try to deal with yourself.
What did l--
Even though from another planet won't
you forgive your forsworn brothers?
Are you gonna say No for us
to be brought in back to the society?
Arif are you going to push us away?
-How did you get out of prison so quick?
-Through Amnesty.
-Amnesty?
-All my power is taken away.
But it's ok be that as it may.
Look l made a bead bird for you.
And l made this one.
Beads are good but the house is naff
to tell you the truth.
You didn't even taste the anti-pasti.
You sat down with your cloak on...
-...you won't feel comfortable. Come on.
-Arif.
Listen what Logar's saying.
He's saying take my ship...
...for the trip to Gora.
No it's ok
we can go with our own ship.
Please allow this to be
our wedding present for you.
As a sign of our friendship.
Take our ship and go.
You are really a good person.
You mean should we go
with your ship for real?
Of course
if you don't beat us up though.
For god's sake stop it.
l swear on bread...
... that there won't be no more
time stopper moves like flying
...escaping floating in the air.
...especially not to you.
Now that you solved our ship issue.
l am a family father man.
Arif dear
did you drink a little too much?
My loveshould we argue in front
of the aliens now?
l will set you a floor bed
real vinilex come.
Come with me. Oopps.
-Arif Arif.
-lt's ok it's ok.
-Wow you are a good drinker.
-You didn't even help me though.
l drank 1.5 bottle just by myself.
Anyway once we are back
we'll drink more.
We will continue by mules from here.
Very nice indoor area you have there.
Our ship was at outdoors became rusty.
lt does not rust
it is made of titanium.
Titanium? Damn l gave the ship
away for nothing then.
Open it Tihulu.
Shoot ahead
turn on the lights.
So those are the departure units
l guess? Well where is the ship?
Arif my dear
can you look at me for a second?
Dad Daddy..
How can one be such a moron.
We cried a little he fell for the trap.
We learned our lesson
in the prison Arif.
-Everything was a lie huh?
- Of course it was!
Tihulu shave this.
What happened now that you
put me in this thing huh?
All you do is the kidnap people and
tie them up to a mechanism isn't it?
Listen to me carefully you retard.
You stole my lover.
l did my time in prison
now l will replace you.
Then l'll go to Gora with your princess
wife and will ascend the throne.
Throne?
Throne yeah. Did it hurt you?
Fire water soil throne.
Are you sure
it's not air?
Replace me? How are you
going to imitate my hair dumbass?
Oh yeah that's the hardest part.
Scissors.
No you can't do this. No.
l exactly copied your outfit
through clothes off method.
...and now we will be completely
the same through face off method.
Ceku won't even be
able to tell the difference.
Ceku will notice the difference
don't worry.
Start the machine.
First of all there is no such
a machine in Face Off you liar.
-How does it look?
-Very nice
lt is not done yet. Give me what
Tom Cruise used in the movie.
Not this one the other movie.
l love you very much my dear. l will
ask your father's permission tomorrow.
Not this one the other one.
Testing 1-2. Wonderful. Ceku
if you are ready let's leave honey.
And you space peasant l am sending
you to where you deserve to be...
...to 500.000 years ago.
-500?
-Ok let's round it. Make it 1 million.
- l will hunt your past and future you.
Don't you dare!
No cussing. Bad for the kids..
Set it to one million.
No matter one million or wherever
you send me l will come and find you.
Don't wiggle you will break the machine
Give me the remote control...
Bye bye Mr. Arif.
The other remote control.
Good bye if you can return from
there bring us some rocks...
You You..
Yaw..
You are here...
l have my parts in place l am complete.
lt's 20 past 5 he didn't send me
that much back the idiot.
Come on Ceku my rose.
l can't believe it. ls it really ready?
Yes my dear completely ready.
Let's celebrate this when l come home.
And tomorrow morning
taking off to Gora.
-Ok honey kisses
-Me too dear bye bye.
Welcome to Gurcan Market.
Hadji bro..
Press 2 to
switch to Turkish.
Ceku where are you
l am about to go there and scream: No.
No...
No way! Shucks.
He did sent me to
one million years back.
1 million years.
And they made me talk to
the hadji market for half an hour.
God knows
how much it will cost.
When l build my bussiness
the aliens kidnap me...
...when l become a family man
they send me to a different era.
Things that wouldn't even happen
in a fancy movie happen to me.
And when you share it with
someone he plays the 3 monkeys.
What the heck?
Oh my god the first monkeys.
Don't come dear.no.
But l am not from this Age..
No stop don't do it don't.
Don't do it dear.
lt's not for you. Give that to me.
Are you taking a picture?
Oh God.
But together...
Cico stop for a sec. Go over there.
Gents l am not asking much from you.
Little bit of civilization...
l need to go to my time period
and save Ceku as soon as possible.
First we start with standing up
Watch. Just like this.
Not difficult. Stand on feet
Keep it straight up
Nothing specific.
Look like this... For God's sake.
Come on man.
Stand up bro.
No. You have to be completely erect.
lt can't be done like this!
l should have accepted 500.000
1 million years are too much.
What am l gonna do?
Play with you or what? No!
Keep it to yourself. lce Age
will come and our butts will freeze.
Fire's not been discovered yet.lt says
June 20th. What kind of June is that?
l turned into a monkey too.
l had a lighter in my back pocket.
Thank god...
Put it over here...
Leave the shoe.
Stop touching
l have a razor in my hand. What?
You expected George Clooney
under my beard or what?
Stop playing at my feet
go over there.
Dear monkeys.
Based on the movies l watched 4 minutes
passed in the parallel universe by now.
lf l hang out with you little longer l won't
be able to go back and save Ceku.
Therefore l am leaving. Our food
and water became scarce anyway.
l will first find the water
and then the other civilizations.
l wish we had met
under different circumstances.
But didn't happen.
Alright bye bye.
No don't stand up for me
You are not able to anyway.
Bye Bye Cino Kati Zino.
''Seeds should turn
into sapling sapling to trees...
...trees to forests in my homeland.
Habitat to birds blanket to soil...
...gives life to nature
forests it is in my homeland.
''...blanket to nature
forests in my homeland home to birds.''
How did it get stuck in my tongue?
...gives life to nature
Wow look at that character.
lf l find the water soon
there is no biting me ok?
This one had not evolved at all
the same snake we know.
Blanket to nature.
There goes the water...
l swear it's water.
Piss off... you turned this
into a Jurassic Park man.
Monkeys lizards bugs...
There is just a bit of water anyway.
What kind of Age is this yo
aren't there any evolved creatures here?
Oh God.
l didn't say that to you for real
it was to the little ones.
To the lizard ones for real...
Oh God thank you millions for making me
experience this classic scene.
Bro l watched all your movies
Jurassic 1 Jurassic 2 Jurassic 3.
Please. Bro there is nothing
you'd like here.
Get off nothing for you in here..
But if you keep screaming like that
all the predators will come around.
Sounds like a war cry.
Please stop...
Wait there..well jungle has its
specific rules you know?
There is a specific food chain of course
This will eat that that will eat this..
You grew up in the jungle with no love
so you have right to do whatever...
...of course you don't know me
but...
Look don't make me
put you in trouble huh.
They make Dino-gods
through computers nowadays...
...don't make me separate you
pixel by pixel..my name is Arif.
Mr. Arif the stone that you threw
hit the dinosaur's testicles.
This means the end of the
dinosaur generation l am sorry.
Doctor
l can't carry this responsibility..
-Dad Daddy
-My son my child..
l understand you very well Jurasic
l have a child as well.
Therefore l forgive you.
This jungle is big enough for us both.
Wow you say butter and honey huh?
Super.
Looks like you are not
that primitive after all.
How lucky there is not even
a single bee around here.
l didn't take it Jurasic gave me.
Since you stung me
you will die yourself right now.
...what was good for bee stings?
Ammonia..
What the hell are you looking at?
Looks like a bee play to you?
Oh my God you are humans.
Last time l left you you were monkeys.
God knows
how long l was passed out for.
lt is so hard to bump into
a human in this Age.
Calm down...
Obviously he doesn't speak our language.
-We can't keep him here he is a stranger.
-This man is not conscious.
He won't get stuck
in our hands if we help him.
Whoever breaks loose
you take them into our village.
-Plus he scared our children.
-Nah that's not true.
What should we do? Rip his head off
feed him to the savage birds?
No bro you misunderstood...
The last thing you said didn't appear.
Sure he didn't say something wrong?
Look teeny if donkey eats weed that
he doesn't know he'll have a headache.
-Write it down l like that phrase. Come
-Ok but...
l don't know where you came from
But we don't want trouble.
l came from a different time
segment trust me.
l have been wandering around
for months in here..
8 minutes passed in the parallel
universe. lf we can get united...
-What unity? Are you a man of Arogans?
-l have nothing to do with them.
Arif carpet rug travel. Damn l wish
l had my bussiness card with me..
-Look l have gum...
-Put this away put it.
He is obviously from Arogan.
Trying to spy on us.
The lady rocks by the way
must be because of the Age. Stone Age.
-Shut up man she is my daughter.
-Wonderful moral principles are present.
-lt's called jealousy. Very beautiful.
-Jerk.
-How's technology is fire discovered?
-Get out of here go.
How could l go?
Give me lightspeed and l will go.
You are looking for trouble
can tell from your guise. Go away.
Arogans are coming.
What's going on?
Look stranger take this
shut up and don't talk.
What kind of fur is that? Just to taste.
Don't you have better ones?
Uncle if fire is not discovered yet
l have some...
What's this dude's problem?
Are the goods ready?
Give me the tools as well.
Nothing else was done
with those tools was it?
No Crow.
l heard that you are drawing pictures
all over the caves is that so?
No such a thing Crow.
Heard that you invent
house tools spears and stuff
-We are just gathering fruits.
-Don't gather eat the ones on the floor
You ruined the village kids are hungry.
You don't even let us make a fire.
-They will die from cold in the caves.
-Dimitell your monkey faced daughter...
...not to chitchat too much.
Her tongue gets longer and longer.
No tools gadgets. l will destroy every
inventor. Open your eyes and serve.
We are not slaves. We are humans
as much as Arogans are too..
Just because you put
a feather on your head...
...you think you became a man?
Bird brained.
-Stony stop her.
-What should l do? Yell at her?
Shut up woman.
Hit go ahead hit..
You think your hand will get dirty?
What are those old man?
Are they edible?
This is leaf.You put it
between your lips like that.
Crow let's take the stoneployees
let's not wait till the sunset...
You you..
...and you.
Me? l am not a man
of this era bro.
-Pardon me?
-l came from a different time period.
Don't take me take this one.
What have l been telling all this time?
Didn't l say ''no tools and gadgets''?
You did for about half an hour.
What is that what?
Fake Rolex but exactly the same
can't tell the difference..
Not from this village Crow
We don't know him either.
What happens if l was from this village?
So what? What's gonna happen?
Don't do it in front of the people.
No lf l was from this village
what's gonna happen bro?
Bidi..
This arrow is poisonous.
Don't throw this anymore.
See... My arm is gone
right now look.
One day we were sitting at our spot
with Yilmaz and Namik...
Tie it well so that
we won't fall my dear.
Be smart l'd burn down your village
with the tiniest civilisation sign.
Hedgehog head..
Come again my bro.
-Move.
Saplings shall turn into trees
in my homeland.
When did you tie me up?
What kind of fate is this?
Whoever ties me up takes me away.
Hey bro..
Won't we stop somewhere?
What is this?
No break no break look ahead..
Ah my arm..ahh.
-Stony be carefull little bit.
-His arm is broken..
Pity. The skies gave you
the skies took you away.
Start the burial immediately.
Bidi bring couple pieces
of rock from there..
How did you know Stony
the son of the Rock?
We knew him well.
What are they doing?
Burying him?
Rest in peace.
Bro what are you doing?
Look at me weren't your hands tied up?
Tied up now bro.
How can you bury someone like that?
Move it for god's sake move.
-What can we do his arm is broken.
-What the hell? Stop.
l have his medicine.
Lad give me that.
lt hurts a lot.
No it won't. Straight up. Move it.
Just dislocated.
lf it was broken he would
not be able to move it like that
lf there were an egg l would rub it.
-Here quail.
-Nice. Give me a stick.
-lt hurts a lot.
-No it won't hurt. Stop.
Now it's fine.
Hold it like this.
Nice.lf we tie it like that
it will be better than before.
You are a strong man.
Don't leave us. Stay alive.
-So won't he die now?
-No bro what are you talking about?
-lt is stronger than before super.
-Go back to your spot you witch.
-l am from another time period.
-Shut up!
Our hands and arms are tied up
and we can't even say a word.
Take the stoneployees
to the torture cave. l am coming.
-Mate how is your hand?
-Good thanks. Move.
Don't forget it because
we have now a connection through that.
-Move move.
-Ok.
-Where will you go with this wheel?
-lt's a millstone.
-Lie.
-My lord l am from South Emencik.
-We are grinding wheat with that.
-You are lying.
Didn't we say agriculture is forbidden?
He will climb up to the tower tomorrow.
-Please forgive us lord.
-Liar. Welcome Uncle.
-Thanks Niece.
-What's that in your mouth?
-Whose mouth?
-Don't smoke that indoors.
-Sure.
-What's that?
-Fake Rolex.
-Can't tell the difference.
-How is the situation down there?
-Dimi prepared the pipes.
-Good.
-Dad.
Stony my son did you nicely
destroy the things down there?
-l did father.
-Good.
What happened to your arm?
He injured it
while beating some Arogs.
lt is not broken though
Otherwise l wouldn't be able to move it.
Look what l found
at the entrance of your cave.
The masks it's a freestyle work
made of tree barks.
Don't work!
You are an Arogan be a warrior.
You are drawing pictures
all over the walls.
Don't waste your time
with those things.
Father l love drawing sculptures
music and dance. l love them.
Don't they bring life
to this tribe anyway?
Lie!
You are lying.
They won't understand and desolate you
You'll become a vagabond.
You'll die of hunger.
Don't be an artist be a warrior
Don't get mashed smash them.
Father my opus is a light
for the future generations.
-Where are the slaves?
-Downstairs.
Go torture the slaves.
Come on son.
Uncle my drug.
Crow watch over this kid.
l want him to be a worthy Arogan
to our ancestors.
My father Sandy should be proud of us.
Don't you worry my Niece.
When tower gets completed
and we find him...
...it will be the beginning
of a new era for all of us.
Father the skies took you away
l will take you back dad.
My Brother Sandy was
a very friendly man.
Didn't he always lose
because of his good intentions?
lt was years years ago.
First years of Stone Age.
We were poor but happy.
Where there is mulberry grove now
there was nothing back then.
-That day an iron circle
descended from the sky.
-lron?
-Probably.
Two creatures
similar to us came down.
They were smiling.
They gave us a gift.
My father Sandy couldn't find
an appropriate gift back for them...
..because of the famine shortage
we were having maybe.
Whatever we he had in their his hands
he gave them they got mad.
They gave us the hand move
then got on to that vessel and ascended
When big Sandy was saluting them
something terrible happened.
My dad was not there anymore.
We vented out spleen on that gift.
We hit it again and again.
Since that day l've been close minded
to novelty against innovation.
l hope
it's not like Mel Gibson's movie...
...with the whole headcutting and stuff.
The gods want a sacrifice and so on.
l dislike those the most.
Stoneployees you will climb
up to the tower in a while.
Whoever sees and brings Sandy down
his life will be saved.
New opportunities and neo stones
will be given to him.
At least we will jump one level higher.
Neolithic Age. Super. To me..
Let the stoneployee dance begin.
Bro l hate two things,
modern dance and the primitive dance...
...things that irritate me the most.
No no... Don't...
Cut it out cut it.
Move move away.
Bro his heart could take only that much.
You can't make anything out of that guy.
Wait a minute give me that
rub that mud on so that...
-...l can go and bring this Hadji back.
-Wait a minute before the dance.
lt is like a school prom
Let's take down that dude.
Then you can dance till the morning
no worries. Load on buddy.
-Load it. You exaggerated so much.
-Who the heck is he?
His hair is very different.
l carried many refrigerators like this.
Crow head when l come back
we will switch to Neolithic Age.
The architecture of this place
is wrong. Construction is wrong.
l just let one fart out
they probably won't smell that.
There he is.
-Hello Uncle.
-Don't come closer to me.
Are you Sandy?
Life and everything is
meaningless to me.
l was going to take you down.
l want to die.
-Don't be ridiculous.
Here take this cigarette.
Nonsense.
How do you want to die man?
Come on now.
Life can't be that meaningless.
Don't be ridiculous.
Shield it with your hand shield it.
Shield it with both hands.
Dude passed over
because of the cigarette.
Who cares? They told me to
put the rock down. l did it.
-Someone is coming.
-There's a returning man!
A returning man.
ls it my father?
l couldn't see that well my friend
will you look?
Thank you very much.
Thanks beautiful girl.
Cut it! Did you see him?
Did you see Sandy?
Yes l did now it's like this up there
l guess by running away from the society.
He became introverted
built this crust over him.
Now since l don't know psychology
in order to approach him with caution...
...l tried to talk to him
but those addictions and things.
How can l say he was going through
something like solitude at the top.
Talk to me man where is Sandy?
-Daddy.
-There he came.
This is not Sandy.
He is from Arog.
How can l know?
Did l check his lD?
Take away that necklace from his neck.
As if l was dying for it.
How do you climb up to the top
and not find my father?
How many more stones
we need to put up to reach the skies
You're talking from the balcony.
The sky has 7 layers.
Am l going to furnish stones up
till the stratosphere Mr. contractor?
Lie you are lying.
Tower building will continue tomorrow.
Rock is upset.
Ceremony is dismissed spread out.
Crowhead what happened? l would switch
to the Neolithic Age you promised.
Shut up. You are the first man
to come down from the tower alive.
You can drink and eat
as much as you want in Arogan.
Based on our traditions
your life has been saved.
What a nice tradition is that.
Generally men die from the traditions.
Then let's build a ladder or something.
8 minutes passed in parallel universe
right now. Help me once bro.
-What kind of a society you are.
-Come l need to draw your picture.
Wait a minute dude
l have enough trouble.
You are the first man to come down
from the tower. l have to picture this.
-But secretly.
-Pictures are secrets too? Look at that.
lt is.
Let's go to my spot.
Bro my name is Arif.
l am a pragmatic man.
l can't take that pressured hammer
feudal system that's my character.
Stop moving stay like that
for a little bit.
Let me see that. What the heck?
-ls my nose like that?
-Just like that.
Look at those lines.
Do you draw those as well?
-My style is like that.
-Nice.
Put your signature on them. They are
published as anonymous in encyclopedias.
Don't be a fool.
Let me write my name over there.
-Bro what are you doing?
-You gotta write your name down son.
Those are nice.
How much do you sell the masks for?
There is no selling bro.
l make them to myself.
But it is a secret
Don't let my father hear that.
Art is for the people.
Why should it be a secret?
They wouldn't understand.
-Make this one smiley and that weepy.
-This one is smiling.
He can only smile this much
in such a pressured society anyway.
This one would make
a good coat huh.
Bro don't.
Leave it alone.
This is not really your style
lsn't she the girl from down there?
-Yes Mimi.
-Flirting games huh?
l am in love bro.
You were showing her
some muscle in the village.
Society pressure.
That picture is nothing check this out.
-Wow. Who did this?
-Myself.
Yourself?
You are in love my friend.
Listen to this then.
lf you see your crying child
forgive his mistake
wrap your arms around his neck
As we lived together...
...they tricked us.
Strangers don't know value my mother
no one loves like you do...
...mother
-You are crying.
-lt is an impossible love bro.
There's no ''impossible love''.
l loved a woman from another galaxy.
lt is not like loving
the girl next door.
When there is 20 years of age difference
between lovers it creates problems.
There is 1 million year difference
between me and my love.
if your eyes meet your crying child
forgive his mistake
wrap your arms around his neck
As we lived together...
You are crying bro.
Look bro l need to go back
to the ones l love.
Situation down at the village is obvious
They are yet in Paleolithic Age.
You dad promised to give me
the Neolithic Age. But he didn't.
l need tools and devices
l need to go back to my loved ones.
Help me out
l need tools and devices.
There is no way bro my dad is
collecting all the inventions...
...he won't let anyone use them either.
-ls this man insane?
l need tools and devices help me.
-They are all locked up in the cave.
-Locked cave?
Take me over there. l will help you.
l will set you up with the girl
-Would you do that bro?
-Surel would even arrange your wedding.
White goods are from me.
What are white goods ?
You will learn all these
as long as we skip one or two levels.
-My bro.
-This is Kibariye not a bull.
You should have grilled it on fire.
Mr. Arif.
Thank you very much
have a good night.
l couldn't come there.
l don't know what you need but
there are all kinds of tools in the cave.
l am down for anything bro.
lf l can find it there is
a gift that came from the skies.
Gift from the skies?
A gun? Fire? A machine?
l don't know but l am certain
that it is not from this world.
Maybe it is a machine of a man
who came before me or something.
Here it is. Hold.
-Are we opening it?
-Yes push
Push hard.
Ok go.
So what do you think bro?
lt is good isn't it?
Wow it is like a museum son.
-There is a bicycle.
-That's a wheelbarrow.
-Ladder.
-Nice it's a step.
Furs. We have spears.
Pass that.
And then there is this thing
3 people can ride it at once.
The thing that came from the skies.
Show me that one.
That one is in
somewhere deeper.wait.
Bro too primitive.
This one was given as a gift
to my grand grand father VHS.
-VHS?
-Are you ready?
Open it bro.
Damn man. This is a betamax video.
You can't even find its cassette now.
Why do you show off telling me that
it came from the sky and get me excited.
-Does this work?
-Stony don't drive me crazy.
-What's happening here?
-Nothing.
Stony. Your father wants to
talk to you right now. Let's go.
-lt was told not to enter that cave or?
-lt was dad.
lt happened like this.
my friend said ''you have'' he said...
...''tools or gadgets with you or not''.
and l said that l have my phone.
My father gets mad at inventions
he hides them in the cave he said.
Then l said
why don't we put it in the cave?
l said why don't you open
so that we can put that in there.
Give me that.
Put a man in front of the cave
so that not every peasant can enter.
Stony my son now it is time
for you to build a family.
We talked with your uncle.
We decided to partner you with Ayu.
Ayu?
Very beautiful girl
fit for winter... Ayu.
Father l love someone else.
Lie you are lying.
This is not possible.
You will marry Ayu.
Dad l have my opinions too.
You ban me from drawing
You even put this hedgehog on my head.
-That's enough.
-Take it slow slow.
-Stay out of this Arif.
-Son how could l?
You are about to jump
on top of each other as father-son.
The society will be left undeveloped
because of a dynasty fight.
Don't make such a big deal
let the kid marry whomever he wants to.
And then free the innovations so that
the society won't be left primitve.
-ln the parallel universe approximately...
-Shut up.
Stony l will refuse you as a son.
You will have to collect
horse chestnuts in wilderness.
l will kick you out.
l am leaving
before you kick me anyway.
Get out. You will be given
neither meat nor water on this soil.
He is a young boy
talked with passion fire...
...you should sit and talk
like two modern human beings.
You won't be given anything either.
Get off our land.
What did l do?
Uncle my drug.
This son will kill me.
ldiot. The man is the owner of the land
and you revolt against him.
What a perfect time
to go against your dad.
Tough luck. Go away bro.
l will build my own civilization.
Two hands make noise
One hand doesn't make noise.
Don't sell me the poverb
that you can't even get right yet
lf your hair wasn't there to cover it.
l would rip your ear off. Go.
Let's go to the Arogs.
Let's go to your woman right?
You fox. Don't come with me.
Arif why don't we go to the Arogs?
More humble l am more arrogant they get
l am 1 million years advanced from you.
lnstead of trying to use me...
Then there will be brain migration.
The brain will migrate of course
what else can it do?
Don't come son.
Stop coming with me.
What are you looking at?
l am not looking.
l am washing my face.
Leave my water alone.
-You own the water?
This is my civilization
Go wherever you will and build yours.
l am an artist my friend
l build civilization wherever l want.
Here civilization.
When it comes to looks you are
Braveheart when tough just an artist?
Look at the way he looks at the water.
Narcissist. God's retard.
Why do you watch to girl?
ls this the civilization you will build?
l was looking
at the water to see if its deep enough.
Liar you were looking at her
l told you l was in love.
You will go and build
the civilization with her right?
What are you talking about?
l am married you idiot.
l will kill you!
Listen for a minute. Go and
build the civilization with her.
...and l will be the brain
behind that civilization.
-Oh really?
-What the heck?
Do you know
how to approach a woman?
l have your medicine.
Come here.
Women like sensitivity
Take this.
Look at me though
l will ask you something very clear.
Did you come from the monkey?
No we came from
the village together right?
You came from an ox then.
l see.
-l have a different idea.
-What's that?
l should slowly get out from the water.
-And?
Like this by showing off my body...
...the way water droplets
glide on your body the vision you get.
.. when sunshine licks the muscles
and gotta contract the hip muscles.
Why don't you break nuts with your hips?
Are we shooting a pirelli calender?
Be a bit graceful.
Take this arrangement
and offer it as a bouquet like this.
When she gets out of the water offer
it to her without looking at her body.
-What happpened yo?
-Nuts are broken
Use your tattoo's charm
The tattoo.
l guess you are
coming from hammam.
Did you remember me l am Arif?
-l remember are you still alive?
l am alive.
Thanks to my Arogan friend Stony.
Maybe you couldn't recognize him
he used to wear a hedgehog on his head.
l recognized leave us alone.
But did he ever mention about
his love to you? The tattoo.
Look what he had done
because of his love to you.
He pictured you
on his body.
lt's done by using a needle
has 250 strokes per cm.
An elaborate work.Maybe his love
maybe by reflecting it on his body...
...a reference to you... like living you
through his body. Crazy boy.
First of all my nose is not like that.
-Then please allow us to carry the furs.
Can't let the ladies to carry them all.
Which century do we live in?
Oh please don't tire yourself.
-For God's sake leave it to us.
An Arogan is coming
You will have tattoo as well.
l thought of it on two cheeks.
Please go ahead please.
This our song first of all
where do you know it from.
l had heard you
once in the jungle.
An Arogan is coming
Mimi likes him not.
He is nuts. He is nutty
He's driving us crazy
He's getting on our nerves.
He is nuts. He is nutty
He's driving us crazy
Pull it hard
Pull. Ok
Hide this one
so that they won't take it away from us.
Where should l put those?
-Lay them right here.
-Get well soon.
-What are you doing here?
lt's me Arif from the parallel
universe. Remember?
Aren't you the Rock's son?
-No.
He is currently free
his dad set him free.
Let him kiss your hand.
Those skills will get better with time.
-Lips don't get worn out by handkisses.
Write that down.
lt's a good one.
lf you allow me
l would like to stay with you here.
Our water and food are limited...
...and you can't adapt around here.
This kid is not coming from a holiday
village. No problem at all.
Plus hard times are over. We will
build a new civilization together.
-How about prohibitions?
-Prohibitions?
There are thousands of tools
in the Rock's cave.
lf we can take that over
the rest will come naturally.
What are you
looking at Out-cast?
Oh yes. All inventions of the last 40
years are there.ln the cave l know it.
Humankind searched for a miracle
in his own soul for centuries.
We have been here
only since fifty years.
Yo bro don't interrupt
the preacher's speech.
My friends the Age that we live in
has its obstacles...
l admit that.but if we can bring out
the treasure we have in us...
...in one week we can reach middle Age
and in 15 days the New Age.
... and we can stretch it out as far as
the French revolution in just a month.
-So can we make a fire?
-Of course.
Can we draw pictures on the walls?
-We have the master of that in here
Wheel?
-l will bring you the best of it.
The caves are too low can't sleep in there.
-What?
l was teaching the kids secretly
ls that's also free now?
Free public education.
lf we do those will we improve?
l received public education myself.
-Oh yeah
Come on kids. Who would like to
draw pictures on the walls?
Me... Me... Me.
Arif she is going to draw pictures
should l go as well?
Ok come on go draw
After all you are a young man.
Long live! Will those all happen Arif?
-Of course they will.
A bright future is waiting for us
with the help of this razor.
Whoever is in for the civilization
project please step forward.
Since your hair is very thin...
l cut it in layers took the volume away
lt's more convenient for daily use.
-Arif...
-Yep?
Bro won't you shave?
-No l am fine like this.
Continue just like that.
But don't try fantasy models
You should have a face to
appear in public.
When will we bring down
the goodies from the cave?
There's a a guard in front of the cave.
We must sneak in
-Stony
-l'm here.
When this dude
goes to the other side...
...we will go
around the entrance ok?
Hey you two!
No way.We can't even see ourselves.
How did you see us?
Stony.
-Frodo
Arif he recognized me.
Wait a sec. l'll blow his mind away.
Psst Harry Potter come here.
Go get me four ten sized nails
from the hardware store.
Move.
-Ok bro.
l bet he won't come back
until the lron Age.
Very nice.
-Are we taking everything?
Don't get into taking spears and stuff
just take the useful ones.
There it is.
My phone.
Hey look at me.
lf there is one more wheel in here
we can make a carriage.
There are so many wheels inside.
Give me that chalk. l will
write a message to your daddy.
Say ''hi'' from me.
Come help us.
Leave it leave it...
l got it let go.
Did you come comfortably?
Arif slept the whole way
l drove.
Wow l had made this one.
-What's this bro?
We never used it
freestyle work piece.
What are those?
-Wheat. We will make bread with them.
You can't make an hungry bear dance.
We are detaching the wheels.
l will use them as a millstone.
And we need soil with clay. Lots of it.
-Why are we building a statue?
What statue? We have long way to statues
That's for the pottery.
Long live!
-Bring them down bro.
Run run harder. Be useful a bit
Run with a purpose.
Load the flour cominge from here ok?
You take care of it.
Long live.
Don't fill it with wheat only
mix it with bran. .
Gentlemen don't waste time.
Young and old everyone will work
How old are you oldie?
-17.
lt's all because of faulty nutrition
Take this.
l found a name for you, Teoman.
Sharpen the tips.
First, there is no eating fruits and
vegetables without washing them.
There are some practical dishes
that working women can cook...
...when they get back to the caves.
For example:...
...you can create surprises by adding
small sauces to vegetables such as...
...carrots and zucchini. Don't get
stuck with the cook book. Be creative.
l make raw zucchini
it's more delicious like that.
Really? Don't you add
small sauces and surprises?
l don't find it necessary.
-Ee... nice.
My dear put those down
a fire will be made there.
Those are ready Arif.
Teoman go take care of the fire.
My friends we are here
with our hunter character right now.
The most important type of animal
nutrition is the swimming ones.
We receive Omega 3
through the fish
Lobster and shrimps are a luxury...
...for us right now.
Watch
That's it.
Go
That's not even a fish. But this one.
Yours look very dry to me.
How is it going?.
Take these.
l will cook those on tile kiln.
Move away.
That's a man's job.
What's up bro? Your boys are
very weak at catching fish.
Long live.
-Did the dough stick?
lt did.
Come on. Look. Just like this.
Where is the oven?
-There is no oven.
What? Build an oven immediately.
Bake them gold brown for 17 minutes.
Allright.
Put it next to the big rock over there.
A hole needs to be drilled in that.
...in the middle of the water canal.
Make it a T-Pipe. Bring the flowers.
Decorate them around four sides
with a tulip shape
lt's supposed to be like a tulip.
Can't you make that one?
Where is that artist?
Uncle Arif how does it look?
Super. You even made the tassel.
You can do anything you want.
Don't worry.
...but it became so slippery and sludgy.
-You... move... dissappear.
Keep it wet.
-Should l hold it like this.
Hold it...Let it go...Hold it.
Very nice.
But l can't hold on to this.
-l am helping you out.
Leave yourself to me.
-But it's slippery
Because it is turning.
You're good.
Ah. You scared me.
l came along like a ghost didn't l?
What are you doing Patrick Swayze?
We are working.
Ok but handle it carefully
so that nothing breaks.
No. Her hands got used to it
Look. No hands at all.
But it is slipping away.
-You will learn with time.
Most important rule of hunting is that
the animal should not notice your trap.
That's the principle.
See it didn't notice
Run!
This is the oil well prototype
l built for you.
Oil can be extracted by this. Should l?
-Do it.
So that you can start a war right?
lt was a test for you.
Listen to my examples carefully
Move.
Asking for oil and stuff.
You need to take this plow seriously.
lt is primitive yet very effective.
Ok set to go.
-Let's put it down.
We don't collect the fruits from trees.
You need to implant and harvest them.
Long live.
Now we need two oxes.
This dude brought a big movement
to the village bro.
He is good yo.
He eats a lot but he works.
You two come here.
Pull pull come on.
Pull it harder.
Dear friends leave your work
for two minutes please.
l am waiting for you at the square
for our opening ceremony.
Young ladies
hold this from two ends.
Congratulations.
May it be good for our village.
Mr. Teoman cut this off
with your teeth.
Give the water from there.
We are clapping just like this.
Let's not waste the water
like this Arif.
This is a symbol of civilization
Every village has one. lt's a symbol.
l see you ate all the crust.
Get the corners. lt is delicious.
Long live.
Even though it is an official holiday.
Let's not give a break to the education
Ok Arif.
Let it be a half day holiday.
Good afternoon my friends.
Children when l enter
you will all rise up at the same time.
You may sit down. What's up?
-Good you?
Stony let's erase the board.
Move over there.
Enough bro enough.
What was you last session Mimi?
Sharp stones and some thorny plants.
Nice. ln local administration
things evolve based on orders...
...that come from the headquarters
and regional population's wishes...
How about something simpler?
-We don't have that much time.
You tell me the duties of mukhtar.
-What?.Arif.
Bro that's how we were educated.
How dare you come to school with such
hair? Stony l want a ruler immediately.
T-Form?
-No. Beat-Form.
Have some passion to learn.
So far we only advanced for 51 years
But we don't have that much time.
l have 1 million years to cover.
-Bro calm down.
Wait a minute dude.
These kids are our past.
if there is a stupidity at this point
it affects the future as well.
Wait a minute. How is the Flora
and fauna here. Tell me now.
Are the mountains parallel to the seas?
-Calm down
We can't have ignorance in here.
Stony please.
Don't judge my education system.
Help me out a bit
ln my own Age... please...
All right kids
let's continue from where we were.
But you are not improving.
-Calm down.
The mukhtar has upset you.
Ceku! 10 minutes passed in the parallel
universe by now. My mind's always there.
l won't be able to go back l won't.
-Arif sit down over here.
l will harm you as well.
-Arif!
l will mess up history.
-Come to yourself!
l will distort history.
-Cool off man.
Here you go young man.
-What's that?
Never mind. Drink it up.
-This is raki man.
-We have melon too.
He is an inventor for real.
Calm down.
l make it by using grapes
l am distilling them over here.
l make as much as l need.
lf it wasn't for his bullying father
l would improve it even more.
But you are drinking this dry
it goes like this as well.
Oh god.
-Cheers yo!
Take the cooked ones.
Here we are.
Such a great idea Arif
The grilled meat is really delicious.
lt's different when cooked.
-Thanks. Here Cuhara.
Don't loosen up though.
We will switch to Bronze Age tomorrow.
Long live.
-Thanks. Mimi get it from here.
l don't meat eat at all.
-Really?
Our 218. lt was our robot
lt never ate meat either
218 cheers mate.
-Cheers Arif.
Camp fire huh?
Mediterranean nights.
...so unique.
...and especially...
...l wish a guitar would not show up
as soon as there is a camp fire.
Does anyone want salad?
-No.
lt was a handmade.
-l think it was beautiful.
What's up ladies?
You burnt my heart with that guitar
l decided that you are a bad egg.
l saved your life over there
So distasteful so repulsive.
Which age do you live in?
-Stone.
Look at that. You stink.
-l drank Raki.
Raki odor pushes ladies away.
Should l save you life one more time?
Put this mint gum in your mouth.
Remember raki repulses
mint attracts.
What's that Arif?
-Mint gum. l'll give you one too.
What do l do with it?
-You put it in your mouth like this.
What's wrong?
-Nothing.
Do you want to set up a swing?
-Let's do it.
Come on.
Mint attracts.
The missile is launched.
Hell no.
No way.
What do l see?
A lion. 1 1 meters long
Staring at me
with teeth this big!
Stone Age bro.
The lion can be 15 or even 20 meters
You can name the lion
by looking at where he lives.
Write that down
lt's a good one.
Arif you lost your joy.
-No l am fine.
Here eat some pumpkin
as desert.
We have soft melon.
Don't hold them like that l beg you.
Mr. Arif the food was very delicious.
Sister move out of the way.
Don't risk yourself.
Arif what's up?
-Good.
Arif you should swing Mimi
and l will picture this moment.
No. Let's not do things like that.
Arif are you OK?
-l am fine. l'll go to bed. Good night.
Arif calm down.
You represent a modern human being here
Calm down.
Chita.
Arif.
Call my mother you own
Call my father your own
come to us as a bride.
Where have you been my elegant bride.
Give me that. Why do you play music
and stir everyone up?
Arif.
-Yep
Quick. Go away.
Arif.
-l am coming.
What happened last night?
-lt was a moment of weakness...
Let's not make it a big deal out of it.
-A shooting star and then Mimi kissed me
Nice. Those things
will happen.
We have many stuff to do.
Move on.
l am not talking about a nuclear one
but hydraulic thermic or wind power...
..then we can get to the
Time Machine's level eventually.
So the plan is very simple and clean.
Let's not make the mistakes
that the future generations have made .
l mean let's protect the nature...
...keep it green.
And please fix this pooping-all-
over-the-place problem
Arif l will show you something.
What's up bro?
-Come
Shame on you.
Take this and continue.
That pooper will come up here.
Who was that? - l
See if you'll like it.
-Bro you make me blush.
Time machine.
Now watch me.
And?
-Wait.
See l came here from a second ago.
-Yes
lf you extend the waiting time
you can even go further in time.
l see.
-How is it?
Bro that's well-intentioned work
but not good enough.
Really?
-Yeah
Well then can it be a closet
or something like that?
That's possible.
-Long Live
Arogans are coming.
-They are coming.
Nobody panic. Do your work.
Close this barrier.
Leave it
let the kids play.
The barrier needs to be extended
from the sides a little bit.
OK.
What did l tell you last time?
Yo tubby does that thing on your head
keep growing all the time?
l don't really know
l wear whatever they give me.
Cut it.
What's that
in the middle of the village?
Fountain. lt hurt didn't it?
-l am not asking you. l ask Dimi.
Dimi left. lf you'd like
l can take a message.
Write down Meto,
l am curious about the fountain
Bidi.
Crow if you will hit someone hit me.
-Who are you l don't know you.
Hit me then.
-Wait my dear.
Dimi no hit me.
Gentlemen wait a min
we are trying to talk here.
Arif.
-Here take this.
Don't move
l will suck the poison out.
Are you ok?
-Good. Very good.
Stoneployeess step forward.
Get lost
we are not lending staff anymore.
l'll destroy this village.
-You gonna build a highway or what?
Cut it Crow.
Things have changed here.
l will come again.
But next time
l will come more crowded.
When you come bring a dictionary
We will be fluent in French by then
Move it
Move Jerk.
Arif what happened?
He got his lesson
and learned it by heart.
Anyway let's not lose our motivation.
Keep working.
Long Live
l don't live with your prayers
and won't die of your curse either.
They put flowers everywhere.
They are laughing and playing.
and in the middle of the village...
- ls a fountain.
Lie!
-He drew a picture on the wall.
What should we do?
-Finish them.
Everyone is so happy in the village
and all children are smiling.
lf children are smiling in a society
it means things are working well.
Get the news from the kids.
-Do you have any children?
No l don't... not born yet.
Mine is a letter to an unborn kid.
You do everything for him right?
-For all the children of the world.
lf l can fix things in this time period
my child will live in a better world.
We didn't build the fountain
for no reason. -True.
Maybe you and Stony
will have children someday too.
l don't know.
Bringing a child to a world like this.
Come on. Don't start talking like this
from this Age already.
You should make kids so that
they will influence our looks later.
lf my ancestors were like you
l would have been Jude Law now.
Do you think l am beautiful?
-l mean you have your charm.
You are the only one who wears
high heels in the tribe you tricky.
But ask that question to Stony
l am neutral towards you.
Neut?
- Neutral.
lt's like saying ''fable''.
Hard to say it hard to do it as well.
Get lost before a new love is born.
Your look is not a normal one.
Yaa. Arif.
Arif we preapared a play
for you with the kids.
ls it a stage play or an opera?
-lt's beautiful
l just need your music box.
Music box?
Oh my phone.
Our play is called
''War and peace''.
Son that's a classic.
Won't it be too heavy for the kids?
Didn't we say
everything is forbidden?
Get out of our village.
-l came from a different Age.
Lie you are lying.
-That's what you get leave us alone.
He really acts just like me.
Mimi l baked you a bread.
-Hello Mimi l love you very much
See that's for you.
Come on monkey friend
let's get some fresh air with you.
Call my mother your mom.
Hey hey! Not that part.
Cut ... cut !
Cut it.
Not that part.
Come on everyone. To the village
before it gets dark.
Let's not stay in the jungle.
Come on kids.
Take the monkey part out.
-What's wrong?
Take the monkey part out
Please.
Come on.
Bro Stony.
Please take out the monkey part.
The rest was very funny.
-You didn't even watch it till the end.
Bro...
Stony... Rock
Does the play reflect me?
lt does not reflect me bro.
lt should be about me arriving
and improving the village.
lt has nothing to do with monkeys.
Father.
Stony.
No... No oh my god.
How did they do this to you?
They didn't do anything to us.
But they burned down the village.
Look at that
They broke the fountain too.
Enemies of civilization.
What did you want from the fountain?
Cuhara.
How could they kill you
without pity.
l was burying myself in order to hide
But l got caught.
-Why didn't you resist?
-They were armed.
This coup caused us
to fall ten years back.
Why don't we destroy the Arogans?
-Destroy them with what your whistle?
Let's make arms. Let's fight back.
-Fight! Fight.
No. A war would make us
fall 4 years back.
Let's make spears sticks.
Arrows or something.
Let's dive in them with gyro knives.
-Gyro knife?
Gyro knife.
How ls that possible?
-Can you add some more chickpeas?
There he is.
Arif.
Got it. We will fight back.
-We will fight back.
Uncle Arif didn't you say
that a war was terrible.
You are right my dear.
War is bad.
We will have war
but on a different field.
Come with me.
l get rid of daily stress
in this rockuzzi.
What happened?
You didn't like the new village?
You want another lesson?
Look Rock you are in good shape here.
But you are oppressing the people.
lf l had not sworn
l would make you look like an ape
Let's handle this with kindness.
-Send 4 people to the tower tomorrow.
Shut up get out.
Let's do this.
Let's play a game with you.
lf we win you will let
the inventions free.
No more slavery to Arogs.
lf you win...
...l'll finish the tower all by myself
until the moon. Are you in?
Bravo Arif.
-You are lying. What game is that?
We will play ball.
-Ball? Can't do the ball Arif.
lf he sees a ball he'll take it
to the police like it were a bomb.
What kind of a ball game?
-Football. Team of six.
Arif... Bro...
l explain you the rules, lt is
played by feet there are goal posts.
At 5th score half-time
at 10 it ends. Are you in?
Bro why did you get into
the ball bussiness?
The ball huh?
Like this?
Yes ball. You have guts to play?
-Yes we do.
Ball has been played here for years.
To the honor of my father Sandy.
lt is an old tradition.
And we are a bit good at it.
Did my stupid son
give you that advice?
You guys play ball ?
-Bro did you ask me?
Devil Platin Ziko
Vele Zobizaretta.
...bring Carlos in.
He hasn't seen a ball for 8 months
he's gone crazy.
ls this a joke?
Be at the field
when the fullmoon is up.
l will take your panties off your ass.
lt will be played as fairplay ok?
Why are you looking at me bro?
-Where am l supposed to look at?
ls there anyone among us who can play?
-There is only one person
..and he'd never play.
l know a little bit too.
My voice is not that thin.
lf l tell you to draw a picture of it
you would though.
Can you picture a football Picasso?
Yes bro l can...
What ball? lt is an Arogan game.
What do we know about it?
At first l offered ping-pong
but this shabby said let's play ball.
Has noone touched the ball before?
Just a team of six man.
lf we win we will be free l said.
Only Cuhara knows
the Arogan ball in here.
Cuhara we will play ball with Arogans
would you come?
l quit that stuff.
Pass me.
Yet you gather around the square
like a parade .
Are we making a musical here?
They abuse us... They oppress us.
-Show some effort.
-Their voices are not that thin.
Wait a sec.
Why doesn't he play?
He was Arogan's goal keeper. A panther.
As he had eight goals he became sulk.
8 goals? l am not surprised that
he invented the raki.
Let me play.
No Mimi you can't play.
Those guys are too tough.
So won't we do anything?
Not to discriminate
but you can sew up uniforms.
OK.
Let me be the goal keeper then
Because l can't run too much.
Nice.
l and Stony will play forward.
Aren't there three more brave
young men to play huh?
Uncle Teoman stay out of this.
You!
You Meto and you.
Are we set?
-Yes.
Stony come with me.
We'll go for a walk.
Players come here.
Will you be able to play son?
-Yes we'll play.
Long live.
The field is favorable
but we fell into the death match!
Look at Carlos
Three guys are holding him.
What's that?
-Will you look?
Zoom in.
We will practice then.
What else can we do?
This a ball. Like every modern society
we have take balls seriously...
...and we will. This is our future.
Our opponent is very strong.
...but we have our special tactics.
Here is a prototype l prepared for you.
it is a terrific weapon that
wraps the foot 100 % ...
...and increases
ball control by 47% .
Later on write your shoe size down
We will all wear these during the match.
Now let's see your skills.
Let's see you shoot tiger...
Let's go for a lap around this rock
so that they can breathe openly.
Run. Come on.
Faster.
Arif is this OK?
-The uniforms. Beautiful.
But the pompon is too much
Take that out. -OK
lt will be more masculine.
Come on guys.
Arif.
-Be dynamic!
lt's been 3 laps.
-Running
Like this...
Pick up a stone from the ground
Dynamic. Bend your knees.
Don't stand like a poll
Dimi go to the goal post.
Go to the corner.
Play your game
instead of showing off like an artist.
Goal post is very important guys.
l expect a lot from the defense
because our goal keeper is weak.
Weak. Like this.
But it can't go on like this.
Meto send me the ball
everytime you get it
Let me see how you pass him.
That's it. Nice
You'll cover this psycho in the middle.
That guy is crazy
.. if only that guy was in my team.
My father wouldn't give him away
he has two more years.
Shoot.
lt's yours.
Tapu l like your center pass
He put it in?
-Goal !
Here you go.
This is yours.
Here you go Meto.
Dimi size 42.
-Long Live
Stony.
-Will we win Arif?
They might be better than us
but they ignore something: The Audience
One two three!
Firm like a rock solid like a rock...
.. erect and rigid
We're about to smash Arogan now
He's coming... coming
The Rock's husband is coming.
Whoever doesn't cheer
you'd better leave.
Arif !
-This is not a movie theatre....
The team... Come here!
14 minute passed
in the parallel universe.
Win or Die we will win
We got this game.
Win this game.
Well then
-Arog Arog Arog hey!
You are either mine or dead Ceku.
We will win this game Ceku
There is no other way.
May it be a good match.
Come on guys.
Come on Stony.
Look! They are trying to give us
the finger to demoralize us
That's the score board.
Zero zero.
Coyote you think
you can just do that?
Wet or dry?
-Dry
Dry. Ball or goal?
-Goal.
Enigma.
These tricks won't work on us.
The goal just shrunk.
Don't get upset.
Come on. Start.
Don't you have a whistle?
ls that a soother in your mouth?
Where is your whistle?
-Play !
Darn the ball you'll play...
You are a rascal
A rascal!
You really are a rascal.
-Come here.
Step on it
step on his foot.
lnside...
Don't let yourself down.
Don't get spoiled. Come on.
This is all because of me l know.
Take someone else if you want to.
lt has nothing to do with it.
They are not human. Look at them
Actually l have incredible powers
but because l took an oath...
Ask if there is any bread
in the tribune.
lf you break a bread above my head
l can use the special powers
that Garavel gave me.
Break this apart
above my head.
We called you a crowd.
Where are our fans?
Firm like a rock solid like a rock
erect and rigid...
...we'll smash Arogan right now.
Yo 300 Spartan check if you still
have the ball under your foot.
l am here.
Play the game!
Goal dude!
Firm like a rock solid like a rock
erect and rigid...
...we'll smash Arogan right now
Goal !
That's a goal too.
-How's that a goal man?
lt's just a replay.
Ok then.
Count this one as well.
Look at the pass.
Guys if we score we win.
Come on.
My pass was so good.
What you laughing at?
-Penalty.
-How's that a penalty?
Reversed one.
He rescued it.
-Your hands...
-l can go on.
His hands are gone.
Daddy.
-What happened? He's out?
Shut up.
-What will happen with the goal post?
-Come bro come.
-l want to continue.
Daddy your hands.
l saved it daughter.
-Mimi take care of your father.
Come on.
-He won't feel it yet...
Who will be the goal keeper?
Kova.
-My name is Cuhara.
Long Live.
Come on.
Lie ! That's not you but someone else.
-So what? lt 's a stuntman.
Why would he throw himself
on the ground like that?
Shall we score Stony?
-Let's do it Arif.
l am scoring this goal in the name
of all oppressed civilizations.
lt will be a goal.
Arog. Arog !
Arif.
-You played a good game. lt's yours.
Thanks but l don't have any bussiness
with time anymore.
We won the match Arif.
We are free now.
l am happy
for my Arog brothers and sisters.
But for me,
it is the end of the road Stony.
What are you talking about?
l didn't come here with
my own will. l was sent.
My purpose was to find the time machine
as soon as possible...
...and get back to my wife and my child.
But didn't happen.
But everything is free now Arif.
We can improve.
We can not.
We know how to use fork and knife.
That's something too
but not enough.
Plus half an hour passed
in the parallel universe right now.
l am sure Logar has already
taken my wife to Gora.
What are you gonna do then?
-l don't know
l'd rather dissappear in desserts
rather than mess up with the history
lt's all good. l got to know you guys
whom l'd only seen in encylopedias.
No one had a name in those books
although you do have names.
Mimi Stony Cuhara Crow Dimi
-Yes Arif.
They portray you so blury
and hazy in the books.
They portray you like monkeys.
Whereas it is not true.
Maybe we don't come from the monkeys
but we move certainly in that direction.
Don't forget me.
Your friend Arif.
l am not saying that
you should build my statue but...
...at least you can draw my picture
on a cave's wall.
...l am at least as worthy as an ox
ain't l Stony?
For the love of god move away.
Stony l congratulate you.
l didn't know that
you play ball so well my son.
Mr. Arif we learned so much from you.
Stay with us.
l learned a lot from you too.
But l have to go.
Stony come here.
Here your wedding present.
This is yours.
Fake Rolex but same as the original.
Mimithis is my wedding ring.
My wife's name is written inside.
lmprove yourself
and improve others ok?
All right bye bye.
Or to say it in your language:
Behind you !
Oh my god.
Ceku!
-Arif.
Ceku l can't believe this.
Here came my honey.
My wife came.
Ceku how did you find me?
Whole world is alert.
Everyone is talking about you.
Talking about me?
How?
After you left with Logar
to check the ship l went online.
A mystery from Afyon Turkey.
1 million years old but still intact...
The cave wall writings from...
...500.000 to 1 million years ago...
..shook science world up deeply.
The name Arif written on a cave's wall
is evidenltly visible.
Also a ring with the inscription Ceku
is among the findings. World is shocked.
Daddy.
-Tomorrow we'll leave for Gora.
That's when l understood
that Logar set you up.
l was prepared
when the doorbell rang.
ldiot. He dropped one of his lenses
and als combed his hair wrong
l had told him that
he can't make his hair like mine.
Arif!
-Thank you.
My lady and l are leaving.
We don't want to cool the machine down.
We'll make a wedding gift for you
when we get back .
Yes we will.
Arif.
-l am Logar.Commander Logar.
l am coming from the skies.
From the skies?