Baikie is a douce,
respectable town,
notable for its equable climate
and for the bracing quality
of its sea air.
We have never gone in for brash
advertizing in Baikie.
It has always been felt that
the attractions of the town
speak for themselves.
Foremost among
these attractions
are the waters
of the Baikie spa.
For 100 years,
discerning visitors
have gained much benefit
from their medical properties.
Mohammed has been in the habit,
so to speak,
of coming to the mountain.
We propose to change that.
Times are hard. Rates
and unemployment are rising.
So the forward-thinking members
of the governing board
of the spa
recently came to the conclusion
that we should capitalize
upon this valuable asset.
They provided substantial funds
with which to set up
this enterprise,
to make Baikie water
more widely available.
Mainly in the interests
of the health
of the general public,
of course.
But there is no doubt
that the advantages accruing to
the town will be considerable.
"Bottled in Baikie,
the Vichy of the north..."
- The Vichy of the north?
- ..will become a catchphrase.
It is therefore with confidence
in our future prosperity
that I now set this project
in motion.
(Applause)
Here you are, Willie.
Provost.
Thank you.
Hello, there, Captain.
Come on in.
- That's it, then, Mrs. Curran.
- Oh, thank you.
That's the stuff. They'll soon
be better with that.
- Good night.
- That's it, then, Captain.
- Are we taking a dram, then?
Damn it, not tonight.
I've people waiting.
OK. I'll look in tomorrow.
Come up to the house. You want
to see Peggy, don't you?
- You'll get your tea.
- That sounds like a good idea.
- You'll get a dram as well.
- That's even a better idea.
(Tom) Right. Shut the shop.
(Hums tune)
- Hello, Katherine.
- Oh, it's you, Peter. Come in.
Thank you.
- Tom's still busy in the shop.
- At this hour?
Dr. Monroe's just finished
his surgery
but he shouldn't be too long.
We're in the garden, actually.
There's folk waiting
for him already.
Tom's too easy. His hours
are stated on the door.
- People should keep to them.
- So should he.
He makes appointments
to see folk
and then leaves me to cover up
for him when he's late.
Exactly.
You know Mr. Houston, don't you?
Good evening, Provost.
- Mr. Carmichael.
- Evening, Provost.
The Baikie Advertiser here
in strength, I see.
A social call, I presume.
Not exactly. We just wanted
a wee chat about an article
your brother wrote
some time ago.
About the spa.
This seemed an opportune moment.
Can I get you something
to drink, Peter?
Eh? No. No, thank you.
It's a little early for me.
- John?
- Just a wee one, please.
Aye, thank you.
Sorry you're having such a wait,
but I'm sure Tom'll
not be long now.
My brother's getting to be one
of your regular contributors.
We're very glad to have him.
Thank you.
Tends to be a little outspoken
at times.
He has the knack of putting
his finger on a home truth, yes.
Um... Would you excuse me
just for a minute?
I suppose his lively style
would appeal to your readers,
though, of course, I've no ill
will against your paper.
It's excellent in its way.
Thank you, Provost.
Aye. There's room for
everything.
That's one of the admirable
characteristics
of our community.
The spirit of toleration
coupled with a willingness
to move with the times.
Like bottling the spa water.
Exactly.
Look at us. We used to be just
a quiet little seaside town.
Not now. People are beginning
to know the name of Baikie.
They see the name of the town
on the label of the bottle,
and want to visit the place
where it's made.
House and property values
are going up.
This is not to be quoted,
but we could be the only council
not to increase its rates.
Better get two bottles.
Goodness knows how much longer
your father's going to be.
Oh, and Peggy, get some crisps.
You know, nibbling things.
Otherwise they'll be in no
fit state
to talk to him
when he does come in.
Have you seen the most recent
unemployment figures?
Tourism and the bottling plant
will reduce them to the lowest
in this part of Scotland.
We'll be featuring that
in our next issue,
alongside
your brother's article.
Yes, I believe you said
it was composed some time ago.
Yes, it was published originally
in a technical journal.
This'll be a simplified version
for the general public.
All about the therapeutic value
of the water.
Tom's quite a fanatic
where the spa's concerned.
So he should be, Katherine.
He draws a generous fee as
technical adviser.
And they do say he was
the driving force behind it.
Do they?
Any mention of the work put in
by the board of directors?
Nobody would deny you've all put
a lot into it, Peter,
least of all Tom.
It was the board who initiated
the bottling project, after all.
Were you aware that Thomas
wasn't too keen on it?
Oh? On what grounds?
Oh, his argument
was somewhat vague.
It was something to do with
the balance of nature.
I fail to see the connection
myself.
I'm afraid when it comes
to practical matters,
my brother's not exactly gifted
with commercial foresight.
I was surprised to find you open
so late, Tom.
If I wait till after surgery,
they start getting better
12 hours earlier
with very little effort
on my part.
Cannae turn sick folk away.
Hope the news hounds have left
some tonic in the bottle.
Kath?
They must be outside. Ho-ho!
The symbol of civic authority.
I see we've got another
distinguished guest.
- Aye. The Provost?
- None other.
In that case, Tom,
I think I'll push off.
Not at all. The best thing
about my brother's visits
is their brevity.
Kate? Kate?
The captain for a dram.
- Hello, Donald.
- Is that all that's left?
There's more coming.
Peggy's bringing some.
- You might have known.
- That you'd be so late?
Any letters?
Well, there's bills
by the look of them.
Could I see them?
They're on the hall table, dear.
Donald?
Brother Peter. David, John.
Take that stuff neat, Donald.
It's a good malt.
We need strong young men
like you to stir things up.
And what, may one ask,
needs stirring up in Baikie?
Oh, well, Provost. The best
broth deserves a good stir.
That's a very peculiar remark.
Don't take it too literally
for the minute.
Mr. Houston tells me he's going
to publish an article of yours.
- Oh, aye?
- About the spa.
Ah, well, yes.
Cannae publish that just yet.
Well, that's bad news. Why not?
The town needs all the publicity
it can get.
In normal circumstances.
What's abnormal
about the present?
Now, look. I cannae say anything
about it...
(Katherine) Yoo-hoo! Tom?
Excuse me.
Is that the lot?
Was there a telephone call
for me from Glasgow?
- No.
- Oh.
Well, it's a bit late now.
But I might be able
to say something more definite
tomorrow.
You see, there might be
something very abnormal
or I might just be
imagining things.
I simply do not know. Are you
gonna take a dram before you go?
This sounds very mysterious,
Thomas.
Is it something I should know
about?
Look, Peter. I can't...
I insist that all matters
concerning the spa
should be passed through the
proper channels.
I can allow no one to go
behind our backs.
Nobody is going behind
your back.
I'm not so sure.
You have a pig-headed
determination
to go your own way.
And that's not the way
to do things
in our well-ordered community.
As for publishing anything about
the spa in a newspaper...
I happen to own the newspaper,
Provost.
Mr. Carmichael's my editor.
We...
I'm addressing my brother,
Mr. Houston.
Nobody's publishing anything
at the minute,
so why don't you sit back
and relax?
My wife assures me
that our sadly-diminished stocks
of liquor
are soon to be replenished,
so you can join us in a dram.
I don't feel like
an evening's drinking.
I wasnae offering you
an evening's drinking,
but please yourself.
I shall. Gentlemen.
- (All) Provost.
- Captain.
Provost.
I'll see him out.
- Good night, Katherine.
- Oh, are you away, Peter?
Bye-bye.
I'm afraid my brother-in-law's
not in the best of moods.
He's a man used to getting
his own way.
He is that.
Perhaps the presence
of the Advertiser's upset him.
I don't think so.
You seemed to be getting on fine
with him.
An armed truce, Mrs. Stockman.
The provost and I are on
opposite sides of the fence.
Are you sure there's nothing you
ought to be telling me?
Not just at the minute.
I've warned you. You can't say
I haven't warned you.
There's nothing we can do about
that either.
Are you sure there wasn't a
telephone call from Glasgow?
Quite sure.
Couldn't have rung and nobody
took any notice?
- Don't be silly.
- It could happen in this house.
Well, it didn't.
All right. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
When will you be sailing again,
Captain?
Ooh, I've no idea.
My ship's been laid up
for two months, refitting.
If there's another strike or
go-slow,
it could be the same again.
That's how it goes these days.
Dear, oh, dear, Captain. That
must be very frustrating.
How do you pass your time?
Quite usefully, as it happens.
My parents left me
a great barracks of a house,
but I had no use for it,
so my sister turned it
into a hotel.
- It's a good site.
- It's doing very well.
We're building a new extension.
That'll cost you a pretty penny.
When the anticipated tourist
boom takes place,
we'll all end up very rich,
though I have no romantic
notions of it.
You see before you a happy man.
Aye, it looks like it, Tom.
Sorry about the article, John.
So am I. We'd like to have used
it on Saturday.
Maybe it'll still be possible,
but send me out a copy first.
I sympathize with Peter.
You're being very mysterious.
I'm not gonna rush into
this one.
(Phone)
That could be him.
- Hello, Peggy. You're late.
- That's the phone, Dad.
So it is.
Tom Stockman.
Ah. Angus.
Great. Well, better late
than never.
Just a minute.
Right. Read it to me.
Thank goodness. You take that
out and hold the fort.
Who's out there?
Mr. Houston and John Carmichael
from The Advertiser.
Oh, and someone else!
Oh, Mum...
Chrome sulphate?
Now, what would its toxic effect
be in these quantities?
No, no, no. I suppose it isn't
your business
but it shouldn't be there
at all.
Aye, yes. Go on, please.
- Hi.
- Hello, Peggy.
- Well, here it is.
- Ah, great.
At long last.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- Hello. You're late.
Parent-teachers meeting
on top of everything else.
- Not a good day, huh?
- No worse than usual.
It's the size of the class.
I've got nearly 40 just now.
40?
And thousands of teachers
unemployed.
- Quite.
- How do you control that many?
I can control them all right,
but I can't teach them.
You see, they range from
very bright to rather slow.
I have to go at the pace of the
slowest
while the bright ones get bored.
That's not fair.
And are the dull ones
not entitled
to as much consideration
as the bright?
You've missed the point. I was
thinking of equalizing upwards.
I was just checking.
Do you know what I'd like to do?
I'd love to start a class in the
evenings
and give the slower ones
the attention they need.
- In your own time?
- Why not?
- You're tired enough as it is.
- I'd be doing something useful.
I don't think the provost or
the town council would allow it.
- Never.
- I could do it off my own bat
but accommodation's a problem.
There just isn't enough
room here.
Listen, that mightn't be
such a problem.
I'm not just talking about two
or three kids.
More like 10 or 12.
Maybe we could find you a room
at the hotel.
(Houston) There you are.
- Could you?
- I'll see.
This is gonna make everybody
sit up.
Who?
The whole population.
Why? What is it?
- It's a discovery.
- Oh, hell. Another one.
It's a very interesting piece
of scientific detection.
It'll teach people to talk about
my pig-headed determination
to go my own way.
What is it, dear?
This is an analysis of the water
of Baikie spa.
Generally considered to be
of therapeutic value.
Invalids drink it
when they can afford to.
And we're now stockpiling
vast quantities of it
to ship abroad and get ourselves
a reputation
of the Vichy of the north.
(Katherine) We know all that,
dear.
But do you know what the waters
of Baikie spa really are?
- Yes, they're medicinal...
- They're a slow poison.
- Absurd.
- But perfectly true.
Could you pour us a dram, dear?
What gave you this idea?
I've had a number of customers
with similar illnesses.
I can tell by the prescriptions
and by the look of them,
jaundice for a start.
So I began to think there was
a toxic element.
And I began to look for
a common source.
And I discovered that they'd all
been drinking spa water.
Cheers.
People have been taking it
for years.
Drawing it by the cupful, fine.
But now they're taking off
vast quantities
and I believe that's affected
the water table.
That's the general level of
water below the ground.
I suppose it's possible.
What about it?
The well is being forced to
replenish itself
from further and further afield.
New constituents
are seeping into it.
Your brother said you were
against the plant.
Had you foreseen this happening?
I warned them. If tinker
with the balance of nature,
unexpected things can happen.
It now contains appreciable
quantities of chrome sulphate.
And my customers were suffering
from chrome poisoning.
My God. Any idea
where it's coming from?
Well, chrome sulphate is used
to tan leather
and the Dalhousie tannery
is only four miles away.
What?
Your father's tannery's
the probable source.
Well, I don't know what he'll
say about that.
But I'm sure it's a good thing
that you've discovered it.
- Of course it is.
- (Peggy) What can be done, Dad?
- It'll need to be sorted.
- Can it be sorted?
I don't know. We cannae use
the spa in the meantime.
Why did you not tell anybody
about this before?
Because I wanted
an independent analysis.
Baikie folk wouldn't believe me.
Still, I think you might have
told us, your own family.
(Tom) Still, your grandfather
should be the first to know.
He'll be interested.
It's his tannery.
I put a formal report in
to Peter.
He won't like it.
He'll be glad it's been brought
to light.
Tom? Will you give us a piece
for The Advertiser?
Two or three paragraphs.
Simple language.
I don't see why not.
It's a matter of public concern.
Precisely.
You know, of course, Tom.
This will enhance your
reputation even further.
(Houston) Your concern
for the welfare of the people
is very refreshing.
(Peggy) That's true, Dad.
- (Tom) Kate?
- Hello?
There we are.
Ten past 12 on the dot.
Well, you're too early.
For once.
Any messages?
Peter rang. He wants to see you.
He said he'll be at the bottling
plant this afternoon.
Is that all he said?
I don't think it's all
he wanted to say.
He was being careful
over the phone.
Aye, that's why he didn't phone
the shop.
He's a funny fellow.
Hates to think of anybody
doing anything for this town
if it's not himself.
Could you not share the credit
with him?
Make out that he gave you
the idea. Something.
I don't care who gets
the credit.
The important thing
is to get it sorted.
My father phoned. He wants to
see you too.
I'm not surprised.
Mrs. Mackintosh.
I've got her pills.
She must have forgotten
it was early closing.
I'll call in on Archie
on the way back.
Well, don't be too long. I've
got the women's rule at three.
Who's there? Who is it?
- Oh, it's you, Mr. Stockman.
- Hello, Mrs. Mackintosh.
- Good afternoon.
- He's looking very well.
- Oh, aye. He's fine now.
- I brought your pills.
Oh, dear. Aren't I silly
to forget those, eh?
It's no trouble,
Mrs. Mackintosh.
Oh, taking up
your precious time.
My time is my own.
It's my afternoon off.
Oh, you're kind.
You're very kind.
Oh, heavens.
Oh, damn!
Morning, Archie.
What's the trouble?
I've got black spot.
How does it affect you?
Can you describe the symptoms?
God's sake, it's not on me.
On my roses. Look.
I don't know much
about gardening.
- I leave that to Katherine.
- It's a fungus.
Catch it quick or it spreads
and can destroy the whole plant.
Hey, by the way. What's this
damn fool story of Peggy's?
Something about poison.
- She told you.
- Yes.
Came in this morning especially
on her way past to tell me.
What's she up to, eh?
She's not trying to take
the mickey out of me, is she?
- No, no. She wouldn't do that.
- I should hope not.
Do you mean to tell me
it's true?
Perfectly.
Oh, well. I don't blame you.
Must be quite a temptation.
What is?
To make a fool of that brother
of yours.
But it's perfectly true.
The water's contaminated
all right.
With chrome sulphate
from my tannery?
Probably.
(Scoffs) He's not gonna
believe that.
He's got to believe it.
Everybody will.
Everybody?
(Chuckles) Oh, well.
Good luck to you.
Ah, well. Serve 'em right.
They threw me out of the council
because I used to give them
a bit of my mind now and again
and they didn't like it one bit.
There's nothing in these fella''
heads
but feathering their own nests
and running other people's
lives for them.
You pull their legs good and
hard. It'll do them no harm.
Look, it's perfectly true.
The water's contaminated.
Oh, sure, it's true, yeah.
(Chuckles)
Perfectly true, I'm sure.
Tell you what.
I'll give you a box
of Havana cigars
if you can get away with it.
- Right. You're on.
- Good.
I think I'll go and see Houston
before I see Peter.
Houston? Is he in on this?
Aye. You could put it like that.
Oh. Well done, Thomas.
You're going the right way
about it.
Get it into the newspapers and
you'll pull it off all right.
What about the spa piece?
Well, I've kept half a
half-column for the front page.
That should be enough.
The first blast of a trumpet.
- Aye, when we get started...
- Houston?
- Mr. Stockman's here.
- Which one?
The human one.
I'll see him in my office.
That's fine, John.
You're doing a good job.
Oh, Mary. Bring three coffees.
On a tray.
(Tom) Sir, has the provost
seen you before?
- I'm seeing him this afternoon.
- I've been thinking about this.
Good.
For you,
it's an isolated incident,
but I don't think you realize
how much it involves.
A considerable expense,
but that can't be avoided.
See, that's what I wanted
to talk over with you.
You think the source of
pollution is the tannery.
- Yes.
- Well, there's another source.
And it's contaminating
more than the spa.
It's contaminating
the whole town.
- Know what I'm talking about?
- No idea.
Mainly, I'm talking about
the council.
Not all the council. Some are
reasonable, decent people
doing what they think
is a decent job.
But a few of them have the whole
power of this place
in their hands.
They and the people behind them.
- What people?
- Oh, come on, now.
The people who don't want change
unless there's something in it
for them.
The people on the council are
there
because they've got ability.
Did they show any ability
or experience
when they agreed
to the bottling plant?
- Against your advice?
- No, but that was a mistake.
That'll be put right.
- You think it's that easy?
- It's gotta be done.
It will be done
if I take the thing up.
I want your campaign.
Oh, no. That sort of thing's
not necessary.
I'm sure that the people
on the council
have the interests of the town
at heart.
Well, I'm not.
When I bought The Advertiser,
I wanted to break
these people up.
Let in some fresh air.
I wanted this town to be
a friendly, cheerful place,
for the fellow who's earning
his daily bread.
I know, you told me.
They nearly broke you instead.
Yeah.
Yes, very nearly.
I was on the edge of going bust.
Then I got help from...
well, someone I didn't expect.
I've been keeping quiet
for a while, Tom,
but now I'm just about
ready again.
It's the corruption
behind the red tape
and official bloody-mindedness
I want to get at.
I want this town run for
the sake of the town's people
instead of a few
wealthy parasites.
Commendable.
You have given me a peg
to hang it on.
- A what?
- I had to work my way up, Tom.
I know what it's like
to be the bottom of the heap.
- (Phone)
- Hello?
Do you know what people
think of me?
Sorry, he's in a meeting.
They think I'm dangerous.
They think I'm an agitator.
- Do they?
- Yeah. And they're quite right.
- (Knock on door)
- Come in.
I thought I'd save the lassie
the stairs.
Thank you, Mr. Geikie.
Machine coffee, I'm afraid, Tom.
Ah. Thank you.
Missed my dinner.
Thank you.
Is it true what I hear, sir,
that you've been demanding
improvements
in the water supply to the spa?
Well, I suppose you could
put it like that.
Any scheme to improve the town's
amenities will have my support.
That's very kind of you.
It wouldn't do any harm
to have the working people
of Baikie behind you.
The proletariat. We form,
as it were, the silent majority.
And it's always a good thing
to have the majority
on your side.
It is, but not necessary
in this case.
No, the whole thing is perfectly
straightforward.
If you'll pardon me, sir,
I know our local authorities
very well
and they're often
quite reluctant
to act on proposals
that come from other people.
If we could get up
a wee demonstration...
A demonstration?
Aye, about the new water supply.
With moderation, of course.
Great moderation.
That has always been
my watchword.
A well-known characteristic
of yours.
Both in my trade union capacity
and as chairman
of the rate-payers.
I'll see you have
the full support
both of my members
and the rate-payers.
Geikie, about
this demonstration.
We'll have a word later,
Mr. Carmichael.
Now we must show
great moderation.
I mean, no point
in offending the authorities.
That never did any good
to anybody.
But they can't take exception
to a moderate and reasonable
demonstration of public opinion.
I'm sure it'll not be necessary.
Well, the authorities
are always slow to act.
We'll stir them up in
The Advertiser, Mr. Geikie.
Aye. Well, remember,
do you no harm
to have the ordinary folk
of this town behind you.
No, of course not.
Well, I'll away and get on
with it, then.
Well, it's er...very reassuring.
He's a well-meaning
sort of chap.
We've too many well-meaning,
decent folk
that wouldn't put out
their tongues at a tame rabbit.
You can't blame the council
for kicking them around.
This town needs people
with drive and guts.
Tom, did you do that piece
for us?
No, I brought you this instead.
It's a copy of my official
report to the provost.
That's even better.
Treat it as confidential
for the minute.
Now, if I have any difficulty
in getting what I consider
to be adequate action,
then you can make what use
you like of it.
We shouldn't start the ball
rolling?
No. I think we give the council
a chance to put matters right.
I'm inclined to agree.
Let's save our ammunition
until we need it.
All right.
But the moment you find you're
up against a brick wall,
and I'll be very surprised
if you don't, you let me know.
Certainly. But I don't think
we'll have any trouble.
No?
I noticed you express yourself
with your customary violence.
The remark that we're peddling
an expensive but effective
method of self-destruction.
That's what it'll come to
unless we do something about it.
You conclude that
the toxic material
- is coming from the tannery.
- Yes.
I called in on Charlie Duncan
this morning.
You play bridge
in the mornings now?
In his capacity as chairman
of the environmental
health committee.
Sorry, sorry.
I put your theory to him
as a hypothetical possibility,
something that might
have to be dealt with
some time in the future.
- In the future?
- We had a good laugh.
Did you?
The effluent from the tannery
goes into a settling pond.
It is then carefully filtered
before it passes into
the public sewerage system
by which time
it is completely harmless.
No, it's nothing to do with
the public sewerage system.
It's probably seeping
from the settling pond
down into the water taper.
We considered that. It's
imaginative to say the least.
- It's in line with the facts.
- In your opinion.
Have you considered what might
be involved?
Well, that's not my business.
The tannery would have to close.
To rebuild the settling pond
would require a very large sum
of money.
And with the spa closed,
that would be the two principle
sources of prosperity gone.
I've no choice.
And in the end,
your theory may well prove
to have no foundation.
It's unlikely.
I am not convinced the water
is as bad as you make out.
The figures are in my report.
They come from
a reputable analyst.
If we go on drawing water
at the present rate,
they're bound to get worse.
I still think you're
exaggerating somewhat.
Would it not be possible,
Thomas, for a capable chemist
to prevent any injurious
influences
from becoming too obvious?
This plant is an established
fact. We must face it.
And the council might be
prepared
to consider certain improvements
consistent with a reasonable
expenditure.
I'm not gonna have anything to
do with trickery of that sort.
- Trickery?
- Fraud. Criminal fraud.
All I am asking you to do
is wait.
Later, I'll raise the question
in council
and we'll do what we can
in private
but in the meantime...
In the meantime, not a word of
this must get to the public ear.
- It's too late.
- What?
Too many people
know about it already.
Who knows?
The Advertiser.
They know.
Oh, you're aye independent,
Thomas.
(# Pop music plays)
Aye. There's a lot of people
earn a shilling here.
Have you thought what this could
do to you?
- To me?
- Aye. To you and yours.
Explain that.
I've always tried to behave
in a brotherly sort of way.
- I've always tried to help.
- Im trying lto help you...
But the moment you get an idea
into your head,
you must write to the newspapers
about it.
It's part of my duty as
technical adviser to this plant
to keep the public informed.
The public has got enough
on its plate.
You see, here, Thomas,
I'll be blunt with you.
You are doing yourself no good.
You're aye complaining about
this, that or the other thing.
You complain about the local
authority.
Not just you, your daughter too.
You complain about
the health service.
Now you're complaining
about the spa.
You have no consideration
for anyone else's opinions.
You seem to have forgotten that
you've got me to thank
for your appointment at the spa.
- I was the best you could get.
- True enough.
And I did a lot of work
in developing it.
But it was the practical men
who initiated the big project.
When the right time came,
I and the council
took the matter in hand.
And look at the ruddy mess
you made of it.
Well, you only did it
to bolster your own egos.
Now we're getting down to
the tooth of it.
All you're wanting is to pick
a quarrel with your superiors.
You have no time for anyone
set in authority above you.
Any stick is good enough
to beat them with.
I'll tell you this, though.
You are not going to get
the better of me.
You have been indiscreet,
Thomas.
All sorts of rumors
will get about
and rumors against established
authority are dangerous.
So is that water
you're bottling there.
It'll be necessary for you
to issue a public disclaimer
saying that after further
investigation,
you found that the condition
of the water
is not as critical
as you first thought.
Do you really expect me
to do that?
Yes.
Oh, well, sorry. I can't.
And you'll never bend it by
tickling. That's my opinion.
As a private individual,
you can think what you like.
As our employee,
you have no right
to express any personal views.
I've a moral duty to.
Not on any subject
concerning the spa.
I forbid it!
You forbid it?
You oblige me to take that tone.
And you really expect me
to issue a statement
saying that I don't know my job?
Aye. Some statement on the lines
I indicated.
Well, you know perfectly well
that I won't do that. I can't!
Well, that's unfortunate,
Thomas.
Because I have some influence
with the regional medical board.
I could have your license taken
off you.
Car or dog?
You know what I mean.
They'll stop you dispensing.
On what grounds?
You don't keep
to the stipulated hours.
I go over them. That's legal.
And what about your amateur
doctoring?
Oh, I know what goes on.
A few pills here,
a bottle of medicine there.
- Doctors...
- Frown on it.
One little slip-up, one wrong
diagnosis and you'd be finished.
- It's never happened.
- Are you saying it couldn't?
My God, you've sunk pretty low.
I will use any means I can
to make you see reason.
It's not just you. It's
your family I'm thinking of.
Leave them out. It's the town
I'm thinking of.
You'll do it no good
by cutting off its principal
sources of income.
What kind of an income is it
that thrives on the sale
of corruption?
You should be ashamed to make
offensive remarks like that
about the town
that gives your livelihood.
Perhaps I should say gave you
a livelihood.
And with no help from me,
you'll soon find yourself
without customers
when the people hear you've
ruined the town's prosperity.
- He said that?
- Arrogant pig.
What are you going to do?
He's not gonna get away with it.
- Good.
- He's got power behind him.
And I've got power behind me.
I've got the people behind me.
I've got the press behind me.
But you can't fight
your own brother.
Do you not want me to stand up
for what I believe to be right?
- Of course. He's got to.
- It'll do you no good.
I've done my duty. I'm not
thinking of myself.
You're not thinking about
your family either.
Oh, Mum...
- Don't worry about me, Dad.
- I'm sorry, Katherine.
I'm not gonna give in
to blackmail.
It's red-hot.
He does have a persuasive
literary style.
"There can be no conflict
of interests.
"My public duty must outweigh
"any filial
or commercial loyalty."
(Woman) Mr. Houston? Telephone.
I've made one or two cuts.
It'll save us
half a dozen libel actions.
Houston.
Oh, hello, Mr. Stockman.
Do I take it you've run into
that brick wall?
He's got to let us use it.
That's good news.
Good God. That's going a bit far
even for him.
Mmm. What? Yeah.
We'll be seeing you, then?
Right. Goodbye just now.
- OK, the fight is on.
- Good. It'll start something.
But we've got to follow it up.
They won't fall down at the
first blast of the trumpet.
But if the provost and the
council sit back and do nothing,
the rate-payers
will want to know why.
The council sank a lot
of their money in the plant.
But it's the shareholders
who get the profit.
It won't take
the rate-payers long
to detect the faint,
sweet smell of corruption.
Do you know,
I get the impression
our provost's in
a very satisfactory mess.
I had to give it to the papers.
That Houston man's
just using you.
- I'm using him.
- He's a rabble-rouser.
That's just what
this town needs.
Well, I don't trust him.
He's on Dad's side. You heard
what he said yesterday.
He wants public recognition
for Dad.
You're easily taken in.
And so are you, Tom.
It's happened time and again.
You've a better brain than
anybody else in this town
but anybody can make
a fool of you.
That's the kind of thing
Peter would say.
You're beginning to talk
like him.
Thanks very much.
Are you gonna make the tea?
It's not too late to stop them
printing the report.
I wish you'd go and see Houston.
Dad?
All right. I'll go and see
Houston
and you go and make the tea.
- (Peggy) You can't.
- Be quiet.
Is there any shortbread? I
didnae get my dinner.
- Did you really mean it?
- What, to see Houston?
Cross my heart.
What's the matter with you?
Well, I never thought
I'd see the day.
You convinced me I should go
and see Houston.
I did?
Public recognition.
All that sort of nonsense.
I'll put a stop to that.
So you're going to let him print
the report?
Absolutely. And give him
ammunition for the battle.
Fantastic!
It's strong meat, Geikie.
I hope it doesn't alarm you.
Oh, I've no objection to
strong meat, Mr. Carmichael.
That's the stuff.
Hit hard and often.
- Aye, but with moderation.
- Moderation, aye.
All the incompetents
are gonna be kicked out,
and we're gonna put in
honest, vigorous men.
This article is just the weapon
we've been looking for.
Tom Stockman's gonna be useful
all right.
It'll be fine
if he sticks to the spa
but I don't think it would be
wise to follow him further.
Geikie, I detect a distinct
tinge of yellow in you.
I'll thank you not to make
personal remarks
about my appearance.
It's all right, Mr. Geikie.
It just means perhaps you're
inclined to be overcautious.
Oh, aye. I'm a bit timid
when it comes to offending
the authorities.
I'm an older man than you are,
Mr. Carmichael,
and I've found
it doesn't always pay.
- Nothing more you want me for?
- Not at the moment.
Fine.
Look, I know he's the father
of the chapel and all that,
but can't we keep out of the
editorial side?
It's not that simple.
I'm bloody fed up with all this
card-carrying business.
You seem to let him get away
with it.
Geikie has a lot of influence.
He's got a finger in every pie.
Unions, rate-payers, the lot.
- In a small town, that's good.
- I realize that.
There's something
you don't know.
That time we nearly went bust
cos we couldn't pay bonuses.
It was Geikie who persuaded
the workforce here to carry on.
Even now, if he insists on
higher rates
and withdraws his labor,
we have to put up the shutters.
But surely...
I'm perpetually balancing
on a knife edge.
A few issues not published
could finish me.
And the workforce. They'd only
be cutting their noses off
to spite their faces.
One of the big newspaper groups
is waiting for just that to
happen,
to take over this part of
Scotland.
They'll snap this one up
and the workers will be kept on
with higher wages.
- Oh, I didn't know that.
- You know now.
So, I'm afraid we'll have
to carry on with this.
Excuse me, Mr. Houston.
Mr. Stockman's here,
the other one.
The provost?
What the hell does he want?
He wants a word with you.
I don't think he wants to
be seen.
He came in through
the case room.
All right, send him in.
Oh, Mr. Geikie? See we're not
interrupted, will you?
(Geikie) Do come through,
please.
It's the provost, Mr. Houston.
Good evening, Mr. Houston.
You'll be surprised
to see me here.
Yes, we didn't expect you. Have
we got a chair for the provost?
You've very snug in here,
Mr. Carmichael.
It serves its purpose, Provost.
It serves its purpose.
Long may it continue to do so.
Thank you.
A free and flourishing press
is an essential part
of the community.
And here I come, Mr. Houston,
without notice,
to take up your time.
Well, we're delighted
to see you.
I've had a very annoying
experience today.
Sorry to hear that, Provost.
Was your civic lunch
not up to standard, Provost?
My brother was responsible
for the incident.
- Really?
- Mm.
He submitted a kind of report
about certain alleged defects
in the water supply to the spa.
- Indeed.
- Did he not tell you about it?
- I thought he said...
- Yes, he did say something.
John, do you remember about
a report...
I'm sorry to trouble you,
Mr. Houston,
but I forgot to take the copy
with me.
I can read it
during the tea break.
Mr. Geikie. Is that, by any
chance, my brother's report?
Aye, it is.
Mr. Houston and I
were just chatting about it.
- I take it you've read it.
- I've glanced through it.
- You'll publish it?
- Why not?
- Well...
- Just a minute, Mr. Geikie.
- You don't mind, Mr. Houston?
- No, not at all.
You have the reputation
of being an intelligent
and thoughtful man, Mr. Geikie.
It's very kind of you
to say that, Provost.
And a man of considerable
influence, eh?
I'm just a voice
of the citizenry, sir.
I've no doubt you're aware
of the general trend of opinion
among them.
I believe I am.
Aye. It's evidence of
an excellent public spirit.
Mind you, it'll be no
small sacrifice
the people of this town
are going to make.
Sacrifice?
I don't think we understand you,
Provost.
Are you talking about the spa?
I would make a rough estimate
of 150,000
to put the water supply right.
- 150,000?
- Aye. More or less.
It'll make a big difference
to the rates.
The rates?
Good God, don't say the town's
going to pay for it?
Where else do you expect it
to come from?
Not from the tannery?
There's no hard evidence
that they're the source.
The bottling plant
is a private company.
Surely the shareholders
would have to find the money.
- Exactly. Good point, Geikie.
- No, no, no.
They're in no position
to find it.
And they've already incurred
a substantial capital outlay.
Let's remember that they are
good Baikie men.
But if they're pushed too far,
they may be forced to sell out.
To London, perhaps.
Well, that puts a different kind
of complexion on things.
Nevertheless, Geikie,
that report has to be published.
It'll mean closing the spa.
And the tannery.
And we'll not get many visitors
if we announce that the water
supply is contaminated.
And frankly, Mr. Houston, it'll
hardly improve your circulation
if you're seen to be advocating
unemployment
and an increase in the rates.
Is it possible, do you think,
Provost,
that Mr. Stockman has been
exaggerating this thing
a wee bit?
I must confess, I find myself
driven to that conclusion.
Indeed. You might even say
that he's been...
imagining the whole thing,
so to speak.
The possibility
had occurred to me.
Well, I must say, I think that
very remiss of Mr. Stockman.
You'll excuse me speaking about
your brother in this way.
I'm a great believer in
moderation, as you well know,
- but in the circumstances...
- I take no offence, Mr. Geikie.
My brother has aye been
headstrong.
I've tried to curb his excesses
but it hasn't always been easy.
Difficult position for you,
Provost. I can see that.
You won't want to take this
matter any further, Mr. Houston?
Of course we bloody will!
Now listen to me, Geikie.
Tom Stockman may be right
or he may be wrong.
The only way to find out
is to publish that damn report
and have the whole thing
thrashed out in public.
All due respect to you, Provost,
but we cannot suppress
that report
just because you disagree
with your brother.
It's not quite as simple
as that.
You see, once this thing
gets out, the town is ruined.
If that thing doesn't get out
and is proved to be right,
this town will be really ruined.
In the meantime,
we must leave ourselves
in the hands of the provost.
He wouldn't say his brother
was imagining the whole thing
if he didn't think it was true.
Don't you agree, Mr. Houston?
Well, good God, man.
Of course you don't!
I'm afraid I will have
to put it to my members
that it might not be
in the interest
of the ordinary people
of this town
to publish such
a dangerous report.
And while I was making
that proposition,
all labor would have
to be withdrawn.
I'll be in the case room
if you need me.
John? John?
Oh, well. I'll be off to
my work, Provost.
It was very good of you
to straighten us out
in this matter.
A painful duty.
Aye.
We'll get together
and sort this out.
I bloody hope so.
It's a sensitive area.
You don't understand...
I understand, all right.
It gives me a pain
in my sensitive area.
Now, look. I've had small-town
politics up to here.
If you want to placate those
two bastards then you may do so,
but without my help.
I'll sort this out.
Just leave it with me.
I've drawn up a short statement,
Mr. Houston.
It indicates the board
is always on the lookout
for possible defects
and will not hesitate
to put anything right
without incurring
too much expense.
Have you got it with you?
As it happens...
Ah. Carmichael.
Now, this...
Mr. Houston? The other one.
Well, well, Peter.
I'm surprised at you coming here
behind my back.
I'm sorry to trouble you,
Mr. Houston,
but I thought we should include
some statistics.
It's no trouble.
You know I had a number of
customers with chrome poisoning.
There'd be no names, of course.
No means of identification.
It's an idea.
But can we talk about it later?
We're very busy now.
As you wish, but...there's one
other thing
that I thought
I'd mention to you.
You know what the folk here
are like.
They're a good bunch
in the main and, er...
Well, so far as I know,
they think quite highly of me.
Oh, they do indeed, sir.
They do indeed.
- So far.
- Exactly.
So I thought
when this became public,
they might feel
they should make some gesture.
Look, Tom.
I can't hide it from you
any longer.
No, I won't hear of it.
If anything of that sort
is being planned...
Anything of what sort?
Well, I don't know.
I mean, anything.
I mean, whatever it is,
you must give me your word
you'll put a stop to it.
Don't think I'm ungrateful,
I appreciate it very much,
but I have done nothing
except my duty.
See this, Houston?
- The symbol of office.
- For God's sake, Thomas.
The symbol, not the man.
If I was to open this,
I wouldn't find a small lie
or a tiny hypocrisy
or even the slightest whiff
of corruption.
But if I was to open
its owner...
Would you please put down
my umbrella?
You've been wasting your time,
Peter,
if you've come to try and stop
Houston publishing my report.
And does Mr. Houston
intend to publish your report?
No, I don't.
That's what I've been trying
to tell you.
I don't quite understand.
Well, he's not gonna ruin
himself and his paper
and the people of this town
for the sake of
an imaginary grievance.
What's all this about, Houston?
You've given us
a highly-colored account.
What do you mean by that?
Your report
exaggerates the whole thing.
I'm not asking you
to understand it.
Just publish it. Leave the
explaining to me afterwards.
Sorry. I can't.
What? You own this paper.
Carmichael edits it.
Between the two of you,
you control it.
That's not quite true, sir.
It's controlled by the public.
Public opinion, of course.
The opinion of the men
and the women of this town.
- They would be against me?
- Oh, aye, they would.
They've changed their tune
very quickly.
It would mean disaster for them
if your report got out.
Economically, maybe,
but a physical disaster
for thousands of others
if it doesn't.
Is this final, Houston?
I'm afraid so.
The official statement
will appear in Saturday's issue,
Mr. Houston.
Yes.
Well, I'll get my report
published privately.
And distributed.
You won't find it easy
to get it printed in this town.
I'll hold a public meeting.
I'll tell everyone about it.
- Are you a gardener, Houston?
- No.
Ah, but you've maybe heard
of black spot.
It's a fungus
that attacks the leaves
and eventually spreads
and destroys the whole plant.
Well, it seems to me
that there's more than roses
are prone to it.
Great things are done
when men and mountains meet.
And this is not done
by jostling in the street.
Small mountain.
Blake might have considered it
big enough.
Imagine your father not getting
anywhere else to speak
but out here.
What's everybody afraid of?
I'm not surprised. After all,
it's a controversial subject.
In circumstances like this,
people are a wee bit nervous.
(Peggy) So am I. I'm glad to
have someone around
in case they
start throwing things.
Let's stand by the archway.
We can make a quick exit
if things get too brisk.
You don't think there'll be
trouble, do you?
You can never tell
with a crowd like this.
(Captain) I see they're all
here, eh?
(Applause and cheering)
- Can you hear me?
- Yes!
Ah, well, look. It's 5:15.
I think we should just begin.
(Tom) There's no point
in waiting...
Would it not be better
to elect a chairman?
- (Tom) What?
- (All agree)
I think it would maybe be as
well for us to have a chairman.
(Tom) All right,
have a chairman.
If you want to have a chairman,
pick who you like.
The provost will accept
the responsibility.
For various reasons,
I must ask to be excused.
But I'm sure we would all find
Mr. Geikie acceptable.
(Applause and cheering)
Brothers and sisters.
(All cheer)
This is a
democratically-convened meeting
on a matter of public concern.
And I hope that we can give
a full and frank discussion
to the issues involved.
Within the bounds of moderation,
of course.
(Man) Up the moderates!
I'll have no interruptions
from you, if you please.
Now, the chair recognizes
the provost.
The provost has the floor.
Fellow citizens of Baikie.
My friends, I hope.
You all know that I stand
in close relationship
to the technical adviser
of the spa.
He is my brother.
I would therefore have preferred
not to take part
in this discussion.
But my official position
and my concern for the interests
of the town compel me to.
I think my statement in The
Advertiser
puts the position
plainly and simply
so that any fair-minded
son or daughter of Baikie
can form his or her own opinion.
But I'm bound to add
that the expert view is
that my brother's proposals
would saddle the rate-payers
with the unnecessary expenditure
of a very large sum of money.
I feel it is my duty
to save you from that burden.
(Applause)
I vacate the chair to say that I
personally support the provost.
There is more behind his
brother's ideas
than you might think.
(Man shouts out)
I'm not saying he doesn't mean
well. No two ways about that.
And I am all for the free
expression of opinion
as long as it is
a moderate opinion
and doesn't do anybody any harm.
But nobody is going to tell me
that his opinion
is a moderate one
if it means a rise in the rates
and in the unemployment.
You can pay too dearly for
some things.
(Man) Shut up and get on
with it, Geikie.
The chair recognizes
Mr. Houston.
Come on, Houston.
Let's get your views.
Mr. Houston has the floor.
(Man) Current views, that is!
Thank you, Mr. Geikie.
(Clears throat) Ladies and
gentlemen.
I hope this meeting
is in no doubt
about the honesty and
independence of The Advertiser.
We try to make our political
attitude objective.
We try to be fair
to all parties.
And we always try to reflect
public opinion.
That is the first duty
of a newspaper.
(Crowd) Hear, hear!
There can be very little doubt
where public opinion lies
in this matter.
Against any substantial increase
in the rates.
(Applause and cheering)
I say all this with regret.
I've personally always had
the greatest respect
for Mr. Thomas Stockman.
Nevertheless, my duty to my
paper, and to you, the public,
has compelled me to break
with it. Thank you.
(Applause)
I will now put the provost's
motion to the fore.
No, no, Geikie.
Enough of that nonsense.
I ask you to show respect
for the chair.
Shut up, Geikie.
Give the man a chance!
Hear, hear.
The voice of reason.
Mr. Stockman has the floor.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
There will be no vote
here tonight.
Wee, sleekit, cow'rin,
tim'rous beastie...
(Man) Come on. Get on with it!
The water supply is poisoned
and our curative spa...
That's a bloody lie!
I've been drinking it
since I was a boy.
..that is what they won't admit.
But I've no bond with such
a trivial matter.
Because once your
elected leaders
have had a certain amount
of profit out of it,
that matter will be attended to
with your money
by some nameless, faceless
overpaid bureaucrat
from somewhere or other.
But that too is a trivial matter
compared with what I have
discovered.
I have discovered
that the very sources of our
spiritual life is poisoned.
That the whole fabric
of our society
is infected with lies
and deceit.
(Crowd uproar)
If we don't do something
about it,
you'll all be dead as a dodo.
(All shouting angrily)
All right, brother Geikie.
I'll stick to the point
as you call it.
And my point is that suddenly
in these last few days,
my eyes have been opened,
and the first thing
I have become aware of
is the overwhelming stupidity
of the authorities.
And I do not know how,
for so long,
I should have believed
that these were dedicated men
with our best interests
in front of them.
But I did believe that.
I did believe that there were
men who wanted a society
in which a man could live
as a man
rather than an animal.
Hey, Jimmy,
Is he calling us animals?
(Chants) # We are the animals!
(Claps hands)
# We are the animals! #
They're no' dedicated
to anything
except their own self-interest.
And I don't know why
it's taken us so long
to find this out.
Because day in, day out, I've
had living right under my nose
a prime example of their kind!
Your own provost.
The one you elected.
My brother Peter.
(Man) You're out of order,
Mr. Stockman!
I'm no' bothered about
your leading citizens.
They're all planted with the
seeds of their own destruction.
And they are not the ones
who are poisoning
the very sources
of our spiritual life.
The most dangerous persons
in our community
to truth and freedom
are the ones who put them there.
- Who are they?
- What are you talking about?
Of course I will name them.
That is precisely why I am here.
The most dangerous enemies
of truth and freedom
in our community
are you,
the majority.
The damn silent majority.
You are responsible!
The majority is always right,
Stockman.
That is the fundamental
principle of democracy.
Aye, you heard Mr. Houston.
It's fundamental all right.
It's fundamental trickery.
And it is also
the most obvious lie
that any individual
free-thinking man
has got to fight against.
Well, who are the majority?
All over the world, there is a
majority of fools over wise men.
How then can it be right
for fools to govern wise men?
Tom, Tom. Yesterday you were
fighting for a good cause.
Now you're talking like
a bloody fascist, man.
Yesterday, Carmichael,
you walked out on a good cause.
I walked out on censorship of
the press.
Censorship?
Censorship by Mr. Houston.
Right!
And yet he's supposed to be
a revolutionary agitator.
Prove... Prove that!
When did I ever say that
in my paper?
You're attacking everything
and everybody.
It seems to me you're
the revolutionary.
My God, for once you're right.
I'm starting a revolution
against the lie
that truth and the majority
go hand in hand.
What kind of truths do the
majority generally rally around?
Meaningless catchphrases.
Because that's what
their leaders want.
Their leaders do not want to
declare the victory.
They want the battle to continue
because they believe that the
continuation of a state of war
is to their advantage.
And far less do those leaders
have the vision to see
the new horizons of thought.
That is something that is only
given to a brilliant few.
Keir Hardie was such a man.
You keep Keir Hardie
out of this.
What do you know about
Keir Hardie?
Keir Hardie won the battle.
Now, a hundred years later,
brother Geikie and his like
are picking over corpses.
The new horizons are far, far
ahead of their miserable vision.
Listen to me, my friends.
You are not so stupid
as to think that it was
the majorities
who achieved advances
in the field of science.
You cannae be that stupid.
And all I'm saying to you
is that in the political arena,
in the management
of our society,
it will be one man,
one Keir Hardie,
one brilliant individual leader
of thought
who will reveal to you
the new horizons.
The majority tramples
the individual underfoot
while you search for
the truths of today.
The majorities
all over the world
have to trample
all the individuals
under a million brutal feet.
Whose side are you on?
I'm not on any side anymore.
No, no, no.
Don't you see?
I have to be free.
Your leaders want you on sides.
One side against the other.
Divide and conquer,
one of them said.
And by God, they conquered.
Some of them are stupid enough
to do it in his name.
They conquered the individual.
Trade unions, managements,
political parties,
whatever you like.
They have to conquer
the individual
because they want
to get your brains
and grind them
into a single mash,
so you're no longer capable
of thinking for yourselves.
They pander to you on the telly
and in the press
so that you shall be their
majority. Theirs, mark you.
They do not want you to wake up
and chuck the whole lot
of them out.
Stockman out! Stockman out!
Stockman out!
(Geikie) That's an exaggeration.
(Tom) I am not exaggerating!
- They don't believe you.
- Of course they don't.
They are the majority.
The majority stifles the
conscience of the individual.
The point, Mr. Stockman,
that you want to close the spa
and ruin this town.
It sounds unimportant.
It's not unimportant to them
because they are not gonna ruin
themselves.
That is exactly what they are
doing. That is the whole point.
I mean, a majority
becomes the enemy
of the individuals
who compose that majority.
You are the enemy,
the enemy of the people,
because you want to ruin
the town.
I'd rather see it ruined
than have it flourish on a lie.
What does it matter if a lying
community is ruined?
I mean, let it be razed
to the ground.
Let all communities who live
by lies be exterminated.
He's away. The bastard's away.
Aye. I'm gonna smash his windows
in! I'll teach him!
Here. What's come over
the chemist, Mr. Carmichael?
Suffering the fate of old men
who swim against the tide,
Willie.
Aye. They would rather have him,
is that it?
You see that? A pebble.
Didn't even have the courage
to be full-blooded hooligans and
chuck bricks.
What did the joiners say?
I phoned both of them.
Ben said he was too busy.
McDowall was more honest.
He said it was more than his
business was worth
to do a job for you just now.
I suppose he's right.
We'll need to do a proper job
on this, though.
- Can I have the shovel?
- Just a minute.
Mind your hands.
Well, Mr. Downy phoned.
He wants to terminate the lease
at the end of the quarter.
- He can't do that.
- Oh, I didnae argue.
- Oh, Tom.
- No.
I have been thinking
about Canada.
The air's fresher and a chemist
can aye get work.
We can't just up and away
like that.
Why not?
We're not as young as were,
for a start.
And what about Peggy?
She'll not want to go.
Oh, it's a great place
for teachers.
She's aye complaining
about the education system here.
Well, I think she'll have other
reasons for wanting to stay.
Well, you can't expect me
to stay.
This town...
Well, they've insulted me.
Called me an enemy of the
people. Broke my windows.
Torn my best trousers.
Did I show you my trousers?
Yes, dear, you showed me.
Aye, well, it's a lesson to me.
I'll never again go out to fight
for freedom
and the rights of the individual
in my best trousers.
I know, dear.
Och... I'll sew them up again.
They'll be as good as new.
What surprises me is their
ingratitude.
I know, and it's a shame.
But you did give them
provocation.
I told them the truth about
themselves
and they didnae like it.
No, they did not.
Come on. I've got to get moving.
I'm still open for business.
(Car horn beeps)
Guess what? I've been suspended.
- Why?
- Because I used school property
to run off Dad's handbills.
I've been to see Grandad.
He said to give you these.
Cigars?
Here's Peter. I'll away and get
you a tool box.
Are you going to the house,
Peggy?
Yes. I'll run you, Mum.
Keep your bonnet on
and your brolly up.
It's kind of drafty
in here today.
I see you have a lot to do.
I won't keep you.
Good.
I'm sorry I wasn't able to put
a stop to that demonstration.
Is that all you came in here
to say?
I have to give you this.
That's a termination
of my services
as technical adviser to the spa.
Yes.
Now, you'll excuse me.
I've got rather a lot to do.
Are you expecting customers,
then?
Maybe, after sore heads
last night.
If you'll take my advice, you'll
leave the district for a while.
Funnily enough,
I was just thinking of that.
In my own time, of course.
That's the first sensible
decision
you've made for a long time.
Maybe when you've had time
to think things over,
you might be able to persuade
yourself to write an apology,
perhaps admitting
that you made a mistake.
Do you think maybe...
I would get my job at the spa
back if I did that?
Aye, it's just possible.
I can promise nothing
but I'll do what I can for you.
And what about public opinion?
Public opinion
is a fickle thing, Thomas.
You wouldnae go against it,
surely.
There is no saying what the
public will think in six months.
And to be candid with you,
it is of considerable importance
that we should get some kind of
written statement from you
to that effect.
Aye, that's what you really came
in for, isn't it?
But you've no chance, Peter.
You'll never get a statement
like that out of me.
You've no right to behave
like this, Thomas.
It's no attitude for a man
with a family to take.
I wouldn't have a shred of
self-respect
if I did anything else.
Very plausible -
if there were no other
explanation for your obstinacy.
- But there is, of course.
- Is there?
But if you take my advice,
you'll not build too much
on your expectations.
They could very easily fail you.
My expectations?
- You have a father-in-law?
- What about it?
Sir Archie's well up in years.
He's been failing of late.
And he is a comparatively
rich man.
Aye, I suppose he is.
You can take my word for it,
and you can take my word for it
that you and Katherine
are his principal legatees.
I didn't know that.
- How did you?
- We don't need to go into that.
Another member
of the bridge club?
After what happened
at that meeting,
it wouldn't surprise me
if Sir Archie changed his mind.
Oh, no. There's no fear of that,
Peter.
He was enjoying the whole idea
of the thing.
And he's got no love
for your crowd.
I see.
This explains everything.
- Does it?
- Conspiracy.
Conspiracy?
There's no word of truth
in any of it.
It was merely the price
you had to pay
for Sir Archie's goodwill.
Do you really believe that?
And you have the effrontery
to talk about corruption?
Your dismissal is final, Thomas.
I have a weapon against you now.
- Morning, Archie.
- Got them on the run this time.
This solution of copper
carbonate is first-class.
It kills the fungus.
Thanks for the cigars.
Not at all.
You did me a good turn.
Did I?
Oh, yourself really, I suppose.
See, I went down and enquired
in the morning
and I discovered that shares
in the bottling plant
were going for chickenfeed.
So I bought them.
What?
A controlling interest, really.
You see, I've been putting aside
a bit of money
for you and Katherine lately.
You know, in the event of my
unhappy decease, and so on,
and it struck me, why the hell
should you wait for it?
So I bought you
the bottling plant.
You bought...the bottling plant?
I bought the bottling plant.
It's useless. It can't be used
in this state. It's a dead loss.
Absolute nonsense. It's up to
you.
It's your money.
Yours and Katherine's.
You mean you put all my
and Katherine's money
into that useless load
of rubble?
- Yes.
- You must be mad.
Not at all.
I don't believe that story about
chrome sulphate
getting out of my pond.
- But it's true.
- It's a matter of opinion.
All you've got to do is to say
that you made a mistake.
Nobody's gonna argue with you.
By and by, the shares in
the bottling plant will go up
and you'll have made
a small fortune.
I cannae lie like that.
I think it's about time you came
to terms with the facts of life.
You're not getting any younger,
you know.
I wish to God I wasn't
so certain.
I admit I've got a
responsibility to my family.
Of course you have.
Maybe I'll talk it over
with Katherine.
Good idea. Get a sensible
woman's advice.
But look, don't wait too long,
cos if you're not gonna use
those shares,
I've gotta do something with
them.
I don't know what. Give them
to a charity, I suppose.
And what'll Katherine get?
Katherine will get
sweet damn all.
But why didn't you have a word
with us beforehand?
Just a hint to Mr. Houston
or myself
would have made all
the difference.
A hint about what?
About what was behind it all,
sir.
Behind all of what?
Say what you mean, Mr. Geikie.
Ah, come on.
No need to make such
a mystery of it.
We're all men of the world here.
I mean, you're not gonna tell me
that your father-in-law
hasn't bought up most of the
shares of the bottling plant.
No, no. I suppose he has. What's
all that got to do with it?
Well, wouldn't it
have been better
to have got somebody else
to do it?
Somebody who was maybe
not so near related to you?
I myself think
it would have been better
to have kept your name
out of it altogether.
I mean, there was no need
for anybody
to know the attack on the spa
came from you.
Pity you didn't have a word
with us about it.
By the way, where's Carmichael?
Ah, he's away.
Maybe just as well.
Didn't understand us
being a stranger, so to speak.
On the contrary. I think he
understood you all too well.
- And Mr. Houston?
- He's not well.
But as I was saying, you should
have spread the responsibility.
You kept it too much
to yourself.
All right.
Now what's your game?
Well, the fact is, now we know
the way the wind blows,
we thought that we might be able
to put The Advertiser
at your disposal after all.
We? Who the hell are you
to speak for Houston?
Oh, but I do.
Good.
What about public opinion?
Aren't you afraid of that?
We'll change it.
Your reason for wanting to get
hold of the bottling plant
was in the public interest.
Oh, naturally. I mean, that's
why Sir Archie came in with me.
We'll tinker with the settling
pond, make it look all right.
And it'll not cost a penny
of public money.
That might work if you've got
The Advertiser behind you.
The press is a power and free
country, sir.
And the rate-payers?
What about them?
Oh, I think I can answer
for the rate-payers too.
And er... What exactly is in it
for Houston?
Well, financial support
for The Advertiser
would be very welcome.
It's a bit shaky just now.
I would... Well, we would be
unwilling to suspend it
while it still had so much
useful work to do.
And er...what if I was to refuse
to give you a single penny?
I mean, we rich men don't like
parting with money.
Well, I'd just have
to remind you
that this business of the shares
can be presented in two ways.
Ah.
And you're just the man to.
Oh, well, Mr. Geikie.
You can rest assured
I'll give careful thought
to all that you have said.
No hurry, sir.
Just take your time.
Thank you, Geikie.
You know, one of these days,
somebody is gonna spray you
with a solution
of copper carbonate
and it'll be a great
improvement.
(Tom) No, no, no, Archie. That
is my answer and that is final.
(Hangs up phone)
Dad, are you serious
about Canada?
- Perfectly.
- Fantastic. When are we going?
No.
We are not going to run away.
We're not going to Canada.
But you're not going back
to that school.
Well, what am I going to do?
You're going to make a start
with those backward kids
you're aye on about.
We are going to teach them
that truth is truth.
That was your grandfather
on the phone.
Even he...
I gave him the answer no.
That means your mother
has lost her expectations.
You think that's gonna bother
her?
- Oh, I think it will.
- Rubbish.
Maybe she'll have to pinch and
scrape a wee bit on the house,
but she'll manage that. Come on.
- How are you doing, Kath?
- Not too bad, Donald.
At least the cleansing
department
won't be able to report
us to the higher authorities.
Don't be too sure.
We don't have union cards
for this kind of work.
- It's no joke, Donald.
- Believe me, I'm serious.
I don't think Tom realizes
just what he's stirred up.
I told Peggy to let him know
if things get really bad,
you can have rooms at the hotel.
You mean you think he's ruined
the tourist trade?
- Maybe he's the making of it.
- With the spa closed?
You can buy spa water
anywhere in the world.
But there's very little truth
on offer today.
Kate! Kate, my darling Kate!
We have it all sorted.
Here is the battlefield.
Was, you mean, and it looked
like it before we tidied it up.
Is and always shall be.
We're going to start our own
school.
This is my native place.
Beginning with the backward
kids.
We shall teach them
nothing, Captain.
No facts,
no predetermined values.
They shall grow up
as free and independent men.
What do you think the school
board is going to say?
I shall preach in season and out
of season as it says somewhere.
Surely you saw last night that
preaching does you no good.
To hell with the school board.
I just want to bang it
into every idiot's head
that democracy is the craftiest
enemy of free men.
Why, it can strangle any
promising young truth at birth
even before it's born.
Majorities of fools can turn
justice and morality upside down
till life isn't worth living.
I think I'll be able to explain
that to quite a few folk.
Probably, but I don't know
a lot about...
Of course.
My main trouble
is going to be finding someone
with enough independence
and integrity
to carry on my work after me.
For goodness' sake. You've got
all the time you'll need, Dad.
It's the leaders.
They must be wiped out.
They are like ravening wolves.
They have to feed on a certain
number of small creatures
every year in order to keep
themselves going.
I mean, look at Peter
and Houston and Geikie!
See all the poor wee traitors
that they polish off year after
year or else mangle and maim
until they are fit for nothing
except to be members of
the electorate and subscribers.
My God.
Subscribers to
The Baikie Advertiser.
I have made a great discovery.
Oh, no. Save us from that.
I am the strongest man
in the world.
- Oh, God help us.
- Right.
But say nothing. Not yet.
You see, the fact is, I am
the strongest man in the world.
(Peggy) Dad?
The strongest man in the world
is the man who is most alone!