KADR Film Group
presents
ASHES AND DIAMONDS
Screenplay based on the novel
by Jerzy Andrzejewski
Starring as Maciek Chelmicki
Cast of Characters
Director of Photography
Camera Crew
Production Manager
Directed by
Who is this guy again?
Name is Szczuka.
The Communist Party's Secretary
of the Province.
- Sir...
- Get lost!
Could you open the chapel
for me, please, sir?
It's locked, see.
Run away!
- What now?
- They're coming.
I am used to waiting for bigger things.
- Hurry up!
- Bloody ants!
Hurry up! Run!
Guys, hurry up! They're coming! Hurry!
- Take his papers!
- He hasn't got any.
Jesus! Mary! Let's run away!
Stop!
Where are you going?
Wait!
What's this?
Two of ours have just been killed.
Smolarski from cement plant
member of Workers' Council.
And that one?
Also from the plant.
Gawlik, not yet twenty.
He came back from labour camp
in Germany a week ago.
Came back home to die.
That's where the scoundrels shot from!
The two of us were meant
to be killed, not them.
- You think so?
- Naturally.
It doesn't matter.
Excuse me, comrade.
My name is Szczuka.
So you're the Party Secretary
we've been expecting.
That's me.
I have a question. We all do, that is.
Tell us, how long will such men
continue to be killed?
They're not the first.
Nor the last. Are you scared?
Everyone wants to live.
Haven't we lost enough people?
Smolarski lost two sons.
One in 1939, the other
was shot here by the Germans in 1943.
And now it was him.
Why? Who killed him?
Poles?
How long is this going to take?
It would be wrong for a communist
to console you like children.
The war is over, but our struggle is not.
The struggle for the future of our country
has just begun.
Today, tomorrow or the day after
any of us can be killed.
We understand you,
but what do we tell his wife?
What can we say?
It's not easy for me, comrades,
as I know it was me they meant to kill,
not the two of them.
Heads up! We must do our thing
as long as we live.
That's what really matters.
This is a special announcement:
Today, on May 8,
among the ruins of Berlin,
the German High Command signed an accord
of an unconditional surrender of Germany.
The German High Command
was represented by:
Keitel, Friedeburg and Stumpf.
On behalf of the Red Army Command,
Marshal Zhukov.
Where is he?
He should be here by now.
Where does he get the information?
From his boss.
Who's that?
The mayor. The moron is his secretary.
So he works for both sides?
I hate such things.
Can he be trusted?
And who is?
Look at the tanks. Not bad at all.
Polish tanks head for the battlefield...
Take a look!
Welcome, gentlemen.
- You're late. Did anything happen?
- I just had to change.
- You're getting married?
- Nothing of the sort.
I'm in charge of the whole banquet, look!
Give me that.
The pictures not clear, it's too early.
Count me out when you plan such actions.
OK, don't bother.
Information? OK.
But nothing of that sort.
Don't bother me. Maciek?
- Yes?
- We're off.
- Where to?
- We're invited to a banquet.
No kidding?
Don't worry. I know what I am doing.
- The risk is pointless.
- Stop bothering me.
- Bye.
Good evening, sir.
Look, who's here!
- What brings you here?
- Duties, Mr. Kotowicz, duties.
I see. The banquet.
You're looking for the manager?
You'll certainly find him here.
A masterpiece! You can trust me on that!
Hello. How you doing?
I hope the mayor will be satisfied.
He really hopes everything will be perfect.
I see, the end of the war.
A very special moment.
A private passage to the toilet.
How are things?
Thank you, sir. All quiet.
It looks fine to me.
Rest assured, Secretary,
it will taste even better.
Let's go.
- Do you see that pretty girl?
- Come on.
Let's have a drink.
Good evening. Can we have something to drink?
What will you have?
Two vodkas straight will be OK.
Miss Krystyna!
Yes, sir?
Krystyna, such a pretty name.
- Stop fooling around.
- But I'm not.
Drink it up and we're off.
Two double vodkas and sodas.
A pretty bar you have here, you know?
When do you close?
At 3 a.m.
Do you like violets?
Very much.
So do I.
- Did you see them?
- What?
Almost like girls from Warsaw.
I wish I could stay.
- Then stay.
- It's easy to say.
There's no one waiting for you there.
That's why there is no point in staying.
- I don't get it.
- Neither do I.
It must be our master.
Wait. It's all right.
Hello... Yes...
This is Mrs. Staniewicz speaking.
I'll put you through.
Major! It's for you.
This is Andrzej speaking.
It's done and over with, sir.
Everything is in order. Yes.
No complications, none whatsoever.
Yes... yes.
Good evening.
Have you got the room for Comrade Szczuka?
It was booked by the Town Committee.
Naturally! We have for you
room 18 on the 2nd floor.
Here you are.
Yes...
Yes.
A moment...
What's the matter with you? Are you there?
I don't get it.
The business fell through...
Yes, I see.
What can we do?
Well, come over immediately.
- Have you got any cigarettes?
- American? Hungarian?
- American will be fine.
- Here you are.
Thank you.
Wait for me at the bar.
No problem,
I am used to waiting for bigger things.
Do you know the Staniewicz family?
Yes, sir.
They live at their old address?
Yes. Not far from here.
They have a phone. Should I call them?
Here you are.
Thank you.
This is their phone number - 1214.
Here you are, sir, your key.
So at what time is this banquet?
At 11 p.m.?
Yes. The car will be waiting.
How can I help you?
A pack of cigarettes, please.
- American or Hungarian?
- Hungarian, they are stronger.
- Here.
- Thank you very much.
- Let me get your change.
No, please, keep it.
Will you smoke?
No, thank you.
Too strong for me. I cough. At my age...
Come on. How old are you?
- Almost sixty.
- You don't even look fifty to me.
You are very kind. Alone?
For the time being.
A blonde?
Why not?
Doubles are always difficult.
I am OK with a single.
The more intimate the better.
- Are you from Warsaw by any chance?
- Exactly.
So am I. I used to work at the Savoy.
- In Nowy Swiat St.?
- Exactly.
I was two months short of 25 years.
You lived there through the Rising?
Downtown to the last day. And you?
Here are there. The Old Town first,
next downtown... You know...
Without Warsaw we are not the same.
As if we missed an arm.
The chestnuts are in bloom now
in the parks and avenues.
In bloom, you say?
I though I would put you up
in a bedbug-ridden room on the 3th floor...
- I will give a room on the 2nd. Number 17.
- Thank you.
You deserve it.
We Varsovians must stick together.
Any luggage?
- Just this.
- Not much.
I used to have even less.
Here you are.
- My ID.
- Oh, a Kenkarte.
- Chełmicki Maciej.
- Yes.
Born in Warsaw in 1921.
- Occupation: worker?
- It's to fool the Krauts. Occupation: student.
Thank you.
Why do you cry? Did they tell you
something in the kitchen again?
You're beautiful so they are
all jealous of you.
What happened?
Stasiek has been shot dead.
Which Stasiek? Who did it?
Stasiek Gawlik, my fiancé.
Those damned rascals.
Why would they...?
How should I know?
It's probably just a lie.
Jeziorek has just been here.
The constable?
He mixed everything up or
wanted vodka from you.
He said two men from the cement
plant had been shot today.
I knew something was wrong. "Who?" I ask.
"Smolarski and Stasiek Gawlik" says He.
I thought I'd drop dead.
"Killed on the spot" he said.
They were killed by mistake,
they were after someone else.
Have a drink. What's done can't be undone.
Don't cry.
I'll give you a pair of stockings.
Hands off! Can't you wait?
Is that what you've been waiting for?
Why not?
Innocent people died meaninglessly after all.
Pricks of conscience...?
You think they're out of place, Major?
Who were they?
Workers of the cement plant.
Everything clear.
It was a mistake and it must be corrected.
May I have question?
Yes?
Is it necessary to kill Szczuka?
As an experienced soldier like you, Lieutenant,
should know I don't have to
answer such questions.
I think...
What you think is immaterial.
What's your answer?
Yes.
I'm glad we're on the same page.
However, I will answer your question.
I understand your doubts.
I'd be surprised to find you didn't have any.
The situation is very complex and difficult,
but years of the war taught us
to deal simply with such problems.
We accept no compromise. Either they or us.
When did you join the underground?
In 1940.
You wanted to fight for the
freedom of Poland, didn't you?
Did you fight for the Poland we have now?
You must realize that for you
and for thousands of people like you
there is only one choice: to fight.
Where will you go with your experience?
Every door in this country is closed to you
except the gates of prison.
I know.
As far as the man who caused us
some trouble is concerned.
Szczuka is a member of the intelligentsia,
engineer, communist, brilliant organizer,
who knows exactly what he wants.
After many years abroad he is back from Russia.
Delegated to sit on the
Party Provincial Committee.
You realize what power he has
as the First Secretary.
It'll make quite an impression
if we remove him swiftly.
His death will have both political
and propaganda significance,
the more important now that
our local situation is quite grave.
Tonight Capt. Wilk's unit was surrounded
by the army and Secret Police.
We suffered great losses.
Only a few units managed to retreat.
As far as I know Wilk, he will manage.
Unfortunately, the captain was killed.
The colonel's house is a perfect place to rest
and forget the ugliness of the external world.
I'm glad to hear that, dear Count.
Please, no titles.
Will you, please, sir?
And how's our business?
Quite promising.
Are you sure, my dear?
Sure? Don't you forget the time we live in.
Nothing is sure these days.
Away with this pessimism!
Our friends will always be our friends.
Our fate is in your hands.
Rather in my husband's.
He'll do all he can to get us abroad.
Let's then drink to the colonel's health
with brandy at the hotel.
Great idea.
Mr. Szczuka has come.
Who?
Mr. Szczuka.
Will you excuse me for a minute?
I have some boring, mundane business to attend.
I sympathize with you, dear.
Business is always boring.
But it is getting harder and harder
to live without it.
The attack of the Western powers
will come as fast as lightning...
Mrs Staniewicz will be able to visit us
in our estate within a year...
How are you, Katarzyna?
You do recognize me, don't you?
I do.
It's been but a month
since I returned to Poland.
I know, I received your letter.
I sent three.
I had nothing more to tell you.
And nothing has changed since.
By the end of 1941,
friends informed me of Maria's death.
They told me you took care of Marek.
Should I've sent him to an orphanage?
I explicitly wrote that
I didn't want you to bring up my son.
I suggested my friends.
Did you receive the letter?
I did not. No letters whatsoever.
Yet even if I had,
Marek would have stayed with us anyway.
You seem to forget that Maria
was my sister after all.
Where is he?
I don't know.
I wrote you the last time he was here
was in October, right after the Rising.
You haven't heard from him since?
No.
Is this all you can tell me about my son?
He is 17.
I know.
But seventeen-year-olds are grown-up men now.
Who's he now?
What kind of man have you made of him?
A good Pole, I can assure you.
I know your kind of patriotism,
so I can easily imagine
what a man my son is now.
This can't be helped now. But he's 17.
Mark my words. If he's alive,
sooner or later he'll be my son.
No. It was nothing important.
Just a moment. This apartment is not safe.
You're in a hurry?
Not really, I have a date.
- A woman?
- Disappointed?
- Who?
- You.
It's none of my business who you see.
Is it?
I hope so.
And if I don't believe you?
Whatever you say.
So I don't.
Will you be here long?
Till closing time.
You have to? All alone?
Another barmaid comes at 10 pm.
You see?
What should I see? The two of us hardly
manage when it gets crowded.
Here comes your date.
I see you've remembered him well.
A very handsome man.
Sure.
Come.
What's up?
The next room is quiet. Let's go there.
What did he say?
Come.
You're mad. This is the quietest place.
Don't you like this table?
It's like dreams come true.
You see?
It'll do.
Are you leaving?
Are you crazy?
You were supposed to go to Warsaw.
What happened?
Has the major canceled everything?
Quite the opposite.
Who do you think I am?
You think I would quit a botched job?
Guess who is staying at this hotel in room 17,
next door to our common friend?
All right, Maciek.
Who's that moron?
Who?
That one over there.
What a stupid back.
And the face is no better.
Good evening.
The usual - vodka straight and vermouth?
Tonight brandy!
You have something to drink about?
Artistic success.
Thank you.
How's your show?
Superb!
You're most welcome...
Ladies and gentlemen,
let me welcome you to our evening.
Tonight we're celebrating the end of the war.
Who could measure up to this occasion...
let's see if the incomparable
Hanka Lewicka can succeed.
Remember?
What?
The spirits at Ginger's.
I don't.
You don't?
When was that?
Oh, but you do.
Stop fooling around.
No!
I don't remember.
Haneczka,
Wilga,
Kossobudzki,
Ginger,
Kajtek...
We are alive!
Those were the days, Andrzej.
You think so?
The way we lived and in what company...
Were there ever such great guys and girls?
And so what? Almost all were killed.
That's another matter. But life was great.
We were...
Younger.
It's not just that.
We knew what we wanted.
Let's say...
We knew what was expected of us.
What a discovery! Sure.
What else could they expect now?
That we should die. Nothing has changed.
What's the problem? We can afford it.
Stop being cynical!
To die is piece of cake.
What do you mean?
We can't do anything else.
Not enough?
Hopelessly little.
You're exaggerating.
You don't have to take it so seriously.
We have to get by through all this muddle,
stay calm, keep away from boredom.
What else is there?
Perhaps...
We must have a serious talk.
What a noisy crowd!
How will you handle the man?
Don't worry. I'll manage.
I got the order from the major.
And I got it from you. That's the way it is.
And there's this other thing...
I'll carry out the order.
What thing?
Firstly, I was told not take part in this.
Yeah...
I have to beat it and real fast.
Well, this is news.
I'm replacing Wilk.
And what about him?
I'm to replace him.
I see, that's another one...
You said there was no one waiting for me.
Will you take me?
You mean it?
Do I mean it?
No one means anything in this country.
But I've got used to it.
If you take me along, I'm going.
When are you off?
Early in the morning. 4:30 am.
You have damned little time to off the man.
Let's see. The bloody wake starts about 11 p.m.
It will take some...
Three hours.
That's easy. He'll go back to bed.
See you, Maciek.
Don't mess it up, buddy.
I won't. Bye.
So you've been left alone.
Unfortunately.
Your friend due at 10, isn't she?
She is.
So you could disappear at about 10:30?
You will say you have
a headache or something, whatever.
Miss Krysia?
They can wait.
I'd like to pay.
I want to pay!
Will you?
Suppose I do... And what's next?
I'm staying at the hotel.
Are you? Nice of you.
First floor, Room 17.
You're sure?
It's easy to check.
I'm so sorry. I check bills only.
Only?
Enough for me. They never tally.
Only checks?
If you check up on me,
you won't make a mistake.
So?
These violets are smelling nicer and nicer.
Room 17. First floor, 10:30 pm.
I swear I'll be waiting.
Miss!
Sir!
What's up?
Your check!
Wait, wait...
Miss!
Just a sec...
Look who's here!
Having a good time?
Excuse me. I'm here in official capacity.
The Town Hall is apparently
ill-disposed to the press.
Not to my knowledge.
And still I haven't received an invitation.
I am sorry. Mr. Pawlicki has got one.
Yeah, but Mr. Pieniąźek does not count anymore?
Excuse me.
It was the mayor himself who drew the list.
That's what I mean. My colleague Święcki.
The Mayor.
Why are you staring at me?
A thought has just crossed my mind
that could be of interest to you...
Me? I don't think so.
What's up?
Just a minor problem...
If my colleague Święcki...
Sir!
If you insist...
Should my former colleague go to Warsaw,
will he take his current
secretary along or not?
Do you know anything about it?
Pieniąźek knows everything.
Two double vodkas, Miss.
We shall have a drink!
I'm on duty. I can't.
That's fine, then.
You should drink the minister's health then.
It's your duty.
Is that true then?
What ministry?
Of Health.
Not bad. I'd rather it was
the Foreign Affairs department.
So would he.
Let's drink to the Foreign Affairs!
Will he take me along?
Sure he will. Shit will always surface.
You'll see! In five years..
Sure I will. To the 5-year plan!
How are you Mr. Słomka?
I'm always fine, Sir.
Look, gentlemen.
At last a citizen who isn't complaining.
Excuse me, Sir. Naturally,
I already know the editor.
But the other gentleman...
Mr Kalicki.
Exactly, I don't know his position...
Oh, I see. Well, if titles mean so much to you,
as of today you can address me as...
What, Sir?
Minister, Mr. Słomka.
Watch out, Mr. Słomka.
Gentlemen! Excellent, Mr. Słomka.
Where is my secretary?
Has he been here?
He has, Sir. Minister, that is.
Mr Drewnowski saw to it all personally
and I must say, he was delighted.
Where's he? He should be here.
You want... an appetizer? No?
So tell me what it is that you want.
I want it all!
Piles of money!
So you'll have it.
Sure I will. Enough of misery.
Miss, two more!
Who is it?
It's me.
Were you sure, I'd come?
I was.
Do you know why I've come?
It's simple. I couldn't fall for you.
Hello?
What?
- You don't want to fall in love?
- With you?
- In general.
- Rather not.
- On principle?
- Why complicate my life?
- It can do it fine by itself.
- Why add more trouble?
Hello!
Yes?
Tell me something about yourself, would you?
What for?
Why not?
I used to live in the country,
my parents had an estate.
- Before the war?
- Yes. Near Poznań.
- And then ...?
- Then we moved to Warsaw.
We?
My mother and I.
Father was immediately arrested by the Germans.
He died?
He did. In Dachau... I guess that's all.
Your mother lives?
She died in the Rising.
And your siblings?
Luckily, I had none.
Luckily?
Fewer losses.
Well, you're right.
You have no family?
None.
Will you stay here long?
I don't know. It seems so.
What will come next?
I don't think about it.
I wasn't that sure you'd come.
You don't know me at all.
Neither do you.
Good... Come.
Have you invited me or not?
Are you a minister's secretary or not?
I have but not on this side.
Both sides are good.
From today on there is only one for me.
Nonsense. You can keep changing sides.
Both sides are always good.
Will you take your secretary along?
Sure.
Good evening, Comrade. This way.
He's a magnificent boy. Working class.
I'll make him a man.
When I become a director...
You surely will!
Will I?
You'll be a director.
I will.
Come. You'll be a director!
Good evening.
This way, please. Over there.
Jurgieluszka...
Poland has exploded.
Hooray!
Where are the directors going?
To the banquet!
I'll lead you to a glorious
vision of the future!
What is this? Where have you been?
What is this scum doing here?
It just happened this way...
Minister, that is...
I thought the press, Sir...
What nonsense is this? What has come over you?
Everything in order.
Congratulations, minister.
On behalf of the democratic press...
This is a scandal!
What a happy day! All the best!
Thank you, Comrade Major.
This is Comrade Wrona,
the Head of the Chief Security Bureau.
I can't look you in the eye
after what happened.
It is not the way I thought
it would be in the forest.
We're not in the forest any longer.
Welcome, Comrade. This way, please.
So you won't go?
I won't! Is this a democracy or not?
Comrades, please be seated.
You won't? Just you wait...
Are you threatening?
Me? And who kowtowed to the old regime?
Shut up, you scum!
Didn't you?
Shut up!
Didn't you kowtow to the old regime?
And what about you?
I did.
Poland has exploded on us.
Director!
You will be one.
There is too few of us still.
You must win them over.
Who?
The people!
So you've already drunk some.
Sure I have.
So will you too.
Hush. Hush.
I don't like this kind of fuss.
It's good for the bourgeois.
You don't like it?
I don't.
You surely will.
Silence!
Minister Święcki.
Comrades and citizens.
Today, May the 8th,
is a great achievement of the reborn Poland...
So how are you doing, Mrs. Jurgieluszka?
Speeches now.
The Minister himself.
Has anybody puked yet?
No, too early. Everything in its time.
Now the speeches.
Then the people will start running here.
This is going to be your night.
I think so too.
It must be his birthday.
It isn't anybody's birthday.
An anniversary, then...
What're you babbling about? It's about Poland!
You know what?
We've known each other
for a couple of hours only,
but it seems ages.
Tell me.
What?
What kind of man you really are?
What do you mean?
You seem different now.
Is it bad?
It doesn't matter, I guess.
Not at all?
Are you cold?
A little.
Good now?
Better anyway.
Why do you wear shades?
A souvenir of my unrequited love for homeland.
During the Rising I walked
too much in the sewers.
No, no.
Why not?
I don't want it. It's pointless.
Why?
Don't you get it? You're leaving.
I don't want any partings, any memories,
nothing one can leave behind.
Not even nice memories?
Not if they're meant to be only memories.
You have your life, I have mine.
We just met, it's nice.
What else do we need?
What's up?
It's nothing. Our neighbor's back.
You can hear everything here.
Everything.
Hug me.
Have you got cigarettes?
Sure I do. American or Hungarian?
Hungarian will do.
Here you are.
Thank you.
What about tomorrow?
It is tomorrow already.
Shall we spend the day together?
Well, you know...
Where were you taken?
In Międzyborze forest.
Captured with Wilk's gang?
Captain Wilk's unit.
What's your name?
Krzysztof.
That's all?
Krzysztof Zawadzki.
And your name?
Turn around!
How old are you?
A hundred.
How old?
A hundred and one.
You have to go?
I should or else Lili kills me.
Bye.
Could you give me a light?
Light? Sure.
Thank you.
What happened?
It's nothing. Stay with me for half an hour.
OK?
Sure.
It's beginning to rain.
Here. Hush, hush. Let's go.
A penny for your thoughts.
You won't tell me?
It's just...
I've been thinking about what I shouldn't have.
All right. No more thinking.
Spare me the reproachful look.
It's not reproachful.
But...?
Don't you know yet?
It's going to pour.
You want to go back?
No.
Oh God, how beautiful life can be!
Knock on wood!
It was just a wish.
Touch wood.
Life is dangerous.
Let's hide over there!
No, here!
Aren't you cold?
Look! What an old tombstone.
An inscription.
"You are as a torch blazing with flames,
burning rags fall about you flaming,
and you do not know if the fire marks
freedom or the final loss.
Will all that you cherish be lost in ashes"
The letters are unclear. I can't see any more.
That's Norwid:
"Will there be among the ashes
a sparkling diamond,
the dawn of everlasting victory?"
That's nice...
Will there be a sparkling diamond...
And what are we?
You? A diamond for sure.
Listen! I must tell you something.
Anything sad?
No.
Well, I don't know.
I just don't know.
I'd like to change some things.
Rearrange my life.
It's not easy to talk about it all.
No need. I can guess a lot.
You do?
Is it so hard?
You know, I haven't given
many things a thought until now.
Things just worked out by themselves.
The point was to survive.
Do you follow?
I do.
I'd like to have a normal life, to study.
I have a high school diploma.
Maybe I could enter the Technical Academy.
And you?
You promised not to say anything sad.
This is sad? Should I knock on wood again?
My God, had I known
yesterday what I know now...
I wouldn't have come to you then.
I haven't known what love is. I really haven't.
My heel!
Where?
Don't worry. I have repaired bigger things.
What's this? Are you in a circus?!
What's going on?
Hush.
The lady had a minor disaster.
Should I look for a cobbler at night?
Shame on you. On you too, Miss.
The young these days!
You can't even respect the dead.
What?
Can't you see?
You think it's funny.
There are two murdered people here.
Maciek, what are you doing?
Come in.
Where was that?
You don't remember?
I was so totally drunk.
This wine is so treacherous.
It is.
"Alwaseta", the early days, the Spanish...
Grabowski was killed in the forest,
Kubacki, in France in 1944.
Do you recall? There were 36 of us at first.
Who's left alive?
Those were the days.
There'll be good times now as well.
I feel lost in all this.
I'd introduce order here very fast.
The lot down there is not the whole Poland.
I know. But that's not very comforting.
I don't know how to govern.
Don't learn it, Franek.
Believe me, don't learn it.
There is so much suffering,
tears and wrongs here.
Everyone here carries his baggage...
Learn to understand it.
What's there to understand?
German.
Have you found them?
We haven't, but we will.
There are some English as well.
At close range, it makes no difference.
It's time to bed.
Tomorrow we start to work.
It's going to be a nice day. The rain's over.
Till tomorrow. Salut.
When are you leaving?
Tomorrow, I guess.
But maybe I could still change it all.
What?
Various things.
You could?
Perhaps...
Buying yourself flowers?
We need to talk in earnest.
I thought we already did.
So?
You know, I'm not a coward.
So what?
You see, I can't go on killing...
hiding any more.
I just want to live.
Nothing else. You must understand me.
I don't have to do anything.
Are saying this as a soldier or as a friend?
I don't get it.
You don't want to, I'd say.
In this case I can only speak
as your superior officer.
You volunteered to do it.
You're my only friend.
Leave this sentimental crap.
You've fallen in love.
That's your business.
But If your things come first,
then it's called...
I've never been a deserter..
What about now? You volunteered.
People change. I'm not running away.
But you'd like to.
You want me to say - OK, you're in love.
Do as you please.
How many times have we fought together?
What if you fell in love then?
Would you come to me then?
What about the Rising?
It was different.
It wasn't.
You keep forgetting you were and are one of us.
It counts, doesn't it?
You did it now.
You can kiss your career good bye.
Out with you.
You'll sing a different tune tomorrow
when the Minister gets you.
When he gets me. No matter.
Life's but a house of cards.
Have a drink, sir.
No. I'll do it myself.
Just like that?
Have no fear. Now I care about my life.
I'll be waiting for you at 4:30 am. Remember!
No.
So we must go separate ways.
I don't think we will ever meet again.
Only one of us may be proven right.
Bye.
Andrzej!
Tell me, do you believe in all this?
Do I? It's immaterial.
Will you buy violets, sir?
ZoŚka, let's go home.
Everything's in order.
Come in!
Excuse me, Comrade, but it's important.
Major Wrona sends me.
Do come in.
Do you have a son?
Marek, 17 years old.
That's too bad.
What happened?
He was with Wilk's gang.
Wait. We'll send a car.
The porter will tell you it arrives.
Good. I'll wait. Thank you, Lieutenant.
Do you know Wilk's name?
No.
What did you do in the Rising?
I shot... at Germans.
And now at Poles.
And you at sparrows.
Porter!
Our car comes any minute.
Tell Comrade Szczuka when it arrives.
Szczuka? Room 18? I will.
And here it is! Let's drink to our Warsaw!
It's a beautiful night.
I will take a walk before I depart.
Are you leaving already?
What can I do? My wife's jealous.
Stop it! I can't take it any more!
It's time to go home, gentlemen!
Just a moment, gentlemen.
Are you artists or not?
At this hour? Sir...
An artist shouldn't care about the time of day!
I demand absolute obedience!
It won't work.
We've never played it.
I will not accept any excuses.
Young man, please. A-Major!
Ladies and gentlemen! The last dance. A-Major!
What happened?
Nothing. I must go.
Right now?
My train departs at 4:30.
So you couldn't change it all.
I couldn't.
Not a word more. No more excuses.
Don't say a word. Go!
Superb!
And now a big discovery.
Welcome of the dawn!
An idea of genius.
Ladies and gentlemen, let's have the Polonaise!
I proclaim general concord!
Aren't they having fun...
If it could be in our Warsaw not in ruins...
As long as I'm here,
you'll always get a good room.
Thanks. Goodbye.
Hey! Give my love to Ujazdowskie Avenue.
Hi.
Come here.
Give it back.
You changed your mind.
Why?
You don't know?
Now you want to be a hero.
You've come only because your career ended!
Maciek!
Maciek, wait!
Are you crazy?
He's armed.
Halt or I'll shoot!
Watch out. He's armed!
Where is he?
Come!
Come on!
He couldn't go far.
I saw him.
There he is!
THE END
Authoring - Wojciech Janio
Menu design - Juliusz Wojciechowski
Subtitles: Translation - Krzysztof
Fordoński Synchronization - Ewa Jankowska