GORGEOUS
Attention, please!
We have a special message
for all our dear, faithful listeners!
Fathers, mothers, relatives!
Stella Film has organized
a great contest
to find a little girl,
a child from 6 to 8 years of age,
a pretty little Italian girl.
Bring your daughter to Stella Film,
to Cinecittà offices,
Via Tuscolana, km 9.
It could turn your luck
and hers around!
All the girls from 6 to 8 years,
can enter the theatre,
quietly and calmly
to be seen by
the film director Blasetti!
Now, go along inside!
Hurry! Hurry! Move along there!
Vito!
Where is this little girl?
- What's her name?
- Maria Cecconi.
Maria Cecconi!
Quiet, please! Quiet!
There! Good manners will get you far.
You will get your daughters
tested by us,
as you'd like, quietly and calmly.
We'll be able to see them better.
Right? Fine!
- Ready?
- Ready!
Glori, send over the first child.
Let's see the first child. Come on!
What can you do?
I can do an imitation
of Betty Grable.
Good! Go on!
Very good!
Well done! You're starting early,
how old are you?
- Eleven.
- Eleven! Give her a number.
Next!
Another child, hurry!
Be quiet over there!
Fine... Keep that child quiet!
- What can you do?
- "Arrivano I nostri".
Perfect!
Sing "Arrivano I nostri". Go!
Fine!
- Very good!
- Her voice is a little low!
- We need a louder voice.
- Louder!
Very good! Give her the number.
Next!
Please, be quiet over there!
Good, you with the Chinese hat!
Quiet!
Incredible! I've been looking
for you for three hours!
How could I go home without you?
Look what a mess you're in!
Just look what a mess you're in!
Stand up!
You deserve a good smack!
Now you're crying?
Look at you! Damn!
You're all dirty. You drive me crazy!
- They called you over the megaphone!
- Mummy!
What do you want from Mummy?
What did she do wrong?
She nearly gave me a heart attack.
I've been looking for her
all over Cinecittà!
They won't let us back in.
Are you happy?
- Are you here for the contest?
- Yes! Look what a mess she's in.
She looks like St. Lazarus!
Come here!
If I had to take a child to the
contest, I'd leave her like that.
All dirty? Beautiful!
They're prettier grubby and with
their hair tossed. They look nicer.
It's you who's nice.
She has a pretty face.
She's photogenic.
And she has lovely eyes.
Let me see!
Really lovely eyes!
Good thing! Let's hope they pick you.
Come on!
- Goodness! I'm lost now.
- I think they're at n. 5.
- What's that?
- Studio n. 5.
How do I get there?
I'm completely lost!
- I'll take you there.
- You will?
- Sure.
- How kind! Thanks. Let's go!
Wait till we get home!
This is the little girl who got lost!
- The lady can go in through here.
- If you say so!
I brought some photos of her.
Did I do the right thing?
- She really is a pretty child!
- At this age, they're all pretty!
Right. They're all pretty,
but I prefer their mothers!
Listen, allow me to give you
a piece of advice:
the second time
the test will be a bit harder
and these photos
won't help you much.
- They're not very good.
- Yes.
You need to get them re-done larger
and better by a professional.
- I will.
- I can give you an address.
- That'd be great!
- Tell him I sent you.
I'm Alberto Annovazzi.
The photographer
is at 14, Via Quattro Fontane.
Go to him. He's a real artist.
I'll go there! Thank you so much.
- Not at all.
- I don't know how to thank you.
- Can I go in?
- It leads straight to the studio.
- If I hadn't run into you...
- Best of luck!
- Say bye-bye!
- Bye! Don't run off again.
- I'll hold onto her tight!
- That's best.
- Goodbye!
Good. Well done, little one!
What's your name?
Mario! Give her a number.
Now, the other little girl
who is waiting her turn.
Come forward.
Madam, we're not at the races!
The incident's over!
Go back to your places! Enough!
Back to your places!
The incident is over!
This is the child who got lost!
- Ah, that one!
- I lost sight of her!
- Where?
- I don't know!
- It's a village, you can get lost.
- Where was she?
- Near the pool!
- Silence, please!
For goodness' sake! Quiet!
Where did you find her?
- Near the pool, fishing!
- She got dirty.
Yes. I struggle to iron her dress!
- Cute! What's your name?
- Maria!
- He didn't catch that.
Nice! Maria what?
- Maria...
- Zecconi!
- No. She lisps slightly.
- So, what's her surname?
- Cecconi.
Cecconi.
Repeat: "Maria Cecconi".
Okay, maybe she likes that way.
When I made the announcement
you were looking for your girl,
but I said the child has to be
6-7 years old and no younger!
- Mr. Blasetti, she's 7.
- She's a little...
You find her small?
The dress makes her look small.
To tell the truth,
she hasn't grown much this year!
She will. For sure!
What are you going to do for us?
Do you dance? Sing? Or what?
- Venice.
- You're doing Venice!
Mr. Blasetti won't understand!
- The poem on Venice!
- Fine! Off you go!
- Do you want to hear it?
- Of course!
Venice, your final hour has come
Illustrious martyr, you are lost
The plague is spreading,
we are starving,
A white flag
is fluttering on the bridge
Did you teach her that?
She's a star!
She didn't recite it that well
even at Christmas!
Come on, don't waste time. It's 2pm.
If we get to the stadium late,
it'll be full,
we'll be standing like idiots!
Hurry up!
I've had enough,
I don't feel like coming.
What?
You're not coming to the match?
Bruno, did you hear him?
There's nothing odd about it.
I'm worried.
She's been out since this morning
and she has the child with her.
Why hasn't she turned up?
I'm not coming, don't insist!
She said: "I'm going to give
an injection in Monteverde".
Where do you expect her to go?
What's the point of going
as far as Monteverde to give shots?
It's Sunday and the tram
costs 20 cents each way,
and the child pays full fare.
Your wife is nuts!
Come on, Franco, drink your coffee.
See what you've done?
This idiot's always laughing!
- Drink your coffee!
- Can't you see it's boiling?
Mum, it's best not to fret over her.
- She does as she likes anyway.
- Make her respect you!
Right! Make her respect you!
Once and for all!
Do you know what I think?
She didn't go to Monteverde!
What are you saying?
She has your daughter with her.
That's the reason!
Because she has the child with her!
Come on! Let's go! It's 3pm
and we're still chatting! It's late!
Let's go, Spartaco! Hurry!
Give her another kiss!
Mum, you're always the same!
- I dropped food on myself.
- I'll clean you up. Bye!
- Won't you kiss my forehead?
- Bye! Don't catch too much sun!
- Don't worry!
- When you see Maddalena...
I'll tell her not to bring
the child with her any more.
- She hasn't eaten yet!
- Don't take it out on her.
I won't, don't worry.
Bye-bye. See you soon.
- Have a good time!
- Come on!
Spartaco! Your wife's there!
There she is!
- I want to know where you've been!
- Spartaco!
Slow down!
You're in such a hurry now.
- I did go!
- Where?
To Cinecittà,
for the film role contest!
- Are you crazy?
- Crazy or not, they picked her!
- Who?
- Our daughter, not me! If only!
Don't tell lies.
You're always telling fibs!
Leave her be, she always does what
she wants. And she's always talking!
Let's go, the match is starting.
Why don't you mind
your own business?
Don't you talk
to my brother like that.
I'm coming with you.
No, you go home
and feed the child.
- Your mother can do it.
- You feed her!
- Take me to the movies tonight!
- I'll give you the movies!
We'll discuss tonight.
Let's go, Franco!
- What needs discussing?
- She's always talking!
- Cut it out!
- Bye, Maddalena.
We're going to the movies, right?
Be serious and take the child home
to feed her!
You grouch! Come on! Bye!
Two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
Mrs. Molteni!
What do you want, Maria?
I can't hear you! Shout louder!
They start waking people up
very early in the morning, dammit!
What do you want, Maria?
- Is my mother up there?
- No, she's not here, Maria!
She's at Margherita's giving her
an injection. I'll call her.
Mrs. Maddalena!
- What's up?
- Maria's looking for you!
- Who?
- Your daughter's looking for you!
What do you want?
Mummy, there is a lady
who wants coffee!
- I can't understand you! What?
- A lady wants coffee!
You're holding me up. I'm giving
an injection. I'll be right down.
Be good, now!
Thank you so much, Madam.
Mummy's on her way.
She's giving a lady an injection.
You see this egg?
God sees and provides.
- Your daughter's been calling you.
- I know!
Is she ill?
She's fine, she was picked!
We're going to the photographer.
When are you going to have
this baby? Hurry up!
You're always on the stairs.
Go home!
Mrs. Gisella, please, ask your
daughter to do Maria's homework.
We're going to the photographer's.
She was picked! Bye-bye!
She's mad! That fanatic!
For heaven's sake, don't choke!
Is this the lady
who wanted some coffee?
Do excuse me. I had
a sort of cramp in my stomach.
I asked for a drop of coffee.
We don't have any. We do have
some eggs, but I see that...
- They're better.
- Yes, I know they're better.
- Excuse me, but who are you?
- How silly of me, you don't know me.
I'm Tilde Spernanzoni.
The actress.
- What?
- The actress.
I've given up the stage now,
I'm tired.
When you get to a certain age,
you have to rest.
Anyway, you have to make way
for the young.
I do a little film work.
Mummy!
- The lady drank an egg.
- It doesn't matter. Don't worry.
Little blabbermouth!
This is the child who was chosen
for the second test?
Dear lady, who sent you here?
Cinecittà? Stella Film? Who?
No one.
Someone must have sent you.
You're wasting my time!
An acquaintance gave me the names
of the ones who were chosen.
She's pretty, very pretty.
Take my hand, dear.
Give me your hand. Good girl!
While Mummy's making some coffee
with lots of sugar,
you'll recite something for me.
It's nice here! You have a garden!
Wonderful! Will you come with me?
- Let's go into the garden.
- Yes, it's a real palace!
Thank goodness we're moving.
Where are you going?
I've already asked
and she doesn't need lessons.
They want her just as she is,
provided she's bright
and intelligent. Look at her face.
My daughter doesn't need coaching.
Anyway, we can't afford it.
I see, but for our children
we can make sacrifices.
- But...
- Our children are our children!
Come here, dear, come here!
Have you turned up to teach me
how to bring up children?
You're holding us up.
We're going to the photographer.
How else can I put it to you?
Be reasonable!
- You'll go there later.
- What?
Where are you going?
Maria, recite
"The final hour of Venice".
She'll be satisfied and we can go!
What a clever girl!
Say "The final hour of Venice".
- I want to hear that poem.
- Who ever sent her here?
Who ever sent that mad woman
to my house?
You come home happy and
you find a mad woman in the house.
"I'm an actress..." She tells you
her life history. "I'm retired..."
I've so many problems of my own,
I'll give her coffee so she'll go.
How much time we're wasting here!
"I'm tired", "Now I'm teaching"...
But she's far from being mad!
You're tired,
but you drank three eggs!
What bad manners! How uncouth!
I'd best lock the meat up.
Now, we're wasting half an hour
to let her hear a poem?
It's simply incredible!
We'll miss our appointment
with the photographer!
Have you nothing better to do?
In this heat!
It's nice and cool at the park!
Instead of drinking others' eggs!
This really bothers me!
I can't accept it!
- Excuse me! Listen!
- Is the coffee ready?
I'm making it. Do you want it sweet?
With lots of sugar?
The little girl is talented.
But she'll get to poetry later!
Now, it's too soon.
It's tiring for her.
I'll teach her something myself.
We'll find a suitable,
quiet spot. Let's see.
Here we are! Take my hand, dear.
Come with me.
Come with me, here we are!
You'll see what I have to teach you.
This is an ideal spot.
Come with me. Good girl!
Imagine you're in a meadow,
a large, green meadow
that's cool, like here.
You're here to pick strawberries.
Excuse me! Excuse me!
She's even deaf.
The first exercise is
in role-playing.
Imagining yourself in a situation.
Do you like strawberries?
So you're happy
to pick strawberries.
Oh! Look how many strawberries
there are under that oak!
She's mad!
Where can she see an oak?
Run, run! Pick them! Go on!
Bend down, there's a good girl.
Pick them! There are so many!
Look how many there are!
And that silly girl listens to her.
Excuse me,
but you're sapping her brain.
Maria, what are you up to?
What are you doing?
She's picking strawberries,
isn't she?
Can't you see
she's picking strawberries?
Give it to me. What a lovely one!
Bend down and pick it, dear.
You see?
- They don't understand anything.
- If she doesn't leave...
Maria, hurry!
How long does it take you
to come here, sweetheart? Hurry!
Come on, you're making me late.
She drove us both crazy.
Who is that woman?
You must only listen to Mummy.
You're making me late! Come on!
Goodness me...
Wash your hands.
Wait! Let Mummy pour the water.
Pick up the soap! Be quick!
Look what a state you're in.
Where did you go, in the coal shed?
Oh, what a slowcoach!
Can't you go any faster?
Now, rinse your hands properly.
Give your face a wash too.
Look what a state you're in.
Hurry, while Mummy gets ready.
How odd that woman is!
"Honey, pick the strawberries".
She was just pretending!
She was teaching you to act.
Yes, right, to act.
What is there to acting?
If I thought I was someone else,
if I pretended
to be someone else,
I'd be acting.
You're not interested, are you?
It's like when you say that poem,
the one about the butterfly.
"I'm a butterfly,
half white and half yellow."
The one you recite with
your hands like that! Show me!
I'm a butterfly,
half white and half yellow.
How do you move your hands?
My goodness!
You see that you can act!
You see you can act too?
But don't stutter, sweetheart,
otherwise they won't pick you?
You must speak without stuttering.
Do you understand?
Picking strawberries...
Listen to your Mummy.
All the mothers in this block
make me laugh:
"My daughter, my daughter..."
They don't have what it takes!
You're my daughter,
you certainly can be an actress!
You can be an actress, you know?
I could have, if I'd wanted to.
Come here and let me fix your hair.
What a mess you're in!
How would you look
with a centre parting?
Oh, Lord! You look ugly like that!
No, let's leave it.
All combed back, like Mummy!
Let's see.
Let's see how you look.
My beautiful potato!
Let's fix your plaits.
Let me see.
These plaits!
But... But you're cute!
You look pretty like that!
You look simpler and more natural.
Today, we'll just do the photo.
We can't afford anything else.
Understood? Understood?
Mummy, am I going back
to school tomorrow?
Oh, my Goodness! You're stuttering
and lisping. What are we to do?
Repeat it.
Louder!
What are you up to?
Are you doing it on purpose?
You never stuttered before.
You never lisped.
Pronounce it properly.
You can't speak Roman dialect
if you want to be an actress!
What's happening here?
Come here, next to Mummy.
This is a problem a real problem.
No, no, without lisping!
You're making me lisp too!
What's going on?
Here! Take your shoes
and go and get dress in there.
Put on your socks and shoes.
Then put on the dress
that's on the coffee table.
Don't toss your hair!
Do you have to stand there every
time I open the window? Scram!
What a brazen boy! At his age!
What a house this is! It's crazy!
They come right into your flat!
I'm lisping too! Really!
What's going on here?
Are you ready?
Don't toss your hair putting on
your dress, or you'll get a smack!
That's too high a pitch! Ready?
We have to do everything
in a hurry...
You're still there!
You're bothering me.
Supposing that mad woman's right?
Maybe you do need to study...
Is lisping a family trait?
Are you ready?
What's she like?
Show me.
There she is! Just a moment.
- What pose are you putting her in?
- This one. How's that?
That's not suitable!
- Put her in the tomboy one.
- Don't interfere!
Sorry. My wife's been an invalid
so long, she likes to get involved.
Let's hurry, now!
Would you like to choose a pose?
- Now, poppet, sit up straight!
- Put her in the pose I suggested!
I thought you knew each other.
That would be normal,
both here for the contest
and acquaintances of Annovazzi.
Me? I hardly know him.
Lift up your chin, won't you?
Come on!
Lift up your chin!
Keep your head straight!
I met him at Cinecittà
and he was interested in my girl.
Look over there, over there.
Don't cry!
Mummy's sweetheart!
Let's take a nice picture.
It was he who advised me
to come to you.
Because he particularly liked
her eyes.
Why are you crying, sweetheart?
Poor thing, she's not used to this
and she's a little scared!
Smile, come on! Smile!
Your daughter takes ballet classes.
They have to dance in the film.
- Not at all! Who said it?
- I thought they did!
Because one of the little girls
I photographed
was from the Opera school.
- The Ruskaja School.
- No, the Opera school!
- The Ruskaja School!
- That woman!
Excuse me, but are you sure
they have to dance?
In the novel the film is based on
the little girl dances.
I've read it!
That's exactly how it starts!
I do believe you're mistaken.
I don't want to insist.
It starts with her saying
she can't stand it any more.
Yes, it starts like that,
then the girl dances around
the table on her birthday.
No. She tells him she's leaving him.
He wants to kill her.
The girl is very happy
because it's her birthday.
She's cheerful and dances and hops,
there's a cake on the table!
In the book, the girl dances!
Excuse me.
Anyhow, if they can dance,
it'll be for the better, won't it?
No, she doesn't have to dance!
- Ready?
- Wait! I just need to settle her!
- A big smile!
- Please step aside!
A big smile! Look at the camera,
he'll take a nice photo of you!
There we are!
- You nearly set me on fire!
- It all went fine!
The bang will have frightened her
and she'll have closed her eyes!
No, they were wide open!
- Did you watch them carefully?
- Don't worry!
- They're what I'm worried about!
- I'm busy now.
- I'm the photographer!
- No need to lose your patience!
Now it's the turn of the pretty girl.
- How did you have your eyes?
- Open.
You tell so many lies.
Were you feeling afraid?
We risk wasting time
and money here. Excuse me...
When shall I come
for the negatives?
- This evening. Tomorrow, rather.
- This evening, please!
Why not yesterday?
I can't do them for this evening!
- Come tomorrow, they'll be ready.
- You're so kind!
Do you want to take it home?
Mummy will get you one like it!
It's really late, now.
Daddy will be starving!
- Goodbye! Thank you.
- Goodbye.
You know what the photos are for.
I'm in your hands!
Don't worry.
- Don't worry about a thing.
- Say goodbye to the gentleman!
Are you ready for your shot?
- Yes I am!
- So am I, I'm almost ready.
- Thank goodness.
- Decide where you want to have it.
I have. On the right again.
Always on the right!
You're full of holes there!
It hurts on the other side!
Very well. The right side it is!
But if it hurts, don't complain!
- What is it? Penicillin?
- No, we've finished with that.
You've had 8 million shots.
- So what are you giving me?
- We're back on Balerofosforo!
- I've had a whole box of that!
- You need another. You're run-down!
Look at the white of your eyes!
You're heavy,
but you have no strength!
Let's hope it helps!
What a chatterbox! I'm wasting time
here and I've so much to do!
Are you ready?
I must ask you for a favour.
- May I make a phone call?
- Of course! Naturally!
You're still lying there?
Come on! Show me where you want it!
I must phone my daughter.
We had the photos done!
They came out very well.
Don't hold me up, now!
Come on! Turn over!
Careful with that
or you'll set fire to the bed!
Hurry up! Turn over!
- Come on, skinny!
- Don't hurt me!
You're nice and plump!
Who enjoys all this abundance?
- Relax your leg.
- Don't hurt me!
Don't delay me. I must stop in on
the Commendatore.
- What's he got?
- Diabetes.
- He's worse off than you.
- That's life!
You'll get it too if you go on
eating, smoking, drinking...
They're vices.
I can't give them up.
- You're mad! Relax this leg.
- All right, but don't hurt me!
You hurt me!
You make me break out in a sweat
every time I give you a shot!
You didn't even feel the needle!
I have a very light hand!
The Commendatore, the diabetic,
says he only has his shots from me.
- He's in love with you!
- What do I care?
As long as he has his injections.
There you are, as good as new!
Rub the spot yourself.
I need to make that phone call.
- Go on, then!
- Thanks.
If you don't mind,
I'll move the phone over there.
All this stuff is open.
I don't want to spill anything!
- Come in!
- Are you expecting company?
It's my breakfast.
- Lord! You're having four eggs?
- I have to keep my strength up!
Your liver must be bombproof!
- What's she got to complain about?
- Who knows!
- Do you want an injection as well?
- No, I don't need one, do I?
- You do! You do!
- I don't need any injections.
You do! Can't you see how fat
you are? I'll help you slim down!
- She's huge! Where did you find her?
- Who knows?
Hello! Mrs. Gisella?
Listen, this is Mrs. Cecconi.
Would you do me a favour?
Thanks. My little girl
is in the courtyard.
Would you please tell her...
No, don't bother to go down.
Call down from your balcony
and tell her
that I'm not coming and
she is to carry on with her lesson.
What do you mean, what lesson?
Acting! She's with her teacher.
Right! And tell her we'll collect
those things tomorrow.
We've even crossed paths
with a black cat!
Has he died by any chance?
- Who is it?
- Oh, you've answered at last!
- It's me, Mrs. Cecconi!
- Oh, right! Sorry!
She's locked herself in.
- Do come in!
- Another black cat!
- Don't be afraid. Come in.
- No. How is the attorney?
- Oh Lord, another one!
- Well, actually...
He's not well.
He has a fever again.
The doctor says he has
to go back to taking
the streptomycin every 12 hours.
And not to stop
even if his fever goes down!
- Of course he shouldn't!
- This was to be your last visit.
But you'll have to come back,
my dear.
- Thank goodness for that!
- What do you mean?
No, I meant for him, poor man!
I'll be right there. Just a moment.
I'll get my syringe and go through.
- Quietly, please.
- I'll walk on tip toe!
How could I do otherwise?
He's unwell, fortunately!
In five days, I'll pay for her dress.
Thank you, St. Joseph!
You're so kind to me!
I'll light a candle to you, later.
Eleonora!
What are you up to? We've been
waiting for you for an hour!
- Just a moment! Here I am!
- Don't keep the lady waiting!
This is all the tulle I've found!
But the storerooms are full of it!
You're making me look bad!
- That's all there is!
- Nonsense!
Look, Madam.
- Do you like it, Madam?
- Lovely! Just like a cloud!
- Let me feel it, Miss!
- Here!
A little hard, isn't it?
It's a pre-war fabric.
I'll sell it to you cheap.
- This is better.
- At cost price!
- This is nice and soft.
- You see?
This is the pattern
with a fluffy tulle skirt!
It's a classical tutu with
a sleeveless satin bodice.
- I see.
- Have you seen "The Red Shoes"?
I'll make it identical to that one.
Don't worry! You'll love it!
How pretty you'll look!
Here! Do you like it?
It's the price that worries me.
Don't worry! I'll ask a fair price!
Since I'm a little short after
all I've had to spend on her,
at times, you never know,
one can think that...
I'm a nurse,
should you ever need shots!
Dear lady, are you joking?
If there's one thing I enjoy,
it's really good health!
You don't have shots
only when you're at death's door!
You have them when you're well,
as a tonic, to give you a boost!
- Are you here to bring me bad luck?
- You've misunderstood.
Maybe at home you've a relative
who needs a course of treatment.
What? I'm fine as I am
without you making holes in me.
And my family too. Right, girls?
Tell her we're bursting with health!
You can't get round me, you know?
Come here, dear. I'll measure you.
Come on!
She's cute!
She's about my daughter's age.
- Yes, she's very young.
- Right!
Oh, goodness!
Excuse me, but must she always
stay so close to the wall?
She'll hurt herself like that!
Don't worry! She won't hurt herself!
It takes time.
We're in a hurry! Why doesn't she
put her with the others?
Aren't I right?
Always stuck to the wall?
Excuse me, does my daughter always
have to stay stuck to the wall?
It's been three hours.
Put her with the others!
But they've been studying
for two or three years.
You marched in here saying:
"Make her dance like a butterfly".
Where's your common sense?
You're asking for a lot!
That child is very small!
She isn't old enough for ballet!
- How old does she need to be?
- Eight!
Am I supposed to wait three years?
Do as you think best!
Anyway, her little legs...
Her legs? Look at them closely!
Her legs are as straight as a dart!
Straight legs are not enough!
You need other things.
You need intelligence. You dance
with your brain, not your feet!
What?
You dance with your brain,
not your feet!
She has a good brain. She was born
healthy, she wasn't born backward!
That's your opinion!
You're getting on my nerves!
We're the teachers! We decide
if a child is intelligent or not.
I decide because I'm her mother!
I assure you
my daughter is not stupid!
Sweetheart,
why are you crying like that?
They're not going to hurt you.
You too will become a good dancer.
Look at that girl!
How good she is!
Look! Can you see her?
Do you want to become like them?
You'll learn to be good too!
Did you have to make her cry?
How rude you are!
We're going home now.
Give Mummy a nice smile!
Don't let Daddy see you crying!
Let's go home! Come on!
Naturally, the child is rather
disheartened now,
but I must make it clear that
here, we study, study, study.
I've been dancing for 40 years,
but if I didn't practice daily,
these arabesques,
these temps levés...
You see these steps?
I couldn't do them!
You tell her, Placida!
Unfortunately, it's the truth,
you have to study
and sweat, sweat, sweat!
That's the way it is!
Hello, Spartaco.
Now you go out after dinner?
And you take the child with you?
What could I do? You weren't here.
Was I to leave her on her own?
- Where have you been?
- Giving injections.
- Say hello to Daddy, won't you?
- Hello, Daddy.
Daddy's little darling!
Give Daddy a kiss!
- Maddalena!
- Yes?
The instalments aren't
60,000 lire, but 65,000.
How come?
The lift has to be paid for.
We didn't include it.
Everyone's paid for it,
and so will we.
What happened to you, poppet?
- Tell Daddy what happened.
- I'm tired.
Daddy's little sweetheart!
This is the new house
that Daddy has bought you.
We're putting your bed here.
And Daddy will buy you a Pinocchio.
Do you know the story of Pinocchio?
The boy whose nose grew longer
because of all the lies he told.
He lied to his father,
an old man who...
There's only 60,000 lire here.
I don't have another cent.
How will we manage?
Spartaco, do we absolutely have
to pay the instalment on Monday?
Yes, on Monday.
We're only 5,000 short.
You'll just have to ask
for some arrears!
Didn't you feed the little one?
So now I'm starving her!
That's all we need!
She had a cup of coffee and milk
and two buns. Tell him!
- That wasn't much!
- Tell him!
- Leave it!
- Mummy will undress you.
- I'll do it!
- You'll tear her dress!
There! You undress her.
Daddy will put you to bed.
Tomorrow, I'll take her out
and buy her a big ice cream.
Ice cream's bad for her tummy.
- Maddalena, go away!
- You know I do whatever you say.
See how tired the child seems!
Look!
What do you want from me?
How pretty you are.
The baby of the family!
Do you love your Daddy?
Give me a kiss and a pinch.
Tomorrow Daddy's taking you
for an ice cream all the same.
Are you happy?
- So, are you coming?
- I have a lesson tomorrow!
No, you're coming with Daddy.
No lessons!
Give Daddy a kiss.
Be good! Go to sleep now.
I'm turning off the light.
You see? It's Montgomery Clift.
He's nice, isn't he?
Maddalena,
forget about the cinema!
Spartaco, you don't understand me!
Look what lovely places!
Look where we're living.
When I see those things, I...
- Maddalena, it's all make-believe.
- It's not make-believe!
Oh! Look!
They're taking the wagon across!
Incredible!
All the horses are in the water!
Lucky them, having a bath!
Isn't that fantastic?
It's fantastic!
I'm falling asleep.
- I can't keep my eyes open.
- Let's go to bed.
- No! I'm before her!
- Calm down! Calm down!
Stop being so pushy!
- Who's being pushy?
- Stay calm!
- He's holding my ticket!
- No! I'm first!
- Where must I go?
- In the room next door.
- Were you bitten by a tarantula?
- Such unfairness in this world!
- She never stops yakking!
- You're always so pushy!
Come here!
Don't you ever get tired?
- I am tired! I can hardly stand!
- It doesn't look like it!
Look, I had my granddaughter's
picture taken,
but I made her stand because
it looks better, doesn't it?
I only had one done
because they're so expensive!
- They told me one was enough.
- Of course it's enough.
Did you want to bring them a film?
My child only has one, too.
The photographer wanted
to take her while dancing.
I said to him: "She'll show
what she can do at the audition".
If they choose her for the audition.
I think they've already
made up their mind!
- Really?
- And we're all wasting our time.
If I hadn't seen it with
my own eyes, I'd keep quiet!
- What did you see?
- What did you see? Tell us!
I was here yesterday because
I got the dates mixed up...
Got the dates mixed up! She came
on purpose to be here first!
No, it was a genuine mistake!
They were doing special auditions.
For the recommended candidates!
I saw them with my own eyes!
There was a lady with a little girl,
who didn't ask for the director!
No, no.
She asked for the other man!
- Who's that?
- The other one! That ugly man,
the fat one who's always
yelling into the megaphone.
- That nasty fellow.
- Glori!
As soon as he saw her he said:
"How cute this little girl is!".
"How pretty she is..."
What's wrong with that?
My child's pretty too!
"How pretty she is", looking at
the mother in the meantime.
What are you insinuating?
It was just an impression.
Don't exaggerate!
Sure! We're all stupid here!
I understood perfectly
what the lady was saying!
But we'll go to the producer
and the director and make a fuss!
It's a real disgrace!
Because there are some favourites,
some recommended candidates!
And we're all supposed to be equal.
It's not right! It's unfair!
We must do something about it!
My husband knows someone
who works here at Cinecittà.
I'll ask him to put in a good word
for me with Stella Film!
My husband is a close friend
of one of the phone company heads.
What does the phone company head
have to do with all this?
He's a personality too!
Don't make us laugh!
We can all find someone
to pull strings for us.
We can all find someone important!
I have a relative who's a friend
of a waiter in Cinecittà.
He knows him very well, really!
He's high up...
Amerigo! I'm in a big hurry!
- Bath, shower?
- No, we don't need them.
Just a trim and a couple of curls.
Go on in. Amerigo, a cut!
- Don't I get a receipt?
- No, you don't need one.
- The child needs an hair dye too.
- Are you crazy?
We need to lighten her hair, no?
If I take her home blonde,
all hell will be let loose!
But just a slight...
She just needs a trim.
- And a couple of curls.
- One moment, then it's your turn!
What... Where are you?
They're making us waste time here.
- Well, if it's just 5 minutes...
- Listen to me a moment!
- We'll give you a good tip!
- It's not a question of a tip.
But it's just a quick job!
These darned balloons!
Just trim her plaits
and make a couple of curls.
- I'm serving this lady!
- You've almost finished!
A quick rinse and she's off!
I haven't finished yet.
I've paid and I have my rights!
Are you going to keep on washing
her hair till tomorrow?
I have another client waiting!
You don't have an appointment!
- Just two minutes! Do me this favour!
- Sit her there, I'll do her later!
How jumpy you are!
The balloons don't bother you?
See how kind he is?
Now, sit here...
Give me the balloons,
I'll tie them here.
Do you mind if I tie them to this?
They'll keep you company.
Mummy will be right back! Be good!
- Will I make it in time?
- I think so.
If I don't come back,
Mrs. Spernanzoni will collect you.
If I'm not back in time, she'll be
picked up by middle-aged lady
who's called Tilde Spernanzoni.
A slightly odd lady! She's her acting
teacher. Understood, sweetheart?
- I don't want to stay here!
- What?
You have to stay!
They'll make you look pretty!
If you need to stay with her,
we'll go out another day.
No! I don't have to stay.
Fine. Remember to lighten her hair
to give it a softer tint.
- A hair dye.
- No! Are you joking?
Just highlights, natural streaks.
- Just touched up a little?
- And a light perm.
No! Don't spoil her hair!
Just a set, then. Her hair's fine
and won't stay in place!
- She got that from me.
- I could give you a nice hair-do...
You'd waste your time on me.
No one has managed that!
- I would!
- You'd be wasting your time.
- How much? I want to settle up now.
- 1,250 lire!
Do I pay out there? Fine.
- Well, let's go.
- Be a good girl, now.
Just a trim and a couple of curls.
So when I comb her hair,
it'll be all fluffy.
- Bye, honey! Be good!
- Let's go.
Mummy's coming back.
I don't want to stay here!
You're not alone, you're with him!
Behave nicely!
Be good! I'll look after you.
Be good!
I don't want to stay here!
Don't start! Be good!
If you behave, I'll buy you
some sweets afterwards.
You be good
and I'll give you some curls!
Amerigo, you have to set my hair!
It's still all wet!
I'll call Michele and he'll take
care of you! Just a minute!
- Michele, come here!
- I'll be right there!
I want to go home!
I want my Mummy!
- Give the little girl a trim.
- How can I? I'm busy.
- Call Guido!
- Okay.
Hurry up!
- I went to get the shampoo!
- Come on!
- I want to go to my Mummy!
- Guido, give her a trim.
Give the little girl a trim,
then maybe she'll pipe down!
- Amerigo, my set!
- Coming!
Listen, Guido,
just a simple trim.
Don't worry! I'll take care of her.
- Just a little trim?
- Yes, just a trim.
Let's cut it here... Here.
Here's one, young lady!
And the other!
Are you happy, Miss?
Is that all right?
I wonder what you think of me
asking you for an appointment.
When a lovely lady asks me for
an appointment, I think well of her!
If you take it like that, great!
I'm no longer so used
to walking so far.
Listen... Tell me frankly...
Do you think my girl will be picked?
I'm a little discouraged.
It happens, for no reason
something seems easy, natural,
then it no longer seems feasible.
You start feeling worried
about everything.
I don't know if you understand me.
I wouldn't like to make
so many sacrifices
then see the recommended one win!
You do understand me, don't you?
- Yes, but it depends on you.
- How can it be?
A recommendation can help
or hinder!
No, no! It helps!
No, you see, we're used
to recommendations.
If they were worth anything,
there'd be no unemployment!
In Italy
we live on recommendations:
"Please, don't forget...",
"I assure you, I promise..."
but we don't remember,
because we can't.
Who are we supposed to remember
and why should we remember them?
- There's only one foolproof method.
- What's that?
Putting the person who can help you
in a position to request to help you.
You see?
- No.
- Do you already want to leave?
No, it's so pleasant here.
I'd never been here.
Well, just once on a Sunday,
but it was very crowded.
It's so nice and peaceful today.
Yes, it's nice, but not on one's own.
You have to come to a place
like this in good company!
- Am I good company?
- Very.
If you like me,
do me this favour, won't you?
- I like you a lot!
- Better still!
I want my daughter to have
the best recommendation of all.
She has to do a screen test.
It's as if she'd already auditioned,
it's certain.
It's just that it depends on you.
That's simple, isn't it?
Now I understand.
You know what we say in Rome?
"Nothing given, nothing received."
As well as friendly,
you're also intelligent.
- Really? Everyone says so.
- And you're quick witted.
To make a big profit,
one must run a big risk!
50,000 lire sounds right to me.
You're crazy!
50,000 lire is 50,000 lire,
not a small sum!
Today, 50,000 lire is nothing.
To you! To me, lots of sacrifices,
don't even think about it!
It's the bare minimum
we need to reach our goal.
I'll manage the 50,000 lire
and get you a contract.
You'll earn,
at the very least, a million,
which is 20 times
the amount you staked.
Do you think I'll be spending it?
No, it's not for me, but for
the favours that will be needed.
- Who will you do these favours to?
- Everyone and no one!
Flowers for the producer's wife,
perfume for his mistress,
who is often the wife
of the leading actor.
In the film world that happens...
They don't need them, of course,
but they help since
these favours
remind them of a name.
In this case, your name.
Cecconi.
Kind Mrs. Cecconi
who sent that gift...
The word soon spreads. Have you
never thrown a stone into a pond?
The stone falls in just one spot
but from that spot
waves ripple out
until they reach the ocean.
- How shrewd you are!
- Shrewd...
It's just a practical way
of getting through life.
Am I to take this risk
with no guarantees?
What risk would it be otherwise?
Do you want a guarantee?
I'll give it to you!
Your child will have a screen test!
All right?
I accept.
I accept. I do have that sum.
I brought my savings book with me.
The trouble is
I need the money right away.
No problem!
Let's hurry.
The banks are closed
but a friend of mine is a clerk.
I'll swap the book for cash.
Then tomorrow morning,
she can withdraw the money.
Listen, Madam...
If it's difficult for you,
shall we forget the whole idea?
Especially since...
I'm sorry to have
business relations with you.
I'd have preferred, maybe,
I don't know...
It's fine by me. It's much better.
Let's hurry as it's late.
- Did you bring the money?
- Of course! Here it is!
- 1, 2, 3, 4, 50,000. The scooter?
- It's outside!
This is the scooter.
Do you like it?
I'm 10,000 lire short.
But who's complaining?
I'm just saying "stop"!
The little girl has learned enough!
Do you expect me to thank you?
Naturally! I'm used to being
thanked and respected!
I thank you and I respect you!
Did my wife pay you?
This is the door! Get out!
Your wife is the only person
who understands art!
Art, sure! Get out,
before I start swearing at you!
- Watch your language!
- What's all this racket?
- What's happening?
- What's going on?
It happens that I've had enough!
I don't want to see
strangers in my house!
I don't want my daughter...
I've never been fortunate,
but I have been respected!
Who's ruining your daughter?
That silly...
Don't exaggerate.
I've been so patient,
but now I've had enough!
Will you stop making a scene?
- Madam, please leave!
- Spartaco, stop that!
What did you do?
You're asking her? Where were you?
You left the child with this wretch!
- You're calling me a wretch?
- Yes, a wretch!
- I'm reporting you to the police!
- Spartaco, don't make such a fuss!
It looks short because it's curly.
I'll wet it and straighten it out.
- You'll make her catch bronchitis!
- I won't make her catch anything!
Didn't you notice anything?
Look at the state she's in!
- I'm not her nanny!
- So what?
- I'm an actress!
- Do you have no eyes?
Just because you're an actress,
if they cut off her head,
would you stand by and watch?
- Madam, this is the door!
- May I?
- Who's this?
- Is Mrs. Cecconi here?
Dressmakers Fracassini!
Shall I leave it here?
Did I get here in time?
I have the invoice with me.
- I must collect the balance.
- Thank you.
What did they do to you?
They gave you a "gamine" cut!
Don't take me for a fool!
Pay up what you owe me!
That's 1,260 lire.
1,000 for the lessons,
200 lire for the child's haircut
and 60 lire for the tram!
Madam, don't get agitated!
We'll pay in full! I'll see to it.
You won't see to anything!
You've got to stop this nonsense!
Don't you touch me!
How much does she owe you?
There, 1,260. Now, go!
- I'm 10 lire short!
- We'll give it to you!
- You can keep it!
- How generous! Now, go!
- You scoundrel!
- Get out!
You were right
to get her a "gamine" cut!
She'll feel cooler in the summer!
Won't you, honey?
Signorina, why don't you leave?
- What's in there?
- Don't touch it! It belongs to me!
- I paid for it with my money!
- No, it's my money too!
I never asked you for a cent
for these things!
Spartaco, please,
let's not fight over it!
You take advantage of me
because I'm weaker!
Can't you see
you're scaring the child?
For the last week, our life
has been turned upside down.
- Am I no longer in charge, here?
- I've had enough of you!
I've done far too much for you!
Is that clear? Get out of here!
- Get out!
- I'll kill you?
Concierge!
Come down!
He's killing Mrs. Cecconi!
- Concierge!
- What's going on?
Hurry! They're killing each other!
Concierge!
Just a minute!
I'm coming as fast as I can!
- The Cecconis are fighting!
- Of course! They're always at it!
Spartaco! What are you doing?
If you take the child away,
you won't see me again!
You won't see me again!
Take her away with you!
You always say
she's unhappy with me!
He's the only one who loves her.
Only he makes sacrifices for her.
I ruin her.
It's just because I want my daughter
to become somebody.
Yes, I want my daughter
Do I have this right or not?
Or is it a crime?
She mustn't become a loser,
she mustn't depend on anyone,
she mustn't get beaten like me!
You don't know
what sacrifices I made
to find the money
to pay for these little things.
I went all over Rome
without telling him,
not to have to touch his money.
And how does he thank me?
He's beating me!
Get out!
I can't stand the sight of you!
Get out! You've ruined me!
I'm covered in bruises!
Look, my face is swollen!
Go away!
I can't stand the sight of you!
You've ruined me!
Stop this play acting!
Come on!
I'm not play acting!
Come on, Mr. Spartaco...
She's made so many sacrifices!
She went to the other side of Rome
for a diabetic! What more do you ask?
Give her the child!
We'll settle this score later!
This man will be the death of me!
Give me the child!
We made it.
If we didn't do that,
we wouldn't have got an audition!
My dear, am I working for nothing?
Cheer up! You have to sing!
I've lost my voice,
but you'll see how I sing tomorrow!
Mummy's little darling!
We made it.
It's the voice
of Commendatore Blasetti!
I'm going to faint!
Madam!
Good morning!
Maybe it's my child's turn!
- Will you let us hear him?
- What does that woman want?
- Madam, please.
- If you say so...
Come over here a minute.
I have to tell you something.
- I'm leaving.
- Good!
- All the gifts, the presents...
- All taken care of!
- Did you send the flowers?
- To Blasetti's wife, of course.
It's important, you see...
- Did you send the perfume?
- To the cameraman.
To the cameraman's wife, sure!
Cigarettes to the cameraman.
Right!
Did you send a big bunch of flowers?
Instead of a bunch of normal flowers,
I sent orchids.
They cost more
but are more impressive.
You'll see that the gifts work!
I'm nervous,
I don't care about anything!
My heart is in my mouth.
My hands are shaking!
- I hope you won't faint!
- No, I won't faint like her!
She was a fanatic who...
Who's this?
- With that funny hairstyle.
- That's Mimmetta!
How are you?
What a rogue you are!
- Did you buy yourself a scooter?
- Yes, I did!
When are we inaugurating it?
With a solemn launching,
a bottle of champagne
and maybe even a patroness!
I don't enjoy ceremonies!
I may get a part
in Colamorucci's next film.
Glori promised it to me.
Good for you! Congratulations!
So in the end, it's you
who have to thank me, right?
Right!
Mummy, I've finished!
You've finished? How did it go?
- Very well!
- Tell me about it!
Mr. Annovazzi, I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
- May I go for a minute?
- I don't think that...
It's my daughter's turn!
How discourteous!
This isn't at all correct!
That's her!
That's her. How pretty she is!
Look how that dress
suits her so well.
She looks like a hen!
Mummy's sweetheart!
- What's he saying to her?
- Blasetti's telling her what to do.
- Oh! She has to eat the cake?
- No, they're lighting the candles
and she has to blow them out
as if it were her birthday.
- And she doesn't get to eat it?
- No!
What a pity! She'd have done it
well since she loves sweet things!
What's he doing, picking her up?
She's cute!
He kissed her!
He kissed my child, see that?
Everything's fine. I'm sure of it.
Come to lunch at my
mother-in-law's restaurant on Sunday.
- I will.
- Bring that young lady with you...
- Mimmetta!
- Yes, the one wearing trousers...
Your fiancée, I mean.
You should have seen her!
She was phenomenal!
Under those lamps!
All the spotlights on her!
It was like being in Piazza Navona
with Commendatore Blasetti
who overawes me!
I couldn't watch him...
She was quiet, confident and calm!
The child was very calm.
While she was so nervous,
as if it was she auditioning.
- Don't say such silly things!
- You were trembling all over!
All right, just a little.
My child's future is at stake.
It's understandable, isn't it?
Your medicine! I forget everything!
My head is in a spin.
You must take this medicine
because in a few days
you have to start working so hard
that if you don't get a boost...
What is it? Glycerophosphate of...
- Sodium!
- It'll do you so much good!
I don't want it! It tastes nasty!
If you don't take it, I will!
I'm going to take it myself!
And you know what will happen?
The little girls who don't take it
turn into geese!
Tomorrow morning, you'll wake up:
quack, quack, quack!
Come on! Take it!
It tastes like water! Quack quack!
- Look, I'll take it.
- You see?
Did you have to bring here
this chancer?
You're always complaining!
What's it to do with the chancer?
You're never happy if you're not
fighting with someone, are you?
You should try
to sweeten your character.
You know why I bought him here,
because he helped me!
Don't pretend not to understand.
He helped my daughter!
- Here's the fruit!
- Thank you.
Up with Roma!
Are you a Roma team fan now?
Oh, Lord! Get out of here!
I want him to meet Spartaco, so
Spartaco can tell you if it's true!
- Mrs. Maddalena!
- What?
At least you'll believe him,
you never believe me!
- Come down to the river!
- Are you mad?
- You'll see how cool it is there!
- He's mad!
I can't come
because I'm in high heels.
Don't worry about your heels.
I'll give you a hand!
- Take my advice, come on up!
- You come down!
What a pain! I'm coming!
I'm in heels, it'll be tough!
- I'll give you a hand!
- Thank goodness for that!
Be careful you don't hurt yourself.
I'm coming!
- You make me fall.
- Here you are.
You're crazy to make me come down
in these heels!
- Can't you feel the breeze?
- It's terribly hot, here.
- The breeze is cooler!
- Don't let me fall!
- What lovely greenery!
- Where's the greenery?
- I mean nature!
- We're so used to it!
Then why do you stay
indoors all the time?
It's nice walking here!
It's shady and cool!
There's a refuse dump here!
We're hiding like quails.
Don't push me down! No tricks!
- What... Oh, Lord!
- Don't hit me, or you'll fall!
Let me take off my shoe
which is full of sand.
Don't push me down there
or I'll take you with me!
- No! Otherwise I'll fall too!
- I'll drag you down with me!
Let me take my shoe off.
Heavens! It's full! Look!
- Look at all this!
- Nice earth!
- I must wash my feet! Hold me!
- I'll hold you!
Oh! It's so cold!
Oh, Lord!
My digestion has stopped.
It's really nice here!
- It's almost nicer than the Naviglio!
- This man is nuts!
- You did the right thing coming!
- What a mess!
- I really needed it!
- What?
- 10 minutes alone with you.
- Really? Why?
Did you want to thank me
for the gift I gave you?
- What are you talking about?
- What's it like? Does it run well?
How fast can it go?
- I'm not following you!
- Oh, poor fellow!
May I give you some advice?
You'd take care of it.
You need to get a cover for it
so it won't get wet!
If you ruin it, you won't find another
chump like me to buy you another one.
You can't be thinking that I...
- Not me! I wouldn't dream of it!
- Really!
What do I care!
I understood perfectly.
I was interested in getting
what I wanted.
Comb your hair, you look dishevelled!
- You're fun to be with!
- I know, everyone says that!
No one can resist my cheerfulness!
So... don't be cruel.
I'm very kind. I'm kindness itself!
And I'm obedient!
It's so pleasant here!
A nice lunch, sunshine, all I need...
It's a girl, I know. I invited her,
but you didn't bring her!
- Mimmetta? She's not my girl!
- Really?
We dated for a while and we may
get back together, but not now...
- Did you break up?
- Me? I never broke up from anyone!
- And if I said it was your fault?
- Sure!
- Where do I come into it?
- You do!
If you want to talk seriously,
we'll talk seriously,
if you want to joke...
I saw her with you twice...
- Right!
- Is she jealous?
Of me? Pull the other one!
A pretty girl like her!
Do you think a girl
can't be jealous of you?
I'm not saying that, but...
- Did your husband never tell you...
- Of course he told me, and how!
Let's hope they win!
- The Lazio team?
- Roma! Let's not fight!
- Very well, very well!
- Roma will win!
As you wish!
That's more like it!
Let me hear what they're saying.
I can't make out anything
from down here, dammit!
- This is the way to go.
- No, that's not proper!
- Stay still! Stop that!
- Who, me?
- Look what a shrewd face!
- Let's be honest!
- I fixed things for your child.
That cost me my girlfriend!
You bought the scooter!
What more do you want?
Don't make me say what I think!
Lord, how cunning he is!
What a son of a...
- I got the scooter!
- You deserve...
Life's great, isn't it?
Sure! Life is great.
It would be great,
but you only live it once,
quite briefly and quite badly.
I know you love your husband
and you feel good.
You're happy when you're with him
and your daughter.
But...
Today, at this moment,
we're happy here together.
Why shouldn't I say so?
It's true.
And we're on the same wavelength.
It's nice being here.
I feel a great urge to hug you.
Is there anything wrong
in saying so?
No.
My mother,
who's a little old lady now,
if as a young woman
she'd let someone hug her,
like this, in the sunshine,
on the riverbank,
instead of torturing herself
thinking
what my life would be like
when I grew up,
today she might be less sad
seeing the days go by
while washing my four shirts.
My mother...
All the things she gave up
she turned into hopes for me.
Poor thing!
And now, like Mimmetta,
she says to me all day:
"Be a go-getter. Be a go-getter!".
I am a go-getter.
You know that very well!
I never pass up any opportunity
that comes my way.
I don't get my hopes up.
But I don't want to have
any regrets.
Am I right, Maddalena?
Don't make me finish up my Sunday
counting the ants in the sand!
Maddalena, listen...
Have you ever tried
letting yourself go?
Doing one of those silly things
people do just like that,
once in a while,
without thinking about it much,
without mulling it over, like
the rich, when they squander money?
They're the most fun things,
they brighten up our lives.
They're everything.
Right now, in this light,
your eyes are blue.
No, they're green, like the water.
They change, it's the reflection.
And now they're very pale
and seem to be laughing.
Come on! Don't talk nonsense!
Look... I'm all dirty!
- Why did you stand up?
- Because I have to go!
Do you want to stay here
counting the ants?
Stay, if that pleases you!
Shall I send you my mother-in-law?
She can help you a little, no?
Let's go.
What? Aren't you coming?
To do want to have a swim,
to cool your hot head?
Let's go and watch the auditions.
Come on! Get moving!
Poor tousled fellow,
you were unlucky. No matter!
You'll be luckier another time!
Oh, my jacket! Excuse me.
If you want to see the screen test,
come to the Cinecittà editing room
and ask for Iris.
- Thanks so much.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye, everyone!
Did you take off only your shoes?
May I? Is Iris here?
I'm Iris! Come in!
- Am I disturbing you?
- No, do come in!
Mr. Annovazzi told me to come to you.
He mentioned that!
I was expecting you!
He said you have the auditions.
Of all the little girls.
- Do you have my daughter's too?
- Which one is she?
- This one here.
- Number 7! It's in the can!
- What do you mean?
- To take it to the viewing room.
The film! I see!
- May I watch it? Is it this one?
- No, this is a different test.
- Ah, it's another little girl!
- Right.
But it's not very clear.
She seems like a cat!
She gives me the shivers!
- May I see my daughter's?
- No!
Blasetti is waiting for me
in the viewing room.
Iris, hurry and bring the tests
down as Blasetti is waiting!
- I'm coming!
- He's angry!
- They are in room n.3.
- Fine, bye!
- Are they viewing the tests?
- Yes, they are!
- Including my daughter's?
- Yes!
- Please show it to me!
- Believe me, I can't!
- I came all the way here!
- They'll tell me off!
- But who'll see me?
- Nella, you try telling her!
- Try to understand...
- It's just impossible!
Where did I see you? I saw you!
Where did I see you? Help me!
Tell her! Are you ashamed?
- You'll have seen me in a film!
- It's true!
That really nice Roman film,
"Under the Roman Sun".
How lovely that film was!
Was it you who got slapped?
How I enjoyed it!
Do you remember it?
You loved it!
- Are you in the film with my girl?
- No, I don't make films any more.
I work here. I do editing.
You're no longer in films... Why?
I'm not an actress.
They hired me once or twice,
as I was the type they needed.
I even got my hopes up
and it cost me my job
and the fiancé I had then.
You need to be real,
professional actors
or give up your dreams
and have a job to turn to.
I'm sorry to say that.
You're getting your hopes up.
You may well be right.
I doubt it, though.
So many people ended up badly
thinking they'd make it in films.
I'd convinced myself
I was very good and very beautiful.
Yet, here I am, editing films,
no one called me any more.
Really?
Poor thing.
It can't be the same for everyone.
That would be terrible.
That would be really terrible.
With no solution.
I'm staking everything on her.
I'd be disappointed!
Don't worry, Madam,
everything will work out.
She's so pretty.
- Have you seen her screen test?
- Yes, I have.
- Is she cute?
- Yes, very.
- Show it to me.
- How can I?
How can I? Nella! What do you say?
Shall I send it up for viewing?
Why not, give it a try!
No one will see me.
I'll stand behind you.
You're so kind.
I'll take you there,
provided you stay quiet!
I won't say a word! I won't move!
Thank you!
There is my daughter.
Please, let me see my daughter.
Thanks.
You see her? The girl who was
at the photographer's! Remember?
- Do you see her?
- Yes, I saw her.
Quiet, or they'll throw us out!
- What's this one's name?
- This is Maria Cecconi.
That's you!
How small you look from afar!
What are you doing?
Now you have to put out the candles.
Blow, blow!
Poor thing!
Couldn't you manage?
You've so much breath at home,
but not here?
My goodness, you make me feel ill!
Guys! Please!
It's really incredible!
Laugh, laugh... You too...
- Who brought her, Glori?
- Not me! Maybe him, Annovazzi.
Did you bring her?
I only directed her here,
because her mother asked me...
Now, you say the poem.
I know you can recite it well.
You burst into tears?
Why did you burst into tears?
They're amused, can't you hear?
Perhaps you made them laugh!
What do they have to laugh at?
What are they saying?
Are they talking badly of her?
Why are they so amused?
Why? What's so funny?
She's a dwarf, look!
Swines!
Swines! I can't take this!
I can't take it, I can't stand it.
Aren't you overdoing it?
Stop the film
and restart it from the beginning!
- What's so laughable?
- She's funny with that fringe!
She's not a child, she's a dwarf!
In '25 she was at school with me!
Are you insinuating
you're 30 years old?
- Fine. What do you think?
- It's a counterproductive test.
Sorry if I express my opinion,
but I think it's a waste of film.
I realized immediately that
the girl would come out like that.
I believe I already told you...
Your name's Annovazzi, isn't it?
Have you served in the army?
Stand up!
Good! By the left!
By the left! Quick march!
Glori, get rid of him!
Go away!
Sorry, Blasetti!
Carry on like this and you're out.
I won't be able to hire you.
- You've no chance.
- At least let me apologize.
You'll make it worse!
Is it fair that I lose my job
over this?
Let me explain,
I'll apologize to him!
- You'll make it worse.
- What do you mean?
I was right, we've wasted
time, money and film!
Time, money, film and our health!
We work hard for two weeks
to find this little girl
and then you tell us
we've wasted money.
Filippo, please!
You've laughed up till now!
Go and see what's happening there?
No, let me through!
- You can't come in.
- Leave me alone!
- Don't you dare touch me!
- Madam, calm down...
- Can't I talk to the director?
- What do you want to say to him?
What was so funny in this little girl?
Is she so funny?
Where is he? There he is!
- Mr. Blasetti...
- Later!
Let me through! Let me through!
Excuse me, Mr. Blasetti...
I was hiding up there in the booth...
I heard you all laughing.
What made you laugh so much?
Do you find this little girl
so laughable?
Look at her!
She's just like all the others!
- One of you called her a dwarf!
- No, no!
How rude! You've no respect
for other people's feelings!
You've no respect
for sacrifices people make!
I made so many sacrifices
to buy her this dress...
- All these sacrifices...
- Don't worry, Madam.
And Mr. Annovazzi...
Where is Mr. Annovazzi?
- We kicked him out.
- You did the right thing!
You're a person who understands.
You did the right thing!
How can we tell if someone
is hiding in the projection booth?
Mr. Blasetti, I beg you,
don't send me away like this,
without a glimmer of hope.
You see? This is the cinema.
We're responsible for all this.
Glori, come here!
We can't deal
with the mothers too!
- Put reel n.7 back on.
- The one with Maria Cecconi!
I want to see the test again.
Do you want to go to Doney's?
- No, I'm going to watch it again.
- I'm pleased. It's such fun!
The dwarf in the land of the giants...
Remember I'm from Milan,
I don't have lunch at Doney's!
- Do you go to Motta?
- No, I have lunch in the office.
"Today, tomorrow and never".
Seventh screen test.
Annovazzi! Alberto!
Wait for me! Stop!
You must immediately find the child
who did the screen test!
The one that made us laugh,
what's her name?
- Cecconi?
- Right, Blasetti wants her!
Blasetti kicked me out,
it's no longer my business!
Don't be stupid! Don't be a fool!
You have to find that child!
You find her! Here's her address:
via Alberto da Giussano, 4. Bye!
If you find her for me
and we sign the contract tonight,
I promise you'll be in the film!
- Swear on it!
- I swear. I give you my word!
She lives in Prenestino,
via Alberto da Giussano, 4.
I'll go ahead by scooter,
you join me by car!
All right. Orsini, move it!
The contract is ready
and signed by the producer.
All we need is your approval.
We have the best actors!
- There's...
- Amedeo Nazzari.
- And that American actress...
- Lana Turner!
- If not her, a better one!
- That's what I said!
Maybe while we're talking to him
he's worried about his wife.
Don't worry, she'll be back.
She's not a child.
I'll take care of that!
We and the police are very close.
Orsini, go straight to talk
to Superintendent Giusillo.
Tell him Glori sent you
and that I need a favour.
- Forget about the police.
- He's right. Forget about it!
My wife will be here soon!
She wanted to do her own thing!
I'd really like to know
where she got to!
I even asked someone
to let me know when she arrives.
- Do have a seat.
- Orsini, you can go.
- We can discuss the contract!
- Fine.
So...
With this private agreement,
we are hiring the child...
Maria Cecconi!
As the leading juvenile player.
Mr. Spartaco! She's here!
Come on up! She's here!
At last, you got it!
Stay still! Don't touch her!
Don't touch her!
Maddalena!
Spartaco, don't wake the child up!
Don't wake her up.
Will you let me through?
Thank goodness she's arrived!
Her eyes are red, she's been crying.
Maddalena! What's the matter?
- You got what you wanted!
- Well...
For once you're successful,
and you start crying!
Let's sign this contract!
Otherwise, we're done for.
Either we sign the contract,
or we all sleep in the street.
She's crying!
Here she is, our Greta Garbo!
Don't touch her!
Madam, let's sign the contract!
We just need one signature!
I'll give you 250,000 lire now!
A further 250,000 in a week,
and more in 15 days.
I'll give you the first instalment
straight away.
Where's the cheque book?
Do you have it, Alberto? No.
It must be at Cinecittà.
I'll be right back to pay you!
It's two million lire!
You're going to get two million!
Plus a thousand lire a day
with the lunch and other things.
Don't turn your back on luck,
it only comes round once!
Do me a favour and sign it!
Very well...
How do you want the child?
With curly hair or straight?
Is she to lisp? Is she to stutter?
What makes you laugh most?
Haven't you all had enough fun?
I'm really sorry,
but my daughter's staying put!
I didn't bring her into the world
to amuse anyone.
For me and her father,
she's very pretty!
She's very pretty!
We're keeping her here!
Go now, or you'll wake her up.
Leave us alone.
Spartaco, what are you waiting for
to tell these gentlemen
that your daughter
will never be in films?
Kick them out!
Kick them out, Spartaco!
Kick them out, kick them out...
Can you hear me?
I fear there's nothing we can do.
I know her well.
Take back the contract,
return to Cinecittà. I'm sorry.
What are you doing here?
You're always a nuisance!
Get that!
We're always a nuisance?
What about you
and the racket you make?
I'm the concierge. Haven't I
the right to tell these ladies
what goes on in the house
where I work as a concierge?
Be quiet!
My daughter's sleeping!
Be quiet! Do me the favour
of taking all these whales away!
Quiet! My daughter is asleep!
Go away!
What are you doing here?
Out! Come on! Move!
You must stop it
or I'll send you my husband.
Send us your grandfather
and your uncle! Go away!
What a harridan!
How will I look in front
of the producer, of everyone?
Orsini's already driven off.
- How do I get back to Cinecittà?
- I'll take you on my scooter.
Well, let's go!
- Good evening. I mean goodbye!
- Good evening.
That infernal cinema!
Always disturbing us!
My poor little house...
My poor little house,
where did you go?
Give me four slaps!
Give them to me
and you'll feel better. Hurry!
What are you waiting for, Spartaco?
This crazy wife of mine!
Don't worry about the house.
Don't you worry, I'll see to it.
I'll pay for everything.
Even if I have to kill myself working.
Even if I have to get all of Rome
to come down with diabetes!
Don't worry, Spartaco. Don't worry.
- Can you hear him?
- Who?
Burt Lancaster... What a nice man!
Maddalena, now I'll beat you for real!
Can't you even take a joke?
Quiet, don't talk,
don't wake the child up!
Don't wake the child up!