DA ZUI XIA
Yang Chi-Ching, Chen Hung-Lieh,
Han Ying-Chieh, Shum Lo, Lin Chien-Chuan,
Ku Feng, Lee Wan-Chung
Wong Chung, Kwan Ying-Chi, Wong Shing, Lan Wei-Lieh,
Fung Ngai, Simon Yuen Siu-Tin, Hao Li-Jen
Out of the way! Out of the way!
What do you want?
Here's a letter for Master Zhang.
A letter? You wait here!
Sir!
What's the matter?
Someone ahead is blocking our way.
He has a petition, sir.
To Master Zhang. We the 5 deadly
tigers, top in the martial arts world.
Return our leader and you will live.
- Jade-face Tiger.
Our Master would like to talk to you.
Move aside! Go!
Master Zhang,
out of the sedan chair, please.
TEMPLE LIBRARY
Speak! Where's our boss?
What will the authorities do to our boss?
Speak!
Executed by the law.
Stop beating him.
Please write an appeal to the Governor.
If he's willing to release our boss,
then we'll let you go.
This way, no one loses.
No, I'm here to enforce
the laws of the country.
As for the Governor,
he is the supreme commander of these lands.
How could he be intimidated by bandits?
You can do anything you want with me!
Zhang Buqing, the Governor is your father.
He don't believe one second,
to safeguard his position,
he'll sacrifice his own son.
My father will uphold the law at any cost.
He will never exchange hostages
with bandits like you.
I beg that you to have a
change of heart and let me go immediately.
I won't take any offense
for what has happened.
About to be dead yet he still talks boldly.
No. 3, write a letter to his father.
Tell him to send someone
to exchange for his son.
If there's no reply after 5 days,
we'll kill his son
then burn down his quarters.
If he sends soldiers coming,
then that'll be bad news.
With his son in our hands here...
he wouldn't even dare!
Sending soldiers won't scare us. But it's
that Golden Swallow that we're afraid of.
Who is this Golden Swallow?
Last time we were captured,
he killed a few of our men.
Good, I'd like to meet him.
Waiter!
What will you have?
Tiger-bone wine.
Tiger-bone wine?
Do you have any?
Sorry, we don't.
Then some white wine and two dishes.
Yes, sir.
Good work.
We've tailed him all the way.
He's alone.
What's your problem?
That's my order!
Let me go!
- What are you looking at?!
What now?
Waiter, where's my wine?
Coming!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Brother, where do you make your riches?
I work as an official for the Governor.
Oh, an official?
My apologies for not knowing.
What official business brings you here?
To speak with you.
You... know me?
You are Smiling Tiger Zu Gan.
How observant!
You wrote this letter?
You can say I wrote it.
But as for the details,
better to discuss it with you.
I'm all ears.
We have news of Master Zhang.
That's why I'm here.
That's great then!
Our boss is locked in
the Governor's prison.
Please tell the Governor
to look pass the laws
and clear him of his death sentence.
Then we'll let Master Zhang go immediately.
Otherwise what?
Otherwise, we'll be saying goodbye
to two lives then.
Then your boss's crime
will become more serious.
Never mind that.
Will you release our boss or not?
He committed crimes and must face justice!
Don't you forget.
Zhang Buqing is the Governor's son.
And he's my own brother.
In this case, we'll end our little chat.
You think it over, alright?
How did it go?
Dammit! Get rid of him?
White Face Wolf, get me a jug of wine.
- Alright!
Catch!
What bad luck. You got drunk without wine.
Your turn to treat me.
Alright, drinks are on me.
Catch!
Don't just stand there.
I'll get you a bench, alright?
Watch me.
If you guys won't treat,
then I'll treat then.
I'll chip in also.
Little brother, you should return my money.
Take it!
Golden Swallow!
Golden Swallow is the name.
A toast to you.
You flatter me.
I knew you're a sensible man.
No more playing games.
Let's talk business then.
We'll listen to you.
I'm here to free Master Zhang
and take you with me.
I'll ask the Governor
to lighten the sentence.
Did you hear that?
That's fine! If you can take us then.
Then you won't cooperate?!
Yes, we will,
but first you must meet our No. 2.
I will when I'm good and ready to.
You must go right now!
My hand! My hand!
Open the door! Look down! Look down!
Open the door!
My goodness!
What do you want?!
Get some wine.
Later, later. Come back later.
My losing my senses. Can't wait.
Alright, alright. Go then.
- Yes, yes.
Stay out of our way. Don't move around.
Waiter, my bill.
- Yes, sir.
Innkeeper, what's going on?
Never mind about it.
Just hurry and go.
It's so rainy! How can I go?
I'll pay this man's bill.
He won't be leaving today.
Excuse me, sir. May...
Out of my way!
Quite a narrow escape just now.
Zhang whatever you are,
you've gone too far!
That's right! Third Master...
Out of my way!
Innkeeper.
Give me a clean room.
I won't be leaving.
Sir, no need for this much money.
Buy me two horses with the rest.
I came here alone but won't leave alone.
Find me a guide.
Fine! Today I lose to you.
But we'll wait and see about later!
Smiling Tiger, go back and reconsider.
In five days, I want to hear your answer.
I'm telling you one more time.
If you don't handover
our boss in five days,
I will take Zhang Buqing's life!
That's right, Third Master!
Show him no mercy!
Shut up!
It sounds like this kid thinks he's smart.
Wait till he comes here.
He'll learn the hard way.
Eat, eat, eat.
Gentlemen.
If you keep Mr. Zhang tide up in here
and should something happen,
I'll be in trouble.
Hey! You shut your mouth!
Yes, yes.
But I am in charge of this temple.
All of you staying here like this...
It's not like we broke in!
I know, I know.
However Abbot Liao Kong isn't here.
When will he return?
He said he went to search for someone
and will be back in 3 to 5 days.
I beg of you, sirs,
before he returns,
please don't create any trouble.
If the Governor...
Stop!
Hold on! It's only a junior monk.
Are you all right?
Sir, help stop the bleeding, quick please!
It's no use.
The dart is poisoned.
Sir, forgive me. Give me the antidote.
- Alright.
You go and end his misery.
You all... you all are too cruel!
How many times have I told you?
Don't let your disciples near here!
Next time if it happens again,
it'll be your turn!
No. 5.
A lot can happen in one night.
Take two men to the inn
and bring that kid back.
Yes, sir.
Who's there?
It's me.
What do you want?
I couldn't sleep.
Let's have a drink together, alright?
You're drunk!
No. I'm not.
- Get out!
The roof is leaking where I'm sleeping.
If you don't mind then I'll...
You!
- I'll go! I'll go!
I'll go! But I saw you fighting today!
Don't you do anything to me.
If you do, I'll die here!
You get out!
Alright, alright, I'll go, I'll go.
Get out!
I get nothing for being nice.
Return my things to me.
Coming!
Rats! It's empty!
Retreat!
This green bamboo staff.
Long and slender.
With it, traveling all over,
from north to south.
The wind blows, rain pours,
the sun shining up high.
I live begging door-to-door, living on end.
Living on end. On the end.
The way of the world is full of sin.
High post and salary, all I dream not for.
Fame and wealth, they will pass.
Nothing brings me pleasure
like wine.
Oh wonderful wine, wonderful wine.
May it be gin or may it be sherry.
A cup in hand, it's all too merry.
The world is full of sorrowful things.
Yet in my beloved wine gourd,
good memories, it carries.
Good memories, the wine gourd carries.
Sorry for not singing well, sirs.
Please forgive us.
All that singing
yet not enough money for a drink.
I'm not drinking today.
Are there any meat buns today to eat today?
You and your eating!
I want some meat buns too.
Alright, we'll definitely have meat buns.
Waiter!
What would you like eat, drunkard?
Give us some meat and 10 buns.
Uncle, don't pay any attention to him.
We'll just have some
corn bread and pickles.
And some white wine.
Forget the wine.
It's alright, I'll keep a tab.
Uncle, we haven't paid our debt.
Just forget it.
Such a pitiful boy.
Sir.
My deepest appreciation for your
generous help. I must say thank you.
Thank me for what?
It's enough. It'll be enough.
Last night if you hadn't led me out,
I fear those bandits would've
succeeded in their plot.
I was drunk last night.
Let's have some noodles, alright?
- Alright!
Sir, may I have the honor
to know your name?
I'm called Drunken Cat.
Yeah, let's have noodles!
Do you have any money?
Money? Yes, I do.
Buy me a drink, alright?
- Certainly.
No no! I won't just
take your money for nothing.
I'll sing for you in return.
If my singing's good,
you give me more.
If my singing's bad,
you give me less, alright?
Sit down, please.
Bandits come, on high mountains from.
The Inspector-General, kidnapped and done.
Rob at day, night they stay.
This message is worth a heavy sum.
- This message is worth a heavy sum.
Gold or green, for that, I do not dream.
The fight against the bandits must be won.
The Governor's office is panic-stricken
and on the run.
A lone swallow flies... over the hill.
A lone swallow flies over the hill.
We're so hungry!
- Sir.
Be quiet!
Sir!
Thank the young master.
Thank you, young master!
You guys go over there.
You wait! I'll order then!
Sir, since you are aware of my matters,
I'd like to seek your advice.
What are you talking about?
- I'm asking.. Sir!
Innkeeper, this should pay off my bill.
Put the rest on the account.
You've really met a benefactor today.
I sure have!
Sir, Master Zhang is nowhere to be found.
And this has made me worried.
Sir, you must know,
where they've hidden Master Zhang.
You surely talk a lot for someone so young!
I'm only asking you to
show me the way, sir.
My way is the bad way.
A dot and a stroke long.
A stroke to south of Nanyang.
A slant and two crosses.
The moon and the sun.
A dot and a stroke long.
A stroke to south of Nanyang.
A slant and two crosses.
The moon and the sun.
Temple
Thank you.
Miss, best be careful inside the temple.
Oh? Why?
Nothing, nothing.
Miss, why pray to a
clay Goddess of Mercy Pusa
when you can pray to a living god like me
and make all your wishes come true.
Miss, don't need to be in such a hurry.
A little later, I have made
dining preparations, just you and I alone.
We don't know each other.
Please show some respect!
Golden Swallow, do you know me?
Good! You're the ones
I've been looking for!
Stupid girl! You were lucky last time
and lost to you.
We'll see if you can escape today!
Good. Everyone's here!
Stop! These are sacred Buddhist grounds.
How would Miss dare to spill blood here?
I have a mission
to capture criminals on the run.
Miss, better to make friends
than make enemies.
Better that we go back, share a drink
and have a nice chat?
You stay out of it!
Or you'll suffer the same fate as them.
Then what about your brother's life?
Who are you?!
Pity with such beautiful eyes as yours,
can't even recognize me.
You're Jade-face Tiger?!
How about having that chat?
I've long known that
you're a devil in disguise!
However, if you're willing to repent
and return with me,
I can plead with the Governor
to give you a lighter sentence.
She truly overrates her charm!
To simply grant us a lighter sentence
when we see the Governor.
To receive Miss's kindness,
I'm truly grateful.
Don't you forget -
your brother is in my hands.
Sooner or later,
you'll be in my hands as well.
Your mouth is full of bullshit!
On the verge of death has left you mad.
Come on!
You really want to fight.
Then let's have a fight then.
Out of the way!
Alright. I'll undress and fight with you.
After her!
She can't run too far.
Search the woods and bring her back.
That way!
What are you doing out of bed?
Should lay down.
You...
Hey! What's the matter?
You... why did you try to trap me?
What evil intentions do you habor?
What happened to calling me "sir"?
Perhaps I deserve it. So we're square now.
You're reckless. Why should I respect you?
You... you're a hopeless drunk!
But this drunk was right, wasn't he?
I told you to observe more
and fight less
but you didn't listen!
You went ahead and used
mediocre kung-fu in a fight with them?
Learned your lesson now?
You know what's wrong with you?
Unreasonable and get mad too easily.
Let me examine your wound.
Didn't ask you to care!
That poisonous dart
should have made her collapse
in half an hour's time.
We've searched the woods
and nearby villages many times.
USELESS IDIOTS!
How can an entire group of men
get beaten to a pulp by a little girl?!
When word gets out,
YOU'LL BE LAUGHING STOCKS!
If I get hold of that stupid girl, I'll...
You shut your trap!
No. 5.
Bring some men to find her.
If you don't find her,
DON'T COME BACK!!
It's bad.
Miss Zhang, there's no other way.
I must suck the poison out with my mouth.
It's all right now.
Drunken Cat, aren't you the lucky one!
Gentlemen, please have a seat inside.
Thank you!
Trying to take advantage me?
And you call yourselves men!
Now wait a minute!
We only came to see
about your condition in goodwill.
How can you think so poorly of us?
Sorry for the trouble men
and carry the miss on over.
What are you up to?!
- Don't talk so much!
No. 5, she hasn't recovered yet.
Please let her go.
You think you have a say here?
Get out of the way!
Dammit!
Still here?!
Take a rest inside.
You guys must be tired of living.
What do you want to see me for?
I brought some corpses for you.
Corpses?
You take a look.
Who ordered you to bring them here?
How about a drink?
- Speak up!
What's the matter? It's a hot day
and I pushed them for miles.
The hell with you!
Where did you find these bodies?
In the woods.
How did you know to bring them here?
I knew your No. 5.
What else did you see in the woods?
I saw a young girl fighting with No. 5.
A young girl?
What else did you see?
Talk!
I was passing through the woods
when I saw her fighting these men.
The young girl
really let them have it like this
and sent these men to heaven.
At that moment,
scared the living daylights out of me!
She did it herself?
The girl asked me
to deliver the bodies to you.
Said you'd reward me
at least five taels of silver.
I never thought...
Wait.
I'll give you the five taels of silver.
What else did she say?
Thanks. She said...
She said something about,
the dart's poison wasn't strong.
It's fine so don't you worry.
What else did she say?
She said... she said...
her name's something Swallow.
Oh, that's right! That's right!
She also spoke of a business deal.
Told me to bring back any message
you have for her.
Let's go, let's go.
You can remove the corpses yourself.
Drunken Cat, take me to see her.
She said she wouldn't meet me
till tomorrow morning.
In what place?
We didn't set a place.
She said she'd find me.
No. 3, keep an eye on him.
And clear those beggars out.
I still haven't eaten yet!
- Shut your mouth!
Get him some food.
Fetch the monk
to prepare a funeral for No. 5.
Hey, Third Master.
The girl mentioned a business deal.
What's it all about?
Stick to drinking
and mind your own business.
Sure, sure.
Third Master, Abbot Liao Kong is here.
Second Master wants you to greet him.
Keep an eye on him.
He sleeps after eating
and don't let him run off.
I understand.
Don't move!
It's hot. Can I borrow a fan?
I said don't move, don't move!
I won't. I won't.
Just now, Third Master
went to see an Abbott Liao Kong.
Who is he?
Nobody you know. Don't ask.
Yes, sir.
Where was No. 5 wounded?
In the heart.
Doesn't look like a dagger wound though.
Open the coffin and examine the corpses.
That little girl couldn't have done this.
Then the Abbot means to say that...
Did the beggar carry a bamboo pole
with a gourd fixed to its top?
Yes, sir.
It's truly when one
will search high and low
and only to find it when
one least expects to.
Then you know him?
I went out to find him.
Why would an Abbot look for a beggar?
He's my brother.
Had I known,
I wouldn't have been so rude.
He doesn't look like someone
with kung-fu skills.
His kung-fu has already
reached the highest limits.
However... compared to me,
he still has a way to go.
Then what's his name?
He's called Fan Dabei.
From morning to night,
he likes to drink and pretend to be stupid.
Some boring people call him
the "Drunken Hero".
These five were killed by him.
So he's one of us
and it's all a misunderstanding?
Misunderstanding?
When our master was on his deathbed,
he stole his treasured heirloom,
the bamboo pole
and established a new sect.
The elders have ordered me
to kill this treacherous infidel
and recover the pole.
Where is he?
In the rear hall.
Seize him.
What happened?
Where's the beggar?
He escaped!
He won't get far!
Sir, you should have something to eat.
You've been uneasy
since you returned from the temple.
I know there's something
certainly bothering you.
You've helped me so much
and I've also troubled you.
My matters from now on,
I'll figure it out myself.
You will fail.
Come here.
Lift up that stone.
No, the big one.
Take that stone and throw it at my head.
Come on, hit me in the end.
Do it again.
Fling it higher this time.
Are you all right?
My days are numbered.
What did you tell Jade-face Tiger
at the temple?
My Brother is Abbot
Liao Kong of the temple.
Then you can entreat
him to save my brother.
Even though we had the same master,
we are enemies.
He wanted to inherit this bamboo pole
and become the sect's successor
so he secretly killed our master.
The next time we meet,
only one of us will live.
Then how come he's with Jade-face Tiger?
He hid his evil ways from master.
The Abbot and Jade-Face Tiger
are birds of a feather.
In this case, why don't we arrest him,
and rid of them for the people?
His kung-fu skills are unsurpassed.
I'm afraid I'm not his match.
He once did me an act of kindness.
Ten years ago,
I was a homeless orphan on the streets.
It was he who brought me
to master and learn the arts.
Because of this kindness,
I've always avoided him.
I see.
No need to be concerned about my problems.
I'll find a way then.
Miss Zhang.
Wait.
The only way now is
to bring the Governor's prisoner back
and exchange for your brother.
I can't underhand secret
dealings with them.
My father would never agree.
Fortunately, he's still unaware of
what's going on here.
Just bring the prisoner back...
- But...
I'll think of a way for him
to get arrested again.
If I deliver your leader,
you'll give Master Zhang to me.
What do you think?
Sir, since you're willing to help us,
then we'll do as you say.
Good!
Where shall we make the exchange?
At the southern slope.
What time would be suitable?
How about noon tomorrow?
Alright, it's a deal. Please.
This green bamboo staff,
long and slender.
With it, traveling all over,
from north to south.
The wind blows, rain pours,
the sun shining up high.
Brother.
Brother, you still recognize me?
We are fated to be together.
Can't run away from each other.
Haven't seen you in years.
You're still begging?
Better to be an honest beggar
than a devil in a monk's clothing.
I've worked hard for years
to wear this robe.
But dyed red with our master's blood.
Where's Master's bamboo pole?
Master's bamboo pole is sacred to our sect.
You have no right to ask for it!
I'm the eldest disciple in our sect.
Why cannot I ask for it?
I swore to uphold master's dying words
even though I'm not worthy of the sect.
36 branches fall under
the bamboo pole in our sect.
Should anyone in our sect
commit crime or evil
no matter what his rank is,
he will be punished.
And does that include me?
Master said,
the day you see the bamboo pole
would be the day you die.
So you mean to take my life?
To take your life is
to pay for master's life!
If master so ordered it on his life,
then what are you still waiting for?
I can't forget you once saved me.
You truly know how to break one's heart!
Enough of your idle chatter.
Give me the bamboo pole,
and I'll let you live.
Otherwise, we'll fight to the finish!
I can save your life
and I can take your life.
May brother grant me three days' grace.
So you can run away?!
Because I promised
to escort Master Zhang home.
You're on the verge of death
yet still meddle in others affairs.
May brother do me a favor.
So please back away from this matter.
Your affairs are of no concern to me!
Then after three days,
we will settle our score.
You couldn't escape even if you tried.
I'll wait three days.
Just go!
Brother!
Sir Fan, what's the meaning of this?
Sir Dan, you have the reputation of
a man of integrity.
How can you break your word?
I made a promise. There was no alternative.
Please try to understand.
Fan whatever you, I know what you're up to!
Sir Fan, we won't say anything this time.
But if our paths cross again,
you better stay out of our way.
Alright, I won't forget your benevolence.
I'll never interfere in your affairs again.
Good.
- But!
Till we meet again.
Let's go.
Thank you.
Protect the sedan chair.
Are you all right, brother?
Yes, I'm fine.
Tell them if they don't stop,
I'll kill you!
No. 2!
- Hold it!
Take some men and go on ahead.
I'll have a look up there.
Good!
Let's trap them all.
Go up the other side.
Be careful, don't hurt the boss.
We searched east and west
but can't find them! What to do?
Wait here. I'll find them.
Yes.
Attack!
Stop the prisoner's wagon!
Let's go!
After them!
Pursue them!
Where's the prisoner's wagon?
- It's headed for the hills.
Out of the way!
Abbot, grab her!
- Why are you still here?!
Right!
- Get out of the way!
You're so young.
Why must you be so murderous?
Who are you?
You don't need to know!
Where's that beggar?
You... you're Abbot Liao Kong?
Abbot, please keep out of this.
Better that I send you to heaven!
Sir!
Take the men out of here!
Brother, have you thought
about what I said?
Yes, brother, I have.
From this day forth,
you are expelled from the sect and exiled.
I will not seek revenge
for your past doings.
Fan Dabei, your death is your own doing!
Get out of here!
- Sir!
Fan Daibei, my life is in your hands.
Do as you please!
Don't try any of your tricks!
I am not beholden to you!
From now on, no one will never again
feel obligated to anyone!
Listen to me clearly!
Best that you go and hide
far in the mountains.
Change your name, mend your mistakes
and start afresh.
Otherwise,
the next time should we meet again,
my sword will not be so sympathetic!
What say you?!
Brother, I must take my leave.
That's what you think!
Thank you, master.