IMAGE AND SOUND RESTORATION
BY MOSFILM CINEMA CONCERN
BELARUSFILM and MOSFILM
Hey! Are you crazy?
What do you think you're doing?
Playing a game?
Who are you playing with?
Who?
Digging?
Digging again?
Well, go on digging, you little bastards!
Stinking brats!
Hiding, eh?
Can't hide from them now.
They'll find you no matter what.
No stone unturned.
Come out! You hear that?
Come out! Now!
Do you hear me?
"Sit tight. Stay out of sight.
Use your finger to clean your shite."
Think you've found your wretch?
I'm not simply some dumb clown.
Now I'm German, I won't back down!
Very well, then!
Better do as I say
or I'll see that you pay!
Gee up!
Holed up here? Hiding out. Gutless rat.
Pioneer brat.
Spineless, stinking scum.
You think it's funny?
I'll give you something to laugh about.
That's it! Now, you're done for.
Do as I say. Get used to it.
Back to work, you worthless dog!
BELORUSSIA, 1943
Come on!
Can't join the partisans without a gun.
Pull!
The dead don't give a damn.
"Gott mit uns."
Not a damn thing here! That's it.
Where do you think I got my gun?
Think I bought it?
I'm doing this for you.
I've got one already.
Hello!
Hello! Berlin?
Well? Too much for you?
Didn't I tell you?
COME AND SEE
Screenplay A. ADAMOVICH, E. KLIMOV
Direction - E. KLIMOV
Camera - A. RODIONOV
Production - V. PETROV
Music - O. YANCHENKO
Sound - V. MORS
Featuring:
A. KRAVCHENKO, O. MIRONOVA
I. LAUCEVICIUS, V. BAGDONAS
J. LUMISTE, V. LORENTS
K. RABETSKY, E. TILICHEEV
The score includes music by Mozart
My boy.
My son.
How will you ever look
your father in the eye?
What if he finds no one here?
Think of yourself, son.
Pity them, at least, if not me.
Son...
for the Lord's sake.
Have you no heart?
What do you want, Ma?
Everybody's going. I must go.
- Here.
- What is this?
Kill us.
Better kill us yourself
and be done with it.
Them too! All of us!
I won't let you go! I won't!
Mama! Mama!
Good day.
To be more exact, good morning.
So... where's the gun?
- Where's the gun?
- Just a minute.
Just a minute...
Oh, look at you.
Are they twins?
Identical.
From the same litter.
It's getting light.
- Time to begin.
- Not yet.
Once the cows are out, we'll begin.
- We need an audience.
- Take these...
to keep your feet warm.
- We'll keep him warm.
- Nothing to worry about.
Our camp is quite safe.
Just like a summer camp.
Would you like some milk, boys?
Have you got anything stronger?
If I had known...
I assure you, we seldom drink.
Only on holidays.
And at wakes.
We're disciplined.
Commander's in the regular army.
Kosach?
Yes, Kosach is strict.
If you get too close, he'll back away.
And chase you down if you don't stay.
- Remember Bobok?
- What Bobok?
That one-eared guy.
He fell asleep at his post.
- Kosach didn't even wake him.
- Well, so what?
Does it matter now?
Funny?
- Mama...
- Shh, quiet now.
Women here like to sleep in, eh?
Take a seat.
It's too risky to sit around.
Any moment they'll come,
and we'll be done for.
I once sat around. Now I can't sit at all.
A hunk of shrapnel the size of my fist.
Don't laugh. It hit me just here.
Where are the cows?
One shot and they'd wake up fast.
Oh, Lord.
Lead out the cows!
Right. Let's go.
Why are you taking him away?
Breathe deep, boy.
Lead them out, milked or not!
Where are you taking him?
Such a quiet, kind boy.
Never harmed anybody.
He's never done anything wrong.
Kind people, he's such a harmless boy!
- What's wrong with you!
- Hands off!
Let's see him off. Let's go.
Hold the bird. Don't move.
Go back!
Forward!
Step back.
Step aside, I said!
Yustin, our village elder. He's an idiot.
I don't understand.
Flyora, my son!
My little boy!
Good day.
Keep on going, boy.
You're skinning me alive!
What are you doing to me?
I'm still breathing!
Water, nurse...
Hello.
Keep moving.
- Good day.
- Hi.
Who's next? I'm after you!
This seat is taken.
Oh, shut up!
Move closer.
Look straight into the camera.
Yes, you!
What a face you have!
Just look at that face, comrades.
What a suit!
Come here.
You lie here.
Just so. Keep the suit on.
Like this.
No. Like this.
Bring in the cow!
EAT ME BEFORE THE GERMANS DO
Make room for her.
- We're wasting time. Get on with it!
- Keep calm.
Only one sheet left.
I'm using it for the third time.
So...
The chief is here.
Quiet. Don't move.
Look at the guy in the new suit.
Lying perfectly still.
Let's swap.
I took mine off a living soldier.
Here's our sergeant-major.
Will we get a copy?
Rise up, great country
Rise up for a fight to the death
Against the dark fascist forces
Against the cursed hordes
Let noble wrath
Boil over like a wave!
This is the peoples' war
A sacred war!
Who goes there?
Give the password.
The password!
- New recruit?
- Yes.
- Your name?
- Gaishun. Platoon 3.
- Why didn't you shoot?
- I recognized you, Commander.
If a person doesn't stop
or give the password, shoot!
- But I...
- Doesn't matter.
Take on extra duty.
Yes, sir.
- Where is he?
- Who? Password!
- Which way did he go?
- Give me the password!
Idiot.
That owl, again.
Go and sleep. We'll take over.
...In all conditions,
under the enemy's nose,
at risk of a Nazi attack, night and day,
they carry out their duty.
From June 22,
to this very day of the war...
And yesterday he sent me
Two very puzzling letters
He left them completely blank
As if to hint, "Need I say more?"
And who knows now what he meant to say?
Come here, Ivan.
I won't hide it from you.
This is a difficult time.
The older partisans here know
what a siege is.
Hitler is waging a total war against us.
A war to wipe us all out.
To the last man, we must hold
the positions we have been
ordered to defend.
It's a tough situation.
A changing situation too.
So look sharp!
You've each got a rifle
and a head on your shoulders.
As our commander in chief says,
"Just keep my head down?
Ha! I'm not that kind of man!"
I have always said
that a partisan doesn't ask
how many fascists we face.
He asks, "Where are they?"
And they are still here... on our land.
The duration of this war
depends on each and every one...
of us.
There won't be any cowards here.
Not one.
Hitler's greatest weapon is our fear.
He will turn you into slaves...
into insects... to be crushed!
But we'll make them tremble.
We'll be ruthless.
That's what they deserve.
Every one of us will be asked,
"What did you do here?"
Anybody injured?
Anybody unable to march?
Don't be shy.
We will leave men behind anyway
to set up a reserve camp.
-Nobody's injured. Everybody can march.
- But I want to say...
- What is it?
My boots are falling apart.
Take the new recruit's boots.
He'll stay behind.
Form ranks, four abreast!
Forward march!
Look lively, men!
Come on. You heard the commander.
Get down.
Keep in step!
Don't fall behind!
And what do they call you?
Flyora.
Is that your name?
It's Flyora. Flyora.
And you?
Rosie. Rosie with pockets full of posies.
Ever heard of me?
How did you come to be here?
Sent me to Germany, ended up here.
Kosach rescued you?
Hey, who did you come
all dressed up for then?
What do you mean?
Today, when we were lined up. Really, why?
Rosie?
My name is Glasha.
Glafira.
Got it, silly boy?
What do you mean?
And what about you, Flyora?
What are you doing here?
They took pity on the little boy.
They left you behind.
Kosach felt sorry for you.
- For me?
- Yes, he pitied you.
I dare anybody here to feel sorry for me.
Kosach feels pity. Sometimes.
But afterwards he has nightmares.
Kosach? Nightmares?
He will be killed.
I feel it.
It's all a lie!
You're lying!
Why don't you say something?
Why don't you see me?
I'm right here.
I exist.
Here I am.
It's you. You're not alive.
You don't hear the birds.
You're deaf.
Blind.
Here I am.
Here.
I want to love.
I want children.
Do you hear?
I would do anything...
anything for you.
Just say the word and I'll blow myself up.
No, don't.
Idiot! You're crazy!
I have... 60 cartridges,
a rifle and a hand grenade.
I came here to fight.
You think I'm some half-wit.
Stop talking about Kosach.
Have you lost your mind?
What is this?
What's with you?
You're just too good.
You're a real "flora."
- Hurt your feelings, kid?
- At it again?
Don't be angry.
Cut it out!
What's that?
Beavers.
Maybe I disturbed their dam.
Seems everyone is crying out today.
Look.
In the air already. Hanging over us.
- Want me to shoot him?
- Give me back the gun.
- Give it back!
- No way.
One... two... three...
Glasha...
Glasha!
Come on. Quickly!
Oh, God...
Glasha. Glasha!
My ma will be so glad.
When we're back, I'll hide you all.
I know just where to go.
You'll like my sisters.
Then we'll rejoin Kosach.
Wait here.
Mama!
They went away. Come in.
They're gone.
It's still warm.
Try some. My ma cooked it.
Go on.
I know where to find them. Let's go!
What an idiot!
Come on.
It's not far away.
Come on, let's go.
It's close. Come on!
They're here.
On the island.
They must be here!
Come on!
Glasha!
They're back there! They aren't here!
They're gone.
They're dead.
Dead! They're all dead!
They're here! Here!
They're here!
Glasha!
What happened?
His family was killed.
He dragged me into the bog.
He's deaf.
He's crazy.
Crazy! Deaf!
He dragged me into the bog.
They are all dead!
They are all dead! Dead!
Oh, Flyora! They killed your folks.
Didn't I warn you?
Didn't I tell you?
"Don't do this, don't dig."
They got us all.
Every single person...
They covered me with petrol.
I was burning.
I ran after them.
I begged them...
"Pray, kill me."
They laughed.
I told you, didn't I? "Don't dig."
Flyora!
- Well?
- Get rid of the nose.
He's got syphilis.
- He's feeble. Diseased.
- Impotent.
It was torn off in the First World War.
What would you do to him
if you caught him?
We caught a horse thief once.
We pulled off his pants
and sat him on an ant hill.
Should have sat him
on a hot frying pan so it stuck.
The women would know what to do to him.
- Should I give him ears?
- Go on.
Let him hear what folks say about him.
Your hair is so soft.
As soft as a child's.
Now he's ready.
- What do you say?
- Cover him in shit.
Ain't got enough. We are too poor.
- Make his tongue stick out.
- Give him a wart.
I know what I'm doing.
I've done this before.
- So, what do you think?
- He's ready!
Wait till you hear him roar. Let's go!
Scum.
Don't worry. You'll get it back
when we return from our mission.
He's no weakling. He's pretty strong.
Come along then. Earn your keep.
I know a storehouse nearby.
There'll be food. Get up.
Get up!
Dear boys, don't abandon us!
Come on, we're not
skipping out on alimony here!
What can we bring you this time?
- Place your orders.
- Some bread.
- Salt too.
- Milk, please, mister!
Potatoes.
Get bread this time, whatever it takes.
You didn't know that would happen.
You couldn't have.
Flyora, look at me.
Tell Flyora we'll be waiting for him.
No, it's my fault. Mine.
"Look how round I am, how bright I am.
Anybody could spot you fools,
a kilometer away."
Don't jinx us.
Faster. This isn't some damn picnic.
Why did I insist on carrying this?
What an idiot.
Well, did Hitler run off
with your storehouse?
Oh, your poor legs!
And nobody helping you...
Who could have known
they'd be there already?
We went for wool,
but we ended up being shorn.
"Serves you right, you imbeciles.
Thought you'd help yourselves?
Now you have nothing."
Why carry that lunatic around?
The Germans chased us
so they could take him away.
But for him, we would never have met.
You'd be stuck in Babruysk,
in your lamp-oil store.
And Gleb would have stayed
in his swampy Leningrad.
Hear about that man in Slutsk
who made home brew out of soap?
Why are you so happy?
A hunchback might say,
"Better bent double
than always in trouble."
- The incurable optimist, Rubezh.
- We'll have to cure you!
Why cry about it?
There's plenty who weep as it is.
For his ma, it must have been grim
to know she had a son like him.
Loadit
He's going to roar like thunder.
Hurry! Come on!
His belly's already fit to burst.
Don't tickle him.
He'll blow Europe to bits.
The old devil doesn't
seem like much, does he?
Let's go.
It'll be a show when he goes off!
Okay, let's go.
Couldn't you drop some tobacco
to wrap the paper round?
"Slam the Bolshevik Yids!
Make them pay for what they did."
Is that all?
It's not much.
Hey.
Yids!
Get up. March on.
Well? Let's try again?
What does Rubezh say?
"Listen to me and you'll be sorry."
Let's go.
Why not wait until dark?
And let folks starve while we wait here?
Keep moving.
The Germans need a clear road.
Goddamn it.
Come on, you.
Wrong way!
"Well, here I am. It's been a while.
Must be missing me.
I'll just fly by overhead
and drop a few presents.
Want a motorbike? With a Sidecar?
Long time since you drove one."
Get down!
They get drunk up there,
and we return the empties!
Stand still, mister. You can finish later.
Who... Who's that? Who's there?
- Be quiet. Who are you? Polizei?
- And who are you?
Button up. You'll catch cold.
- Is this Kamenka?
- No. It's Bagushovka.
The Germans came two days ago.
- Cowshed not locked?
- No.
Bring your cow and we'll set out.
Understand, old man? And no tricks.
Afterwards you can go back.
Do it quick and neat.
- Okay, okay.
- Okay, as you say.
So obedient. You sleeping, Flyora?
You need to oil those creaking hinges.
The Germans didn't shoot the dogs?
What a mess.
You're white, the cow's white.
We need some camouflage.
- I'll go get something.
- A rifle?
Try that trick of yours on someone else.
It won't work on us. Got it?
There's horse manure. Roll in it!
Good. What's your rank?
There are no ranks in the Home Defense.
Quick, let's go,
before your wife gets lonely.
Come on, you! Get going!
Stop looking round. You'll fall!
Lie down!
Now go back. Go.
Back home, understand?
Don't say a word.
Off you go, then.
Run. Or your wife will be angry.
- I wonder where he is now?
- He never saw us coming!
He had a fine pair of boots.
Box-calf leather.
Maybe he's looking for us,
to swap boots with me.
Good cow, sweet cow, hold still.
Hold still.
Good cow, hold on.
Come on, come on!
You could get drunk on this. What a life!
Uncle Rubezh. Uncle Rubezh...
Gee up! Get going.
- Go!
- Hey!
What are you doing?
What the hell are you doing?
I don't have time to talk to you.
Got an ax? I've got a cow to cut up.
You can't take my horse.
- Folks are dying of hunger.
- And we're not?
They're out there fighting
while you're sitting at home.
Keep sitting then.
Look at what they did.
- You see?
- Be quiet, boy.
Quiet!
Out of your mind?
Over here! Everything down here.
Hide the belt, the jacket... everything.
Quick!
Oh, my God...
- What's this place called?
- Perekhody.
- I know families from here.
- There are many. You're one now.
- Got it?
- Yes.
A young fella here drowned.
- You'll take his name.
- What is it?
You have a mother, sisters and brothers.
Seven of them.
Olga, Katya, Fedya and little Sonya.
Got it?
Your mother's name is Fekla.
Fekla Perekhod.
And your name is Zhenya. Got it?
Let's get out of here.
I INSULTED A GERMAN SOLDIER
THIS MORNING
- And where is my "father"?
- Father?
Say... You'll say he's missing.
Missing where?
Where? Well...
Damn. Better come with me.
You'll be my grandson Mitrofan. Got it?
Here are my kin -
my daughter-in-law Aksinya.
My sister and her children.
- Who is he?
- My son-in-law. He's Kazik, a bookkeeper.
My sister's children -
Lima, Raya, Zoya,
Vika, Veronica and Boris.
Get out. Park together.
Search the houses!
- We're here too.
- These are our neighbors.
Maria and her children -
Lusya, Frosya, Fenya and Ivan.
It's obvious.
They'll send more of us to Germany.
Who are they going to take? You?
Go inside. I'll handle this.
Keep a lookout.
Quiet now.
Do you speak German?
Me? Yes.
Do you also speak German?
- Thanks.
- Sit down, please.
You're very welcome.
Help yourself, sir.
What's this here?
Ah, a partisan!
There are partisans among them.
Drinking alone?
Pour me some!
Some schnapps.
People of the village of Perekhody!
Every inhabitant!
Listen carefully. Listen carefully.
Bring your children and your documents,
and gather in the square
at the designated location.
There will be a check
of the lists of families...
and of whether you have observed
the orders of the German State.
You must provide documentation
of farm produce deliveries.
There will be a routine inspection.
Do not remain inside your houses.
Or hide in the shed or the cellar,
on the roof or in the loft...
HITLER THE LIBERATOR
Run!
Save yourselves!
Where are you rushing to?
They'll kill everybody!
What are you staring at?
Stop staring, you rat!
I'll kill this one!
Take supplies with you for two days.
Bring your children.
Don't leave your children behind...
Come here, you brat.
Observe appropriate order and discipline.
Hurry! Hurry!
Germany is a civilized country.
All those going to Germany
should take along
a toothbrush, toothpaste,
shoe polish, soap,
and a towel
for every member of the family.
No fruit or vegetables are allowed
in order to contain the risk
of contamination in Europe.
As a medical troop NCO,
I declare that the cause of death
was the seven bullets
in the upper half of the chest.
Anyone who refuses to carry out
the orders of the German command
can expect the same fate.
All in order, Herr Major!
We're ready, sir.
Will you give the signal?
Are we inviting them in, or what?
Will there be a signal?
Oh, goddamn it!
Well, come on in.
We caught a Yid!
Got you! Thought you could get away, eh?
Jew bastard! Force him in!
Let me go! Bastards! I'm with you!
Quiet!
I declare the meeting open.
Who wants the floor?
My little boy!
Fascists!
What can you see?
Quiet!
Leave the kids and you're free.
Come out here.
Through the window.
Leave the kids behind.
Quickly, please.
Beasts! Beasts!
Let us go!
Did you hear?
He took over command of the division.
Great news, don't you think?
Let me go!
Pretty as a picture!
I'll kill you!
To the right.
Look! It's empty!
We ought to get rid of you bureaucrats!
Intellectuals!
More petrol. Let it soak through.
Fire!
Round up the cattle!
You there!
Come on! March!
Here, you bastard!
Petro, I found honey. Want some?
We'll leave you out here for breeding.
Go on, granny, produce lots of kids!
Yuma...
To bear children...
Let me through!
Stand back!
Stop!
What are you thinking? These...
You want to kill them?
Just simply kill them, and that's it?
It was the 88. They lit the fire. Not us.
- Sit still!
- They forced us to do it.
Scum! My children were in that fire!
Rank?
Unit?
Major Walter Stein of the SD,
15th Einsatzkommando.
The fuhrer gave the orders.
He's an elderly man and unwell.
He never hurt anybody.
He, his family, his father
have always upheld certain principles.
He bore no hard feelings
against your people...
He... He's never killed anybody.
He's never even hurt a fly.
Anybody here can confirm that.
He's certain they will.
He really is an ill, elderly man.
I just want peace now.
That's what he says.
He wants to care for his family.
He has many grandsons... your age.
This is war. No one is to blame.
That's what the German said.
You dog! You swine!
Typical German!
Asshole!
It was him.
He's the one who said,
"Leave the kids and you're free to go."
If they left the kids, they could go.
He's a fascist, a butcher.
He has no heart.
Yes, I'm the one who said,
"Without the kids, you can leave.
But the kids must stay."
Translate.
Because all the trouble starts with kids.
Your nation doesn't deserve to exist.
Some nations have no right to a future.
Listen.
I want everybody to listen, all of you.
Inferior races spread
the communist contagion.
Your nation doesn't deserve to exist.
We will fulfill this objective.
If not today, then tomorrow.
I didn't say that. He did.
We're not Germans!
Never again. Forgive us! We won't.
We're not Germans! We're not Germans!
Germans or not!
Have you forgotten what they did?
They're cannibals!
Shooting them isn't enough.
We're not Germans!
Then what are you, you bastard?
They forced us to do it.
We're not Germans!
Kill the fascist rats!
Kill them! Kill them!
You can do it, seeing as
you're right there among them.
Give it here! Give it to me!
Brothers! I'm on your side, brothers!
I'm one of you. I'm on your side.
Matches, comrades.
Comrades! Matches!
- Make way!
- That's enough! Enough!
Recruit!
HITLER THE LIBERATOR
Come, boy, we're leaving.
628 BELORUSSIAN VILLAGES
WERE BURNT TO THE GROUND
WITH ALL THEIR INHABITANTS
Come on!
THE END
Restored by: Igor BOGDASAROV
Viktor TAMAZIN
Alexey SENKOVSKY
Irina AGAFONOVA
Producer of restoration:
Karen SHAKHNAZAROV
© Mosfilm Cinema Concern, 2017