At the end of the last century,
on northern Europe's coasts,
lived men who feared
neither God nor the law.
They lured ships towards the rocks
where they were smashed to pieces.
These men then plundered the wrecks.
They were called wreckers.
The captain is their leader.
He is a brute.
His strength gives him
power over his henchmen.
He has committed so many crimes
that he's become almost mad.
Villagers say he is haunted
by the ghosts of his victims.
His madness makes him
dangerous and unpredictable.
Le Bosco, cursed by all navies,
the bad seed of any crew.
He landed there dead-drunk from a foreign
ship one night with his bag on his shoulder.
He follows the captain,
but this sailor,
never without his knife,
dislikes taking orders.
He bides his time like a vulture.
He is false and crafty.
Paul.
He, too, is a former sailor.
He suffers the captain's orders,
but grovels to Le Bosco.
He will be on the winner's side.
He is cruel and cowardly and has
a worse temper than the others.
He is the strongest, because each of
the three thinks he is on his side.
Tina, the wrecker.
The angel of the accursed.
Wild and perverted.
This cruel animal is always
ready to snap up the
innocent who come too close
to her she-wolf jaws.
She will show no pity.
It's a game for her to plunder wrecks
and kill survivors.
More than one dead man,
his throat cut,
takes with him the image of her
magnificently shameless naked body.
Help.
Help us!
Help!
Something wrong, Captain?
Leave me alone.
Look!
Hey, clear off, you drunk.
- Get lost.
Now what's the matter?
Have you gone mad?
There. A moment ago.
Didn't you see anything?
Here? I'm the only one here.
Are you afraid of ghosts, Captain?
I thought I saw something.
It's nothing. It's nothing.
It's nothing.
Sounds like he saw a ghost.
Maybe there was a ghost.
Just for him?
Yes. Just for him.
Help!
Bring us some drinks.
A ship has been wrecked on the rocks.
A ship? When?
Only a few hours ago.
How do you know?
Were you there?
To cause a shipwreck?
O" Purpose?
Of course it was on purpose.
Shut up!
You know very well there
are no wreckers anymore.
Who knows?
The tide may have
washed up the bodies.
I asked you if you were there.
What about you? Were you there?
- Me? No.
I was here!
So, why have you got
blood on your shirt?
You're crazy.
There's nothing there.
God curse the wreckers!
The sun is rising over the shore!
A sad and gray day!
The tide is out!
I can see two small figures.
They are getting up!
They start walking.
- That's enough!
Shut up!
They are still weak.
They support each other
and stagger forward.
Be warned! If they discover the
secret of this cursed village,
nothing will stop
them from taking revenge.
Let the ghosts come.
I'm not afraid of anyone.
Let them come and see the captain!
God or devil.
Come and have your throats slit.
Come on, then.
Come on, ghosts.
Come on, phantoms. Come on, demons.
Come back and see the captain.
I challenge you.
You died tonight.
I will kill you again!
We have to shut him up or
he'll tell them everything.
He's drunk.
I saw your heads smashed
against the rocks!
What the hell is going on'?
I don't want any trouble here.
It's morning. We're closing now.
Finish your drinks and go.
- It happened one windy night ~
- It happened one stormy night ~
- Crashed on the rocks, a stray ship ~
- Leaves two beautiful innocent girls ~
- A celebration of beauty ~
- Some accursed men were wandering about ~
- Full of wine and alcohol! ~
- They plundered the wrecks at night ~
- Innocence destroyed by rape ~
- A celebration of beauty ~
I should've killed that bastard.
What are you going on about, Louise?
It's only a song, Bosco.
A story about wreckers.
There are no wreckers nowadays.
It's just a song.
As long as it's just a song.
I don't want to hear your damn song!
It makes me sick! Bloody hell!
There's a curse on this village.
The demons are free.
What did you see? Tell me!
There were two ghosts.
They were staggering about.
Pale and covered in blood,
with crazed eyes.
There were two women.
- Where did you see them?
Over there, by the ship cemetery,
near the haunted ruins.
Come with me, you two. Hurry.
The devil has been set free!
God help us.
He has been imprisoned in
the ruins for centuries.
Now he is free.
Misfortune is upon us!
I can sense that he's still in the ruins!
Maybe now his long wait will be over.
They're here.
We must drive them out.
They won't come out alive!
What if they are ghosts?
- There are no ghosts.
That's enough. If they are alive,
they must be exhausted.
We'll easily catch them.
We must try to capture them alive.
Why?
- I want to finish them off.
Over here. I can see them.
Give me that.
Stupid bitches.
They've gone.
- They're in one of the wrecks.
We can't search all the wrecks.
Did you see anything, Bosco?
I haven't seen them.
They must still be here.
We must wait until daybreak.
We'll find them eventually.
I know how to drive them out.
Paul, bring your lamp.
Come here, all of you.
Le Bosco has an idea.
You come down too!
Hurry up.
- Let's go.
What are you going to do?
- I'm going to burn them.
Give me your lantern.
Stay here and tell me if you see them.
Bosco!
Tina?
Bosco! Captain!
Come on, we have to find Tina!
There they are!
They're heading for the ruins.
The cursed ruins.
Let me go!
- No.
You mustn't go there.
Look! They're over here!
Captain! Bosco!
They're over here with me.
Come back.
Don't go over there!
Stop! Don't go over there!
Come back!
Tina!
- Follow me.
Come on.
Tina!
- Don't go there!
Let go of me.
Let me go.
Leave me. Don't touch me!
Leave me alone.
I want to get them.
I want to kill them!
For God's sake, let me kill them!
Let go of me.
Don't go there!
Come back here. It's high tide.
You'll be caught in the seaweed.
You'll be killed. You crazy?
Don't go to the ruins. Come back!
They were in the marshes.
They are wounded.
Let me take care of them.
I'll look after them.
All right.
You knew the risk you were
taking bringing them here.
It's too late now.
Look after them so they can rest.
I'll speak to them afterwards.
I know you are there!
You saw them!
They can set you free if they wish.
But you're the one who has to wait!
They have to come of their own free will.
I've seen how pure they are.
How innocent they are!
I won't intervene,
but I beg you to spare them!
So be it.
Let destiny be fulfilled!
Don't you want to play,
Madame Louise?
Last night ended in tragedy.
What happened?
- There was a shipwreck.
And the captain thought
he saw the ghosts.
Le Bosco was also acting strangely.
And at dawn
- What happened at dawn?
They were in the marshes near
the haunted ruins at dawn.
And now
...there they are.
How do you know all of this?
I just know.
What if they're still alive?
For God's sake, shut up!
The captain has shut himself in his house.
He's afraid.
You're all crazy!
You know what's hidden
away in the ruins.
If they made it there
Two girls. Wounded and exhausted!
I think they must have drowned!
I hope so.
If they are hiding in the
ruins and they free
Don't mention his name!
We don't really know what's
hiding in the ruins.
Yeah.
But
if they manage to get that far
What will happen?
All I know is that no one has been there
for at least a century.
Shut up! You don't know
what you're talking about.
Do you understand?
Help! Stop it!
That's enough from you.
Come here with me instead.
With you?
All right.
We're not allowed to talk about
what's down there, in the ruins.
You know it. We are doomed
when he will be set free.
They can no longer speak!
We have to help them.
You're the only one who can help them.
I will save you.
I will give you back peace.
You needn't be afraid of us.
The ludicrous costume helps keep
the villagers away from the ruins.
As for me,
I'm the keeper of this tomb.
Try to tell me how I can assist you.
Revenge.
You are free to take your revenge.
The one supposed to be in this tomb
is trapped somewhere in these ruins.
He can only be liberated by
innocent hands, by victims of evil.
Tonight he will call you.
He knows you are here.
It's up to you whether or not
you want to set him free.
Only he can give you the means
to take revenge and find peace again.
But he's a black angel, a
demon wearing a habit.
If you set him free, you will
also release his dark forces
which have been locked
away for a century now.
The entity imprisoned in these
ruins can be very dangerous.
Right now he's possessed.
Evil lives within him.
The one behind the door is two-faced!
You can find peace there, or death.
It's up to you now.
You can expect him to call you tonight.
Stop fidgeting.
I know they will return.
Until I touch their corpses
with my own hands,
I won't believe they are dead!
Where do you expect them to be?
They're dead, I tell you.
It's as if I can see them.
I can feel them watching me..
Their spirit is searching
my head to find me.
Their hatred won't leave me!
I know they will return.
They can think of nothing else but me.
They're looking for me in
order to take their revenge.
Dead or alive,
I know they will be back.
I saw them in the tavern!
They were covered in blood.
They were watching me.
You don't care, do you?
You weren't there.
You don't believe in ghosts!
You're nothing but a trollop.
No.
No, you can't make me forget them.
They will kill us!
They came back from the dead
to tear us apart.
Good for them if they are alive!
I will kill them like
wicked creatures.
I want to strangle them.
I want to feel their bones
breaking between my fingers.
I want to overpower them,
drink their blood and wounds.
I'll smash them with my heels
and you'll be there to see it.
There will be nothing left of them.
Nothing!
I tell you I saw them,
as clear as I see you now.
The captain's gone completely mad.
He should be locked up.
He's becoming dangerous.
Everyone seems to know about it.
News travels fast around here.
People are staying indoors.
There's no way they can know.
- We've said too much.
There's that sailor who saw the
girls in the ship cemetery.
What about Louise, did she see anything?
Louise? Yes, maybe.
She has second sight.
Tragedy is upon the village.
Tonight he will be free!
Who do you mean?
The one who hides in the ruins.
I can see him!
He is waiting
He is calling.
I can see you!
Open this door,
so the devil's fury may be
unleashed on this cursed land.
Let the death of us all be
the price of your life.
Unleash all the forces
of evil upon us!
I will give you the power.
Go on.
That's it!
Now open the door.
Good.
He is free!
You came when I called to you.
I am free and you will sacrifice
your bodies to me. Come.
You say nothing,
but you speak to me with your minds.
I will give you all my power, so
that you may carry out your revenge.
You may go.
Now I am within you.
You have all of my
power until sunrise.
Once the daylight comes, you will
be just as weak as you were before.
Go now.
You only have a few hours
to carry out your revenge.
They're alive.
I saw them. Poor things.
So, Louise, who did you see?
- Tell us what you know.
I didn't see anyone.
But I do know everything
that happened.
That's the way I am.
I know things I have never seen!
I've heard about your
gift of second sight.
Are they alive?
They're alive.
- Where are they?
Right here.
No, Bosco!
- Calm down!
Captain, stop him!
So there you are, my children.
You are very much as I imagined.
Yes, I've seen you before.
Here, in my head.
What's your name?
You don't want to tell me!
What about you? How old are you?
I see. You're not very talkative!
Are you hungry?
Thirsty?
Good that's a start!
But I would like to hear
the sound of your voice.
Maybe you aren't able to speak!
Is that it? Are you mute?
Poor wretches, they are mute!
Monique, bring them some grenadine.
I understand.
You have to leave.
Let me look at you a while longer.
I'm afraid I may never see you again.
Listen, I would never betray you.
You can always think of me as a friend!
Are you afraid of those girls?
Cowards. Coward.
You're running away.
You're terrified.
I'm not afraid of them. I'm going.
I'll bring you back their heads.
Where are they?
I'm not afraid. I want them.
They just left for the hills.
Would you shut your mouth, bitch.
Who asked you?
Help me.
Beware,
the sailors were here.
They were completely drunk.
Save yourselves.
There is nothing I can do.
I have no more power left.
Yes, I can save them by myself
if you wait here until daybreak.
You will keep them alive until then!
My powers will leave
you and return to me.
I will save them.
Yes, I know what will happen.
You will be left powerless
against your enemies.
You will be quite defenseless.
But they will live thanks to you.
That's good.
It's nearly dawn.
Leave as soon as it's light.
Try to save yourselves.
They will live!
Your revenge escapes you.
In this crazy world
the only thing that might possibly
be left for you is generosity.
Do they have to die?
- In a short while.
I would like to save them.
They gave us their lives.
Can't you help them?
Nothing can save them now.
No, I cannot leave the ruins.
But their revenge will be carried out.
The four pirates are condemned.
They will perish.
We will go to meet them!
You will be too late.
That doesn't matter.
We've finally got you.
You will die here!
You little she-devils!
No magic can save you this time.
Stupid whores!
Take advantage of them again!
Tear it!
More. Go on!
Tear'.
Trash.
Bitch.
Here I go, slut.
Hit the sluts!
Blood! Oh, yes!
It's gonna hurt.
I'm gonna I'm gonna
Hurts, doesn't it?
Arching
You liked it?
Stop it. Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Are you insane?
What have I done?
They're going to drown.
No!
They're innocent.
Innocent.