Wang Chen-Kang, you're strong.
It's a pity your teacher isn't here.
The wrong must he avenged.
Double Phoenix Basking.
Get away!
- 0k.
Father....!
are you doing
Stop quarrelling!
Why are you laughing?
Continue practising!
Somebody kicks wrongly!
Get into ranks!
Our boss is not here.
Find him, but not us.
Don't come!
I can fight!
Stop, otherwise, I'll act
Don't come here!
You move, then I strike!
Stop, or I strike!
I come to learn kung fu.
I'll tell you something!
Snake four pieces, hanging eight!
Drunk fist nine pieces!
South North Drunk Fist 15 pieces
80 per cent discount.
Laughing Fist is costly
What do you learn?
I Learn everything.
Little chap, deposit money!
I have no money!
You waste my feelings!
Give money, otherwise...!
Get away!
What's the matter?
Someone applies!
- Apply?
What can we do?
Abilities?
Stork Stroke.
Real kung fu.
Leopa rd stroke.
Tiger stroke.
Snake stroke.
Dragon stroke.
Really something!
Is it solid?
Fatty, feel the bottom.
Feeling bottom?
Let you show off!
Go q u ickly!
Come and try yourself!
Me alright...!
I try!
What's wrong!
Dragon, Snake, Tiger, Leopard, Stork!
Not bad, I'll try again!
Fake?
Beat!
You'll suffer!
That fellow again!
Him again!
You can pretend!
You must suffer.
You must taste my "Misleading Lock".
Strike out!
Boss!
Boss, please sit down!
what's tha matter?
Teacher!
This fellow pretends!
To be assisant teacher!
Is it so?
- Yes.
I'm serious to learn
One should be patient!
Good talk, Fatty!
We'll be advertisement.
Teacher, this fellow wants to learn kung fu,
but he's poor fellow.
0h...! Penniless?
Without money won't do!
Still you're penniless.
I'll pay by installements!
Skinny!
- Teacher!
Payements by installements in future.
By installements?
We can increase the interest!
How'll you pay?
I don't have cash deposit.
We'll lose a bit for you.
You'll help in the kitchen.
Learn from the Skinny & Fatty teachers.
Thank you, Boss.
Teacher, we're losing much!
We can withhold salary!
You can pick a suitable place!
What're you up to?
You want to boil me?
I'm hot-tempered.
Luckily, I retreat fast.
Damned old chap!
Show you something.
Hit the melon.
You've no luck.
The youth is formidable.
You're much behind me.
You can see.
Older, chillies are hotter.
It doesn't enough?
Th is is rotten .
It's not recommended to throw it.
Come.
Even the capital is lost.
I won't play with you anymore.
I'll pay the medical expense.
I won't be cheated by you.
Stay.
Clean up before leaving.
You!
Come back.
Aren't you here for a living.
Yes...
You'll do heavy work here.
You're bullying me.
Much heavy work here.
It's not fair to me!.
Do you want justice?
Two buns here.
One with red prune, the other without.
First one should do heavy work.
The other does no work.
I'll try my luck.
It's exciting.
Look, just look.
Which one you take.
Let you choose first.
I want this one.
Wait I choose this.
Now can you compare with me.
Open....!
I needn't open.
You'll do household work.
You'll do all chopping work.
Sister's clothes!
The devil robs pearls.
Still won't die!
Deaf fellow, where're you?
Big-headed Ghost Ringing Bell.
Blind chap, get away.
Deaf fellow, let me get up.
This is Fatal Blow.
Crumbling Ghost Close Up.
Stop.
Tiger's Tall Feet.
Don't fight! Damned deaf fellow.
Hea rt Ta rget Foot.
Lazy Dragon Rolling Foot.
- Don't fight.
One Word Divides Gold.
Relax the muscles.
Spreading Lotus Foot.
No use to hold my foot.
Stop fighting.
I'm deaf, sorry.
Deaf fellow, you want to kill me?
How can you resist Chang!
Invincible Blind Fist Deaf Foot.
One, Two, Th ree.
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, J.Q.K.
K, Q, J, I
10, J, Q, K, I.
Stop.
You'II be in the time.
The time is right.
Do the practising.
Thank you teacher.
You couldn't be the first.
Stand behind, quick.
You want to be the first!
Practise.
3: 4: 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, J, Q, K.
Golden cock stand alone.
Stand firmly. Stand firmly.
It's you again!
Fatty.
Sister's clothes are short....!
Hold carefully.
Don't need your help.
You're not so kind.
Trouble uncle, ah?
You...!
Let it be.
Where's my snuff pot?
My snuff pot is stolen.
I'll fix you up.
Still I can't find Chang.
How did you become crippled?
Little devil!
Father...
My eyes.
My ears...
I must teach you.
Kick all kung fu schools in town.
Chang Tien-hsiang, you can't hide!
Who's the boss, come out!
From where are you?
Very boastful.
What's the matter, find me.
I'll frighten you to death.
What's the matter?
Teacher...they came for you
I'll tackle.
Teacher, your chap is here.
Tear off!
The boss has come.
Deaf and blind join forces.
One is deaf, the other's blind!
It's easy work.
No good boxer in whole school!
There's still me.
Half-filled tub!
I'll fix him up.
Deaf fellow, looks a tiger.
It's 250 after all.
Get away.
There's no Eagle's Claws.
You really have something.
Can't tackle two cripples.
Aren't you stupid?
You're boasting.
Almost ruined.
Cut off your fingers if you dare.
You couldn't be beaten like this.
Look.
Old chap, be faster.
The fast worker survives.
The slow one will starve.
Make the deaf fellow blind.
Also make the blind fellow deaf.
You talk big only.
It's useless talking to you.
Wait.
Let us have a nice talk.
Don't be so hot-tempered
I have nearly died.
Why I came to such a school!
Whole school can't beat two cripples.
Isn't it disgusting.
When did he become so cute?
Talking about me?
Clear off.
Teacher, drink tea.
- What are you doing?
Drink tea, please.
- Drinking tea?
Any pepper powder?
No, special spice.
Spice!
Teacher, sit down.
Sit down.
Teacher, cigarette.
It looks evil.
Uncle is experienced
I won't be fooled by you.
I'm sincere.
Teacher, accept me as pupil.
You better prepare rice.
Help mending the pan.
Asking me to do heavy work.
It's trifle only.
Sorry, not my business.
Why's the pan leaking.
You better suffer slowly.
This is a gloomy place....!
Just promise to teach me kung fu.
I won't teach, then what?
What can you do to me.
Let me out quickly.
- No teaching, is it so?
Let me free soon.
What?
it's urine.
Let me out, I'll teach....
Is it really?
It's really.
Gentleman's words are binding.
Certainly....!
Teach you....!
Teacher.
Teacher, are you alright?
- Sure.
When I'll learn kung fu?
We're only cooks.
You're only talking?
You want to learn kung fu?
Lift.
Heave.
Chop.
Fry.
knead, then you'll be fine.
Old man, again you pester me.
I'll tell you a story
A young cowboy used his hands
After 20 years, a cow escaped
He killed the cow by slapping!
How terrible are his palms
You think I'm a child.
You're ignorant
I've been playing this spade 30 years.
Just watch.
You just practice
if you want to achieve it.
Would be very boring.
You think it's not exciting enough!
Show you something exciting.
What excitement?
Stand firmly.
Teacher, be careful.
You get off.
Go that way.
Go.
That direction.
Alright.
Run, quickly.
Run that way, run...
Good, good.
Take rest.
Such lifting, will maim you!
The you'll suffer long.
Teacher, don't you have a wife?
No, I have not.
Why didn't you marry?
Who loves an old man?
We're bachelors.
Have you feeled with women?
You are childish!
You must have!
Before yes, but not now.
Really?
Teacher when is your birthday?
May 15th.
May 15th?
You're 30 years my senior!
Your birthday will come soon.
Why you ask this?
You'll know them.
I'll go pack off.
I want real stuffs
It's raining, purchase stuffs quickly.
Three dollars.
No, it's five dollars.
How did you give $3?
Yesterday, you said $3.
You want to rob?
I only have $3.
Stand firmy.
Who's robbing? Come back.
Teacher, today is May 15, your birthday.
Today's dishes are poor.
The dishes will be spoiled by wind!
Only such dishes could be bought.
I don't know any wind.
You've slept the whole day.
I hope the storm arrive now.
Dare you cheat me.
Give us rotten food.
Light punishment for first offence.
Next time I'll be severe.
Put it here.
Let the joss-sticks burn out.
Then you can come down.
Somebody will have bad luck!
Again you want to outwit me.
He gives me little
Want to be Iasy!
Quick.
The back will be broken.
What's the meaning.
Steps are unsteady, back is weak.
U p practice slowly.
Good.
Am I very heavy?
Teacher, I can't do it!
You must do it.
I will fall and hurt you too!
Teacher, why shaved off the beard?
I've been unlucky recently.
Yesterday I consulted fortune-teller
He asked me to shave off my beard.
Did it actually happen?
Don't commit nuisance here!
I'll take Ah Wen to lunch.
You're esteemed persons
Let us congratulate the magistrate.
Don't stand on ceremony, please.
Teacher, I've nothing to eat.
Of course, you can look only.
I do thankless job always.
Young people shouldn't mind this.
There's a foreign friend here.
I'll introduce him....
How was it?
Shevchenko.
Going outdoors without pants!
Come...bottoms up.
He's a Russian boxing champ.
He admores our Chinese Kung Fu.
I want to confront Chinese Kung Fu.
I think chinese kung fu is for show only.
The various strokes could be fun
Our Russian kung fu means business
Russian kung fu is fast.
Powerful too.
Fists are used.
Hows that?
Three percent effort is sufficient.
It's really fantastic.
I haven't made any effort.
Sit down.
I'm catching mosquitoes.
Don't be afraid.
My heaven.
These strokes are wounderfull.
Four Taels Uproot 1000 Catties.
Beat you to unconsciousness
Eagle's Claws.
You're progressing very fast.
I'll teach you more unique boxing.
You still have more unique strokes?
Of course.
You came so long ago.
How's that nobody told you.
Nobody.
Tomorrow I'll teach you.
Let me be comfortable.
Can't enter such place.
Teacher, I haven't taken launch.
I've forgotten .
Here's $2.
Take it.
Don't let mistress know it.
I don't know you.
Good dog stays at home.
Do you want to die?
Where did you learn kung fu?
Will you talk?
How long can you bear?
I can't bear anymore.
Teacher!
Let alone distant lands.
You're not safe in your mum's wombl.
It's not confusing.
Eagle's Claws? I'll burn you!
Who's your teacher?
You better talk!
Neck can't resist knide.
Speak, or not?
Crawl here.
Crawl.
Come....!
Come....Take....
It's here.
It's with me, come here.
Go there.
That side.
Go over.
You are delighted?
Take it.
Your life is in my hands.
Next time I'll take back.
Go!
Why you let him go.
Must bait him.
Watch him.
You seek trouble.
They forced me to talk.
I Never talked. I will present this jade
to you afterwards.
Let it be broken
He is the son of Chen-Kang
I'll teach him "Eagle's Claws".
For revenging his father.
Is this "Five Plums Stick?"
This will be ridiculed by others
Take it over.
I'll show you how.
Lea rn steadily.
Teacher, I can't bear anymore.
Heavy rain.
Fatty, receive the guests.
Has come.
Please come in.
Come in.
Please!
Son, please come.
I have been kind to you.
I'll kill this animal.
No animal is allowed on the table.
Do you need it anymore?
No, I don't.
Re move it.
Keep calm.
I'll help you.
Not so bad.
You should have come earlier.
Now I've come.
Please sit down.
Dog is not allowed here.
Son, you go down.
Keep order, no confusion.
I'm disciplined and educated.
Then you're very learned.
- You are flattering me.
Have you read a poem?
Such thing is trifling.
Please.
Answer me.
Who cares for me in trouble?
Then?
Recite from the end.
I can also sing reversely.
For whom do I suffer?
Admit "I'm a dog!".
Don't laugh.
Act! Kill!
Get away soon .
Damned him.
Stop fighting.
You're still not running.
Sit down.
Young boss, are you alright.
Young boss!
You're pestering the nobleman.
You're too conceited.
The restaurant is smashed.
Clean it before leaving.
Want us to sweep the floor?
I've been leading an easy life.
Dishes are ready
The buns are coming.
Eat it.
Bosqu
Why not yet start sweeping?
Want us to do the sweeping?
Do the sweeping!
I don't need to sweep anymore.
Keep the tables and chairs in order.
Thank you.
Take it, put it down.
One more there!
Go q u ickly.
Up, turn!
Son, it's me!
This is "Dog Bites Dog!"
Wait for me!
Bill not paid yet.
$14....so much tips!
You all, please.
Son, let us go.
Watch this!
Alright, yesterday you hit my boss.
Now fight!
Ahh, you wanna fight, right?
You are a damn dog.
You wish to be lazy?
No!.
No? I saw you changing dress.
I want to go outdoors.
Before learning kung fu?
Who says I'm lacking in kung fu!
I've learned Eagle's Claws, Five Plums Style...
I've defeated others.
Don't be happy before being skilled.
I'll spar with you
Teacher, be careful.
Teacher, what strokes are these?
This is "Shadow Eagle's Claws".
What is "Shadow"?
Image af animal and imagination
Attack foe's strong point.
Can attack and retreat.
Very fast.
I taught your father "Shadow Fist"
Was licked by Liaotung Phoenix Eyes Fist.
Ma Fei-jen is skilled Liaotung Phoenix Eyes Fist.
His Double Phoenix Basking is terrible.
Your father was killed by him.
Shadow Eagle's Claws are elusive.
To oppose Liaotung Phoenix Eyes.
Heart is the general.
Eyes are pioneers.
Fists are like arrows.
Body is like the bent bow.
Be natural in movements.
Strong wrists and powerful fingers.
Fast tough kicks.
Stand firmly.
Avoid foe's strong points.
Eagle's Claws tactics.
Practise Shadow Fist.
Shadow Eagle's Claws.
Ah Wen, teacher is going.
Teacher is used to loneliness
You may now go outside.
Teacher, nothing for you
I am like your father
Remember how your father died.
Teacher, teacher....
Boss, you'll go there?
Going back to the village.
Why?
Misfortune never comes single.
I must hurry, it's raining.
What has happened?
My father's school has been robbed.
Robbed by whom?
By the blind fellow and the deaf chap!
I'll help you to get it back.
Higher, still higher.
Right, lower still.
I said "higher still".
Damned Fatty, can't you see!
Yes!
Fatty.
Getting rich?
Good morning sir.
How are you?
Ah Wen, how are you?
Lucky in lottery?
You're not noble-minded
We're not right to refuse helping him!
It's such a world.
Our poor Boss is kicked out
It's fair.
We work from 9 to 5.
How comfortable.
Or, accompany him to the village.
It's fighting without mercy!
You talk correctly.
Ah Wen, you're clever.
I help the boss to get back school.
His idea is to rob.
Good, up.
My back!
Stork? Left peck, right peck.
Peck.
I peck hand, head.
Peck you rself.
Peckuu
Damned blind chap.
Peck.... I peck.
I peck.
Peck
Peck the head.
Peck, I peck....
Peck your buttocks.
Our new boss isn't here!
Where's he?
He's in the teashop.
What has happened?
Haven't seen you a long time!
Not so!
Not here, it's there!
Deaf joining hands with blind.
Your Cock's Claws are weak.
You're teacher can't instruct you.
Finish him off, right
These Cock's Claws are tasteful.
Joining hands....?
Are you mad? Not these strokes.
Not me.
Deaf joining hands with blind.
My eyes.
My ears.
My eyes
Ma Fei-jen.
I've said before.
I would kill you next time.
Is this stick too small?
It is big enough?
The longer, the better.
Shorter is more terrible.
Older is gentler.
Left, right, front, back.
Left, right, up, down, foot, head
This is "Red" and "Green".
Five Plums Stick!
Attack heart and lungs.
How, not sufficient strength?
We suffer.
Shadow Eagle's Claws to fight Liaotung Phoenix Eyes.
Taste my Liaotung Phoenix Eyes.
Heart is "General", eyes are "Pioneers", fist are "Guard"
Steps a re steady.
Double Phoenix Basking.
Chinese dub tracks synchronized by INFAMOUS
Subtitles by ha14 (ADC-2018)
Please don't upload this dvd to other trackers.