(Latin) You have preserved,
protected and saved the three holy children...
(Latin) Speak!
(Latin) Speak! Why have you come here?!
(Latin) You summoned me!
Protect us from the power
and the curses of the devil!
I'm from the Liberation Order.
Marco!
Sister Giunia!
Father!
How dare you show up here?
You brash little bitch!
Let's wash you up first.
Is all that holy water?
A wretch who hasn't even been ordained!
Mom's spank hurts the most, doesn't it?
You damned mass of cursed energy!
That won't come out.
Not until the exorcism is over.
Prepare a Franciscan bell, please.
You vile filth!
Ring it, and resume the prayer.
Who performs an exorcism so incompetently?!
Coward, taking over a child's body...
(Latin) Expel yourself.
Protect us from the rulers of the dark world
and from the evil spirits under the heavens.
Come to the aid of the human soul,
redeemed at great cost from Satan's oppression.
Lord, have mercy.
(Exorcism: A Roman Catholic ritual)
(to free someone from evil spirits)
Lift up Your mighty hand
and extend Your powerful arm,
(Nun: A woman who vows chastity, purity,
and obedience, living celibately in a convent)
(Priest:An intermediary between)
send forth an angel of peace and strength,
(God and humans, officiating at Mass and rites)
to visit and protect Your servant,
made in Your image.
Let all malice and wickedness,
(Possessed: A person
with an evil spirit residing within)
brought by envious
and destructive forces, be overthrown.
Grant that Your servant,
safeguarded by Your mercy,
(The Rosicrucianism: An exorcism group)
may raise their voice
(created by the Vatican to combat evil spirits)
in gratitude and proclaim:
(12 Manifestations: Types of evil spirits)
(classified by the Rosicrucianism)
The Lord is my shepherd;
there is nothing I shall fear.
Lord of peace, Master of all creation,
and God of my ancestors.
Look upon Your servant
and deliver them from every evil
and every threat that comes from the enemy.
Protect Your image
from all harm and danger.
Through the intercessions of the most holy,
and the ever-virgin Mary,
the radiant archangels,
and all Your saints, we pray to You.
We pray in the name of
Amen.
the radiant archangels and all your saints.
You will die.
The most wretched death among humans.
You'll burn in pain,
crying and cursing your God as you die.
The blood of all the demons slain by your hands
will echo in your womb like a drum.
Let's end this, what's your name?
(Latin) My subordinates,
whom you cast into hell,
(Latin) asked me to tell you
that you will never see spring again!
What a load of shit.
Father! Father!
It went into hiding again.
DARK NUNS
Not at all.
He doesn't seem like
a patient like that at all.
Thank you for graciously sharing the room.
We'll move him to a private room
as soon as one is available.
There's no need.
Even if he's possessed or whatever,
this hospital is under God's protection.
Father Paolo is the
new attending for Patient Choi Hee-joon.
A physician who denies possession...
Michela, what do you think?
Does possession really not exist?
There's a saying: the existence
of evil proves the existence of good.
It's the result of a combination
of dissociative disorders
and borderline personality disorder.
With a supportive environment, regular therapy,
and medication,
it's a condition that can fully recover.
We already have enough similar clinical cases.
Wow.
You really are Father Paolo's protégé.
Alright, very well.
Is she human?
She spoke like an Al.
She felt so cold.
You've even performed a Buddhist rite?
I've heard of a renowned monk in Busan...
I just thought we should try everything...
Mrs. Choi.
A series of events beyond human understanding
can occur at times.
If you flip a coin ten times
and it comes up heads every time?
It'd be an astonishing coincidence.
But imagine that instead of coin flips,
unfortunate events
are happening to our loved ones.
Weak humans seek answers
in the occult, superstition,
or in the baseless doctrines of charlatans.
God tests us in these ways.
Your faith in Him.
(Psychoanalysis and Treatment of Possession)
What your son needs is,
psychiatric counseling
and proper medication-that's all.
But Father Andrea said...
and the nun from Liberation Order...
A nun?
An unordained nun
performed an exorcism on the child?
We must hurry.
Father Kim in Rome must be contacted.
If not him, at least Father Choi.
Personally, I'm not entirely against exorcisms,
but everything has its procedures.
A nun, though...
Father Andrea called to request my help.
And you personally
approved the exorcism that day.
I'm not denying it, but...
the situation right now...
Even the Seoul Archdiocese
is expressing disapproval.
You're infuriating.
Easy!
Sister Giunia!
Why don't you wait at the convent for now?
If you keep dodging like this,
you won't be able to handle it later.
Sister Giunia.
Ignoring a confirmed possession
is also a form of murder.
Father Kim taught her his way.
But they say her prayers are pretty effective.
She's still just a nun...
What will you do back in your hometown?
I'll teach some English to the folks there.
These are Hee-joon's.
He attempted suicide?
He probably thought
everything would end if he died.
How could the boy know
that dying doesn't get rid of the devil?
The chief spirit inside that child...
it's not just some
minor ghost or wandering soul.
Did the boy draw these?
Yes.
There was just one other case
very similar to this child.
You know, the unofficial one.
All the records were destroyed.
Devils that deny God and commit heinous
acts using human bodies,
that one is definitely
of the 12 Manifestations.
You haven't been
getting regular checkups, have you?
Just tell me.
Haven't you...
noticed anything unusual with your uterus?
The cancer is rapidly
spreading to surrounding areas.
Doctor.
Yes, Sister.
Am I dying?
Sister!
Your next appointment--
I need to meet with Father Paolo.
Exorcism is a cultural practice
shaped by the needs of its era.
It has been long since degenerated.
Those who believe they
possess spiritual powers and can confront evil
call themselves "Light Workers."
I heard about your nickname too:
"Dark Nun."
I'd like to discuss possession,
not get a lecture, Father.
Mystics who believe they're special
often possess egos far stronger than average.
That intense ego, bordering on obsession,
can sometimes create
illusions that people think are miracles.
I'm not well-educated, so this is hard for me.
Hee-joon created these illusions
in response to bullying and ostracism.
Possession isn't real.
- Yes, ma'am...
- Hello?
Mrs. Choi?
Call it a devil or an illusion,
whatever you want,
what matters is saving the child.
He's in tremendous pain.
Rituals won't save him,
only medical treatment will.
Without extensive medical records,
getting exorcism approval is impossible.
He's had all possible psychiatric treatment.
It is unfortunate that he came to me so late,
but my treatment starts now.
Delays could put him in more danger.
A rushed exorcism could endanger the child too.
That's already happened, hasn't it?
- Do you even know what day it is today?
- Yes, ma'am...
- Will you ever pay me back?
- Of course!
If you keep this up,
we can settle this legally!
Please, just give me
until the end of this month.
I'm working to get another loan...
Same old story! Are you sure this time?
Yes, yes, of course, ma'am.
Fucking ignorant bitch!
You killed off your hubby,
it's a matter of time for your son.
Sister.
There are lines that should not be crossed.
Have you heard of the 12 Manifestations?
Sister Giunia!
Either whore yourself,
or sell your organs, bitch!
I took pity on you because of your crazy son!
You and Hee-joon are fundamentally the same.
God is with neither of you.
He exists solely in heaven.
Let me make it official
once again, Sister Giunia.
So long as he's under my care,
exorcism will not be approved easily.
You should start by learning respect
for the church and its teachings.
Sister Michela!
I'm sorry, Father.
Patient Choi Hee-joon has...
...jumped off the roof.
And the boy?
He's been sedated.
He may be at risk
of self-harm when he wakes up,
ensure the staff takes shifts monitoring him.
Yes, Father.
You impure spirit, in the name
of Lord Jesus Christ, I command you:
depart from here at once.
And never return again.
You shall no longer trouble us.
You have no place
in this sinner's body, depart now.
Let's go together.
Sorry?
I'll drive you to Mrs. Choi's funeral.
I have a hearing impairment.
It's congenital, but only in my right ear.
Without an earphone,
it's hard to enjoy phone calls or music.
But when it comes to evil spirits,
I can hear even their whispers.
Some claim to see spirits,
feel chills or warmth,
or sense them intuitively.
They call that having "spiritual sight."
What do you mean...
What about you? Do you see or hear spirits?
I know you're one of us.
You're spiritually gifted.
Those who reject the path
of shamanism decide to become nuns instead.
Did a shaman tell you that working
in a hospital could make up for it?
You're being very rude!
Before the funeral ends,
the exorcism must be performed.
The mother's death
can distract Father Paolo for a while.
Why are you so invested in this?
Because he'll die if we leave him alone.
I can't do it alone.
You're Father Paolo's protégé.
What exactly do you want me to do?
At least with you, he won't be suspicious.
Father Paolo always said...
that the possession doesn't exist.
Moron.
What?
Did I ask you to perform the exorcism?
Just help me smuggle the boy out.
Go over this and think about it.
Shit...
Who does she think she is?
Demon!
Say your name!
I am...
your stepfather, your mother's enemy,
the root of your faith, despicable fool!
Do not be swayed by the demon's tongue!
Marco, snap out of it!
(Psychoanalysis and Treatment of Possession)
The Hanged Man.
Don't you think
he could free himself and escape?
Su-young, you can break free too.
You like drawings, don't you?
Keep them.
But don't let the nuns catch you.
Especially not Father Paolo.
Who is it?
Do you know what people call kids like us?
"Cursed."
A cursed child born of a human and a demon.
Who is it?
Had a nightmare?
What could this crying sound be?
A goat for you too?
Must be.
Did you think it over?
Why won't you tell me where we're going?
To Juan in Incheon.
Hyo-won Altar.
What?
Hyo-won used to be
a nun in the same Order as me,
she's a highly skilled
and experienced shaman.
A shaman?
Are you insane?
To most people, you, me,
and shamans are all lunatics.
You're unbelievable.
Is there anything a nun like you wouldn't do?
If it helps with the exorcism.
W-w-which name is the reservation under?
The nun tunic doesn't suit this place.
There are plenty of eyes here.
Was she really a nun before?
Did you take in a child of the spirit?
He's a temple orphan, his mom was a shaman,
so I took him in, but he's spiritually dull.
He's not mute, but stutters badly.
His fortune-telling isn't great either.
What about that girl over there?
She's struggling with her identity.
Let's have a smoke first.
Cake.
H-h-his n-n-name.
(Rice Cake)
Birth chart confirms it,
I see a hint of a snake,
but also a dragon prince
from the Underwater Palace.
A fallen spirit...
I think you're right, a demon.
Even if we exorcise it successfully,
his family's guardian spirits
will end up inhabiting him instead.
There's no other way.
He's bound to be a shaman,
just like the Cursed.
"Cursed"?
A child conceived
during the mother's possession.
He's bound to be a shaman.
That might be better than dying...
He wasn't born to be a shaman,
but forced to become one.
Who are you to judge
and decide things so freely?
You're right.
We acted too hastily.
If one came from water,
we'll handle it with water.
Should we contact Master Dam-eon?
We're running out of time.
The brat has quite a pretty face.
Dress him in ceremonial robes
and he'll shine in the ritual.
Away, away, evil energy!
Suri, suri, masuri!
Sung-ae.
Why?
Do nuns get free health checkups too?
Why? Do you see the Grim Reaper near me?
Go get one, you idiot.
I took you for a greedy shaman,
but you've still got the gift.
It's been fading for a while now.
I bow in reverence
to the complete and exalted one.
May the sacredness
be illuminated and fulfilled.
Let's start the ritual!
Will you save this child kneeling before you?
Yes, don't worry.
My poor, sick child,
I'll soothe your restless ancestors and banish
the spirits that invaded you,
so you can live in peace!
Onward!
The waters of the East and West Seas,
the South and North Seas!
Are you the Dragon King of the Four Seas?
The Seven Stars
Dragon King reigns in the air!
Stop it already... stop!
The Mountain God and Dragon King!
It's hurts, Sister!
Flowing Dragon King, Rising Dragon King,
- On the black earth, where are the people,
- My Lord, my God.
my people are no longer mine.
Today, I will clear the fog
in this child's mind,
and bring him peace and clarity!
You stupid nun!
Do you think you can cast us out?
No! Hee-joon!
He'll just sleep for the time being.
But not for long.
Leave him to Father Paolo.
If he stays in the hospital,
others will be in danger.
Playing hero, are you?
What's your justification
for being so fixated on exorcism?
Do you need justification to save lives?
As you know, I can't help anymore.
I'm truly disappointed in you.
Where exactly did you take Hee-joon?
I thought he should at least
see his mother's last moments.
Are you a funeral director?
I'm sorry, Father.
We're clergy, yes.
But you and I are also medical professionals!
Don't tell me you met that nun.
It's practically a cult founded by Father Kim.
I know you drew these back in the day too.
Be honest with me.
Do you think Hee-joon is like you?
Are you...
seeing visions again?
Of course not.
Michela.
Hee-joon can be saved.
I'll do it, no matter what.
Yes, Father.
You're the proof of it.
Sister Michela.
I'm going to Chungju to be with my son.
Is that right?
Thank you for everything.
Park Myung-ja...
Patient Park Myung-ja,
time of death, 10:15 a.m.
The midday temperature reaches 42°C.
Enduring the heat and ash
is no easy task for the bats.
Some find sanctuary
under the inner leaves of palm trees,
but others must search for shade elsewhere.
This sometimes causes fights.
Exhausted by thirst and territorial disputes,
the bats can move to nearby areas
where water remains abundant.
H-help... Help me...
Father Paolo...
he took Hee-joon to the cloistered monastery...
Monastery?
He wanted to try
treating him with the monks there.
The situation there must be bad.
Is that where you're from?
Over 15 years ago.
It was a prayer center back then.
Father Paolo!
Michela...
Where is the child?
Possession doesn't exist,
but you've barricaded this door tightly.
You came back with two masses of cursed energy?
Did you think I'd be your guinea pig like her?
You thought a bigger cross
would solve everything?
Did you meet your friend on the way here?
You cunning fool!
She says hello.
She asked me how you two are doing.
Michela.
Hee-joon can be saved.
I'll do it, no matter what.
You're the proof of it.
You have glorified your honor
by my non-existence.
Soon, you'll lose that
petty name of yours that you fear most.
And your nephew
will die fleeing from the military,
shot by mistake, his head blown apart.
Your beloved sister
will hang herself the next day!
Like that bitch.
And you'll go mad, just like your mother did!
Father Paolo!
Father!
Please, get a grip!
Father Paolo!
Father, snap out of it!
Father...
Father, please!
Father!
With even one drop of Christ's blood,
we believe the whole world can be saved.
Is this child's body so precious?
Sister Giunia!
You despicable bastard!
Exploiting the child's body--
It's okay, it's okay.
Sister...
Kill me...
Please, kill me...
Don't give up, Hee-joon.
Let's not give up.
No... I can't do this anymore.
I just want to go to my mom.
No, I'm not giving up on you.
We can do this together.
Just hang on a little longer, please, Hee-joon.
I want to live.
I want to live...
Is this a non-smoking area?
Maybe this worked like
a talisman and saved his life.
Why do you fight so hard?
A monster...
Like a monster.
You're a monster, and so am I...
Perhaps God knows
why we were born as such monsters.
I came this far...
I fled and survived everything...
Just face it head-on.
What's the key?
The key to completing the exorcism.
Confession.
The monster's true name.
I'm Sung-ae, Kang Sung-ae.
The Major Arcana card 5, the Hierophant.
The Hierophant is seen with two priests.
Each card has dozens of keywords,
but Hierophant is often drawn
when the situation is constrained.
Constrained situations?
Yes.
The original meaning
of this card isn't strictly the Hierophant-
it symbolizes one
who has experienced the divine.
This deck is from the Golden Dawn.
Monks from the Middle Ages
who studied mysticism within the church.
Like the Rosicrucianism.
Take a look.
If you see here-
when the Knight of Evil appears,
the Emperor is already dead.
But the Hierophant
is standing against it, very much alive.
The Knight of Evil...
The Emperor dies, and the one
who experienced divinity stands up to it?
You're quite the expert.
Also,
what's under the Hierophant
is called Saint Peter's Keys.
Card 4, the Emperor...
Card 5, the Hierophant...
Then what's Card 6?
Card 6 is the Lovers.
Six represents union and completion.
Sister! Where are we going now?
The Hierophant, the two men receiving baptism,
which means, we need a third.
You don't mean the shaman, right?
Do you know any exorcist priests nearby?
No way, tell me I'm wrong.
Hail Mary
full of grace
the Lord is with thee.
Weren't you going
to teach English to the locals?
People often get sick
when their lifestyle suddenly changes.
Just stick to what Father Kim taught you.
What more can you want from a coward like me?
You said the
12 Manifestations take animal forms.
A serpent that symbolizes Satan,
a goat for the sacrificial lamb-
Maybe those aren't demons after all.
Whether it's God or a demon,
never trust the manifestations
that non-human beings take.
Giunia!
Because those manifestations are just clues.
You taught me that.
You're far too rude to ever be...
a proper clergywoman.
Thank you for your guidance.
Father Andrea.
Granted the power and mission
by God to crush the head of Satan,
O great Queen of Heaven, Lady of Angels,
humbly I implore you to send
the heavenly army at your command
to drive the demons into hell,
fight them across the earth,
subdue their insolence,
and ultimately cast them into hell.
Amen.
Father Kim and Father Choi
cannot be here to perform the rite.
I deeply regret this point.
They are currently
occupied with other missions,
and I am unable to disclose
further details due to confidentiality.
Both Father Kim and the Rosicrucianism
believe that the entity possessing
the boy is one of the 12 Manifestations.
This is Father Kim's message.
"The 12 Manifestations will continue to appear.
Save the boy by any means possible."
Can't you join us for the exorcism?
You're a priest
from the Rosicrucianism, aren't you?
I'm sorry, but I am not allowed.
As a servant of God,
I must follow our Lord's plans.
We need Saint Peter's Keys
to seal the 12 Manifestations,
as well as the Gospel of Peter.
Those are sacred objects.
Moreover, they are kept by the Vatican.
These entities are capable
of possessing even priests.
I will help you in every way I can.
Kim, you son of a bitch...
Isn't he your mentor?
You may curse me later.
Okay...
On the first day
of the lunar month, at the hour of Zi,
that is when all forces converge to destroy it.
You must finish
before the hour transition to Chou.
Otherwise, its power will grow even stronger.
Should we call Master Dam-eon?
No...
All the shamans are fully booked
for that day because of the by-elections.
Are you serious?
You call that an excuse?
That's the day
when all ancestral spirits are on the move.
Let's go.
I'm sorry, Sung-ae.
Sister Giunia!
So, have you found a place to conduct the rite?
I plan to perform it at the boy's residence.
It's a remote area.
The Archdiocese of Seoul has approved
the unofficial exorcism of Choi Hee-joon,
and Father Paolo will be participating.
But he isn't even ordained for exorcisms!
The Archdiocese has permitted it,
and as the bishop here, I approve it.
Father Paolo has received
special permission to oversee
Choi Hee-joon's unofficial exorcism.
He doesn't even believe in exorcism!
And a nun is
not qualified to perform an exorcism.
Father Paolo is a priest
of deep faith and knowledge.
Plus, he's a medical doctor.
Didn't you send a letter to Father Kim?
I only requested sacred items
needed for the exorcism.
We cannot recklessly entrust
such sacred items for an unofficial exorcism.
Father Paolo will personally
bring the sacred items and oversee it.
This is insane...
Keep in mind that from now on,
everything you do violates the church law.
Your abilities and spirituality
are only vouched for by Father Kim,
you're not even a priest of the Rosicrucianism.
If I contact the Rosicrucianism,
could they hand over
the sacred items to me directly?
That might be harder than
performing the exorcism itself.
The Day of Exorcism
That was Father Kim's personal opinion,
the Rosicrucianism
holds a different view on the matter.
(Italian) In exchange for our full support,
(Italian) you must eliminate
the demon by all means necessary.
(Italian) This
(Italian) is our will.
Even if the child might not survive?
Malodore.
It's the distinct stench of possession.
It means the demon within
has decayed to its very core.
Couldn't you have told me sooner?
Would that have helped you prepare?
That stench can't be washed away.
It's the main reason
the possessed are ultimately abandoned.
Thankfully, the human sense of smell
is the dullest of all, a blessing from God.
What a know-it-all.
Watch your tone.
You should quit smoking.
Secondhand smoke is worse.
The air feels too cold today.
What about the manual?
Is this a surgery?
There's no manual for a Dark Nun.
Right.
There's only one rule for this exorcism:
use any means necessary.
It's begun.
What's that?
Cotton flowers.
They symbolize the Goddess of Birth.
What?
She's the ancestral deity
who oversaw Hee-joon's birth.
He's destined to be a shaman.
His ancestors will lend their aid.
Are you a shaman or a nun?
Never disregard any information
about a possessed person.
Still, we're nuns, you know?
Even in Europe, they summon
guardian spirits during exorcisms.
Getting approval for an exorcism
is nearly impossible anywhere.
Lord, even though we use any means necessary,
our hearts remain true to You, please, help us.
Check him again.
What?
You're a doctor, aren't you?
Yes.
Even the demon knows.
It knows what you fear.
It shows you visions.
It makes you relive your trauma,
driving you to want to die.
(Latin) And you, son of man,
do not be afraid of them,
(Latin) do not fear their words,
(Latin) for they are rebellious
and deceitful around you,
(Latin) and even if you
dwell among scorpions and thorns.
(Latin) Do not be dismayed at their faces,
(Latin) for they are a rebellious house.
May your faith save this child.
May God's blessing be with you.
Bach Cantatas BWV140
Wake, Awake, for Night is Flying
Are you ready?
It's all over when we find out its name.
Yes, Sister.
Try not to look directly into his eyes.
If you start experiencing visions,
hide behind the icon
or stand behind me.
Yes, Sister.
Begin the prayer.
(Latin) Lord, have mercy.
(Latin) Lord, our God,
King of all ages, Almighty Father,
(Latin) who created all things and change them
(Latin) according to Your will...
(Latin)... who in Babylon
turned the burning flames
Sister...
Thank you...
(Latin) of the furnace into refreshing dew...
I'm okay now...
Where's my mom?
I want to go to my mom...
Lord, have mercy.
I want to see my mom...
Sister...
It's suffocating...
Can you untie this, please?
Sister Kang Sung-ae...
When did I ever tell you my name?
You fucking bitch!
(Latin) Lord, who is the salvation of all,
(Latin) and who cleanses
all sorcery and witchcraft,
(Latin) may Your servant
sing with gratitude
under Your protection and faith.
I hate it...
I hate being unable
to move my hands and feet...
I'm so scared...
Please, let me out of here...
The bullies, they're coming after me!
Please, save me...
Lord, Almighty and Master of all ages,
You created all things and change them
according to Your will.
You, who saved and protected
the three holy young saints
from the fiery furnace
engulfed in flames in Babylon...
- You are the healer of our souls
- I can't... I just can't...
- and the salvation of those who seek You.
- I can't, I can't, I can't!
Piss off, you filthy bitch!
Raise the breaker, and relight the candles.
Just turn it off!
Yes, Sister.
Sister...
This isn't a demon...
It protected me...
It killed your mom.
It hurt your friends.
It's a spirit protecting me...
You understand, don't you?
It's a demon.
It will never protect you.
Don't doubt me, I won't disappoint you.
You still want me, don't you?
I slaughtered your bitch mother.
I slaughtered your bitch mother!
You conniving bitch! Whore!
How long have you starved?
It's dirty! Filthy!
Remove your hand! It's filthy!
You whore!
Remove your hand!
Useless shit!
- How dare you!
- And the savior of those who seek You.
We beseech You...
You deceitful woman,
lying about getting raped by your god!
Whore of a god! Filthy bitch!
(Latin) Your humble servant
may sing under Your protection and faith.
Protect us from every curse,
from the malicious gazes of the wicked!
And from every wicked
act committed against Your servant!
(Latin) Extend Your powerful hands
and Your highest and strongest arms,
(Latin) and come to aid
and visit this Your image,
(Latin) and send upon it Your angel of mercy,
(Latin) a strong
and faithful guardian of soul and body.
You are Jesus' trash!
You drool all night,
lusting to kill whenever you see young ones!
Demon, I command you
reveal your true identity.
(Latin) Demon, I command you!
(Latin) Tell me who you are!
Asking for my name this early?
In the name of Jesus Christ,
I command you to reveal your name!
(Latin) In the name of Jesus Christ,
(Latin) reveal your name!
Don't you get it yet?
I won't be fooled by your tricks.
You're just a snake slithering out of the sea.
(Latin) You will die!
(Latin) The son of Mary
died nailed to the cross,
(Latin) you'll die with a tumor in your womb,
(Latin) unable to even bear children.
Possessing a faithless child,
you're a pathetic creature
that only hunts the weak!
(Latin) Lord, have mercy.
Pretending to react to the cross,
only to slither away like an eel.
You're just a deceitful, insignificant spirit!
A lowly beast's soul at that!
Sister!
We've been waiting for 233 years.
I was there in 1791, 1846, and 1866.
We were involved in the deaths
of the 103 martyrs you revere.
And now...
we will kill the children!
Starting with this child,
we will kill 292, then 471,
until the number reaches 2,340!
The children will perish on land,
in the mountains, and in the skies.
Mark my words: this child is the beginning.
The beginning of your devastating defeat.
"We"?
There's just one of you.
We are one and all.
Foolish woman!
Clinging to your pitiful prayers...
You pathetic humans
lost the ability to think for yourselves!
A beast protected by a filthy legion!
Tell me your name!
You always start
with commands, never with a plea!
Stupid wretch!
Say your name!
Do not fear, my son,
for I am your father.
Then tell me with your own mouth.
What is your name?
If you're going to command me,
do it with some authority!
You dare face me?
How dare you pray? Kneel to me instead!
I am the sacred one you must kneel to!
Worship me instead!
Shut up and say your name!
God created mankind?
What nonsense!
Is this Almighty God's masterpiece?
Pathetic fools, drunk on power
and slaughtering each other?
Forget about us, just tell us who you are.
Who are you, and why are you here?
I told you, didn't I?
I hated you.
I hated you!
I hated you! I hated you!
Bring me Saint Peter's scripture and the keys.
Hurry.
Hey!
What do we do now?
You're a shaman
who should've died performing a ritual,
so why are you here
cloaked in the rags of Jesus?
You're possessed by a spirit, so, why?
Why don't you ask the cards
you worship more than God?
Shut up!
It's not over yet.
We can't end it like this.
Sister, please, just tell me what to do!
I'll do whatever you say, Sister!
No one born of a woman...
Sister, please!
can oppose us!
Profound Dharma, rare to encounter.
By fortune, I now find it.
Who's this worthless shaman? Shut the hell up!
I seek the Tathagata's truth.
Want to save a person with me?
What?
Hee-joon, remember him?
We're going to exorcise him,
but we need another priest.
Me... m-m-me?
The essence of prayer is sincerity, isn't it?
To be honest, it's my first time too.
D-don't die!
Hee-joon!
I... c-can't write a talisman yet...
So... so here...
at least t-t-take this...
Mantra of the Dharma Treasury, Om Aranam Arada.
Om Aranam Arada.
You damn pests!
Shut up before I rip your mouth apart! Shut it!
Great mountains,
small mountains, mountain spirit gods.
Great strikes,
small strikes, mountain spirit gods.
Great evils, small evils,
vanish from this place.
His stuttering is gone.
Those who've experienced divinity,
three.
Bow to the guest spirits,
spirits of the land.
(Latin) Shut up already!
Shut that fool's mouth!
Bow to the mountain spirits,
let go of all obstacles.
Spirits of the soil, protect with sacrifice!
Today, at this very moment,
we seek blessings to go far.
Each and every place, beyond a thousand miles.
Otherworldly beings, do not return.
Hurry, follow the law of the cycle, Svaha!
Lord who loves humanity.
Protector of souls and bodies.
Send the angel of peace and strength,
visit and aid this child,
created in Your image.
In the name of the Son and the Holy Spirit...
(Latin) I have not come to ruin your lives!
(Latin) I am your savior!
He stole the scripture and fled?
Master, should I
send my men to catch that bastard?
Leave it.
Everyone there is going to die today.
Crazy bitch...
Bow to the guest spirits, spirits of the land.
Protect with the
self-sacrifice of the household.
Today, at this very moment,
seek blessings to go far.
Most holy and glorious Mother of God,
eternal Virgin Mary
and the Archangels who radiate light,
I plead in the names of all Your saints.
- Be with us brothers always and everywhere.
- Shut up!
- In the name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Spirit, Amen.
I ask you,
what are your names?
First murderer.
Where did you come from?
Even in the muzzle of the guns
you humans point at each other,
in polluted wells,
and in cities built on deserts...
in all places where gravity exists,
I have been with you.
(Latin) O humans,
who cannot fully understand gravity,
(Latin) I am the God...
It hurts... Please save me...
Sister... Please save me...
The Lord is my shepherd,
with Him, who can harm me?
I do not fear because I am with You, my God.
Sister... Please save me...
You're right.
I'll imprison you within my womb.
How dare you...
even consider forcing me into your rotten womb?
The filthy womb
where you promised purity to Him?
Consider it an honor, you worthless horse head.
You crazy wench, go ahead and try!
Come, embrace me! I'll be reborn as a demon!
I'll honor you as my mother!
Mountain spirits of
the western and southern mountains!
Mountain spirits
of the great and small mountains!
Spirits of great strikes and small strikes!
Great evils and small evils,
What's your name, you vile spirit?
Sister...
Your name.
Call me 'Annihilation.'
You're bacteria that
make rotten fruit decay even further.
Your name!
I existed everywhere since the beginning.
Those who fear us
call us the 12 Manifestations.
Do you dare
call yourself the 12 Manifestations?
Hee-joon... Hee-joon...
Hee-joon! Please hang in there!
Come forth, come forth!
You cowardly spirit dwelling
in a weak child! Pathetic wretch!
You're nothing more than a bug,
found in every corner!
A worthless shadow at night,
a minion of the 12 Manifestations!
A servant of evil bowing
before an unordained nun!
A mere pony of Marbas!
How dare you call me a lowly spirit...
You, of all people...
You arrogant wretch... You filthy woman!
I am none other than the Grand Duke of Hell!
Tell me your name.
Tell me and make me tremble in fear!
I am the Grand Duke of Hell.
I am Gamigin!
Granted the power and mission
by God to crush the head of Satan,
O great Queen of Heaven, Lady of Angels,
humbly I implore you
to send the heavenly army at your command
to drive the demons into hell,
fight them across the earth,
subdue their insolence,
and ultimately cast them into hell.
Amen.
In the name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Spirit, I command you,
Gamigin! Come out of there!
Lord, humans feel such sorrow...
yet the sea remains so blue.
Thank you, Sister.
You've done well.
Lord, hear our prayers.
Saint Michael, hear our prayers.
Saint Gabriel, hear our prayers.
Saint Raphael, hear our prayers.
Lord, hear our prayers.
Saint Michael, hear our praye...
Sister...
Are you okay?
Good job.
Look after Hee-joon first.
Take him to the nearest church.
Gamigin will try to return to Hee-joon's body.
Hurry, go.
What about you?
Ring the church
bell three times from the tower.
So that I can hear it.
What about you?
For heaven's sake...
Go, there's no time.
You need to save Hee-joon.
I... I don't want to.
No... Let's find another way...
There must be another way, please?
Save Hee-joon.
You're insane...
You crazy bitch!
In the name of
Lord Jesus Christ and the Virgin Mary,
I command you, leave at once.
Lord...
Delay judgment and grant me
the wisdom to save my neighbor.
Bestow upon us the grace of salvation.
Lord, please watch over us.
Step aside! Please, step aside!
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry! Please move aside!
Please move!
Make way! I'm sorry!
Out of the way!
Shit!
Is this nun crazy?
Let me go!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Shit!
Are you insane?!
I'm okay...
Get going!
Just go!
Leave us,
and never return to this place.
Never touch us again.
Never hurt the children again.
Lord Jesus Christ, Holy Virgin Mary,
and Saint Michael
the Archangel, fight for us, please.
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry.
Just a moment!
Hee-joon!
Go to the hospital with Hee-joon.
I need to go to Sister Giunia.
N-no, you can't!
I have to go check on her!
Sister, are you okay?
It's okay, I'm fine.
O Immaculate Virgin,
angels and archangels,
all the saints in heaven,
descend upon me.
Melt me, renew me,
cast all evils into the fires of hell,
fill me with Your presence
and use me as Your tool...
So that they may never again touch
any of the creatures of this world.
Please protect us.
In the name of the Father, and of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
The Rosicrucianism Parish
(Italian) I didn't think you'd come in person.
(Italian) I'm the one responsible
for the rite in question.
(Italian) How is the boy?
(Italian) I heard you've been
taking care of him personally.
(Italian) He's recovering quickly
but it will still take a long time.
(Italian) Yes! But...
(Italian) Yes?
(Italian) I heard you
weren't particularly fond of us...
(Italian) Let's just say
we were very cautious about the rite.
(Italian) I wasn't serious...
(Italian) We all have freedom, free to choose.
(Italian) Both you, me,
(Italian) and Sister Giunia.
(Kang Sung-ae Sister Giunia)
Where are we going?
Wherever the 12 Manifestations show up.
Do you think I can do this?
You've already learned everything.
I was told Sister Giunia
taught you everything you need to know.