THE GOLEM
How He Came Into This World
Directed by Paul Wegener
The First Chapter
The learned Rabbi Loew reads in the
stars that misfortune threatens the Jews.
I must speak with Rabbi Jehuda,
danger threatens our people.
Call all the elders of the
community together to pray.
The stars predict disaster.
AGAINST THE JEWS
We can no longer neglect
the popular complaints against the Jews.
They despise the holy Christian ceremonies;
They endanger the lives and property...
...of their fellow men;
They practice black magic.
We decree that all Jews shall leave the
city and all territory in sight of the city...
...before the month is ended.
Imperator
Knight Florian, deliver
our edict to the Ghetto.
Venus enters the constellation of Libra!
The auspicious hour has come...
...to summon the dread spirit Astaroth,
and compel him to reveal the magic word.
Then we can bring the Golem
to life to save our people.
A messenger from the
Emperor is here.
Come with me to the High Rabbi Loew, who
is like a father to our whole community.
It was I who drew the Emperor's horoscope.
I warned him twice of danger.
Tell him now that I humbly
request an audience with him.
The End of the First Chapter.
The Second Chapter.
The hour has come.
The stars favor the wizard.
Guard this secret
with your life.
Knight Florian brings
the Emperor's answer.