Ming Dynasty China...
in the eighth year
of the Jingtai Emperor's reign...
or 1457 A.D.
Eunuchs have seized power
in the palace.
They also control
two powerful espionage agencies:
the Eastern Depot
and the Imperial Guards.
These are the Imperial Guards.
These are agents of the Eastern Depot,
a kind of secret police.
These agents and guards are ruthless.
The people quake in fear
at word of their approach.
This is their second in command,
Mao Zong-Xian.
This is their commander, Pi Shao-tang.
All are well-trained swordsmen,
unscrupulous and evil.
Their chief eunuch is Cao Shao-qin.
He's a master swordsman
and wields great power.
He's unsurpassed in the martial arts.
High government officials
all tremble in fear
at the sight of Cao.
Today he's supervising the execution...
of YU Qian, Minister of Defense
and tutor to the prince.
Though loyal and patriotic...
YU was framed
by treacherous and powerful eunuchs
and sentenced to death
for conspiring with foreigners,
and his family
has been banished to Dragon Gate.
DRAGON INN
Executive Producer
SHA YUNG-FONG
Produced by
L. S. CHANG
Planning by
ZHANG JIU-YIN
Starring
BAI YING, SHIH CHUN
SHANGKUAN LING-FUNG
KO FEI, KO HSIAO PAO
GAO MING, TSAO CHIEN
HAN YING-CHIEH
MIAO TIEN, HSIEH HAN
CHANG YUN-WEN
YEE ANG
WAN CHUNG-SHAN, WEN TIAN
TIAN PENG, HSU FENG
Cinematography by
HUA HUI-YING
Assistant Director
TU CHUNG-HSUN
Action Choreography by
HAN YING-CHIEH
Lighting by
CHI HSIEH-FU
Art Direction by
CHOU CHIH-LIANG
Costume Design by
Ll CHIA-CHIH
Sound Recording by
CHANG HUA
Edited by
CHEN HUNG-MIN
Music by
ZHOU LAN-PING
Production Manager
YANG SHIH-CHING
Written and Directed by
KING HU
Yu's spirit won't die easily.
Even with his children banished,
there'll be no end of trouble.
Your Excellency is most insightful.
I say rip the weeds out by the roots!
Hurry!
- They're coming!
- Go on ahead!
Hold it there!
Stop!
Step aside!
Beat it!
Officer, take them away.
- You are?
....
- Hurry!
Your Excellency.
What is it?
.
Someone intervened?
They can't get far.
We can overtake them.
No, wait for them at Dragon Gate.
- Look.
- What?
.
Just look!
Go tell the boss.
- Boss!
- What's all the commotion?
.
We have guests. Look.
Go help with their things.
Leaving now? Come back soon
..
How strange!
Guests at this time of year?
.
You must be tired.
Let us take your things.
You've had a hard journey.
Please come inside.
This way.
Draw water for washing,
and prepare tea.
I’m sure you're all very tired.
Please sit down.
Have some tea.
Pour tea for our guests.
Would you like a room upstairs?
.
Please sit down.
Make some tea.
Right here is fine.
Where's the innkeeper?
.
He's away. I’ll be happy to help.
What do you do here?
.
I’m the bookkeeper.
How many guests are staying here now?
.
This time of year? None
..
- Good. We'll take the entire inn.
- The entire inn?
We'll probably stay five to ten days.
You're to accept no other guests
while we're here, understand?
Yes, but -
- Go arrange rooms for the men.
- Yes, sir.
A gratuity for our trouble sir?
,.
- Wait over there.
- Yes, sir.
I’ll get you some fresh tea.
Waiter!
Bring some fresh tea.
- How much?
- Whatever you think, sir.
The luggage was heavy,
and we lugged it for miles.
I see.
How many soldiers are stationed nearby?
.
- I’m not sure.
- Out with it!
About twelve.
You there... go handle it.
We need this place
for a little business.
If other guests arrive,
you consult with me first.
Understand bookkeeper?
,.
Yes, sir.
Give them a good burial,
and bring me a nice pot of tea.
I’ll wait for them on the road.
Take some men into the woods.
We'll meet down below.
And leave a few men to guard the inn.
We have no rooms, sir.
- I won't be staying.
- And you are?
....
Is the innkeeper Mr Wu here?
,.,.
He's away on business.
When will he be back?
.
I don't exactly know.
Perhaps you could come back
in a few days.
No, I’ll wait.
I’d leave now if I were you.
Why?
.
Because -
Because...
the thing is...
this area isn't safe right now.
Because of the Tartar soldiers?
.
Exactly!
That's all right.
I’m not afraid of them.
Why did you stop playing?
.
Besides, the inn is full. You'd best -
He just told me that.
Any lodgings will do.
Bring me
some mutton noodles and wine.
You...
Bring mutton noodles and wine.
Waiter...
I’d like a bowl of mutton noodles too.
I want the bowl
on that gentleman's table.
That bowl there.
Sir, I’ll bring you another bowl.
Hold it!
I want that bowl Understand?
..
Yes, I understand, but...
The gentleman can have this bowl.
Thank you.
Here!
Please.
Waiter, don't just stand there.
Go see if my wine's ready.
Take it to him.
Take it to him!
Sir, your wine is -
What about it?
.
Your wine is -
No, don't!
What's wrong?
.
Your wine spilled.
I’m sorry.
What's going on?
What's the matter with you?
.
You!
It wasn't me!
- What's going on?
.
- I have no idea.
Sit down.
Bet this for me.
Get some rope to tie him up
and take him away.
Move it!
You keep away!
- You put something in my wine!
- I didn't!
- No? Then you drink it
..
- No!
You have no choice!
Get back!
You blind dogs!
You've got some nerve!
Don't you know who I am?
.
Waiter, another pot of wine.
What are you doing here?
.
Let me use your towel.
I’m talking to you! You hear me?
.
Pick those things up.
Don't just stand there!
Bring me my wine.
- What happened?
.
- Hold it!
Don't forget your tools of the trade.
One step closer and you're dead!
Oh dear!
- Bring me another bowl of noodles.
- You still want to eat?
.
Do as you're told!
Now you've done it, sir!
- How so?
There are dozens of them.
They'll be back any minute.
Don't worry.
They won't dare return while I’m here.
- I’ll go look into it, sir.
- Wait.
This fellow's clearly up to no good.
Be careful.
Did you kill that man?
.
Why?
- Didn't he tell you?
.
- He did.
Then you needn't ask me.
I heard one side of the story.
I want to hear yours.
What are you to him?
.
I’m his friend.
Seeing as you're his friend, I’ll tell you.
He poisoned my wine!
You killed him for that?
.
What proof do you have that he did it?
My word is proof enough.
A man's life is involved.
How should we resolve this?
.
What do you think?
A debt for a debt, a life for a life.
Fine. Report me to county officials.
I have no time for that.
And I doubt county officials
could handle me.
That's right.
You'd have to explain
how those porters got killed.
- Stop being difficult!
- I thought we'd just forget the whole thing.
Forget the whole thing?
.
It's not that simple.
Why not?
.
You're being unreasonable!
Well?
.
Stay back!
I’ve told you men not to cause trouble
among the people.
But dogs just can't help eating shit!
Sir, this fellow just -
Bring water for washing.
My compliments!
You're too kind.
They're all ignorant fools.
Please forgive them for offending you.
It's quite all right.
Might I ask your name?
.
Xiao Shao-zi.
My dear Mr. Xiao...
what is your occupation?.
- Oh, I’m just a loafer.
Where there's a free meal,
I stay for a while,
but no job can keep me for long.
If I may be so bold...
what brings you
to these desolate parts?
.
The innkeeper is a friend.
And what is your occupation?
.
I work for the
Criminal Investigation Department.
I travel around with these fools.
Really? Are you here on a case?
..
I have no choice.
When paid to solve a problem,
one must deliver the goods.
We might need your help someday.
You flatter me.
What case brings you here?
.
I hope you won't take offense...
but we can't reveal too much.
I understand.
We're here by secret imperial order.
Our instructions say
no outside parties may be present
while we're on this case, so -
I understand.
You're asking me to leave.
Never!
But if you wouldn't mind terribly,
I’ll be sure to repay the favor.
That won't be necessary.
I’d like to help
with your travel expenses.
I wouldn't hear of it.
But I’ll be back when Mr. Wu returns.
Of course. Thanks very much.
My bill, please.
- It's on the house.
- No, I’ll -
- Thank you.
- Good-bye.
Until we meet again.
Please return this to that gentleman.
Good-bye.
Have two men tail him.
Brother Wu.
Ah, Xiao! You finally made it.
- I was just at your inn.
- Why didn't you wait for me?.
Criminal Investigation officers
working on a case there
said I’d be in the way.
They didn't look like officials to me.
They weren't in uniform.
Wait a minute.
Who do you think they are?
.
I don't know,
but they're up to no good.
And every one is a crack swordsman.
What did you want to see me for?
.
Let's get to the inn!
Commander, that Xiao fellow's back.
Put everything away.
You're not to call me
"commander" from now on
or to tell anyone
we're with the Eastern Depot.
We're with Criminal Investigations.
Go tell the others.
Go tell the sentries outside.
- Yes, sir.
My dear Mr. Xiao.
Back so soon?
.
- I met Mr. Wu at the pass.
This is the officer
from Criminal Investigations.
- I’m Wu Ning.
- Nice to meet you.
Please forgive me if service
was unsatisfactory in my absence.
- No, it's been very good.
- Mr. Wu...
my name is Mao Zong-Xian.
We need your inn for official purposes.
Beyond preparing our food,
you're not to interfere
with our business.
And until we go,
no one here is to leave.
That includes you.
And remember: no other guests
without our permission.
Certainly.
Halt!
What do you want?
.
Let's go.
Brother!
Let's just watch where they go.
Let's go have a look.
- What do you want?
.
- A room.
Open up!
Open this door!
There are no rooms. Stop knocking!
Who's the innkeeper here?
.
I am.
I asked politely!
Why didn't you open up?
.
Forgive the rude welcome,
but we really have no rooms.
Then I’ll sleep right here!
- What's this boorish behavior?
.
- Who are you?
- An interested party.
- Mind your own business!
How dare you act like this!
Brother, forget it. Listen to me.
- Forget it.
- No! I’ll camp right here!
No need to camp anywhere.
Please take my room.
We couldn't do that.
We travelers must help one another.
- Who's that fellow?
.
- Just a merchant.
Innkeeper, let's eat!
Excuse me, please.
Dig in, everyone.
- Where are you two headed?
.
- We're going -
To Gansu to visit a relative.
And what is your business here?
.
We're government officials
on the tracks of two escaped convicts.
I’m sure that's very difficult work.
Let me toast you all.
Have you by any chance seen
some convicts being transferred?
.
A man woman and child?
,,.
Yes, we saw several groups, in fact.
Do you know their names
and destination?
Zhang's the last name.
Distant relatives headed for Tianshou.
I haven't seen them.
What about you?
.
I’ve heard nothing about them.
Let's have another drink.
This wine's awful.
Go see if there's something better,
and warm up two pots.
They've poisoned the wine.
My friend, I was very rude earlier.
I’d like to apologize.
Let's drink together.
Fine. We'll put all that behind us.
Cheers!
Thanks.
THE WINE IS POISONED
- Have a little warm wine.
- Thanks.
Here's to you!
What are you doing?
.
- Drunk already?
- I haven't had any yet!
Just a little spill. Not to worry.
Let me refill it.
Cheers!
What's wrong with you?
.
How about some sesame cakes?
You really are drunk.
You'll get chest pains again.
- When did I ever have chest pains?
.
Mother told me to look after you.
She said you'll get
chest pains if you drink.
This is strong stuff.
There's pigeon crap in it.
My little brother's always
bossing me around.
Since your brother can't drink,
let's you and I share a drink.
Sure.
Cheers!
You spilled half of yours.
That's not fair.
Drink from my cup. It's full.
I spilled mine too.
Let me have yours.
Why fuss young man?
,.
They're all the same.
No, they're not!
Why do you say that?
.
Fill his cup.
I want your cup.
What's so special about my cup?
.
Are you trying to start something?
Leave me alone, brother.
Just give your cup to Mr. Zhu.
I’ll handle it!
This isn't how one offers a drink!
You're drunk.
Forgive him. He drinks too much.
His little trick nearly cost me my life.
Stop displaying your incompetence
and let go!
Commander...
I think those Zhu brothers
are somehow connected to YU Qian.
I think Mr. Xiao is the real troublemaker.
He let Zhu know
the wine was poisoned.
When?
.
- When he came over to offer a toast.
- How?
.
I didn't see,
but those four are in cahoots.
Four?
.
Including Wu, the innkeeper.
Then just kill them all!
Mr. Xiao will be a challenge.
Let's set them against each other.
I don't trust that Xiao fellow.
We'd be dead if he hadn't warned us.
But why?
.
He had no reason to save us.
Sleep over there, brother.
On the floor?
.
You've got lots of tricks up your sleeve.
You got that?
.
- Brother!
- Stay there!
I want to explain -
Stop being so unreasonable!
A woman?
.
Mr Zhu what happened to you?
.,.
Officer Mao,
did you hear a noise just now?.
No.
Come to my room later.
Who is it?
.
The innkeeper.
Ah, Mr. Wu.
What happened earlier?
.
I don't know.
I know.
If you have something to say, say it!
Stop beating around the bush!
Who are you to talk to me like that?
.
A young man like you,
always insulting and attacking others!
If not for your sister,
you'd be dead by now!
Watch what you say,
old man, or I’ll -
Still looking for a fight?
.
My brother's hot-tempered.
You were always foolish as a child,
and at 30 you haven't changed!
Do you know us?
.
It's no wonder you don't recognize me.
He was just eight when I met him.
What is your name?
.
Wu Ning.
Were you General Wu
under Minister Yu's command?
.
Your father and I served
in the same battalion.
Uncle Wu!
It's been over ten years.
Get up. Come to my room later.
How can you tell
they're with the Eastern Depot?
.
I’ve seen many of their kind.
They're here for the YU family.
Uncle Wu what do you think?
,.
What should we do?
.
Wait till they're asleep,
then kill them all!
By my calculations...
the YU family should be here
by noon tomorrow.
At dawn we'll go intercept them
and take them to safety,
then come back
and deal with these agents.
These men will probably
go searching at dawn too.
We'll have to risk it.
Zhu Ji and I will head east.
You and Miss Zhu will go west.
We'll have to sneak out quietly.
Search him.
EUNUCH OF THE EASTERN DEPOT
ON SPECIAL IMPERIAL ASSIGNMENT
If anything happens,
get word to me immediately.
If things get tough, I’ll just -
Don't do anything reckless.
They're coming!
Stop yelling and go tell
the second in command.
Let's go.
DRAGON INN
Innkeeper is there a room available?
,.
A room?
.
Yes. This way, please.
Get us some food.
Draw water, make tea,
and bring out some buns!
Hurry!
Water to freshen up.
How long will you be staying?
.
- We'll be leaving tomorrow.
- That's fine, then.
Go on.
This is bad news!
They've arrived.
Go take them away.
If it's too late,
take them to the granary.
I’ll go find Xiao. Take the shortcut.
Master YU, run!
Get your family out of here!
These are Eastern Depot agents,
with many more outside.
Take them upstairs!
Attack!
To the granary! Hurry!
Commander,
there are people approaching!
Stop them.
You go around back
and open the granary door.
You attack from the front.
Out of my way.
Let's just forget all this, young man.
Fine. Release the YU family.
Very well.
Go inside
and ask Master YU to come out.
I’ll stay here with Master Zhu.
Let's go!
Miss Zhu!
Go out through the granary.
You can still catch up with them.
What about you?
.
I’ll deal with these scoundrels.
Brother Xiao.
- Mr. Xiao.
- Who's that?
.
Pi Shao-tang.
Could you step out here a minute?
What is it Mr Pi?
,..
Mr. Xiao, look there.
You asked me out here to see this?
.
No, but I do think
these men were innocent.
Innocent?
.
They're always strutting around.
They needed a little lesson.
The YU family is nothing to you.
Why keep opposing us?
I have no choice.
When paid to solve a problem,
one must deliver the goods.
In that case, let's have a talk.
I’ve chosen my side.
There's nothing to talk about.
Not so. You could still join our side.
Join your side? It's not that simple
..
Why not?
.
This way I win both fame and fortune.
I’m paid for saving
the descendants of a loyal minister.
My friend, don't be offended...
but your Eastern Depot
has quite a reputation.
No need to mince words.
The Depot is indeed known
for being evil and vicious,
but we do pay very well.
Just how well?
.
Depends on what you have to offer.
Well...
you've seen what I can do.
So you're interested?
.
That's right.
Our official price is 100 taels of silver.
I’ll double it.
I can't do it for that amount.
Then name your price.
Two hundred taels of gold.
It's a deal.
In advance.
You've gone too far!
- What's this?
.
- Play games with me will you?
,.
Get him!
Get back.
Keep this up and I’ll get very angry!
Get them out of here!
Now rest a while.
Why bother tending to those men?
.
You be quiet!
It's nothing serious.
- Let them go.
- Very well.
You can all go.
- You can't let them go!
- You keep quiet!
They'll come back after you again!
That's not your concern.
Never mind him. Come along.
Go on.
Thank you all very much.
We don't know what to say.
Remember:
Don't drink too much water.
Hurry now.
Those two are still unconscious.
Mr. Wu...
may I have a word with you?
.
- Don't listen to him!
- Stay out of this.
Go ahead.
Mr. Wu...
we're never going back.
Why is that?
.
If you have no objection...
we'd like to join you.
You wouldn't have
much of a future with us.
There's not much of a future
with them either.
They commit
the most heinous crimes.
We could be killed any moment.
- What's your name?
.
- Duola.
What?
.
Duola.
We're Tartars.
This is my younger brother.
We've always admired Chinese culture.
We dreamed of coming to China
ever since we were boys.
When I was 18,
YU Qian was recruiting soldiers.
We journeyed a long way to enlist.
We never imagined...
Do you know me?
.
Every soldier
under Yu's command knows you.
Then why did you join
the Eastern Depot?.
Just before YU Qian was executed,
I was transferred
to the Imperial Guards.
The day after his execution...
I visited his grave
to pay my respects.
Little did I know
that Cao Shao-qin would find out.
He transferred us
to the Eastern Depot.
He made you agents just like that?.
May we speak in private?
.
Cao took us
into the castration chamber...
and had us castrated.
They probably won't be here
for a day or two.
You say that Cao
is a brilliant martial artist.
Just how good is he?
.
I can't exactly say.
He's a masterful swordsman,
fast and precise.
But with his asthma,
he mustn't overexert himself.
Let's show them, Mr. Xiao.
You think that will do?
.
- He's faster than my brother and me.
- Really?
.
This I have to see.
They're coming.
Open up.
Who's there?
.
Mr. Wu, it's Gui YU-Zhang.
- Greetings, Lieutenant Gui.
- Greetings.
You can all come out.
He's on our side.
Come inside, men.
Where are my twelve soldiers?
.
Killed by agents of the Eastern Depot.
Why did they do that?
.
They came here
to kill Minister Yu's family.
Your men were in the way.
Mr. Wu, we're old friends.
You mustn't do anything rash.
Keep an eye on them.
Wait till I sort everything out.
Out of my way!
Didn't you hear?
Drop your weapon!
Your Excellency.
You've made quite a mess of things.
I have failed, but those men
are formidable opponents.
Idiot! Just look at yourself!
Go change your clothes!
Yes, sir.
Wait!
I hear the innkeeper is a Mr. Wu.
That's right.
Is it Wu Ning?
.
TO WU NING FROM CAO SHAO-QIN
"Brother Wu,
please turn the YU family over to us.
Anyone involved in harboring
those criminals will be punished."
Judging from that, he's in the vicinity.
The arrogance of that eunuch!
I’ll go talk to him.
Your duty is to guard the border.
This is a matter for the state.
Stay out of it,
or you're asking for trouble.
Now go back.
This is my territory.
Palace eunuchs aren't to interfere here!
How dare you!
A lowly lieutenant
speaking to me like that!
You're relieved of your duty!
Very well. Show me the royal order.
Show the lieutenant the royal order.
Your Excellency, come look.
Take cover outside!
TO CAO SHAO-QIN FROM WU NING
"I am occupied with business
and thus can't be here to welcome you.
Take care, and may we meet again.
Wu Ning."
We'll be safe once we've crossed
over that mountain.
Give it here.
Come back!
Duola, cover me!
Go report to His Excellency.
I’ll take care of this sissy.
She got him in the shoulder.
Go for his legs!
Traitors!
Run!
You guard the rear. We'll attack.
They've got us surrounded.
Cao Shao-qin is trying to trap us.
We have no choice but to fight.
Where are Master YU and the others?
.
You stay here with these officers.
We'll go look for the old guy.
I’ll go along. I might be useful.
No, stay here and look after them.
I’m afraid you may be no match for him.
If we don't return by dusk,
take Master YU and run for your life.
Tell us where Cao Shao-qin is
and we'll let you go.
Where is he?
.
Out with it!
Talk!
There!
Go tell Cao that Xiao Shao-zi
wants to speak with him.
Go on.
Oh? Where are they?
..
Just outside.
Tell them to come in.
By order of His Excellency,
Xiao Shao-zi is commanded to enter.
Cut the formalities
and tell Cao to get out here!
His Excellency.
Which of you is Xiao Shao-zi?
.
I am.
You're fond of meddling in others' affairs.
Only when justice is at stake.
I hear you're a skillful fighter.
I get by.
I’d never have guessed.
Appearances can be deceiving.
It's true. I’d never have guessed
you were a eunuch.
How dare you!
Save your shrewish tantrums for your men!
I’ll make you an offer:
Turn over the YU family...
and I’ll let you go
and forget what's happened.
And should you decide to follow me,
I guarantee you
a top position.
And if I don't?
.
I’m afraid the alternative
isn't very attractive.
You're really something, old man!
I understand
you've trained since childhood.
That's a difficult path.
So many pleasures
of the senses to forego.
But I doubt that was so very hard.
You were castrated so young,
certain pleasures were never an option!
Take some men
and look for those YU bastards.
That was close!
I almost became just like you!
Stay back!
Get back!
Cao, you already lost
what you had down below.
Careful you don't lose what's up top too!
Give up, Cao!
You're too old for this!
THE END