[footsteps clicking]
[pleasant horn music]
[boat horn blowing]
[seagulls squawking]
[waves sloshing]
[distant seagulls squawking]
[upbeat electronic music]
[woman gasping]
[boat horn blowing]
[upbeat saxophone music]
[thudding]
[heels clicking]
- By the way, my name's Michael.
Pleased to meet you.
- Good, I'm Sarah.
Take it easy, bye.
- [Michael] Bye.
Oh, Sarah, take care, you hear?
[laughing]
[machinery rumbling]
- We got to clear that cement.
- I asked for a bulldozer, it's coming.
We'll have it done by tonight
before the boss starts bitching.
You tell him.
- All right.
[machinery rumbling]
This is where we got to dig.
- Dan, hey Dan!
- We'll be ready.
- Listen.
- I'm counting on you,Ed.
- Morning.
- Good morning.
- Where the hell have you
been all day, Michael?
- Dan, the most incredible
thing happened to me.
- So what happened?
Come on.
You got laid.
- You know it.
[laughing]
- Was she built?
- Like a shit brick house.
- I think you mean a brick shit house.
- No, better.
- Where'd you get it on?
Your place?
- The ferry boat.
- Ferry boat?
I got to hear about this.
Come on, I'll buy you a beer.
[laughing]
[machinery rumbling]
- I thought, "I'll never see her again."
She was real, I swear it.
- Some broad picks you up on the ferry
and you just forget everything.
- She never told me her last name.
- If I'm not mistake, you're
getting married in 12 days.
- Mm-hmm.
I know, 12 days.
- It's your funeral, pal.
- Yep.
[upbeat music]
Oh, shit.
- What's the matter?
- I can't find my wallet.
[laughing]
- Don't worry about it, this one's on me.
I'll bet one woman's got your wallet.
- I must've left it back home.
- Come on, Michael,
when are you gonna face
reality and grow up?
- [Woman] Well, Sarah, what do you think?
It's not finalized yet but I
think we're on the right track.
- [Sarah] If you say so.
- I only deal with the raw material.
Sarah, I like the idea that the 100th man
be a total stranger while the
other 99 are public figures.
It's stroke of genius.
And the ferry boat, really brilliant.
Absolutely brilliant but--
- But?
- But it's too short.
Too short.
It drops off in midair.
We know nothing about him, about his life.
Who's Michael Terenzi?
You must see him again.
Get to know your subject better.
- All right, no problem.
- How will you track him down?
- [Sarah] I'll just whistle.
- Good.
[horn honking]
[city commotion]
[somber synthesizer music]
- [Michael] Helen!
- Darling, you're late, I've
been waiting for half an hour.
Do you know we have about
a million and one things to do today?
- I'm sorry but I just couldn't get away.
- Listen, honey, now did you
talk to the caterers yet?
- Yes, they said they'd come tomorrow.
- And what about Dan?
Has he found a suit that he likes yet?
- I don't think he'll
ever find one big enough.
- I just hope he doesn't
wait till the last minute.
Oh, I wanted to show you
the bride's maid dresses I saw today.
The most beautiful lime green.
You know, everything goes with green.
I even saw green flowers.
You do like green.
I even saw green satin gloves
and a beautiful light
green tiara with a veil.
I already checked on the
sizes and they have mine.
Thank God.
I think white weddings
are boring, don't you?
- Oh, yeah, listen
Helen, I just remembered
I got to get back to the office.
- But you said you were free today.
- Something came up.
- And don't forget six o'clock
for the living room set.
- [Michael] Wouldn't
miss it for the world!
[somber synthesizer music]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
- Hi, Michael.
It's me, Sarah.
The ferry boat, remember?
- Oh, sure, I remember.
How did you get my telephone number?
- Easy, you lost your
wallet on the ferry boat.
- [Michael] Oh.
- Michael,
I need you.
I want to see you now.
Please, come here now.
13 Ward Street.
Ask for me, Sarah Asproon.
- Hello?
Hello, taxi.
[somber music]
Sarah.
- Hmmm?
- There's something you oughta know.
I'm getting married in 11 days.
I'm not gonna change my mind
and I'm not gonna postpone the wedding.
- Then give me all the
nights you have left.
11 nights just for me.
I won't ask you for
one single minute more.
[sensual music]
- Michael, won't you
have some more ice cream?
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
- What's the matter, Michael?
You don't like my wife's
homemade ice cream?
- Oh no, it's not that.
- Then why don't you have a little more?
Just to please me.
- Mother, please.
Maybe Michael's had enough.
- Helen!
Helen, I understand English.
- It's best he understand how we live,
since the both of you
will be living with us
for the first months anyway.
- [Helen] Father, please.
- Michael,
our Helen is not going to live
in any bachelor apartment.
- We were only thinking of your future.
My husband, Richard, has
bought you a lovely home.
Unfortunately, it won't be
ready for another six months.
Your office thinks it's a wonderful idea.
They're going to withhold
a little something
from your salary every week
for the mortgage payments.
Now isn't that nice of them?
What do you say, Michael?
- I'm sorry but I have an appointment,
I really must be going.
It's been very nice, thank you.
About the house and everything,
I'd like to discuss it some other time.
If that's all right with you.
Helen and I had some plans of our own.
[upbeat saxophone music]
[bell ringing]
You in, Sarah?
Anybody home?
Sarah?
It's me, Michael.
Where are you?
[upbeat saxophone music]
- Hi, Michael.
There's a little hitch, I'm not home
and I don't know when I'll be back.
- That's just great.
I guess I'll stick around.
- Thanks for the champagne
but I don't think you
should drink it without me.
- What?
- Just female intuition, darling.
You wanna make a big impression tonight
and you think I've stood you up.
Right, Michael?
But I haven't left you entirely alone.
You see, Michael,
it's as though I were there with you,
a little bit.
Until we're really together in the flesh.
[upbeat pop music]
I wanna make love to you, Michael.
I want it with every inch of me.
Every ounce of me.
[moaning]
Watch me, Michael.
Can you see how much I need you?
I'm getting wet, Michael.
Oh, Michael, take me.
[heavy breathing]
Take me.
- Video, oh.
- Michael, don't go.
My perfume is in the air.
Yours too, darling.
Let me enter your mind.
Take me into your mind.
[upbeat saxophone music]
Michael, darling.
Oh, Michael.
I want you so much, it hurts.
Your hands on my skin.
Your breath on my cheek.
Our bodies together.
- Christ, I've had it.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
- [Sarah On Phone] Why aren't
you watching me, Michael?
You're being a very, very bad boy.
- Sarah, where are you?
- [Sarah On Phone] I'm
right there with you,
only you don't want me.
I'd die for you and you reject me.
That's not nice, Michael.
- Sarah, would you get right over here?
- [Sarah On Phone] But I am there.
Can't you see me?
- I mean in the flesh.
- Use your imagination, dear.
- There's something you
oughta know about me, Sarah.
Watching just doesn't make it for me.
I guess I'm just old fashioned.
- Are you sure you don't
like to watch, Michael?
Michael, I'm an old fashioned girl myself.
[upbeat music]
[upbeat horn music]
[bottle popping]
[giggling]
Oh, Michael.
You should've seen your
face when the cork popped.
You're so funny.
- You really enjoy making
me look like a fool.
- Let's just say you know a girl
who can open a bottle of
champagne with her body heat
but who couldn't get your fly open.
[laughing]
It was so funny.
- Why don't you try me now?
- Why not?
Hey, what's this?
- Ice cream at Helen's.
- Who's Helen?
- Helen is--
- Oh, it's okay.
I don't want you to talk about other women
when you're with me.
Michael?
Why don't your rape me?
- What?
- Yeah, come on, I'm
dying to be raped by you.
Please?
- Okay, let's go back to your place
and I'll rape you all night long.
- Oh, Christ.
- How about that?
- Okay.
But it's just no fun to be
attacked in one's own bed.
People get raped in the
street, didn't you know that?
[laughing]
Help! Help!
The man wants to rape me!
Help!
- Why is she doing this to me?!
The bitch!
[traffic commotion]
- My husband's very shy.
- I understand.
- Michael, Michael?
Thank the nice policeman.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Goodbye.
- Scared you, didn't I?
- You're a great girl, Sarah,
and maybe with someone else
you'd be having a barrel of laughs
but right now, I don't think you're funny.
Mikey boy's tired.
So I guess he'll go home to bed.
Why don't you call me
again, like next year?
We can go out together again
and have ourselves a high old time.
Okay?
Bye.
[traffic commotion]
[somber synthesizer music]
- Hi.
- You know what, you're
nuts but I'm an asshole.
- [Sarah] Touch me, I'm all wet.
- Where are you panties?
- I ate them.
[laughing]
- [Dan] That invoice didn't check out.
- Okay, I'll look into it.
- What's this?
- I don't know, it's for you.
- Thanks, guys.
- Take it easy.
[boat horn blowing]
- Michael, can we talk?
Recognize these?
They came to the site today.
"These are my panties, put
them on and think of me."
There's more to the message.
"Shangri La Cafe.
"10:30 PM.
"5370 Woodlong, be there."
- Hand them over.
- What's the matter, big guy?
Cold without them?
- Would you cut that out!
- I guess you bought them at Saks, hmmm?
- Will you look at him?
Huh.
- [Dan] I love linens.
[Dan gigging]
- Stop it, everybody's watching.
- Oh yeah?
- They're not even your size!
[laughing]
- [Dan] So long,
sweetheart, see you later.
[laughing]
- [Man] I bet those guys spend more
on underwear than you do.
- [Woman] You wanna bet?
[woman laughing]
[upbeat synthesizer music]
♪ When your eyes meet mine I wonder ♪
♪ What you do to me ♪
♪ Suddenly I need you desperately ♪
♪ Never did my wildest dream ♪
♪ End so recklessly ♪
♪ But where you are is where I wanna be ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ More than I would ever dare to say ♪
♪ You're the only one
I'll ever want this way ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ You're the place someone
where I can stray ♪
♪ And I feel as though my
heart is here to stay ♪
♪ I watch you ♪
♪ Watching me ♪
♪ Say you'll save tonight for me ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Me and you ♪
♪ You and me ♪
♪ That's the way it's gonna be ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Save tonight for me ♪
- Well.
- Would you like to come
in and have some coffee?
- Well, Helen, I can't.
You see, Dan's making me pay
in advance for the honeymoon.
He says I can rest then.
- Well aren't you gonna kiss me goodnight?
Not like that, a real kiss.
[watch alarm beeping]
- I got to go.
I have to finish those damn
estimates by tomorrow morning.
- Right.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, sweetheart.
[lock clicking]
[faint pop music]
[people chattering]
Thank you.
- Are you wearing them?
- Mm-hmm.
- Give me two minutes then follow me.
[upbeat music]
[restaurant commotion]
[upbeat piano music]
- What if somebody should come in?
[shushing]
- Be a good boy.
Come with me.
Come on.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Oh, not bad.
Not bad at all.
A little touch here and there.
Take your clothes oft,
I wanna see if you really have them on.
[chuckling]
- Let's get it on.
[giggling]
Hey, my clothes!
- [Sarah] Wear mine.
One size fits all.
You'll drive the guys wild.
And I'll love you for it.
- Sarah, have you gone nuts?
- Pretty please?
Hold still.
Done and done.
Hey, not a bad looking floozy.
Look.
What do you think?
- Hey, Sarah, you don't
think for one minute that--
- And don't keep me
waiting, darling, please.
- Shit.
[women chattering]
- Oh my God.
[gasping]
[women giggling]
[groaning]
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
- Sir.
Here.
Your signature.
Thank you.
- Thanks.
Look, Sarah, I've had
enough of your stupid games.
I've had it!
[laughing]
Sarah!
Hey, wait,
where are you going?
- Taxi!
[laughing]
- Sarah, please stop this.
- [Sarah] Hello there.
My key, please.
- Oh, shit!
- Ladies don't swear.
Thank you.
We've already taken a room, dear.
After you, darling.
Ladies first.
- What an idiot I was
to lose sleep over you.
Get undressed and give me back my clothes!
I'm going!
- Why don't you undress me?
It's so exciting.
You're me and I'm you.
[sensual music]
[Sarah giggling]
It's a kick to be a man for a change.
And you're a first-class tart.
[sensual horn music]
- [Michael] Yeah, I'm a tart
and a whore.
I'm you and you're me.
Now fuck me, darling.
[pleasant horn music]
[Sarah moaning]
[hufting]
[moaning]
[groaning]
[Michael moaning]
- Not bad.
Pleasant enough.
But something's missing.
Something special, dangerous.
You'll think of something
with your imagination.
- My imagination could
never match yours, Darling.
- Sarah!
[door thudding]
[upbeat jazz music]
- Sit a little closer, darling.
Put your arm around me.
- You cold?
- You're cold.
Whenever we're together these days,
you always seem so far away.
You never seem to notice me.
- I've just been tired.
I'm not getting any sleep.
The work.
The pressure.
- Don't worry, darling.
As soon as we're married,
you'll get plenty of sleep.
- Come on.
[upbeat band music]
[doorbell ringing]
- [Man] Mr. Terenzi, Michael Terenzi?
- [Michael] Yes?
- Your order, sir.
- What?
- [Man] Goodnight, Mr. Terenzi.
- Goodnight.
[hairdryer buzzing]
♪ I've got you ♪
♪ You've got me ♪
♪ That's the way it's gonna be ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Save the night for me ♪
♪ Why don't you save the night ♪
♪ Come on and save the night ♪
♪ Save, save ♪
[upbeat saxophone music]
♪ Save the night for me ♪
♪ Save the night ♪
- [Michael] We'll never
finish all this stuff.
[doorbell ringing]
- Surprise, Michael!
How're you doing?
Come on, gang, there's food!
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Right this way, come on.
That a boy, come in.
Dig in, there's plenty for everybody.
Don't be piggies.
[laughing]
Come on!
[people chattering]
Gotta do something to get
this party off the ground.
What do we have here?
Let's see if I can get this
thing to play us little bop.
That's something dry.
[upbeat music]
- I shouldn't eat these but I love 'em.
- I can't stand those.
- I adore them.
[upbeat music]
- Come on, let's see a
little life around here.
On your feet, girl, let's boogie.
[laughing]
- Hey.
[upbeat music]
- [Man In Yellow] Your
guy enjoying himself?
- I certainly hope so, a lot.
[laughing]
[upbeat saxophone music]
- We're done!
Okay, out!
Everybody out!
The party's over!
- [Man In Yellow] This is it, gang.
- You, stay!
- Can't win them all
The food was divine.
Goodnight, Sarah, darling.
See you tomorrow.
It was a great party while it lasted.
Toodeloo.
- Michael, come on, if
you want me to stay,
it has to be my way.
[somber horn music]
[dramatic synthesizer music]
♪ I'm awake in the morning ♪
♪ And walking to the villa ♪
♪ And without any warning ♪
♪ You walked into my life ♪
♪ Left to beg and to borrow ♪
♪ For today and tomorrow ♪
♪ We've been saving our love ♪
♪ Maybe we've had enough ♪
♪ To give measure to pleasure ♪
♪ Forever ♪
[pleasant music]
♪ I will do anything to follow ♪
♪ I was chasing a new love ♪
♪ Love as strong as you weren't ♪
♪ Would not be a true love ♪
♪ I'll give you sudden pleasure ♪
♪ I've been touching my heart ♪
♪ Oh my pleasure, my leisure ♪
♪ My love ♪
[pleasant beat music]
♪ Living day after day ♪
♪ Drifting any which way ♪
♪ When my life is funny ♪
♪ You'll hear me laughing ♪
♪ Not a lover can do me ♪
♪ The way that you do me ♪
♪ I wanna follow my sun ♪
♪ And I know I will find you ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
[somber music]
♪ We will meet in the garden ♪
♪ In the Garden of Eden ♪
♪ I will give you my love ♪
♪ You will give life a reason ♪
♪ Left to beg and to borrow ♪
♪ For today and tomorrow ♪
♪ We've been saving our love ♪
♪ Maybe we may be enough ♪
♪ To last us forever ♪
♪ And ever ♪
♪ Living day after day ♪
♪ Drifting any which way ♪
♪ When my life is funny ♪
♪ Do you hear me laughing ♪
♪ Not a lover can do me ♪
♪ The love that will do me ♪
♪ I will follow my sun ♪
♪ And I know I will find you ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
♪ Not a lover can do me ♪
♪ No other will do me ♪
♪ And I know I will find you ♪
- Goodbye.
♪ Wherever you are ♪
- [Michael] What do you mean, goodbye?
- See you later, darling.
- Sarah.
Sarah, what kind of stupid joke is this?
[door thudding]
Ugh.
[groaning]
[door thudding]
[elevator creaking]
- Michael!
Hey, Michael!
- Wait, wait, don't move, I'm coming!
[faint band music]
You're a crazy sadist.
Where do you get your ideas?
- [Sarah] Oh, you're not
really angry, are you?
- Hmmm.
It was hours before the
maid came and untied me.
My wrists are all black and blue.
- Oh, poor darling.
- I'm not into bondage.
Just what do you take me for?
- I know, I want to make love to you.
[faint upbeat band music]
Ah.
Here.
- Hey.
- It's a present for you.
A piece offering from me to your wrist.
I love gold against a man's skin.
- [Michael] I'm not used to
getting gifts from women.
- That's why I bought it for you.
I like to show a man I really care.
- "100," what does it mean?
- Do you like it?
- It's beautiful but you shouldn't have.
- Oh, by the way,
can you sing?
- I couldn't carry a tune in a basket.
- It doesn't matter.
♪ Bad breath reminds me of you ♪
♪ I love to lick your eyes of blue ♪
♪ Piss, bark ♪
♪ Poop, poop ♪
Are you auditioning too?
- Excuse me?
- Are you auditioning too?
- What?
- Oh, no, no.
- I'm a song writer, the best there is.
You wanna hear my song?
- Yeah, sure.
- That's great.
♪ Bad breath reminds me of you ♪
♪ I love to lick your eyes of blue ♪
♪ Piss, barf, fart, poop ♪
♪ Whatever you do, I love you ♪
♪ More and more and more ♪
What do you think?
- Oh.
It's great.
[dog whimpering]
It'll be a hit for sure.
- [Announcer] Michael
Terenzi, 5th floor, please.
- Oh, that's me.
- Great, good luck, man.
♪ Bad breath reminds me of you ♪
♪ I love to lick your eyes of blue ♪
♪ Piss, barf, fart, poop ♪
♪ Whatever you do ♪
♪ Bad breath reminds me of you ♪
♪ I love to lick your eyes of blue ♪
♪ Kiss, fart ♪
[dog yawning]
♪ Barf, poop ♪
- Michael, come in, come in,
Sarah's waiting for you.
- What kind of place is this?
- This is a palace of
culture, Sarah's playground.
- You mean this is her's?
- Well, we used to be partners.
Sarah's waiting for you in the studio.
It's straight ahead.
Okay, Sarah, I'm ready to
roll the tape, all right?
- Just a second, Charlie.
Put this on.
Ready.
- [Charlie] You got it.
[upbeat pop music]
♪ Love, love, love ♪
- All right, kids, get ready.
Sarah, we're almost there.
- Okay, Charlie, just get
everything ready and beat it.
[laughing]
- Aye, aye, sir.
It's all set, Sarah.
Good luck, Michael.
[upbeat pop music]
- And now it's up to us.
- But, Sarah, I told you I can't sing.
- You don't have to sing.
We just have to record a
background of heavy breathing.
But I wanted it to sound real.
[upbeat saxophone music]
♪ Love, love, love ♪
♪ This is the power of love ♪
♪ Every time you watch ♪
♪ Every time you smile ♪
♪ This is the power of love ♪
♪ Every time you go ♪
♪ Deep inside of me ♪
♪ This is the power of love ♪
♪ Love, love, love ♪
[upbeat music]
♪ Oh my God, baby, you're so nice ♪
[heavy breathing]
♪ Love, love, love, love ♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪ Oh baby, you're so sexy ♪
♪ Those lips are so juicy, oh my God ♪
♪ Why don't you come
closer something, baby ♪
♪ You look so nice tonight ♪
[music cutting]
[exciting saxophone music]
- Oh, what a beautiful film.
So touching, so romantic.
Great film, Michael?
Michael!
[groaning]
Michael, you were sleeping.
- Oh.
Is it over?
- Take me home, Michael.
- Helen, wait.
Forget it.
[dial tone buzzing]
[coin clinking]
Sarah?
Sarah, are you home?
- What do you want?
What the hell are you doing here?
Who said you could come tonight?
- Come on, Sarah, let me in.
Please, I want to be with you.
I need you.
You drive me crazy.
- Do you want me to spell it out for you?
I'm not alone.
Understand?
- I don't care who he
is, tell him to go home.
- Why don't you tell him yourself?
Go right ahead.
- Don't think I won't.
Huh?
What's this?
- Well, Michael?
What're you waiting for?
- Hi, Michael.
You know, you're real cute.
- So, Michael, as you were saying?
[chuckling]
Michael, meet Francine.
- [Francine] Oh, honey, you
are just my type of guy.
- Two's company.
- Hey, Sarah!
- Have a nice time, kitties.
- Hey, gorgeous, don't be
afraid, I won't eat you.
[giggling]
Come on.
[melancholy saxophone music]
Well, at least I know when to quit.
It was a no-hit ballgame, Sarah.
We never even got going.
I think he's of the gay persuasion.
I did what I could.
Thanks, I'll be seeing you.
[melancholy saxophone music]
[coughing]
- Here.
Take it.
- Thanks.
- [Old Lady] My pleasure, son.
[laughing]
[melancholy saxophone music]
[chuckling]
[distant traffic commotion]
- Helen.
What're you doing here?
- I've been waiting all night for you.
I wanted to spend the night with you
and wake up with you in the morning.
Doesn't matter, you're here now.
- Helen, I'm just bushed.
Let me take you home.
- I don't wanna go home, Michael.
- Come on, let's go.
[somber music]
[distant car horns honking]
- Michael?
There's another woman, isn't there?
More exciting, sexier than I am.
I know I'm not great in that department.
But I love.
I love you so much that I understand
and I know that it's
probably my fault anyway.
I can try to change.
I would do anything to keep you, Michael.
I would do anything for you.
Anything.
[door creaking]
- Hey, lady, fancy meeting you here.
Sit down.
Come on now.
Sit down and tell me all about it.
What'll you have, huh?
- Where is he?
- [Dan] Where is who?
- Michael!
- Oh, I sent him over to the job.
It's getting kinda busy over there.
- He says it's your fault.
- [Dan] Michael's the
best engineer I've got.
- He says you make him work day and night.
All night.
- Sometimes I do.
You know the problems we're
having over there right now.
You know I need Michael over there.
The unions are threatening a shutdown--
- What's she like?
- [Dan] What're you talking about?
- Is she pretty?
- Helen, I don't follow you.
- Don't tell me that
you don't know her, Dan.
- Helen, I...
I don't know what--
- Oh, cut it out!
- [Dan] Cut what out?
- We're friend, right, Dan?
We've known each other for a long time.
- Oh, the hell with it, Helen.
I've only seen her once.
Look, I can assure you
there's nothing to it.
It's just a fling, a last hurrah.
Just give him some time to
get it out of his system
and you'll have nothing to worry--
- We're getting married in five days, Dan!
- [Dan] Come on, Helen,
everything will work
itself out for the best.
Trust me.
Now get a hold of yourself
and see this thing through like big girl.
I wouldn't lie to you, Helen.
Helen!
- Sorry, Dan, just forget it.
- Jesus.
Shit.
[machinery rumbling]
Hey, Michael, wait up!
We've got to have a little talk.
I wish I didn't have to say this
but Helen's a friend of mine
and I don't like what you're doing to her.
You can't have it both ways, man,
you've got to make up your mind.
The girl's suffering.
You don't give a damn about her, do you?
- Dan, I'm sorry.
- What the hell kind of answer is that?
Why don't you go home and
relax and take a shower
and go over to Helen's and apologize?
There's nothing to it.
Michael, you're going to
have to make up your mind.
You cannot have it both ways.
You cannot marry two women.
- Sure, you're right.
You're absolutely right.
But I've got to run now, I've got a date.
- A date.
Shit.
[exciting synthesizer music]
♪ When your eyes meet mine I wonder ♪
♪ What you do to me ♪
♪ Suddenly I need you desperately ♪
♪ Never did my wildest dream ♪
♪ End so recklessly ♪
♪ But where you are is where I wanna be ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ More than I would ever dare to say ♪
♪ You're the only one
I'll ever want this way ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ You're the place someone
where I can stray ♪
♪ And I feel as though my
heart is here to stay ♪
♪ I watch you ♪
♪ Watching me ♪
♪ Say you'll save tonight for me ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Me and you ♪
♪ You and me ♪
♪ That's the way it's gonna be ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Save tonight for me ♪
[exciting saxophone music]
♪ When your lips meet mine ♪
♪ You're very touch is ecstasy ♪
♪ And every time ♪
♪ You take me by surprise ♪
♪ You're the lightening in the darkness ♪
♪ You're the mystery ♪
♪ But I know you ♪
♪ Your name is paradise ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ More than I would ever dare to say ♪
♪ You're the only one
I ever want this way ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ You're the place I
wonder where I can stay ♪
♪ And I feel as though my
heart is here to stay ♪
♪ I watch you watching me ♪
♪ Say you'll save tonight for me ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Me and you ♪
♪ You and me ♪
♪ That's the way it's gonna be ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Save tonight for me ♪
♪ When your lips meet mine ♪
♪ You're very touch is ecstasy ♪
♪ And every time you take me by surprise ♪
♪ You're the lightening in the darkness ♪
♪ You're the mystery ♪
♪ But I know you, your name is paradise ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ More than I would ever dare to say ♪
♪ You're the only one
I ever want this way ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ You're the place I
wonder where I can stay ♪
♪ And I feel as though ♪
♪ My heart is here to stay ♪
♪ I watch you watching me ♪
♪ Say you'll save tonight for me ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Me and you, you and me ♪
♪ That's the way it's gonna be ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Save tonight for me ♪
♪ Why don't you save tonight ♪
♪ Come on and save tonight ♪
♪ Save, save ♪
[traffic commotion]
♪ Oh when the saints, oh when the saints ♪
♪ Oh when the saints come marching in ♪
[clattering]
♪ Oh I want to be in that number ♪
♪ When the saints come marching in ♪
- Helen.
- Hi, Mikey.
I cheated on you.
I didn't like that stuff but
he made me drink it anyway.
It was so funny.
- Let me help you, Helen.
[giggling]
[Helen humming tune]
That should clear your head.
[water sloshing]
[somber music]
- I didn't sleep with him.
I wanted to.
I tried but his hands were
so sweaty it made me sick.
- It all started as a joke.
A crazy stunt.
Just a game.
But now she's really gotten to me.
It's like a drug, I can't do without her.
- I can take it, Michael.
I can even give you up if you
tell me that you love her.
But not this way.
Not like this.
- I don't love her.
At least I don't think I do.
I'm so confused.
I don't know what to say.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
- [Sarah On Phone] Hi, Michael.
- Hello.
- [Sara On Phone] I had to talk to you.
I hope I'm not interrupting anything.
- I'm listening.
- Our contract expires in a few days.
I mean, nights,
and I want to spend every
last second with you my way.
Will you do anything I say?
Trust me, Michael.
You won't be sorry.
- Sarah, there's something
important I have to tell you.
- I don't wanna hear it.
All I wanna know is
are you with me or not?
- Yeah, I'm with you, Sarah.
- It's not just the book anymore, is it?
- Of course it isn't.
In fact, the whole story
goes into the shredder.
Michael's not appearing in this book.
I'll make up something
for my 100th conquest.
- What're you saying?
Are you taking leave of your senses?
- Don't you understand?
This has never happened before.
Not with anyone.
I guess I went too far.
No man ever gave me so much.
- That's exactly why the
piece is so exceptional.
Can't you see that, Sarah?
- For me, yes.
Not for him.
And maybe not for the
people who read the book.
I don't want everybody to hate me.
You got everything straight?
- I'm cool, lady.
- Good, now you just drop in like it was
the most natural thing in the world.
Don't worry about a thing.
Okay, okay.
You know you can count on me.
- No matter what goes down.
- You got it.
I'm your man.
- Here.
- Thanks.
- And give me a few minutes.
- All right.
[dramatic music]
♪ I will drink at the fountain ♪
♪ I will taste me a new love ♪
♪ Love as strong as you might ♪
♪ Would not be a true love ♪
♪ I'll give you love and pleasure ♪
♪ I will touch in the heart ♪
♪ Not my pleasure, my leisure ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ Living day after day ♪
♪ Drifting any which way ♪
♪ When my life is funny ♪
♪ Do you hear me laughing ♪
♪ Not a lover can do me ♪
♪ No other lover will do me ♪
♪ I wanna follow my sun ♪
♪ And I know I will find you ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
[pleasant beat music]
♪ We will meet in the garden ♪
♪ In the Garden of Eden ♪
♪ I will give you my love ♪
♪ You will life a reason ♪
♪ Left to beg and to borrow ♪
♪ For today and tomorrow ♪
♪ We've been saving our love ♪
♪ Maybe we may be enough ♪
♪ To last us forever ♪
♪ And ever ♪
♪ Living day after day ♪
♪ Drifting any which way ♪
♪ When my life is funny ♪
♪ Do you hear me, darling ♪
♪ Not a lover can do me ♪
♪ Because our love will do me ♪
♪ I will follow my sun ♪
♪ And I know I will find you ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
♪ Not a lover can do me ♪
♪ Because no other will do ♪
♪ And I know I will find you ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
[somber music]
- What the fuck is going on here?
Beat it, buster.
[smacking]
[yelping]
- Hey, what is this?
- Out, Out, you were great--
- I did what you said.
- Now just get out!
[groaning]
Poor darling.
[shower trickling]
[somber saxophone music]
- Oh.
- Michael.
Good morning, Michael.
Rise and shine.
Would you like to have breakfast with me?
Oh,
Michael, I should tell you that last night
was the last night we'll spend together.
The moment you leave this house,
in exactly one half hour,
we go back to being complete strangers.
- Is this another one
of your games, Sarah?
- Eleven nights, remember?
By the way,
weren't you supposed to
get married this morning?
You better hurry.
We don't want to keep the
blushing bride waiting.
Hmmmm.
I see.
Mm-hmm.
Here.
- What's this?
- Don't look so shocked, dear.
You've given me some wonderful
material for my book.
"My 100 Men."
Oh my, how time flies.
I have a press conference
in exactly half an hour.
You can take a shower while
I finishing making up.
- So I'm number 100, huh?
- There's nothing to fear.
I won't use your name.
I've cut the unpleasant parts.
My book's about fun and games.
And I believe that sex is
the biggest game in town,
only there's nothing sexy about
making a bloody fool out of somebody.
Don't you agree?
- Then you did all this just
for that dirty book of yours!
- Let go!
- Why me?!
Why me?!
- Because you're so defenseless, Michael!
The perfect victim.
The part played by women!
[whimpering]
- This is number 100,
showing you how he thinks
the story's gonna end!
[whimpering]
Number 100 has learned a thing
or two these last 11 days!
[Sarah whimpering]
- No.
No, don't!
- Hold still, damn you!
[Sarah whimpering]
You're not worth the trouble.
Fuck you!
[crying]
- I...
I didn't mean it.
Michael.
I love you.
[crying]
[doorbell ringing]
[pleasant beat music]
- Helen, forgive me.
♪ When your eyes meet mine I wonder ♪
♪ What you'll do to me ♪
♪ Suddenly I need you desperately ♪
♪ Never did my wildest dream ♪
♪ End so recklessly ♪
♪ But where you are is where I wanna be ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ More than I will ever dare to say ♪
♪ You're the only one
I'll ever want this way ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ You're the place I
wander where I can stray ♪
♪ And I feel as though my
heart is here to stay ♪
♪ I watch you watching me ♪
♪ Say you'll save tonight for me ♪
♪ Keep savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Savin', savin', savin' ♪
♪ Me and you ♪
♪ You and me ♪
♪ That's the way it's going to be ♪