[Man Narrat/ng] Near the end
of the [hing Dynasty,
there was a large inﬂux
of opium into China,
and a large amount ofsilver
/eﬁ‘ China.
The country
was rapidly becoming poor,
and people ’s standard of /i ving
was deteriorating
This, in turn, led to
a breakdo wn in la w and order
China saw the need
to ban opium,
so in the 7 8th year of
the Emperor Tao K wong’s reign,
special commissioner [in Ze Xu
was sent to Canton...
to enforce
an /mperial opium ban.
— YourHonor.
— Master Wong.
I would thankyou
foryour warm welcome.
I shall need yourfull cooperation
ifwe‘re to succeed with the opium ban.
You can count on me, sir.
As head ofthe martial arts
association,
|sha|| do my utmost to wipe out
the sickness that is destroying us.
Good. We shall work together
to get rid ofopium.
- Right?
— [All Shouting]
[Men Shouting]
Destroy opium! Strengthen China!
Destroy opium!
Strengthen China!
[Shouting Continues]
[Onlookers Cheering]
[ Boat Horn Blows]
— [ Cheering Continues]
— [Man] Hello!
[ Men C on i/ersing ]
[ Man]
Greetings!
This is the government permit.
— Oh! Very good! [ Laughing]
— [ Men App/auding ]
[Men Shouting]
— Let‘s go!
— Come on!
— Protect them!
- Right!
Come on!
Come on, you!
[Man]
The commissioner has arrived’
— [Chuckles] Master Wong.
— Welcome, Your Honor.
— Out ofthe way!
Close in.
Let me, teacher.
[Chuckles]
Excuse me.
Okay, brothers!
Let‘s destroy the opium now!
[Shouting]
Come on!
Get outta here!
On your feet!
Come on! Come on!
Get outta here!
— Druggies!
—Come on!
Come on!
Up the stairs!
[Shouting Continues]
— Out! Out!
— [ Laughing] Get outta here!
— Move ‘em out!
— Get outta here!
— Outside!
— Get ‘em outside!
— Burn it.
— Yes, sir!
[Cheering]
[Man]
Come on. Give me a hand.
Come on. Move it up.
Move it up there.
That damned Lin Ze Xu
and Wong Fei Hong...
have cost us
great losses today.
Ifthe ban isn‘t lifted soon,
I‘ll order my ﬂeet to sail into the harbor
and show them how powerful our guns are.
We mustn‘t cause
an international incident.
You need a Chinese to deal with the Chinese,
and better still, an ofﬁcer.
I think he means
the 12th Prince.
But he‘s miles away in Peking.
What can he do?
— Anyway, by the time he arrives——
— [Man] His Highness, the prince!
[All]
Your Highness!
You shouldn‘t be frightened
by a mere commissioner.
And Wong Fei Hong is nobody.
They are not strong enough to stop us.
Besides, Lin Ze Xu
is a Han Chinese.
—He can’t ﬁght against me, a Manchu prince.
— But Wong Fei Hong is tough.
He‘s nothing to me.
Let me tell you this.
I also have a tough ﬁghter
on our side.
He is known as Beggar So.
With him we need not fear
Wong Fei Hong.
— Good!
— Very clever!
[Man]
/ wonder what he wants.
[Chuckling ] Thankyou, everybody,
very much for coming today.
First, to all
you charitable people,
let me say
I‘m honored to have you here.
The reason
I‘ve asked you here today...
is to introduce to all ofyou a drug which
I‘ve been working on for a long time——
the magniﬁcent anti—opium pill!
—[A|l Murmuring]
— Poor Kwan.
Since he married
into that family,
he‘s suffered even more
than when he was a beggar.
That‘s why he made those pills—— to earn
himselfa name and get out from under.
[ Laughs]
Quiet, please.
Quiet, everybody.
Be quiet.
Now, | witness every day...
the harm that opium does
to our people.
It‘s sad.
It really makes me want to cry.
So I‘ve spent countless sleepless nights,
as well as money,
trying to come up with a solution,
and | tell you
this does work!
So we‘re saved at last!
— [ Cheering ]
— And China will be saved’
— But...
— [ Cheering, Applause 5ubsides]
too bad the drug
is not cost—effective.
It costs too much to make.
Ordinary smokers may not
be able to afford it.
— [ Disappointed Murmuring]
—That‘s a shame.
Therefore, I‘ve asked you all
to come here today...
to contribute to a charitable cause.
— |fyou have money, give it!
— [Shouting Afﬁrmations]
— Help in anywayyou can!
—[Shouting Continues]
Support the Sos/
Support me, the son—in—law!
That is me! Support me!
Support this worthy cause!
Aaaah/ 0hh/
_ - Ohh!
You okay?
— You can see me?
—[Groaning] Support me!
Get away! Get away!
Get off him!
| see you‘ve
undertaken something.
So he wants you to support him,
to be a real man.
— What were you yelling so loudly for?
— [Continues Groaning]
You trying to defy me?
You want to control me, huh?
You want to help people?
You just want their support.
|thinkyou‘rejust
doing it foryourself.
Check ifthe young master‘s up
and tell him to come and eat.
— So you want to defy me.
— Please,]ean, let me get up. All right?
Idon‘t want my son to see me like this.
It‘s embarrassing.
You‘re the embarrassment ‘round here,
selling phony drugs!
—Get up!
— [ Groans]
All you know is money——
— Ah, honored son.
— Son!
— [jean] You ’re up already?
- Hi.
Hey, what is it this time?
What is ityou‘ve done?
Your father will ruin
the So family one day.
What are you doing?
You only sit after me!
Hey, Auntie, sit down.
Relax.
— Sit down.
— You don‘t know what he‘s done.
He‘s broken our family rule——
Don‘t get involved in politics.
No, no, no, look.
Ijust made those pills because I believe
they‘ll make a name for ourfamily.
You mean you‘ve successfully
made the anti—opium pills?
Don‘t you believe in that.
What anti—opium pills?
They‘rejust a laxative.
You shouldn‘t do that. It‘s fraud.
You‘ll get us all into trouble.
It won‘t kill anybody.
Just loosen up the bowel movement.
— |t cleans up the system.
—Shut up!
I was talking to your son!
— You shouldn‘t cut in like that!
—But he‘s my son!
All right, calm down, both ofyou.
Let‘s eat, huh?
[Both Grunting]
Don ’t ﬁght There ’s plenty of food
/ thought / was the beggar.
But you’re worse than me. You two look
as if you haven ’t eaten for three days.
— [ Grunting]
— [Coughing]
— Have you two ﬁnished then?
—I have.
— I‘m off.
— Hey! Hey, where are you going, son?
You haven‘t eaten any!
You crazy?
Don‘t you remember?
—|t‘sthe 15th. He has to go beg, you old fart!
— Oh, yeah—— Yeah! Enough!
— You‘re living in a daze!
— All right! Don‘t use bad language!
— So what if| do, huh?
— [ Groans]
Hey, you ready?
—Yeah,yeah, I‘m coming.
— Ain‘t got all day.
— Mr. Chang!
— Here you go.
— Hi, Mr. Wong! You‘re looking prosperous!
— Here you are.
— [ Man #7 ]A beggar’s giving money out?
— [ Man #2 ] That’s Beggar 5o.
[ Man #2] The 5o ﬁami/y
are the richest people here.
He’s the on/yboyin the ﬁami/y,
so the granddad beingsuperstitious,
belie i/ed a fortune—teller and adopted
a beggar to be the boy’s godfather.
On every ﬁrst and 75th of the month
he has to go and beg
[People Chattering, Laughing]
Hey, here we are.
— Come on! Food time!
— [Cheering]
Hey, a roast goose!
Come on!
[Chattering, Cheering Continue]
Hey, don‘t ﬁght. There‘s plenty for everyone.
Come on. Don‘t ﬁght.
I‘ll have a bite! Mmm!
[Both Grunting]
— Hey! Careful, Dad!
—[Grunting] No!
Great!
[Laughing]
Mmm! Mmm!
Dad, the two strikes you taught me
last time were excellent!
— Ofcourse!
— Thanks!
But one goose is not really enough
for all of us.
Well, I‘ve come prepared.
Here, catch!
How‘s that? Is that enough?
Wow. Did you see how my godfather
catches them? His kung fu is really amazing.
He ’s a real master, forsure.
[Laughing]
— Yea!
— Come on!
Son, now so far I‘ve taught you
almost everything I know.
I must say, I never thought
I‘d have an heir to carry on my skills.
But, Dad, you‘re a true master.
|fyou agree
to come out of retirement,
I‘m sure the Beggars Clan
would once again become famous.
Mmm. [ Laughing]
I‘m an old man now.
|f| were ten years younger,
maybe I would set up a branch.
Right! We‘d be famous again!
Now, you must have a drink with me,
and you can‘t say no.
But, Dad,you know| don‘t drink!
I‘ll get drunk easily!
— No, Dad, you‘re wasting it. Don‘t do that.
— All our clan members drink.
I really can‘t drink.
It has nothing to do with being a beggar.
Hey, listen to me, boy.
Wine takes you
to another world.
— |fyou don‘t drink, you‘ll never know the clan.
— No, Dad.
— Come on! Drink now!
— No!
— Come on!
—I don‘t want any!
You‘re gonna waste it!
Stop it!
Get offme.
Get him offme, huh?
Master, the Fire Lotus gang,
they‘re having another ritual.
— [Man] They’re hai/inga parade tool
— What‘s that?
To ﬁeld for donations
in return for their blessings!
— They want to drive us out ofbusiness.
— [Godﬁather] Real/y?
— Yeah.
— Huh? Hey! Whereyou going?
Hey! You keep away
from those people!
[Sighs]
The Fire Lotus are pretty strong.
He should ﬁnd out
about those people.
Can‘tjust go in
and confront them.
[Cheering, Laughing]
,‘,‘ [ Drums, Cymbals]
,‘,‘[ Traditional Chinese, Celebratory]
Hey! What‘s going on?
Is there some kind ofcelebration?
[Man] Ha i/en ’t you heard?
It’s the Fire Lotus parade!
— Hey, let‘s ﬁnd a good spot, teacher!
— Hey.
,‘,‘ [Continues]
[ Fire works Crack/ing, Exploding]
[Applause, Cheering]
— Yea!
— Here they come!
— Wonderful!
[ Man #7 ]
Make way. Make way.
[ Man #2]
L oi/e/y!
Yea!
— Is that the holy girl?
— It must be!
[ Man Murmurs]
There she is. The holy girl
[ Woman] Excuse me!
Clear the way, please!
— [ Crowd Murmuring ]
— Thankyou very much.
Hey, teacher!
Foreign women! Look, sir!
— Ready?
— [Photographer] Yeah.
—[Crowd Gasping]
— [Woman Gasps]
The Holy Mother is here!
—[Crowd Murmuring]
— [ Man] O Holy Mother, give us your blessing.
[Chanting]
Holy Mother, give us your blessing.
— [Chanting Continues]
— This is nonsense.
These people are all phonies.
You mustn‘t believe them.
Kwan.
[Chanting Continues, Murmured]
— You‘re evil, possessed by foreign generals!
— Shut up!
[Grunting]
Hyah!
— You‘ve broken the law by assaulting me!
— Huh?
All these people can be witnesses.
Now let‘s peel offtheir masks,
expose their true face,
and / shall write about
their e i/i/ doings in m y paper.
— Aaaa h!
— [ Man Muttering] Uh—oh.
— [Crowd Gasping]
— Stop that!
[Yelling]
[Crowd Laughing]
Hmm.
H ey!
Greetings.
My dear friends, the Fire Lotus
are performing this ritual...
to give blessings
to the general public.
It is all in the interests ofthe people.
Now, to get the blessings
we need the Holy Mother,
who is the divine
messenger from heaven,
to beat the drum
49 times consecutive/y.
You can try,
but ordinary people can ’t do it
— Teacher, you try it.
—I don‘t believe it.
— I‘ll try.
— Please.
[ Cro wd Continues Murmuring]
Hyah—— Oww!
— It‘s a trick. She used darts.
— Really?
[Groaning]
Let‘s not waste time.
Now let‘s have the Holy Mother
beat the blessing drum for us.
—[Fluttering]
— Let me try!
It‘s not so hard!
[ Crowd Gasping, Cheering]
Hyah!
[Shouting]
He really can ﬁght.
Right, teacher?
— [ Man] Yeah!
—Stop him!
[Shouting Continues]
That‘s enough.
You‘ve proved your point.
Everybody outta here!
[Crowd Screaming]
[Groans]
Aah!
Teacher, there‘s many casualties!
— Take ‘em to the clinic.
— Right.
[ People Groaning]
— [ Man] Oh, no!
— Okay, okay.
Careful. Easy, easy. Come on.
[Groaning Continues]
The serious ones inside!
Oh, my leg!
Steady now.
Teacher, this one‘s dying.
— It‘s okay.
— You gotta come. I can‘t handle this one.
— He‘s over there.
— [ Man Shouts] Oh, man! Myleg!
[Sobbing] Oh, please, Master Wong,
my son‘s bleeding to death!
— Can you deal with her?
— Please, you‘ve gotta help me.
You‘ve gotta do something!
— Come on, madam. He‘ll be ﬁne.
— He‘s gonna die!
— [ Man Screaming]
— [Man] Come on. Help me.
— Sit down here.
— [Screaming Continues]
— The powder!
- Oh!
Here.
[Woman Continues Sobbing]
[Screaming Intensiﬁes]
[Man]
Pin him down! He 7/ be ﬁne!
Master Wong, how is my son now?
Will he ever be able to walk?
Don‘t worry. He‘ll be ﬁne.
We‘ve stopped the bleeding.
But, uh, he won‘t walk
for six months.
Thankyou, Master Wong.
[ Man]
In the corner. Over there.
So Chai, you——
you‘re a reckless, bigheaded fool!
Ah. Here, son.
Your tea.
— Tea, Master Wong?
— Hey, come here, Dad.
Why are you serving tea yourself?
Where are all the servants?
Look, we‘ll be having a major discussion.
I don‘t want outsiders here.
— Master——
— Let me do the talking. I can handle this.
Master Wong, you don‘t go for the villains——
instead, you blame me.
— That‘s not fair.
— He‘s right.
Ofcourse the Fire Lotus are at fault,
but you caused a disaster.
I told everybody to leave.
It‘s not my fault they‘re so slow.
Hey, no excuses.
We were there.
|thinkyou should
compensate the victims.
Ah, ﬁnally the truth comes out.
— He‘s after money. So how much? Huh?
— Tell us.
You‘re wrong. Of course you should
compensate the disaster victims.
But still, in order
to calm people down,
you should publicly
apologize to them.
— Right.
- Oh!
So, is that all you want?
Well, that‘s simple.
You can count on me.
Come here, son.
[Chuckling]
My son, this is a good deal. All he wants
is an apology. We don‘t have to pay anything.
| always say “sorry“ tojean.
It‘s no big deal. It‘s like acting.
Look, Father, you‘re already
an embarrassment to the family.
|f| submit to that too, people will say
the So family men are of no use.
— Think so?
— Yes, ofcourse!
— Then no apology.
— No way!
— Ofcourse.
Master Wong, my son says he won‘t apologize,
but he will pay compensation.
But, Master, ifyour son doesn‘t come out
and apologize to people,
it may be difﬁcult for him
to stay in Fu Shen.
What? That was an accident!
You can‘t hold me responsible!
Don‘t you feel anything
for the dead and the dying?
Are you threatening me?
—This is no threat, pal!
— Calm down,young man!
— We can talk this over.
— You should learn to control your son!
— [ Groans]
—You asked forit.
What kind of teacher are you?
Can‘t your students ﬁght?
— You‘re too much!
— [ Both Grunting]
[Both Shouting]
— No, stop!
— Don‘t worry.
— My master‘s not gonna kill your son.
— No, my son might kill him!
Very good. Wong Fei Hong, the Tiger
ofCanton, is really as good as they say.
— [Wong] Who are you, sir?
— [Man] You fool! Knee/ down!
This is the 1 2th Prince here.
It‘s all right.
I came here especially to see So Chai.
I‘m sorry that we disturbed you.
Ah!
[Chuckling]
Your Highness, I‘m so honored byyour
presence here. They werejust fooling around.
— As you have business here, I won‘t delayyou.
—We||, thankyou.
— I‘ll talktoyou later.
— Well, let me see you out.
Well, Brother So,
since I last saw you in Peking
your kung fu has improved very considerably.
Thankyou, sir.
You ﬁatter me.
Look, I‘m sorry.
My son is too cocky.
But he‘s not a bad boy.
Just leave it to me. He‘ll apologize.
Your son is a very good ﬁghter,
but he‘s overconﬁdent.
I agree. I know that.
This way, sir.
So that’s what happened Your Highness.
Do you think / should be held responsible?
Mmm.
It seems that this Wong Fei Hong
is a very righteous man.
—Hmm?
-Oh?
— Why do you say that?
— He‘s asked you to apologize to the victims.
Well, ifhe was,
he should have intervened then.
I think he‘sjust using this incident
to gain credit for himself.
Well, not everybody is like you and me,
Brother So, because we‘re real.
But some want that fame
and they will go to any lengths.
Ah, that‘s why I admire you
so much, Your Highness.
And | feel the same foryou.
— Come, let‘s have a drink together.
— Hey, you know I don‘t drink.
— Ofcourse she is.
— You know I‘m very picky.
|f|‘m not satisﬁed with her,
Iwon‘t payyou, and I do mean that.
— Don‘t say I didn‘t warn you.
— I‘m sureyou‘ll like her.
— Sir, inside.
— Thankyou. Thankyou.
Uh, waiter!
[Laughing]
So, where is she?
Come on. Show me.
There. The one reading the newspaper.
You see her?
Ah.
[Chuckling]
She must‘ve been brought up overseas.
She‘s dressed like one ofthem.
Oh, yes. She says she wants to know
what an arranged marriage is.
That‘s why she‘s agreed to come.
— Miss Yi?
— Madam Bo.
I‘m so sorry we‘re late.
We were held up in trafﬁc.
It‘s true. I‘m sorry.
Shouldn‘t keep a lady waiting.
How are you today?
Uh, I‘m very sorry.
Madam Bo, this girl
doesn‘t seem very polite.
— She‘s asking me how I‘m going to die!
— Maybe we misheard her.
Try saying something.
Go on, see. Try it. Go on.
All right. How do you do?
How do you do?
[Chuckling]
Miss Yi, Master So
is the richest man here.
He‘s so good looking.
[Chuckles]
And very intelligent too!
— Girls ﬂock to meet him like bees to honey.
— T h i s m a n ?
Yes, ofcourse—— Oh, no!
It was so when I was 20 years younger.
It‘s my son, So Chai.
Myson needs a strong woman,
and you ’re educated overseas,
so I‘m sure you‘d qualify for——
[ Men Shouting]
Hey, watch what
you‘re doing there, huh?
[Shouting Continues]
Your father‘s fooling around
with another woman! I saw him myselﬂ
Hey! Whoa!
—Yourtrousers!
- [All] Huh?
—[A|| Murmuring]
— [ Chuckling] See? That‘s my son.
Doesn‘t he look like me?
— That‘s your son?
— That‘s him!
— I‘m a missionary!
—You should go!
— God bless you
— Never mind that. Go on!
Go, go! Quickly! Go on!
[All Murmuring]
— Hey, let‘s take a picture. Come on. Huh?
— Okay.
Put your trousers on!
You have parents! Oh! Oh!
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
— Hey! I‘ve got mine on!
— [jean] Where ’s your dad?
— Come on. Let‘s go.
— Hey, hey, hey! Be careful!
— Over there.
-Ohh!
— Are you all right?
—Areyou okay? [ Laughing]
—|‘m all right.
— I‘m sorry.
— You ruined my teeth!
[Chuckling Nervously]
—| tell you, he‘s with another woman.
— [Continues Chuckling]
See what a nice boy he is.
And he loves playing balls.
Bye—bye! Bye—bye!
| used to play balls as well.
Maybe someday we can play together.
We—— We play balls?
[Whimpering]
Better than music!
Oh, listen, my son‘s mother,
I got lucky today, you know.
I met this pretty thing.
Oh, she‘s really beautiful!
— Is she prettier than me? Huh?
— Oh, no!
— [Yells]
— No, I don‘t mean that!
— [ Groaning]
—You lied?
No, you‘re the prettiest! No one‘s prettier
than you! Oh—whoa—whoa—whoa—whoa!
What have you been doing today?
Nothing. Ijust went
to see about the marriage.
— What‘s that?
— Oh, no, no, no!
You‘re an unfaithful bastard!
My sister would kill you ifshe saw you now!
Aaah! Come on!
She‘s been dead for 20 years!
— Don‘t talk back!
— Hey!
Keep quiet, Father.
Now, Auntie, do it for me. Forgive him.
No more girls, huh?
Areyou chasing girls?
Oh, come on, son!
I‘m not doing anything!
—You heard him.
— Okay, you go.
Okay.
— Hey, son! You‘ll like the girl I met today!
— [Yelling]
Oh, no! No, no, no!
No, please! Oh, no! Let me go!
You old fool! Don‘t you contaminate
your son! You old lecher!
You dirty old man! Scumbag! Garbage!
Good—for—nothing slime!
You really piss me off!
Don‘t you know
I always loved you?
Huh? What‘s that,]ean?
What did you sayjust now?
The last thing you said——| didn‘t catch it.
Son! Son, lock him in the barn
and don‘t feed him today!
Hey, come on! That‘s not what you said!
What was it, huh?
— Sorry, sir. I‘ve gotta do it.
— I‘m not sure I can walk.
[Sighs]
Hey! Hi, Dad.
—This place is not bad.
— |fyou like it that much, we‘ll swap places.
— I‘m no lecher.
— Neither am |. I did it foryou.
Oh,yes, | see. You come visiting me,
and you don‘t bring me a thing.
I can get girls too now,
thankyou.
— Here, a little something foryou.
— What‘s that?
-Ohh!
— [ Laughing] Enjoyit.
Oh, you do care about me
after all.
Hey, I‘ve got wine,
but I‘ve got no food to go with it.
Stop pretending, Dad.
Let‘s see it.
— What?
—Well, what is it?
— [ Groans]
— Wow! Look at all that!
Shh! Loweryour voice!
It‘s better than what I get out there!
— Shh. Not so loud. Your aunt will kill me.
—I know.
Then stop shouting.
The whole goddamn house will hearyou.
— Okay, come on. Let‘s attack this.
— Right.
— For me? Ahh—— Hey, hey, hey!
— Of course, foryou ﬁrst.
[Laughing]
You like to fool around, don‘t you?
— Huh?You bad son.
— Like father, like son. [ Laughing]
— You can have that. Enjoy!
— Enjoy.
— Mm—mmm.
-Ohh!
— This is great, Dad
— Yeah!
— Have a drink.
— You too, Dad.
I‘m too late.
[ So Chai] The chicken
is ﬁesher than that girl today.
— [ K wan ] She studied abroad
— Oh, so that’s why.
[Sighs]
I‘m not on heat or anything,
but I‘m attracted to his na'i'vete.
He‘s kind, I suppose.
He‘s square,
but at the same time seductive.
That mustache ofhis
is driving me nuts.
Well, after all, I‘m your sister.
Can you tell me howl can
get him interested in me?
How can I turn him on likea light?
[ Woman’s l/oice]
Huh?
Hmm. You‘d better not say anything.
I‘ll ﬁgure it out.
Huh!
More tea over here.
Okay, coming.
JM Humming]
— You‘ve got balls, boy!
— Whoa!
— You’re real/ysomething, madam.
- A h h.
So, you can see through me.
My name is Kwan.
|fyou‘re sick, you can come to me.
You‘ve got a smart mouth, boy.
What‘s that?
— Name a price.
— Price?
— How much do you charge?
— Oh, you mean to buy my herbs.
— No, you!
— Hey, madam, are you trying to seduce me?
— Are you a virgin?
— [Yells]
[Groans]
—Oh, it‘ll costyou a lot.
— Is this enough?
I‘m not for sale.
— But as you‘re so keen——
— [ Moans]
Well, it shouldn‘t take long.
Oh, itwill, my dear.
— Hurry up. Time is not on my side.
—Well, maybe next time.
There won‘t be a next time.
— This is my ﬁrst time.
— You silly boy.
An hour is all you need.
It won‘t take long.
Come on. Sing for me.
Sing for me!
Ohh!
— Hey!
— [Chuckles]
You know something?
You two look good together.
My sister—in—law is the most attractive
in the village, especially her teeth.
You‘re a lucky man.
Hey,jean, I‘m so happy foryou
that you ﬁnally found a man.
When are you gonna get married?
How about today?
Wait! My hour is up! Can I go now?
You wanna ﬁnd a husband, ﬁnd someone else.
Hey, you get engaged ﬁrst!
He doesn‘t know
what he‘s missing.
Hey, wait!
[Chuckles]
You garbage! I‘m with another man,
and you don‘t even seem surprised!
[Wails]
You can‘t blame me.
What should I do, cry? Huh!
There it is!
The women‘s association!
[Crowd Shouting]
Where‘s my wife, huh?
[Shouting Continues]
We‘ve come here
to get our wives back.
— You can‘t go in. They‘re having a class.
— What?
A glass ofwhat? Oh, dear!
They‘re trying to drug our women!
— Come on! Let‘s go in!
— [Shouting Continues]
— [Speaks Chinese]
— [Class Repeats In Chinese]
— Man.
— [Class Repeats] Man.
[Chinese]
Woman.
What are you doing here?
Come home right now!
[Man]
Come along! Come home!
— [Screaming]
—[Shouting Continues]
Stop! I‘ve been
teaching them to read!
— Stop it!
— She‘s the one who started this!
— Gether!
— [ Gasps]
Ohh!
[Groaning, Wailing]
Kiki!
Twelfth Uncle.
These people are barbaric.
What areyou doing
in a place like this?
You must remember
you‘re a princess, Kiki.
The reason for this club, and the printing
press, is to educate women in China.
— Do you think that‘s wrong too?
— I don‘t.
But people here don‘t appreciate it.
You‘rejust wasting your time.
You‘d better return to Peking.
You watched me grow up.
You know I don‘t give up that easily.
I will persist with this.
Now, listen, I want you to stop
this women‘s club and printing pamphlets...
because I wantyou to stop
this silly anti—opium campaign.
Right now our country
is very weak, as you know,
and the foreigners are using this
to force us to import opium.
And we can‘t say no to them.
Ifthey wage war on us, we‘ll lose more.
But, Uncle, you know the opium——
Look, you should do something
more useful to help the country.
Here. I want you to
print this for me at once.
“Ofﬁcial opium is better"?
— But, Uncle——
— Hey.
The treasury is short ofmoney.
We can levy a big duty on opium.
This could make China strong again.
Now, here‘s some money.
This is just a deposit foryour work.
[jean]
Who is Miss Yi? Come out!
— [ Grunting]
— Hey! What do you want?
Back off!
Come out, you home—wrecker!
[Sighs]
Just what do you want with me?
So you‘re that man—eater,
heart—stealer!
I thought you were a lady,
but you‘re not pretty!
— Who are you? What do you want?
— Don‘t you know?
— I‘m the boss ofthe So family.
— Oh, you‘re his wife.
His wife died long ago,
but I‘m his beloved woman.
What are you staring at?
Are youjealous now?
Can‘tyou tell
I‘m not interested in him at all?
My goodness!
You ﬁlthy bitch!
So youjust toss a man away.
You need a bonk on the head to wake you up!
[Grunting, Gasping]
— Oh, you stupid!
—You bi—— [ Shrieks]
What are you doing, Auntie?
— Huh?
— What? She‘s your auntie?
Yeah. It‘s all a misunderstanding.
— How dare you take her side? I‘m your aunt!
— No, Auntie.
She‘s young and rich.
She‘s not interested in my father.
Rubbish! I saw them
hugging each other myselﬂ
Dad‘s not interested in
young, inexperienced girls.
He‘s not that blind, Auntie.
[Gasps]
I broke that camera.
[Chuckles]
You should apologize.
[jean]
Mmm.
I‘m sorry.
Leave it.
It‘s a misunderstanding.
— Our family‘s all nervous wrecks.
— Hey!
Are you saying
that‘s my weakness?
No, being rash is not a weak point,
it‘s a strong point.
— I was rash with your father last night!
— You mean, you and he——
— [Whines] I‘ve ruined his life!
—[Sighs]
Oh, I‘m so sorry!
[Sobbing]
I should have believed
what he said!
Why didn‘t he explain everything to me?
[Continues Sobbing]
—I must go and talkto him.
— Wait a minute. You can‘t go like that.
I‘m sorry.
I‘ll pay for the camera.
—[Whimpering]
— Hey, Auntie!
What about me?
[Chuckles]
She‘sjust a bit nuts.
— Brother So, you and Kiki. Very good!
— Your Highness, what a surprise.
—I don‘t know him.
— Oh, my father has arranged everything.
I‘m very happy with her.
I think she‘sjust a bit shy.
Well, we‘ll soon be family.
You can come visit my place.
Thankyou. I‘m ready.
— Shall we go now? [ Chuckling]
_ Hey__
[Gasps]
Huh! Hmm!
Hey, would you
like a puff, hmm?
Idon‘t smoke.
[Chuckles]
—You should tryit.
— No, thanks.
Hey, ifyou thinkyou‘re gonna get hooked,
thenjust look at me.
I smoke it three times a day,
and I‘m not hooked.
Instead, I feel great.
It’s all in the mind you know
I‘m not worried about that.
But no.
A man must try everything.
So, come on.
No, I‘m not interested.
Hey, you‘re not scared, are you?
Come on, Your Highness.
— You want to test me on a thing like that?
—I don‘t blameyou.
Even Wong Fei Hong
doesn‘t have the guts to try it.
Well, Wong Fei Hong is scared,
but it doesn‘t mean I am too.
Okay, I‘ll try it, Your Highness.
That‘s more like it.
[Coughing]
How do you feel?
Fine.Just ﬁne.
[Chuckles]
People say...
that opium must be banned.
Wong Fei Hong has even
opened up a stop—smoking class.
He doesn‘t know anything.
Come, have another pipe.
Come on.
All right.
[Chuckling]
Come along come along!
This is your chance ofa lifetime!
Come along!
Five days in the stop—smoking class,
you‘ll get 15 coppers.
Hurry up and enroll.
Fifteen coppers from the clinic.
So putyour name down
for the stop—smoking class.
— Excuse me, madam.
—What is it?
— Would you like to earn some extra money?
— I‘m not into that.
You‘re not an addict, but maybe your man is.
Men are easily seduced.
They fall deep, and they lose
their body and soul to the opium.
— Would you give your body to seduction?
— [Chuckles] Not you.
— Huh!
—We||——
No, please!
You must stop smoking!
No, I won‘t do it!
I‘d rather take the anti—opium pills!
Hey, those pills are no use.
All right, I‘ll give you 20 coppers.
Huh? Okay?
— Now go back to class.
— No, I won‘t go back in there!
— No more smoking! No! Come on!
— [Yelling]
Hey, hold it!
Let him go.
It‘s you again.
What do you want? Making more trouble?
I know whatyou‘re doing.
All this is to make a name foryour clinic.
— He doesn‘t want it. Let him go.
— You can go to hell.
— [ Grunting]
— [ Groaning]
— No! Please, no!
— [ Men Groaning]
—[ Man ] Come on!
— Please let me out!
—[Groaning Continues]
— You‘re trying to kill them!
[Yelling]
You wanna ﬁght?
Come on then!
[Gasps]
Teacher, it‘s So Chai.
He‘s making trouble.
Master Wong, what are you doing?
— A Chinese sauna?
— You‘re wrong.
That steam bath will help them to clear out
their poisoned systems ofthe toxins.
Have you smoked it?
Well, I have.
You know, a man ofstrong will
does not get hooked.
These people will smoke again
once they‘re out. This is useless.
— Who do you thinkyou are? Why don‘t you——
— Kwan!
Ifthey don‘t kick the habit,
there‘s no future for them, Chai.
It‘s a good thing to try and help,
but then you must
consider the consequences.
Otherwise, you‘ll do
more harm than good.
But what you‘re doing is no use,
and the consequences ofyour action
is to lose your clinic.
Chai, please don‘t push me too far.
— We‘re busy. Have a good day.
— Get out!
I‘ll go when they go.
You won‘t go?
Then I‘ll makeyou go.
[Man]
The commissioner has arrived!
Come on.
Master Wong,
is there some trouble here?
Not at all, Your Honor. | wasjust
practicing kung fu with So Chai.
My respects, Your Honor.
|t wasjust an exercise.
Thankyou, Brother Kwan,
for holding my boots.
Who‘s holding whose boots?
Your Honor, ifyou‘ll excuse me.
— Forget it, Kwan.
— He‘s a very good ﬁghter.
It‘s sad. He‘s still so naive.
[People Shouting, Chattering]
Sign up for
the Stop Opium campaign!
Support the campaign!
Sign up for our campaign!
Hey, what are you doing?
I‘ve done nothing wrong!
— Fingerprints, okay?
— Ah, you‘re crazy!
—Thankyou, sir.
— Hey, hey, hey. What‘s this all about?
For the anti—opium campaign.
Just sign this.
— I‘ll have nothing to do with it. Good—bye.
— Please, sir, come back.
Hey, hey! What are you doing?
— Please, sir, sign.
—Sign what?
What are you talking about?
Hey! Oh, look what you‘ve done
to my thumb. It‘s all dirty.
Damn women troublemakers.
— Ai —yaa h.
— [ Woman ] Sign your name up here!
What you‘re doing is no use.
You‘re wasting your time.
This is not a question ofopium.
It‘s a question ofwill.
[Sighs]
You make it sound so simple.
It‘s not a question ofstrong will.
Otherwise, Master Wong wouldn‘t
have to open a stop—smoking class.
Look, if| weren‘t your ﬁance
Iwouldn‘t waste time with you now.
|f| didn‘t care about you, I wouldn‘t bother
to tell you what I think about this. Okay?
A decent girl with a proper upbringing
wouldn‘t go shouting in the street.
— It‘s embarrassing for me.
— You‘re not my ﬁance.
I went to that meeting with your father
to collect information for my research.
I‘m a princess.
You think I‘d fancyyou?
Iwouldn‘t accept any arranged marriage
with a man likeyou.
— I‘m not so ugly that I need a matchmaker.
—Areyou saying I‘m ugly?
—| thoughtyou liked me.
— That‘s none of my business.
So good—bye, thickhead!
H—How could you?
You insulted me!
Yeah, that‘s right!
I‘m a man. I can‘t argue.
Tryit, and you‘ll lose!
Hmph!
Sign your name!
Join our campaign!
Damned peasant.
He‘s too much.
[Gasps]
What‘s that?
She said you‘re thick?
[Whimpers]
Now, that sounds to me
as ifshe‘s trying to openly seduce you.
So why don‘t you just follow it through
andjump at this opportunity.
Then you‘ll have her and her money.
— Hey!
— [ Groans]
Now, after all,
she is a member ofthe royal family.
Oooh.
So, ifyou can marry this gir|,you could
be made a minister or something.
Then the So family will not only be rich,
but famous too.
Right. | tell you what.
| now orderyou, as your aunt,
to go to her and apologize profusely.
Hey! What are you doing?
Wake up!
Huh? What‘s that?
Huh? Hmm?
Take that camera and apologize.
You know, we need your help
a great deal
You can earn a lot
from this trade.
While I‘m here
everything should be okay.
I promise, there‘s no problem.
—Just you make sure it is okay.
—Sure.
— Thankyou. Good—bye.
— Good—bye.
— [ Prince ] See the guests out
— [ Man ] Sir.
Uncle.
You can count on me, gentlemen.
No one will ever guess
that the opium is stored in my house.
Open that box.
— This is ﬁne.
—All right.
Opium!
[Gasps]
Aah!
[Panting]
No one‘s following me.
I should be safe now.
— [Creaking]
— Aaah!
[sighs ]
[Banging]
[Gasping,Whimpering]
Aaah!
[Continues Whimpering]
[Sighs]
Aaaah!
[Gasping]
[Panting]
Aaah! It’s not me!
— /tisme!
— Huh?
—I came to give you this camera.
—Someone wants to kill me.
Aaah!
Get down! Watch out!
— Help me!
—Go now!
Hyah!
Huh?
_ — Hyah!
[Grunts]
This beggar is still useful.
We won‘t kill him yet.
Your Highness,
what am I doing here?
Uh, my men found you
in an alleyway.
You were wounded and unconscious.
[Groaning]
What happened to me?
|thinkthe Fire Lotus attacked me.
The Fire Lotus gang?
Where‘s Kiki?
She was with me.
—I haven‘t seen her.
- Oh.
But don‘t worry.
I‘m sure she‘s okay.
[Groans]
It hurts?
Have a pipe.
It‘ll take the pain away, you see.
Go on. It‘s all right.
Now, how do you feel?
Isn‘t that better?
He‘s now in a daze.
You ﬁnd Kiki.
But don‘t hurt her.
Idon‘t want problems
with my brother.
— When he‘s addicted, he can kill Lin.
— That‘s clever, my lord.
Hmm.
| see.
You‘re looking for So Chai.
My lord, do you know
his whereabouts?
Master Wong, I know So Chai,
but I‘m not his nanny.
But, sir, Kiki said she saw you last night.
You were both seen together.
[Chuckles]
I was at Madam Chung‘s last night.
I was there the whole time,
but I never saw So Chai.
Look, Uncle, I don‘t care what you do.
I‘m not interested.
But I have to help So Chai.
Kiki, you‘re too suspicious.
Chai wouldn‘t go to a brothel.
Besides,you‘re a Manchu princess.
You can‘t marry a Han.
And yet you‘ve disregarded that law.
— You hang out with these peasants.
— That‘s not true!
I‘m sorry, sir.
Maybe this is not a good time.
Sorry to have disturbed you.
We‘ll go now.
Wait! You can‘t leave.
Mmm.
Wong Fei Hong,
you can‘tjust walk out.
I‘ll lose face.
I‘m sure you understand.
My lord, I‘m just concerned
about a friend‘s safety.
Hmm?|‘lltellyouwhat.
I heard that your kung fu is good.
|fyou can beat me,
then you‘re free to go.
But ifyou lose,
then you leave your head.
Haah!
— You‘re good.
— Huh? Hee—yaah!
My lord!
Lin Ze Xu pays his respects.
Save it!
See him out!
Your Honor——
Local ofﬁcials complain
that you‘ve totally disrupted life here.
The foreign minister thinks
you‘re ruthless with foreign traders.
So what do you have to say, Master Lin?
This could cost you dearly.
My lord, all I can say is, everything
I‘m doing is for the good ofthe country.
I‘ve vowed to destroy opium,
no matter what it costs.
Master Lin, you don‘t seem to have
a grasp ofthe situation at all.
Under the circumstances,
maybe you should leave,
retire early...
and leave
the serious business to us.
|wi|l never quit
as long as opium exists.
I‘m not somebody
who will give up halﬁivay.
Right. The policy‘s changed.
Just to let you know,
I‘ve ﬁled papers with His Majesty...
to impose heavy taxes on opium.
So when people run out ofmoney,
then theywill quit.
Your Highness,
that‘s not the answer to the problem.
We have to ban opium imports,
or China will become
a nation ofdrug addicts.
Hmph! I smoke too.
What do you plan on doing about that?
What I‘m after, sir, are merchants
who have large quantities.
You‘re treading on thin ice.
[Laughing]
Here‘s a word ofadvice foryou:
keep out ofit.
Brother So.
I found Kiki, but she spends all her time
with Wong Fei Hong these days.
Kiki is still veryyoung.
She is very naive.
/’m aﬁaid she ’ll be
taken in b ys weet talk
I regret I didn‘t believe you.
This Wong Fei Hong...
is a real hypocrite, as you say.
Now he‘s using Lin and the opium ban
to blackmail me.
He and the commissioner
are demanding a lot ofmoney from me.
They‘ve even ganged up with local bandits
who give them support openly.
Sooner or/ater,
these gangsters will ruin the country.
[Thinking]
Wong Fei Hong. Lin Ze Xu.
— First we must cut offtheir head.
— [Chuckles]
You‘re a very good chess player as well.
I admit my defeat.
[Yelling]
— Call the guards!
— Hyah!
Hyah!
[Groaning]
Chai!
— You okay, sir?
— I‘m okay. You can all leave now.
— [Men]Sir!
— He seems heavily addicted.
[ Wong] Chai was just being used
Master [in won ’t blame him.
Master Wong, how‘s my son?
Listen.
You mustn‘t blame your son.
He‘s heavily addicted to opium.
— Then what shall I do?
— You better move all the furniture away.
In the meantime, I‘ll go to Korea House and
try to get a ginseng to make a tonic for him.
— See you later.
— Oh, thankyou so much. Thankyou, sir.
[Sighs]
Hey! Don‘tjust
stand there like lumps!
Didn‘t you hear what he said?
Move the furniture!
[Groaning]
Father! Let me out!
Let me out!
I need opium!
/ need a smoke!
Father, let me out!
I need opium!
L et me out!
/ need a smoke!
Father! [Groans]
Let me out!
Son,just hang in there.
— / need opium! L et me out!
— I can‘t.
Don‘t worry.
Master Wong will help you.
Wow!
This is a magniﬁcent place.
[Together]
Please take a seat.
— Thankyou.
— [Chuckles]
Oh, it‘s a real pleasure to meet you,
Master Wong.
— Please sit down, won‘t you?
— Please.
—Oh, this looks good.
— Mr. Kim.
— Ow!
— I‘ve come here, good sir,
to askyou to sell me your
1,000—year—old ginseng to help a friend.
Huh! I‘ve heard that opium
is a health drug.
It brings people longevity.
My ginseng has no value in comparison.
You must bejoking, Mr. Kim.
Opium is poisoning all China.
Your ginseng can save thousands oflives,
so please help us out.
Have you eaten yet, Mr. Wong?
|fnot, then pleasejoin us, would you?
I thought maybe that you‘d like
a taste ofthis ginseng.
Hmm!
[Grunting]
Wow!
Oh. We can cut it up.
Can we have a knife or something?
Huh! |fyou can‘t even solve that
little problem, you don‘t deserve it.
— You‘re trying to test us, is that it? You——
— Kwan!
Just be quiet.
Stand back!
Mr. Kim, I apologize for him.
Mr. Kim, let‘s drink to your health.
The ginseng is still raw and hard.
It needs some cooking to soften it.
— Have you heard oftae kwon do?
— Wait.
Careful!
Mr. Kim, thankyou.
You‘re good.
Your tiger and crane ﬁst, sir,
is really as good as people say.
I‘m very honored to have met
an unselﬁsh man likeyou.
— I‘m sure my ginseng will be put to good use.
—Thankyou very much, sir.
Do you know, wife,
since| married intoyourfamily,
my only contribution is our son.
| feel so useless.
I‘ve remained a widower
for almost 20 years.
Yes, everything
I‘ve done is for Chai.
| used to thinkthat I could
depend on him in my old age,
and now he ’s become
a drug addict
It hurts me so much to see him suﬁ‘er,
trying to quit, and it’s all my fault
| spoiled him rotten.
It‘s nothing to do with the Sos.
I‘m responsible.
Ifthere is blame, then it‘s with me!
— Uh, Master Wong——
— Get away! Leave me alone!
— Oh, please don‘t make it hard for him!
— Get out of my way now!
[Chattering]
-Chai?Chai?
— Missus? Missus?Young master‘s gone out.
What‘s wrong with you people?
I told you to watch him!
— He beats us up. What can we do?
— You‘re useless!
— What‘s up?
— Young master‘s gone out.
— Huh?
— You! Don‘t stand there looking like an idiot!
Go out and ﬁnd him,
and don‘t you come back until you have!
Ohh, I understand.
You want your son to go away,
hopefully die ofdrug addiction.
Then you could get married again.
You don‘t care about your son at all!
[Gasps]
How dare you say that?
For many years I‘ve endured your nonsense,
your abuse, your denigration,
and I‘ve said nothing so far
because ofChai!
Iwould‘ve left here long ago
ifitwasn‘t for him!
— You silly old fart!
—Shut up!
[Moaning]
Huh? My God! Are you okay?
Hmm! Young man.
Huh?
Hmm!
— Huh? Huh?
— Come on! Hit me again! I love it!
— Come on! Hit me!
— Oh, God,Jean! What‘s come overyou, huh?
What? Hey, where‘s your teeth?
What‘s happened to your teeth?
— What‘s wrong? Don‘t you like my teeth?
— Oh, yeah, yeah.
— I‘d better go and ﬁnd our son though.
— Mr. So, where is your son?
— That‘s exactly what I‘d like to know too.
— No!
— Hey, maybe he‘s gone to his godfather‘s.
—Yeah, ofcourse. [Giggles]
Hey, wait, Kiki!
Wait! Waita minute!
Oh, God. I was gonna
ask her to help us.
— Don‘tjust stand there! Let‘s ﬁnd Chai!
— I‘m coming! Oh, I loveyou!
— Oh, my God. She‘s on something.
— Let‘s go.
[Shuddering]
— Let‘s go home.
— No!
Only two more days and you‘ll kick it.
You mustn‘t give up now.
Go away!
Just leave me alone, Wong Fei Hong.
I‘d beg you foryour help, but you‘re
wasting your time.Just leave me to die.
You‘re a talented man,
but you‘re too full ofyourself.
— Come with me! Come on!
— No! I won‘t! [Groans]
You said you had strong will,
so show me now.
Where‘s it all gone? You refuse to tell us
who sent you to kill the commissioner.
You think that’s loyalty?
Get up!
Come on. Fight back. Get up!
You hate me, don‘t you?
Come on!
So you have no strength.
I‘ll helpyou out.
That‘s for the opium.
Find me afterwards.
Your dad‘s a disgrace, and he married
into the Sos for their money.
Now his son is even worse than him——
a co ward! You’re a total disgrace.
You can insult me,
but you can‘t insult my father!
So Chai, you‘re ﬁnally
holding your head up.
Father, please tell me,
what am I going to do?
Have a drink.
You‘re now heavily addicted.
You need to get drunk.
You‘re clever.
Being cleverer is hard.
It’s hard to be stupid
but harder to become stupid
when you start out clever!
— So drink.
—I don‘t understand what you‘re saying.
— It‘s all too difﬁcult for me.
— You‘ll understand when you‘re drunk!
You‘ll forget all about opium
when you‘re drunk. Drink!
Come on!
[Gulping]
— More!
— No! / can’t!
— /don’t drink
— You can. Go on! Drink!
[All Chanting]
Drink, drink, drink, drink!
— Drink, drink, drink, drink!
— You must drink it.
— Drink! Go on!
[Chanting Continues, Scattered Shouts]
Drink it down! Go on!
Drink more. Drink!
Drink.
I‘ll show you the drunken style!
Drink, drink, drink, drink!
You‘re getting tipsy.
That‘s when a drunken ﬁst takes form.
Your head may be fuzzy,
but neitheryour mind noryour ﬁsts.
Attackyour opponent
when his guard‘s down.
Surprise is the essence
ofgood martial arts.
Drink, drink, drink, drink!
Hee—yaah!
Go on! Let‘s go!
You want trouble?
[Man]
Protect the women and children!
Haah!
[ Woman] Give up So Chai
We 7/ spare your life.
— Don‘t go!
— Godfather!
Come on! Let‘s go!
Don‘t worry.
— [Slashing]
— [ Groaning]
— No!
— Father!
— No, Father! Let‘s get out of here!
— You go!
— Father!
— No!
— [ Groans]
— Let‘s go!
— [ Woman] Damn! That So Chai got away.
— [ Grunts ]
[Panting]
— I‘ll get you some water.
— Don’tgo.
Don ’t leave me, please.
Please, don‘t leave me.
No. Please, don‘t go.
[Groans]
[Gasps]
Chai! Chai!
—I think it‘s betterwe both split up.
—All right.
Why won‘t you go home
and seeyourfamily?
You kicked the habit.
You can go back to a normal life now.
The So Chai I know is a man
who risked his own life to help me.
So listen, Chai,
ifyou do care about me...
stop pouting, all right?
You should go to the prince
and avenge your godfather!
You‘ve drunk enough!
Wake up! Where‘s your willpower?
Where‘s your conﬁdence?
Master Wong needs your help.
Help him.
I know. You‘re selﬁsh.
You‘re scared.
Coward! You‘ve no guts.
— You‘re scared. I‘m right, aren‘t I?
— Look at me! How can I ﬁght?
My hands are shaky and my legs are scared
to meet my father or Master Wong.
I‘m too ashamed to face anyone.
[Gasping]
I‘m not ashamed ofyou
no matter what happens.
All right.
I‘ll see Master Wong.
The prince‘s plot
to kill me has failed,
but he‘ll come up
with something else very soon.
We must move fast.
Time is running out.
—[Sighs]
— Your Honor, is something bothering you?
Well, I obtained
information long ago.
The prince is in league
with the opium merchants.
I was going to ﬁle a report with the emperor,
but the prince must‘ve got wind ofthat.
[Man]
Hear ye the edict
The son of heaven,
His Majesty, decrees...
that the special commissioner,
Lin Ze Xu,
abused his authority
and disrupted law and order.
He is suspended. He will return
to the capital for an inquiry.
Hear and obey.
[Chuckles]
Lin Ze Xu, aren‘t you
going to obey the edict...
and remove your ofﬁcial headgear?
You won‘t do it? Huh?
[ Chuckling]
Nobody goes up against me
and then wins.
[Laughing Wildly]
Sir.
— Master Wong.
— Yes.
I don‘t care what happens
to me personally.
— We must go through with our plan.
— Yes, Your Honor.
I shall do everything I can
to stop this evil man.
Mm—hmm.
— Master Wong! Master Wong!
— You can‘t come in. You can‘t, I told you.
— Please, please!
— Teacher, he insists on seeing you.
— What does he want?
—I don‘t know!
Master Wong, my teacher‘s
the Beggar Clan chief. He‘s dead.
— Please help us to avenge him!
— Hey, get up.
Now tell me what happened.
My men have discovered where
the prince is hiding his opium.
Onlyyou can help us.
We want to destroy him to avenge our chief.
Right. It‘ll be my pleasure.
— Kwan, inform the commissioner at once.
— Hmm.
— Over here!
— Easy!
— Move it! Come on!
— Move it, move it!
— Give me a hand.
— Here. Next! Come on.
That‘s a lot ofopium
you got here, Your Highness.
You‘re gonna make a fortune
from this shipment.
[Chuckles]
So will you.
— [Chuckles]
— To the success ofourjoint venture, huh?
— Cheers.
— [Rapid Footsteps]
[All Shouting]
Wong Fei Hong?
Your Highness, I caught you red—handed.
You can‘t deny this anymore.
A dead man cannot talk.
— You won‘t get me into a court.
— [Glass Crashes]
Kill them!
You go, sir.
— Why did you use me?
— You‘re stupid. That‘s why, you fool.
— I‘m gonna killyou.
—Just tryit!
Aah!
Huh! We were friends once.
I‘ll let you drink before you die.
Drink! [ Laughs] Go on!
[Groaning]
Drink it! [ Laughs]
Drinkit! Drink!
Your head may be fuzzy,
but your mind is not.
That‘s all the essence
ofmartial arts.
Get drunk!
Then you ’ll understand
Huh?
[Pained Groaning]
Haah!
Thanks a lot.
— Not at all.
— [Blowtands]
Hoo—waah!
—[Grunting]
- I‘ll kill him!
I mean it!
So Chai, you won‘t get me so easy.
[Spits]
lam the king‘s brother.
There‘s no wayyou can get me.
[Laughing]
Let‘s go!
Back off! Go on!
Don‘t come near me!
You dogs.
You wanna kill me?
Never! The opium‘s mine!
— Don‘t touch it! You hear me?
— Never mind me. Burn it!
Shut up! I‘ll killya!
Don‘t touch my opium!
Huh! Come on! Let‘s go!
Move, move!
[Groaning]
[Yelling]
— [ Groans]
— Chai, are you all right?
I‘m ﬁne.
You saved my life again.
Now I‘ll return it.
Hmm.
[All Cheering]
I never thought that I could accomplish
my mission before I returned.
Our hard work has paid off.
—All right! Burn the opium!
— Burn it!
[All]
Burn the opium!
Strengthen China!
The strength ofthis triumph could
burn through our future generations.