Roberto.
Look, You can level with me.
I had a bad scene, huh?
You're missing your cues, that's all.
You gotta follow me.
Don't hassle yourself, Mirko.
Everything is okay.
We're so far out, who's gonna notice?
Thanks, man.
- Yeah.
- See you.
Mirko.
Son of a bitch.
Hey.
Just a minute.
What do you want?
Take your hands off me.
That's cute?
What do I want?
What the hell do you want?
You've been following
me for maybe a week now.
I'm sick of seeing your stupid face.
Now what are you after?
Are you crazy?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I've never followed anybody.
What are you after, man?
What's your trip?
Lay off me, will you?
Lay off!
I'm not fooling, see.
Now, beat it!
I'm warning you.
Hello?
Go to hell.
Are you still awake?
Yes.
Good night, good morning.
Whatever the case may be.
Who was it?
Nobody.
Never said anything.
UNIDENTIFIED BODY FOUND IN RIVER
THE VICTIM HAD NO ID
AND WAS STABBED TO DEATH
Bye, bye.
Goodbye, ma'am.
You can take them back
and don't make the same mistake again.
Mmm.
I'd like to see you in my shoes,
with all this mail to deliver.
- Hi.
- Hi, Maria.
What's happening?
Oh, that nitwit
He's always making mistakes.
Sometimes it's really embarrassing.
Keeps giving me that old
cripple's mail orders.
You know what kind of mail Rambaldi gets?
Swedish pornography.
You wouldn't believe
some of the positions.
ITALIAN IDENTITY CARD ISSUED TO MR.
CARLO MAROSI
Hey, Roberto.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Why don't you come over here with us?
- Yes, tonight.
- Okay, listen.
I gotta tell you what I saw.
- What's that?
- An execution
in Saudi-Arabia.
It sounds gory.
They're still chopping
off the heads there
This poor guy got his
hands tied behind his back
and they forced him onto his knees
in the center of this enormous square.
Then, the executioner arrives.
He's got this huge
sword in his right hand,
and a real thin stiletto in his left.
First, he takes the stiletto
and jabs it as hard as he can
into the nape of the guy's neck.
The whole body jerks rigid
and before you know it,
the executioner's raised his sword,
the neck's stiff, a nice clean cut
and off with his head.
Ew.
Oh my God, how horrible.
Who brought him here?
Andrea.
Why don't you tell us what
you've been writing lately?
Alright.
Here's a fascinating story,
Something right up Mirko's alley.
It's about the funeral
of a famous French chef.
The service is attended by
cooks from all over the world.
It's a beautiful and moving ceremony.
Just as the coffin is about to be closed,
the mourners sprinkled parsley and paprika
over the deceased.
Well, at least that
isn't as gory.
I could kill you now,
but I won't.
I'll wait.
Who is going to help you?
The police perhaps?
You can't ask anyone.
You're all alone.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I couldn't sleep.
Go back to bed.
I heard noises.
I said it was nothing.
No.
There's something wrong.
You've been acting so strange.
Please.
You can tell me.
Something is wrong.
These last few days-
I told you, it was nothing.
I killed a man.
A couple of days ago I killed a man.
What does he want from you?
I don't know.
That's what's so crazy.
He's never asked for money,
but he threatens me, phone
calls, letters, photos,
souvenirs.
And tonight he nearly killed me.
Look.
I have everything right here.
It's all gone.
Sure!
That's why he came.
He took them.
Are you sure that guy is really dead?
I stabbed him, didn't I?
Besides it was in the papers the next day.
Did they give his full name?
Well, no it-
it just said an unidentified body.
You don't believe me.
Maybe it's all a bad dream.
You've been working awfully hard lately.
Listen.
Tomorrow we can go see Enrico.
He's a good friend.
Yeah?
He's a shrink, too
You think I'm crazy, huh?
I didn't mean that.
Yeah, okay. Okay. Go to bed.
Leave me alone.
Go on! Leave me alone!
Roberto.
What was the name of the man you killed?
Carlo Marosi.
This must be his.
The initials are C.M.
And it's stained with blood.
Where did you find it?
On my dresser.
What are we gonna do?
I can't go to the police.
I can't tell anyone.
What are we gonna do?
Let's run away.
Let's get away from here.
It's the only way.
Do you know where God is?
You surprise me, brother.
God is here,
he is there,
and he's everywhere.
And he's fishing down by the river.
Hey, buddy.
You got a 100 Lira to spare?
I've got 50.
It ain't much but it'll do.
God.
♪ Hallelujah, hallelujah ♪
Oh, for Christ sake, Godfrey.
Godfrey, not God.
What the hell is wrong with Godfrey?
Think of something else to call me,
something less appropriate.
If you're gonna call me God,
at least you can call me God almighty?
God almighty?
What do you want?
Just slumming.
Slumming my ass.
Mmm, come on.
How many did you catch?
Four.
Nowadays the water's so polluted,
they're too pitiful to eat.
You catch them, all you wanna do is
put them in the bed and call the doctor.
Hey, Jerk Off!
What I do?
No, not you.
Not you.
The parrot.
That's my food, Jerk Off.
That's why he's called Jerk Off.
No kidding.
Somebody gave him to me.
Said that was the name he was born with,
so I couldn't really change it.
Still, I guess it's not very elegant.
We'll never crash high society
What an introduction.
"My dear, I'd like you to meet Jerk off."
You've got a problem.
I'll say.
Mm.
You see, I killed this guy
and now someone's after me.
Is that all?
No games.
I'm serious.
Okay, what happened?
What do I do with this?
Put it in your mouth and eat it.
It's raw?
It's good for you
Higher quantities of phosphorus,
protein and all that crap.
I'm not much for microbiotics.
Just as I suspected.
The typical victim of
the consumer society.
It's like this
I killed this guy,
I didn't even know him.
It was an accident.
The police don't know about it,
but somebody else does.
Someone who was there.
Took pictures of me killing him.
Now they're blackmailing me.
But that's not all.
It isn't just anyone.
It's someone who knows me pretty well.
One night some friends were at the house
and I found one of those damned photos
stuck in between the records.
Half an hour before it wasn't there,
one of them must have put it there.
You gonna pay up?
I got no money.
What about your wife, you
said her family's got money.
He's not after money.
That's what's so weird.
He's just making my life a
hell and I don't know why.
Nasty business.
Now, take God's advice.
First, get yourself a private investigator
Have 'em check around.
Tail you. Protect you, too.
'Cause if I'm not mistaken, and I'm not,
your life is in danger.
Arrosio is a good private dick.
A bit eccentric, but he's smart and cheap.
Second, get the professor
to watch your house.
The professor?
Yeah.
You know him.
He's always lying around
here in the hammock
We call him professor
because of his elegant ways.
He kisses the ladies' hands,
he don't pick his nose in public-
And I know 1,280 verses
from the Bible by heart.
What's that?
Let's say, for a thou,
okay, a thou-five a day.
I want you to keep an eye on
the house of my friend here.
He's a great musician.
Hey, you're blushing?
Who's blushing?
You're turning red,
ain't he professor?
As red as the Kremlin.
If you see anything strange,
like blackmailers, murderers, or the like-
I step in, right?
Wrong, you tell us.
Oh.
Fish?
Huh?
Can I have a fish.
Oh.
No.
You, bastard, you!
What do you want from me?
What do you want?
Special delivery.
Eh?
I've got a special delivery letter.
I never-
I'm sorry, I thought you-
What do you want from me now?
Nothing.
You don't understand.
I don't understand?
You mugged me, you tried to kill me.
You nearly strangled me.
What's everyone got against mailmen, huh?
I'm no fool.
Besides, all the evidence I've got here,
I saw you.
Yes.
That's right.
Yes, exactly.
In cash.
Look, I don't care why you're doing it,
I'm only interested in the money.
And don't try any funny business
or I'll go to the police.
Understand?
You know the playground in the park?
I'll be waiting for you there.
This afternoon.
Right.
If you get hit once,
you hit back twice.
Stop acting like a baby.
Stop crying.
You hear?
I never wanna see you cry.
You idiot.
Amelia.
Help. Help!
Hey, there's someone in there.
What's the matter?
- Help me.
I'm locked in and someone,
someone is following me.
Don't worry, I'll climb over.
Hurry, hurry.
It's too high, lady.
I'll go over to the main gate.
No, please don't leave me.
Someone is after me.
They're going to kill me.
- Nothing is gonna happen.
- Yes, it will!
Oh, please!
Oh my God, no!
- Hi, Roberto.
- Hi, Dalia.
How come-
- My little cousin
is taking a vacation.
She's going to be staying
with us for a while.
Look, if I'm a nuisance, I'll go.
Don't be stupid.
I'm delighted.
Dalia, come and listen to this story
It's called "The Rape of Frankenstein" or
Or "The Man Made Molested."
Why right now?
How come Dalia is here?
She just showed up.
You know how she is.
Would you rather I send her home?
Yes.
No, it's okay.
Just as soon the others went home.
Keep dropping in without warning.
What's more, the maid's disappeared.
I haven't seen her since this morning.
This Austrian psychiatrist
is giving the baron a low down
on why his monster's so bloodthirsty.
It's cause he's got no sex life.
Libido frustration.
Consequent homicidal impulse.
The baron figured this head shrinker
knows what he's talking about,
so back to the lab.
This time his monster's
gonna have, uh, sex appeal.
Unfortunately the baron overdoes it,
and the first thing the monster
does is try to rape him.
The baron escapes in the nick of time,
but he is bugged by the thought that
maybe his monster is queer.
No way.
Down in the village the word is out.
The Frankenstein monster
will rape anything in sight.
The local farmers scour the country side,
and so does the local schoolmarm,
not a day over 70,
she rip off her bra and
panties and rushes out.
More willing than able
to sacrifice herself
for the sake of science.
that's ridiculous.
What's with you lately?
Nothing, why?
Come on, Roberto.
Something's wrong.
You didn't even show up
for rehearsal today.
I was busy.
Hello.
Yes, That's right.
No.
Yes, I see.
Yes, certainly.
It was the police.
They found the maid with her throat cut.
They said
it was a maniac.
Tomorrow I've got to go
to the police station.
I'm scared.
They're out to get us.
And it's not blackmail.
They want to kill us.
I don't know how you
can stand living here,
knowing that there's somebody coming
and going to do whatever they want.
Spying on you, following you,
just waiting to kill you.
What can I do?
You've got to make up your mind.
Either we leave here, or you
tell the police everything.
You just remember one thing,
I killed a man.
As frightening as it
sounds, you think about it.
I'll get 15 years.
His name was Carlo Marosi.
I killed him.
Hey.
Hello?
It's me.
See you at my place, huh?
Yeah, well, I think you will be there.
I'm pretty fed up with things, see.
I read the newspapers too, you know.
This time someone really
got killed, right?
I wanted a son,
not a weakling like you.
What have you done now?
You'll end up in an asylum.
Asylum!
Did they steal your cat?
- Yeah.
- So it's true.
Last night I saw someone
run across your garden
with a cat wrapped in blanket.
A black figure.
Look what I got to remember him by.
I tried to stop him and
woke up 15 minutes later.
Hmm?
Hey.
You watch out.
This time I'm armed.
This way.
Look, the bread we agreed on,
I decided it ain't enough.
And here, you can have your toy back.
I've had it, see.
First, I've got to play dead.
Okay.
Then I got to risk my neck
with this nightly visits.
And to top it off, that
disgusting business with the cat.
But now, the real killing,
that maid.
Okay, so she found out.
Did you have to kill her?
We made a deal, sure.
Nobody said anything
about murder.
No! No!
POLICE HQ
Oh.
Can I help you?
No.
I guess I made a mistake.
I was looking for Arrosio,
private investigator.
No, no, wait.
That's me.
Private investigator.
Oh.
You see,
well look, never mind.
No, no.
Don't go.
I'm waiting.
But it's a bit risky.
And I don't-
Oh, yes.
And you're thinking,
this fairy is gonna jump on a
chair and scream bloody murder
if he sees a mouse.
Huh, right?
Yes, that's what I thought.
Oh, you heterosexuals.
I don't suppose you've ever
had a homosexual experience?
Let's forget it, man.
Yes.
We're men, too, you know?
Just a little different.
- That's very comforting.
- Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
Who's paying?
You?
Huh?
What's he had?
A steak, three sandwiches,
two eggs and a bottle of beer.
Guess he wasn't hungry.
Thank you.
I'm not sure I believe you.
Your story is awfully shallow.
I can't think of a better one.
You know, this case is a real challenge.
Fortunately, the odds are in our favor.
- The odds?
- Exactly.
You see before you a fully fledged
highly qualified private investigator
with an extensive
knowledge of modern science
at his very fingertips.
And in spite of this,
in three years of honest practice,
I haven't solved a single case.
Not even one?
Not even one.
Interesting, isn't it?
I suppose so, but it might mean-
It means this.
Statistically speaking,
one of the most impressive
records of failure
is destined to be broken.
84 failures
A fantastic record.
Incredible.
A record like that couldn't possibly last.
I could just sit in my office and wait
for the criminal to show up.
Please, don't do that.
Oh, no.
I'll take a very personal interest
in your case.
What do you want?
Please, inform the mailman
not to leave any more of
this filth at my house!
Had any trouble with your wife?
Other women, maybe?
No.
Oh.
Any money in your family?
No, nothing.
Your wife, maybe?
Well, she was left a
fairly large inheritance.
Oh, haha.
What do you mean "Oh, haha"?
Oh, nothing.
Just "Oh".
Look, you don't think...
What have you written there?
Nothing, just notes.
Okay, let me off here.
You won't realize I'm around.
I'll contact you by phone.
Looks like trouble.
They've been in there half an hour.
Beat it.
"Get thee out of thy country."
Genesis, 12:1.
Commissioner, leave me with my husband?
I'm going with them.
It's about the maid.
They showed me pictures of the body.
It's horrible.
- Mrs. Tobias.
- It's all right, I'm coming.
Listen, you can stay here if you want,
but I can't take it anymore.
I'm not coming back to this house.
I've got to get away.
I've made a decision, too.
Sticking this out is better
than going to prison,
so I'm gonna stay here.
But you're right.
It's better for you to go.
Visit your relatives for a while
but give me a call now and again, huh?
Whatcha standing there
for, huh? Oh, no. I quit.
I'm leaving tonight.
Why didn't you go with Nina?
None of your business.
Don't get excited
It will all work out, you'll see.
All what?
Nina told me the whole story.
The blackmail.
Everything.
Don't worry, you know you can trust me.
Sure.
Besides, Nina was so upset,
she needed someone to talk to.
Okay, so, now you know everything.
Have any bright ideas?
Yes, first thing is a nice hot bath,
to relax you.
Then you can think about it.
Don't miss your train, Dalia.
Oh, come on.
I've got some relaxing bath salts.
I don't want a bath.
My God!
Roberto.
You idiot.
You really gave me a fright.
I'm soaked through.
Come on.
Sit up, and I'll massage your back.
That better?
Hey!
None of that now.
You hear?
No, stop it, please.
It's out of the question.
You know it.
No.
You know, besides being cousins,
Nina and I are very good friends,
but I'm not sorry we're making love.
Kinda sick, don't you think?
Hi.
Oh.
I need more evidence.
Like letters, things sent
by the the blackmailer.
Photos of you, your
family, friends, addresses,
anything you can find.
Everything is right here.
Oh.
About 100 photos.
The whole works.
- Thank you.
Oh, the missus, I suppose.
No, she's a friend,
I mean a relative.
- Good evening.
Wait a minute.
I've got the wallet.
Right over here.
What was it?
Nothing, just a nightmare.
You missed your train.
I have an idea it's not
the only one I'll miss.
No, it's impossible.
PERSONALITY OF THE PERPETRATOR
PSYCHOPATH WITH PROBABLE
SPLIT PERSONALITY
BEHAVES IN A PERFECTLY
NORMAL WAY IN EVERYDAY LIFE
SUSPECTS: MIRKO,
PROFESSIONAL ENVY; ANDREA;
ROBERTO: INHERITANCE OR...?
No, no, no.
- Hello?
- It's me, Arrosio.
No real news, but I was
studying the photographs
and I've noticed a strange
physical resemblance.
Between who?
Well, it may be a red herring.
I'll tell you another time.
Oh, by the way,
I wanted to let you know
you may not hear from me
for a few days.
- Okay, bye.
- Oh, hold it a minute.
Sorry.
Does this name ring a bell?
Villa Rapidi.
No, never heard the name before?
- Okay, bye.
- Why?
Yes, it was a form of paranoia.
In its early stages,
it was characterized by violent outbursts.
I would definitely described it
as an extreme case of homicidal mania.
The patient was here for three years.
After the father died, all symptoms
of emotional disturbance disappeared.
It was our opinion that the
patient was completely cured.
However, there is one important point
I would like to emphasize.
We suspected that the man was
not the patient's real father.
Oh.
Roberto, telephone.
It's Nina.
Hi, honey.
Okay.
No, no news.
No, I'm not leaving.
I've already told you.
Hello.
Looking for something?
Oh, hello.
I was looking for you.
Me?
Yes.
I immediately thought
I need to rent the place to carry on
but nobody else ever comes.
- No.
- Really.
Is that so?
I'd hardly tell you a lie.
Oh, no.
I believe you.
Hold on.
Our friend's leaving.
Thanks for everything.
Bye.
Don't mention it.
Telephone me sometime?
Okay.
Bye.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Pardon me, sorry, excuse me.
Excuse me, thank you.
Congratulations.
You guessed right.
I was right.
I did it this time.
And I've actually established
that in 4000 years of civilization,
there have been only
had 230 years of peace.
Incredible, isn't it?
Look, Andrea.
I'm just not in the mood.
What did you want to see me about?
Mmm.
Nina telephoned me.
She pleaded with me to
convince you to join her.
I see.
Thanks.
Hold on and listen
for a minute, will you?
I don't know why, but she's
terribly worried about you.
Why don't you do what she says?
Hmm?
Is there another woman?
No, not exactly.
You want your marriage to break up?
You wanna see Nina to end up like Maria?
What does that mean?
Well, she
wouldn't want me to tell you,
but the fact is, Maria
is in love with you.
Has been for years.
She never got married, never
bothered with other men.
She waits, in silent adoration
like a little dog.
THE VICTIM'S NAME
WAS GIANNI ARROSIO,
POLICE ARE PROBING INTO THE
MAN'S "PARTICULAR FRIENDSHIPS."
Ladies and gentlemen,
note the beautifully finished interior.
None of that cheap old-fashioned satin.
No, siree.
Nothing but the best.
Pure handwoven silk.
And I'm happy to announce our
special offer to any person,
God forbidding, who should pass away
during the period of the exhibition,
we have a discount of 25%.
Make it 50 and we got a deal.
Some place you picked to meet.
I did it deliberately
Seeing all these worms
make a living out of death.
It kinda knocks the
fear out of you, right?
Let's face it,
everyone has to die.
That's the commercial necessity.
Excuse me.
Could I have a light?
Thank you.
And if that's not enough,
I keep having this dream
about an execution.
The strange thing is during the dream,
it's as if I were living it.
Very kind.
Like maybe its a premonition.
Or an omen.
Can that sort of thing happen
or you think I'm crackin' up?
"Then was a secret revealed unto Daniel
in a night vision."
Daniel 2:19.
Exactly.
Take my advice.
Things are really serious,
more serious than we imagined.
You should go to the police.
Level with them.
Sure, then I'll go to prison
for the rest of my life.
Step right here.
Let's try for size.
There.
Is that alright?
It's a bit narrow.
I feel uncomfortable.
Oh, I can assure you
none of our customers
have ever come back with a complaint about
the comfort of our coffin.
It's a bit gaudy.
Someone obviously
suffering from paranoia
is playing a game with you.
I can't figure out why.
I think someone is
trying to drive you crazy
before finally killing you.
Another charming idea, but
what about the other murders?
A double coffin for double deaths.
Something must have fouled things up.
Someone probably caught on,
realized who was persecuting you,
and that's why they got murdered.
The murderer began to enjoy killing.
He probably thrives on the blood,
the torture of a human being.
The killer is a homicidal paranoid.
Cases like that commit
the most horrendous crimes
for what appear to be most
insignificant reasons.
Mmm.
Why don't you try taking your
wife's advice and clear out
for a while?
Where to?
You think that would solve anything?
I don't know, it's worth a try.
You'll end up in an asylum.
I wanted a son, not a weakling like you.
If you get hit once,
you hit back twice.
Hello?
No, not at the moment.
No, it's impossible.
Is it important?
Okay, I'll tell him to call you at home.
Hello?
Okay, play it back.
A girl phoned before.
Dalia.
She says it's important
you telephone her at home.
Mrs. Tobias.
- Yes?
- Excuse me.
We intend to carry out series
of tests on the victim.
I was wondering if a member
of family would like to be present.
Her parents hardly seem in the condition-
Neither am I.
Speak to my husband.
Won't you come this way, please?
What's this all about?
I want to have a test
performed on the girl's eyes.
It's been recently discovered
that the last image seen
by the victim before death
is retained for several
hours on the retina.
It's a very difficult procedure
but it is possible to
photograph this image.
Experiments carried out in Germany,
United States, and more recently in Italy
have had surprisingly good results.
In some cases it's even been possible
to distinguish the murderer's face
at the very moment he committed the crime.
What are they?
They look like flies.
Four flies.
Yes, you're right.
That's exactly what they look like.
What does it mean?
Yeah, that's one solution,
but don't leave the house.
You choose your own territory,
lock yourself in and hold out.
Sooner or later, he'll show up,
and you'll be ready and waiting.
But it's gonna take a lotta guts.
You got guts?
I guess I'll find out.
Okay.
I'll keep in touch.
- Hello?
- Yeah.
How's it going?
So far, so good.
Nothing's happened.
Do you want me to come over?
It might be easier if-
God?
Hello?
Nina.
Roberto.
What are you doing?
You scared me with that gun.
What are you doing here in the dark?
For a second I thought...
God, Nina, you showed
up at the right moment.
What's the matter?
Why didn't-
Quick, you got to get out of here.
Now, right away.
Listen, I decided that I was wrong.
Somebody has to stay here with you.
But not now.
Look, I can't explain.
There's no time
You got to get out of here, understand?
In the morning, Nina,
come back in the morning!
What's the matter?
What's happening?
Look.
I'm waiting for someone.
Now you go out that door and you run,
you run to my car.
It's parked at front.
Now here's the keys.
Now listen.
You got in that car and you drive.
I don't care where.
You just drive.
Just go, okay?
Now go.
Go, I say!
They look like flies.
I'm a goddamn fool.
I sure didn't have to look far, did I?
What are you doing?
You're crazy.
You killed Dalia.
That's what she saw.
You did it.
You did it all!
You did-
Take your hands off me.
Get over there.
All of a sudden, you're so clever.
Who'd have expected it?
Watch it.
I want you there.
I want so badly see you die slowly,
painfully.
Back.
Back!
Why?
Because you're so much
like him.
First shot got your arm.
It hurts.
I know what it's like.
I've suffered, too.
My pig father!
He made me suffer.
Did you know?
He brought me up as a boy.
He felt cheated because he'd had a girl.
He dressed me like a boy.
And he beat me.
He beat me!
He did all kinds
of things to me,
for years and years.
But I disappointed him.
Because I never reacted
like a man would.
He said I was crazy.
And my mother,
she died in an asylum.
He put me there too.
Three long years.
Do you know what
the doctors said?
They said I was deranged!
A miserable lunatic.
A maniac.
How could they know
about what I had suffered?
I didn't have time to get my...
To get my revenge, because
he died on his own!
He died before I could get him,
before I could kill him.
I had to find someone else
who could pay in his place.
Pay for everything
he had done to me.
I had to get my revenge!
And I found that someone!
When I met you.
I couldn't believe it.
It was like a miracle.
You look just like him.
I knew I'd kill you!
Stop!
I came here as quickly as I could.
She's crazy.