Supreme Master of the Dragon Sect
Long Er
Why did your mission fail?
Master, it was screwed up
By a rascal called Wilson Bond
Is he a kung fu master?
Quite the opposite!
Is he good with poison?
Hardly!
Is he handsome and smart
You fell under his charms?
Definitely not!
He's ugly as a pig, despicable as a dog
A sweet-talking scoundrel
How can he defeat you?
Please punish me!
Maybe it's your destiny
He's probably your jinx
Be careful when you see him again
Yes, Master!
I'm destined to die tonight
You will succeed me
Enter the blood pool now
Resume your true self
And take over my position
Wu San Gui's son will meet
the Qing Emperor at the capital
You must protect him
Yes, Master!
The Dragon Sect
Has assisted Wu for 3 generations
You'll assume my responsibility
And help put him on the throne
Follow me into the blood pool
You will then gain my power
You must remember
Our kung fu is unique
If you lose your virginity
80%  of your power
Will go to your first man
Don't forget!
Supreme Master of the Dragon Sect
Bond, I'll get even with you!
Girls! Come meet your clients!
Be a beggar, be a beggar. . .
Go to hell, go to hell. . .
This time your family is dead!
Says who?
My sister is right here!
That's slander!
1 00,000 taels as penalty
He didn't mean it. Forgive him!
I didn't mean it
Pleading for him? What's going on?
Nothing! We're innocent!
We're pure and honest!
Very pure, very honest!
I can't stand you two! I'll go piss!
- Hey beauty!
- Bastard!
Quiet!
Is Bond in the next room?
Yes!
No! Yes...no!
Yes or no?
What has he done to you?
He's assisting the Qing Emperor
Everyone should kill him!
Thank goodness! I have suffered
And waited for so long! Thank you!
You are. . .
He killed my whole family
Made me worship him!
That bastard! We must kill him!
Go ahead, I'll get ready to celebrate!
Wait! You take us to him!
Sure, let me get my glasses
This way...
We're innocent
Shut up, your bastard!
Bastard...
I'm in deep trouble!
You cannot deny it!
Bond, I want to kill you Skin you alive
and break your bones!
What is this?
Just so you know
I'm Li Ke, pupil of the One-Arm Nun
I'm Wilson Bond?
Guards! Help!
Guards! Help me!
No need to be afraid, calm down!
Lucky I have bodyguards
Of course, you have too many enemies
It's a girl!
Pretty too!
Then. . .let's. . .
I understand!
Stop!
Why are you still here?
You'll get killed!
Don't worry!
I wasn't sure you're anti-Qing
But now
I must disclose my identity
I'm the descendent of the condor hero
Master of Invincible East
My name is Vincible West
Vincible West?
You're the righteous Vincible West?
Don't move!
Or I'll kill them!
Give him poisoned wine!
What?
That one over there!
- What? You. . .
- Don't!
He'll lose his senses
And must copulate with a woman in 1 hour
Or else he'll become a pool of blood
Drink up!
No! Don't drink it!
I cannot implicate you
I have finished it
Let them go!
Fine! Let's go!
Bastard!
How do you feel?
The poison is acting up
Save me. . .
How?
I need to copulate with a young woman
To neutralize the poison
We can't. . .
If we. . .with you...
We can save you?
I'm flattered
But I can't! You better go!
Hurry!
You risked your life to save us
We'll remember your benevolence!
We'll burn you more money
You can't leave me now!
Your pathetic trick can't fool anyone
Miss, don't believe him!
What! You. . . Let's go!
This is none of your business!
- Guards! Beat him!
- Go on!
Don't pursue him!
Are you alright? I am Wu Ying Xiong
My father is Wu San Gui
I'm Li Ke
Master said Wu San Gui is a traitor!
We must not befriend his son!
I know what I'm doing
Thank you! Till we meet again!
- Miss!
- Don't!
You're in trouble. That was Wilson Bond
What? That's Wilson Bond?
The guy inside is a kung fu master
So was Ao Bai, but I took care of him
We better go get help!
- Your Excellency!
- What is it?
His Majesty summons you
Where is His Majesty?
Why do you want us here?
I was bullied today
Take revenge for me after the meeting
Who dares to bully you?
Someone quite capable of course!
His fists are big as pots, eyes are like bells
A long tongue and much taller than me
Hey you! Stop!
You're a bit like him! You 2 come take a look
You look exactly like him!
Is my tongue really that long?
You are the sissy!
How dare you tread on my turf! Fix him!
Hold him off! I'll go get help!
His Majesty is here!
- His Majesty!
- Rise!
Minister Bond, what's going on?
This sissy broke into the Palace
He peeped at the royal concubine
I tried to stop him but was beaten up
- Really?
- Yes!
What is your title, Minister Bond?
426! No!
Secretary of Grand Council and Duke of Deer Tripod
What can I do for you?
Don't you recognize me?
You're the sissy's accomplice!
Watch your mouth, Minister Bond!
He is Wu San Gui's eldest son, Wu Ying Xiong
He's here to discuss state affairs
How handsome you are, Prince Wu!
So nice to meet you!
This is Mr. Long, my top warrior
I brought him to the Palace
Mr. Top Warrior!
You look magnificent!
So nice to meet you!
What did you say I was?
A kung fu expert!
I have utmost admiration for you. . .
Cut the crap, serve dinner!
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely!
Mr. Top Warrior, a toast!
Let's forget our misunderstanding!
Please!
Prince, with Mr. Top Warrior
You'll be triumphant at war
Including the one you wage on the Capital
What? Are you accusing me of treason?
Today. . . I'm so happy!
Let's have some entertainment!
Good idea! What do you have in mind?
Mr. Top Warrior is so capable
I wish to bet 1 00 taels of silver
He beat our men within 1 0 stances
- Maybe not!
- No?
Then I bet 1 million taels you'll lose
- Deal!
- Thank you!
- Prince!
- Don't make me lose face!
Your Majesty!
- Rise!
- Thank you!
Mr. Long, you may begin
1 23456789
One more!
Long! Don't lose face!
1 0!
Well? Thank you for the silver
- Can I pay later?
- Fine!
Please forgive me for hurting them!
Don't blame yourself!
Thank you, Your Majesty!
I have an announcement to make
I've decided to let
Princess Jian Ning marry Prince Wu
He'll be my brother-in-law
We'll all be family
Thank you, Your Majesty!
That's the best news all day!
You'll be the Imperial Envoy
Escort the Princess to Yunnan
Thank you, Your Majesty!
Do you know why I agree to this?
You must have you reasons, I dare not make guesses
Since Ao Bai's death
I have the allegiance of my subjects
Except rebels like Chen Jin Nan and
The Ming Princess, One-Arm Nun
These small potatoes are harmless
But I'm losing sleep over
My mortal enemy, Wu San Gui
Why make the Princess marry his son?
I have received news
He's enlisting an army and colluding
with the Dragon Sect
The bogus Empress Dowager must be part of his plan
He is rebellious
I'm appointing you as Imperial Envoy
Do you know my intention?
Find a way to eliminate him?
Certainly not!
If we kill him, we must uproot him
Control him by conciliation for now
Placate Wu San Gui
Stall him
When the time is right
I'll send troops in for a clean sweep
I understand!
My only worry
Is Jian Ning will refuse
- Try to persuade her!
- Yes!
Your Highness!
- Rise!
- Thank you!
You 2 may step down!
Yes!
You're killing me!
That's too easy for you!
You don't come see me anymore!
- I'm here now!
- That's better!
Congratulations!
I have great news!
Congratulations to you too!
I also have good news for you!
Again?
You go first!
His Majesty has agreed to your marriage
Really?
You will marry. . .
Wu San Gui's son, Wu Ying Xiong
I'm the Imperial Envoy escorting you
No way!
Why?
Because I'm pregnant!
I'm scared...
Really scarred...
What shall we do?
This is serious! I'll be beheaded
Go ask for my hand in marriage
I promise not to beat you
- You're too kind!
- Yes!
His Majesty cannot renege on a promise
Then I'll tell him you raped me
How can you turn things around!
Then I'll marry Wu Ying Xiong
Let him be the father to our child
But you must come to me every night
Then we'll be adulterers
They'll drown us!
Drowned or beheaded, take your pick!
We've reached 1 0 Miles Pavilion
We'll take a rest!
Prince, we'll rest here!
Yes, Your Majesty!
Let me help you!
You look magnificent in the armor
You have my utmost admiration...
Go to hell!
It's so damn hot! This hat looks like. . .
I've been shot in the head by an arrow
Please!
- Have a nice trip!
- Thank you!
- Here's to you!
- Cheers!
Bond!
So boring!
- What is it?
- I want you to play turtle!
Are you kidding? I'm sending you off!
Don't run around, I'm looking out for you
Looks like a lightning rod!
Thunder will strike you!
If it thunders
I'll get struck no matter what!
- Yes!
- Here, take this!
Jerk!
Stand up straight!
You look majestic!
Of course!
No one dares to touch the Emperor!
Bastard King!
Protect His Majesty!
Be careful!
Ice Palm?
Bastard King!
Protect His Majesty, you loafer!
- What?
- Protect him!
Ice Palm!
Are you alright?
Lucky for my Silk Armour
You saved my life, I'll name you...
Protect me!
What?
Protect His Majesty!
Rong!
- What's your name?
- Derek Wan
- I'll kill your family!
- Thank you!
Why is everyone here all at once?
Damn! Why are you bare footed?
Don't push!
Stop grabbing me!
We can't help it!
Who is so cocky?
- You bastard!
- Yes, how are you?
We can't fight like this
Let's push them out first
Alright!
Go to hell!
Your Majesty, you better go!
Please send me away as well!
One moment!
How much longer?
No need to push so hard!
Bastard! How far can you run?
I'll go as far as you go!
Take them hostage!
Go!
Go after them now!
Don't worry, I'll save the Prince
And Duke Bond as well!
Members of the Dragon Sect
Pursue the nun and Prince Wu!
What are you doing?
The sword is in front
Naturally my head stays back
You scoundrel! I'll kill you!
Master
Are you alright?
I didn't expect Kang Xi's bodyguard
To be such a kung fu expert
Perhaps Qing dogs' days are not over
Shall I go find a doctor?
Stop!
Bond is a cunning rascal
Let's kill him first
I was just trying to help!
No! He's Kang Xi's confidant
He's our amulet
Let's kill him instead
No!
Miss Ke, I saved you at Li Chun Brothel
Remember?
You've seen him before?
Yesterday, we almost fell victim to
Bond's treacherous scheme
This gentleman saved us
Why didn't you tell me before?
You also forgot to tell her
This gentleman is Wu San Gui's son
The kung fu expert works for him
He's Wu San Gui's son?
Let me kill him!
No, please don't kill me
You dare to disobey me?
Help! I'm over here!
Release the hostages!
Come and get them if you can!
Don't worry, she's wounded
To die from my Yi Yang Finger
Is your privilege
I took the liberty
To help you
Please forgive me!
What? You used a gun!
Why did you help me?
Mr. Wu!
Relax!
He's just asleep!
You may speak freely now
Please forgive my manners
Qing Ming?
Overthrow Qing restore Ming!
You're from Tian Di Hui?
Yes!
I'm head of the Greenwood Branch
Here's proof of my identity
Master Chen sent me to the Palace as undercover
It's my pleasure to meet you today
Don't believe him! He's a liar!
The token is genuine!
How is Master Chen?
Very well, thank you!
He mentions you all the time
That his kung fu is second to you
Your are indeed the master
He's nowhere compared to you
Master Chen is too kind
I wish to become your pupil!
I wonder if I may have the honor?
Please get up!
Unless you agree
I won't get up
- Alright!
- Thank you!
I know you're prejudiced against me
In time, you'll understand
I'll take you in temporarily
Until I get Master Chen's consent
I cannot teach you anything
Thank you, sister. . .no, Master!
We can't stay here
Let's leave!
One of my pupils is waiting for us ahead
Yes!
Is the One-Armed swordsman your father?
No!
There Is An Inn
Indeed
Minister Duo, who are you staring at that man?
That's a woman!
How do you know?
Everyone else vomits when they see me
Except him
So she's not a man
Brilliant!
My utmost admiration for you. . .
Shut up!
Master! Over here!
Thank you!
Looking for me?
Get lost!
Nan, Master has been wounded
Attend to her inside
Ke, watch over him downstairs!
Bond, go on patrol
See if we're being followed
What about him. . .
I hit his vital points, he can't hear or talk
Don't worry!
I just want to tell you
I'm actually. . .
Get lost!
Minister Bond!
You're truly a man of all men
Even your vomiting is so stylish
Duo Long, what are you doing?
We came quick!
This is the only inn within a 1 0-mile radius
We came here for your rescue
I don't need your help!
I've gained the nun's confidence
I came with them because of her
Such distinguished taste! A nun!
I admire you
Admire my ass!
I'm after her pupil Li Ke
Did you bring my things?
Yes, including your favorite outfit
Smart lad! Your prospect looks good
Damn! Apple-polishing is my specialty!
You're too handsome
Sir, you look magnificent
Endless like the river
My utmost admiration
Forget your admiration
Sorry, Sir! I've prepared this for you
"Lustful Playboy"
"Wanton Grandma"
"Lascivious Bitch"
These 3 kinds of aphrodisiac. . .
Are the worst king
Watch this!
What is it?
Other than "Lecherous Slut"
"I Love Dicky" is the most effective
You can't even smell this stuff
So formidable?
Give it a try!
And you'll know
When it acts up
The victim will be extremely horny
When they see sticks or poles
They will chase after it persistently
No matter how much you resist
Taunt or even beat them
They will not give up
What's the remedy?
Just one spray
It appears to me there's no escape for Miss Ke
"Release me"
Please let me go!
I can't!
Then we'll elope!
How dare you!
This is from the bottom of my heart
When I saw you at Li Chun Brothel
It was love at first sight!
I didn't have the chance to tell you
Why are you marrying the Princess?
That was part of my father's plan
We overthrow the Manchus and he'll be King
I'll be the crowned Prince
My wife will be the crowned Princess
Or maybe Queen
That's none of my business
Don't you understand?
I only love you
Only you are fit to be my Queen
Is he pulling tricks again?
How could he?
That's true!
What's this?
Such ugly handwriting
Did your write this? You're in trouble!
He...
Tell me
What are those words?
"Don't move!"
I wrote it
You must be tired from standing
Let me fetch you a chair
Thanks
- Master. . .
- Yes?
Are you alright?
I'm fine. I cured myself already
I mean. . .are you alright?
Never mind that, you step outside
We have things to discuss
Stop!
Yes, Master?
Are you sure we're not being followed?
I don't think so
- Go now!
- Yes!
What's the matter?
I used "I Love Dicky" on the nun by mistake
I'm dressed as a woman, why is she still after me?
Because you look like a dick!
Master!
Let's leave in this chaos!
You can't betray Master like this!
Come with me, I won't disappoint you
Come on!
Welcome, Master!
Release the Prince and Bond
Or else we'll move in
Who are they?
Never mind! Just hold them off!
Guards, stand down!
Go get Bond that bastard
Me again?
You look treacherous!
Is this what you think of me?
I'm righteous
I have utmost admiration for you
Undying like the surging flood
You traitor!
No! Better sacrifice one than both
At least I'll look after your grave
Look for the one responsible
Here's the one you want
Sissy, why are you dressed as a woman?
How dare you! Kneel before the Master!
No need to dressed like that
I told you I'll be back
Don't you recognize me?
Divine Lady of the Dragon Sect!
You! Plastic surgery?
This is the real me!
You're much better looking now
- Isn't she?
- Yes!
We're old friends, let's clear things up
Duo Long, let's go!
You 2 know each other, I don't
Master, excuse me!
You've gone too far!
No, just the usual!
Where are the Nun and the Prince?
I'm not the perpetrator
He's up there, go after him!
How enormous!
Shut up or I'll cut out your tongue!
That's my livelihood!
One more step I'll cut off your legs
You're after the Nun and me
Whose side are you on?
It's personal between us
You ruined my plan and tried to kill me!
The Emperor ordered the arrows, not me!
I'm not the perpetrator!
It's not my fault!
Come over here!
Coming!
What do you want?
Help me up!
- What are you doing?
- Helping you!
Smells nice!
No? Should I say you stink?
If you help me back to the Dragon Sect
I let you live
Thanks! Let's go!
I know
You're working for Wu San Gui
He is our benefactor
How do you know?
My master told me!
Maybe she's bullshitting you!
What do you mean?
I mean lying
Will you lie to your father?
Yes!
If there's any benefit
What if there is?
- Again and again!
- Bastard!
I'll get you in bed someday, bitch!
Impregnate you!
What? Walk faster!
Look at the skinny tiger!
No, it's a donkey!
No, it's a dog!
Where are you going? Go back!
Master, Prince Wu is here
With special Envoy Feng Xi Fan
Show them in!
Thanks for your help at the inn
So that I can escape from the Nun
They way you put it
Are you making fun of me?
Don't get me wrong!
My father will declare war soon
To thank your help in recruiting and
Training the troops
I'm here to offer you wine
And name you Divine Protector
Thanks, His Excellency!
Serve the wine!
Last time I was too busy
To accompany the Prince
Thanks for your help
Cheers
Thanks
Something fishy!
Good!
I heard the Dragon Sect's kung fu
Is invincible and unique
Is that true?
It's been exaggerated!
Tell me if you can
Resist the top poison
The invisible "Lecherous Slut"
What do you mean?
The Dragon Sect is getting out of hand
His Excellency wants you dead
And a clean sweep of your Sect
Guards! Arrest them!
You think you can win?
We have taken over before your return
Your followers have surrendered
Those who refused are killed
Long Er, I've searched high and low
And found the poison that'll break you
The wine is laced with "Lecherous Slut"
Do you feel hot now?
You must copulate with a man before dawn
Or you'll die from spitting blood
Perhaps I can help
I'll save you, Master!
Master, you're strong enough
Let me have the 80%
- You...
- It's a fact!
Be good! Please help me! Go!
Dragon Blood Escape!
I'll buy you a midnight snack
Let me help you! Are you alright?
I've used my last breath
To execute Dragon Blood Escape
The poison is acting up now
Let me rub your chest!
Don't touch me! Get lost!
Forget it!
I already told you
Everyone bullshits you
I'm the only one who didn't
You should thank me for it!
Don't go!
Now what?
Though he's annoying
At least he speaks the truth
Our Sect has been loyal to Wu San Gui
Yet he destroys us
Will I die here?
Jia Bao Yu?
Come over here!
Changed your mind again?
Just tell me what you want!
Come here quick!
Probably wants me to cure her
She's too kind to me!
Spider Woman!
Help!
Perhaps this is fate
If you disappoint me
I'll kill you!
- You awake?
- I didn't sleep
Bond, I'm yours now
I'll do as you tell me
Please pass me my pants
How obedient!
It's dawn already!
- Come here!
- Yes?
Everyone tells me
Wu San Gui is a hero
Now I know, heroes are not real
I know that now
You're so pretty!
I'm hungry! Let's get something to eat!
What's going on?
You've taken 80% of my power
You're invincible now!
Me? Invincible?
I must be a virgin to practice our kung fu
If I lose my virginity
80%  of my power will go to my man
I only have 20%  left
Really?
Do you mind if I punch you?
Just kidding!
After what happened last night
You're the King of the Dragon Sect
You must avenge our members
Against who?
Wu San Gui and Feng Xi Fan
I will go after them
Minister Bond. . .
Stop crying! Start talking?
Or else I'll kill you
Minister Bond is my only sworn brother
Our friendship is endless like the river
- That night...
- What about that night?
I fought off hundreds of men
But that bitch caught him
Grabbed his arms and legs
And pulled off his head
He's dead?
Yes!
I'm scared...
Really scared. . .
Princess, why the singing mood?
You won't understand. It's between me and Bond
It's alright, Princess
I'm willing to take over his women
Don't worry. Someone else will do it
You can go now!
Yes, Your Highness!
- Minister Duo!
- Rise!
Thank you, Sir!
I've prepared a dinner
I wish you and the Princess will come
I'm in no mood to eat since Bond is dead
- I'll take cash instead!
- Yes, Sir
He died bravely for the country
We must bury him in style
Prepare everything in gold
I'll find the best goldsmith
Save the trouble. Better cash it in!
Minister Bond loved beautiful women
In case he haunts me at in my dream
I'll need women to standby
Put 8-1 0 women in my bed
How considerate!
Minister Bond must be touched
Of course! But I'm a decent man
To sleep with so many women
Is more than I can manage
What's the matter with you?
Nothing!
I wonder when my wish will come true
My wish... come true
Duo Long, what have you done?
Wish come true...
Thank goodness, Minister Bond!
You're alive!
My wish come true!
With a friend like you, I hate to die
Of course!
You've been so loyal to me!
Since I turned you in that day
I laid awake in bed every night
And cried till dawn
I can only remember 2 words
I even tattooed them on my arm
That serious! Which 2 words?
See for yourself
"Take revenge"
That's right!
I can't tell if it is written correctly
It should be
I think about this day and night
What I must do for you
Is take revenge
You're still bleeding
Did you just tattoo them?
Of course not!
It bleeds every time I get excited
I'm excited to see you now
So it starts to bleed again!
Why are you holding a knife?
Why is there a knife?
Who put the knife in my hand?
You are my true friend indeed
I'm glad you're my sworn brother
I'm glad you think so
Let me tell you a secret
I can keep a secret
His Majesty sent me to
Tian Di Hui as undercover
To spy on Chen Jin Nan
According to my intelligence
They have branches across the country
Including one in Yunnan
Really?
That's why I want you
To do something for me
Me?
Shout the password in the market
Someone will take you to their branch
What password?
Overthrow Qing restore Ming
How can I say something so treacherous?
It's the only way to contact the rebels
I will also tattoo a code on your back
- Another one?
- Yes!
When you get inside
The one dressed as a courtier
Is Chen Jin Nan
Show him the code on your back
He'll give you something
- What is it?
- A secret!
Don't interrupt my song
Princess
Overthrow Qing restore Ming
What?
Tian Di Hui branch
That's too obvious!
Monkey knows about it too?
Bond is in Kunming!
He is cunning
Don't underestimate him
Father!
He insulted me repeatedly
I want him dead
You fool! He's the Imperial Envoy!
To kill him is to go against the Emperor
Our troops are not ready till next month
We cannot let a personal grudge mess up our plan
That's right!
When we attack the capital
Chopping him to pieces
Will be a piece of cake
Be patient!
Besides, you're marrying the Princess
Just humor her for the time being
Pretend to prepare for the wedding
Don't let Kang Xi sense
We're up to something
- Understand?
- Yes, sir!
An emissary from Guangdong is here
To discuss the rebellion
I don't want too many people around
Dismiss the guards in the backyard
Yes, sir!
So flagrantly bold!
The door is open!
No wonder Tian Di Hui is
no match for the government
Overthrow Qing restore Ming
Who's speaking such nonsense?
Who is it?
Who are you?
He looks like a courtier!
Are you the undercover?
What's the code?
What code?
Overthrow Qing restore Ming
How dare you? Guards!
I have a code on my back
What? Overthrow Qing restore Ming!
Kill Wu San Gui?
Now you know who I am
I know your ass!
Bastard! I have the code!
How dare you hit back!
Guards! Catch the assassin!
How dare you hit me?
Assassin! Guards!
Arrest him!
Go to hell!
I dare you to fight me
Come on!
Aim to kill?
That's what happens to rebels!
Fix him good!
Overthrow Qing restore Ming
Your Excellency
The Princess has arrived,
accompanied by Minister Bond
I apologize for not welcoming you
Rise!
You'll be her father-in-law soon
Well...
What happened to your eye?
I bruised it accidentally
Summon Ying Xiong
Help!
Minister Bond, help!
Who are you?
I'm Duo Long
Duo Long is not as handsome as you
Take this rebel away!
Yes!
- Minister Bond. . .
- Of course
Remember we went whoring?
Are you really Duo Long?
Yes!
He barged into my mansion
And shouted the treacherous slogan
Overthrow Qing restore Ming
That makes him a rebel
But he really is Duo Long
Why did you beat up the envoy?
Yeah!
He's the envoy?
Yes!
I am indeed
Even so
That was a flagrant crime
But he's a Manchu
To overthrow Qing is against his kind!
Yeah!
Have you been framed?
Definitely! I've been framed!
How dare you accuse me?
Look at his back!
Let me see!
There's nothing! Just a bit dirty!
You wiped it!
It read Overthrow Qing restore Ming
Kill Wu San Gui
Are you accusing me now?
Bond, watch your manners!
Yes!
Let me make a judgment
Please!
Your Excellency is definitely. . .at fault!
Duo Long is the Imperial Envoy
He escorts me bearing the Imperial Sword
If he should use
The Imperial Sword
Against Your Excellency
Even I cannot save you!
That's right!
Who beat me up just now?
Is that you?
Take is easy!
Did you beat me up?
I'm not the perpetrator
Kill the one who fixed you!
Take it easy!
I'll kill you
Here's the Death Exemption Medal
The Imperial Sword cannot kill me
Father, remember the Medal?
Death Exemption Medal?
That's right!
I almost forgot
I dare you!
Can I?
Not if he has the medal
But those who don't have it. . .
Father, let me borrow the Medal
Son...
Give me! You can outrun him!
No, you're the Lord!
Give it to me!
No! Give it to me!
Give me!
Stop! Who do you want me to kill?
You don't have the Medal. I'll start with you!
Give me!
Here!
Give it back!
Where is it? Where's the Medal?
In there!
The Medal is here!
Sorry!
Are you alright?
- Guards!
- Yes!
- Help him inside to rest!
- Yes, Sir!
I'll look after him
- Everything is fine. You may go
- Yes!
How are you?
It hurts!
Really? What should we do?
Can I look?
Maybe not
Don't' be silly, we'll get married soon
Let me take a look
Take it easy! I have the Medal!
Take it easy!
Minister Duo, we all make mistakes
You've already been beaten
Let's settle with compensation!
Fine
Since you're not seriously injured
How about 500,000 taels
What?
Forget it then!
Please continue!
Alright! I'll pay!
The Imperial Jade Seal?
I don't know
Wu San Gui destined to rule,
usurp the throne at once
Imperial Jade Seal is proof
Your Excellency!
I had nothing to do with this
I've been framed
I have no intention to rebel
Sorry!
- I'm scared!
- Son!
Princess!
Are you alright?
What happened?
He tried to rape me!
I picked up a knife and cut it off
Prince, you're so insensible!
The Princess will be your wife soon
Can't you wait?
What should I tell His Majesty?
I'm scared!
- You!
- Good job!
I learnt from you! I'm scared
Guards!
Sir?
Escort the Princess to Phoenix Tower
- Yes, Sir!
- I'm really scared
It's bad luck, Minister Bond
Pardon my poor hospitality
I'm really scared!
Such odd timing for everything to happen
I wouldn't know how to deal with it
Let's go
I'm really scared!
Sir! Young master has not waken
- Summon Mr. Feng
- Yes, Sir!
Alert the troops!
Yes, Sir!
Your Excellency!
Is Ying Xiong alright?
His genitals are seriously injured
Propagation will be a problem
Kang Xi, you Bastard
You wanted to end my bloodline
I want revenge!
Order the troops to attack!
Please stay calm! We're not ready
Chances are slim if we declare war now
Please wait 6 months. . .
I said deploy the troops!
Who's giving orders here?
Sorry, Sir!
Attack Phoenix Tower now!
I'll tear Jian Ning and Bond to pieces
Falling petals shadowing the moon. . .
How poetic!
Have some wine!
What's on your mind?
You're too suspicious!
I just want you to meet some friends
Long Er!
You're into that! Don't touch me!
No! She's a woman!
We'll be family
You're dreaming? What is she?
She won't get half of my husband!
Half is impossible!
You only have a quarter! Shang Er!
I knew there's something going on!
It's common for a man to have 3 wives
and 4 concubines
I only have 3 wives and 1 concubine
That's extremely embarrassing!
Not in your dreams!
They will never be my equal!
No way!
Of course, they're not your equal
They're the wives, you're the concubine
When they sit, you must stand
When we sleep, you pull the covers
Go to hell!
I told you not to hit my face!
Damn your face!
A concubine must not hit the master
That's inappropriate
Shang Er, teach her a lesson
Stop! How dare you offend a Princess
Fine! I'm bearing his child
I dare you to hit me!
Of course you can't hit my child
Don't aim for the belly
Aim for the chest!
Help!
What's the matter?
Relax! Your faithful Duo Long is here!
They're bullying me!
This is Deadly Dragon Palm
It'll leave your body in pieces
If you wish, you can stand right there!
I'll count to 3!
Don't pay attention to her!
You're so agile!
Will you be is concubine?
Can I be his wife?
Fine. We'll be sisters
We're all sisters now
I'll name you Scallop
It's homonymic to "bearing son"
What an awful name!
What about abalone?
Abalone? It's better!
Early dinner?
- Master!
I'd like you to meet
Long Er of the Dragon Sect
She has sided with us now!
You know Shang Er
That' Abalone! Have a seat!
Feng Xi Fan has taken action
He is extremely cunning
His kung fu is comparable to mine
You're no match for him!
Who is he?
I followed your orders
Made a mess at Wu San Gui's mansion
He probably can't wait to rebel now
Yes! He'll attack Phoenix Tower tonight
He wants to skin you alive!
He's bluffing! I'm not afraid of him
Duo Long, get me the fastest horse!
I must excuse myself!
They will mobilize the troops soon
Princess Jian Ning
They'll want you as hostage
What shall we do?
Leave Kunming at once
Master, deploy us as you see fit!
Bond, be careful!
Watch for the child too
I will take care of you both
Go now!
Take Long Er with you
I'll stay behind
- Master!
- You're smart
In this troubled times
If you don't covet after wealth
You can overthrow the Qing regime
And restore the Ming Dynasty
That'll be the best
One thing I still don't understand
Say it!
Kang Xi brought us peace and prosperity
After Ao Bai's death
People are content
They are well fed and clothed
Why must we overthrow him?
Because it's my life long wish
Really?
We go to war because of your wish?
Making everyone suffer
That's a bit. . .
There's no time to argue!
Chen Jin Nan!
You're behind the times!
Feng Xi Fan! Back away!
It's been a long time!
You've become a running dog
A rich man's dog is still better than a poor man
Can't you understand?
You're shameless!
Lu He Formation!
Your power has decreased
Who did you pass it to?
How dare you pick on her?
What? Hula hoops?
More? That's enough!
Again? I'm not playing anymore!
Can't be that formidable!
What's the matter?
Your power is scattered
You can't use it properly
So she passed it to you!
Yes! So what?
She's been injured, leave with her
Master, can you manage?
I can if you can
That's true! I'm leaving!
Sword formation!
Lu He Formation!
You bad-mouthed about me
So that Master kicked me out
This is your retribution
I should have killed you then
I was too kind to let you go
You can only blame your stupidity
You lost!
Cut the crap and just kill me!
Of course not
You're my ticket to fame and fortune!
Be careful!
Long Er, hold on!
How are you?
I'm fine
It's just flesh wound
Don't be so sad!
Emotional is always my shortcoming
Don't be silly! That's not true
You have other virtues
Don't be silly! I only have one virtue!
I'd like some notice before you show up!
I already made a noise!
Didn't you hear me?
Bond, this is...
Long Er is my wife now
You have subdued her?
It's too complicated for a nun to understand
You are unfathomable indeed
How did you arrest them?
Wu San Gui was too busy deploying the troops
Security was loose
She was hiding inside the mansion
So I abducted both of them
I also found a copy of 42 Chapters
42 Chapters?
Let's hide it
This is crucial to our plan in
toppling the Qing regime
Thank you
What about them?
What should we do with them?
They should die for what they did
If you're willing to redeem yourself
I can give you a chance...
Thank you, Minister Bond
. . .to die first
- Kill him!
- Please spare me!
We'll die together
That's your decision! I didn't say that
Please spare my pitiful life!
I'll be your slave!
You don't have to be afraid
You promised we'll be together!
I was just kidding. Don't be so serious!
How can you say that?
I'm almost an eunuch
You don't need me! Leave me alone!
Please don't cry!
Get lost, you bastard!
How can you say that?
You still won't appreciate what I've done for you
He treats you like dirt and yet. . .
Is this what you want?
Bond, what are you saying?
Nothing! Come with me
Wait on my wife in the day time
Wait on me at night
You're lucky he'll take you in
Or else I'll kill you
You should thank him
That's right, you should thank him!
Thank you for not killing me
Thank you for cleaning up my mess
You are impudent!
- Shameless!
- Good job!
You too!
I feel hurt when you're in pain
You've cheated another girl!
It' a living! Don't be too harsh on me!
Your generosity is much appreciated
Your Majesty!
Rise! Bond, come quick!
Thank you
I missed you!
Are you quite well?
I'm fine, thank you!
You have something to tell me?
Yes!
Wu San Gui is plotting a rebellion
You should issue a decree to punish him
Finish him off before he mobilizes the troops
I have deployed my troops 2 days ago
Wise decision, Your Majesty!
I am deeply impressed
In case you're wondering how I know
Of course
I'd like you to meet a new colleague
You 2 can help me rule
Who is it?
You bastard!
Watch your mouth, Bond!
Duke Bond is outspoken by temperament
Using vulgar language is quite common
- You...
- Duke Bond
Now that we're colleagues
Please forgive and forget the past
What did you do to my Master?
See this 2nd rank outfit?
You turned him over to the Emperor!
Feng Xi Fan has submitted
Wu San Gui's plans
And captured Chen Jin Nan
That's a great service
You 2 should get along fine
- Yes!
- Of course!
Bond
You've been accused of being a member
of Tian Di Hui
I have been worried ever since
To clear your name
You will oversee Chen's execution
Then no one will suspect
You're related to him
What do you think?
I appreciate your consideration
Thank you!
Ever since he returned from the Palace
He's laden with anxiety
I wonder why?
We don't know either
He loves you, do you know?
He didn't tell me
I've bathed him since he was a child
I know everything about him
He can't fool me
What is it then?
I don't know
I have been invincible so far
But now, I have no confidence
You had the Emperor's support
But now he trusts Feng Xi Fan
How can you have confidence?
These 42 Chapters?
I still can't find the secret
Burn them!
Why?
I want to
Her Highness is here!
Your Highness!
Your Highness
Rise!
You can leave now!
Yes!
Hello, sisters!
Sister-in-law, how are you!
- Good girl!
- Master!
Something wrong?
Yes!
My brother ordered the Banner leaders to watch you
And besiege this place on his order
You must be careful
Must be Feng Xi Fan's ploy
What's burning?
There are words!
East. . .you read it!
- Invincible East?
- Is come?
It's Eastern Tomb
These words are fire resistant!
The secret is at the tomb?
I have a plan
Your Majesty!
What can I do for you?
I have a bit of a cough
I want to go hunting tomorrow
Would you like to join me?
Yes, I will protect Your Majesty
Good! Guards!
Award the Imperial Sword
Thank you
A sword for a general
Please remember
Do not unsheathe the sword rashly
Or it'll draw blood
Yes, Your Majesty
I'll see you tomorrow
I'll take my leave now
It's my fault that you're suffering
No! I underestimated him
Rest assured, before your execution
I will kill Feng Xi Fan
You're no match for him!
I have 80%  of Long Er's power
Besides
But you can't control the power
With the Lu He Kids
He's invincible
I'll take my chances
Good for you!
Come over here!
Master, what are you doing?
There's nobody here!
Feng Xi Fan, you've been had!
I dare you to show your face!
Be a man and come out!
I've been waiting!
You gained a woman's power
Now you've become a sissy!
Don't you like it?
I'm sewing a pair of underwear for you!
See how mean you are!
Won't even clothe them properly!
Come, let me help you!
Lu He Formation!
Golden Snake Hand?
Lu He Kids eat shit?
How fitting?
I had reservations about you
But now I have the Imperial Sword
You'll be sorry
I'll go find the Emperor
Here I am
Your Majesty?
I want to go hunting tomorrow
Would you like to join me?
It was you!
That's right!
Our paths don't cross
Yet you keep pushing me
You double-crossing bastard
I want to avenge my Master
Lu He Power
Wrong pose!
Sorry!
I'm go play hula hoops
You take a break
Lu He Palm
Wonderful
Your power has increased!
Are you scared?
Bond, you're my only hope
I have taught you everything
You'll head up Tian Di Hui for me
If I don't come fully equipped
How can I kill you?
You've went through a lot of trouble
And used the Princess to trap me
I'm afraid it'll all go to waste
Soul Changing formation!
Dragon Hand
I pinch!
Pinch!
No reaction?
Do it again! I like it!
Shameless!
Soft Debone Palm
Done! Let's go
Lu He formation!
Bond, needles and thread
Ice Palm
I got it!
Have a taste of your own medicine
Bond!
Are you alright?
Can't believe it's so easy!
The Manchu treasure
Has become gold sand
Rumor said it's hidden outside the frontier
But it's hidden within the capital
This is an underground tomb
Tomb?
Eastern Tomb?
The secret of the 42 Chapters
The Dragon Wall was specially designed
It's our fengshui wall
Let's stop fighting
And split the gold
This is what we're fighting for
A handful of this is a lot already
Let's forget it!
You're right!
- Well?
- Why not?
I knew you'd do that!
He stepped on something
A trap!
Run!
You're bleeding!
Yes, but he's in deeper shit
Why is he stabbing himself?
To stimulate himself
Shutting off the vital veins
To fully utilize his latent energy
Really?
This is a serious blow
You must give your best to block him
Bond!
Are you alright?
Stab me on the head with needles
I want to use my latent energy
I don't know his method
But there's another way
With the same effect?
How?
Pain!
Pain?
I'll stab the most painful pressure points
Don't scream
Hold it in till the last moment
Then. . .
Use my clog
Thanks!
Armpit
Spine
Big toe
Let it out!
It hurts!
His latent energy is amazing!
Bond, you won!
These jewels and gold are harmful
So many people died for them
To rectify the situation
I'll keep them
Bond, destroy the Dragon Wall
And end the Qing regime
But why?
Under Kang Xi, people are wealthy
They all go to school
Is that so bad?
I don't care who's the Emperor
As long as he's a good Emperor
Right, Long Er?
Perhaps
Let's move his body to the execution ground
Or else it'll be too late
Stay away!
Behead him!
What's taking so long?
Here they come!
Master!
So good to see you!
I always knew
You're a good pupil
It's getting late, let's go!
If the Emperor finds out about the swap
We'll be in trouble
His Majesty is here!
Put that away!
Let me talk to him!
Your Majesty!
How dare you kill my courtier
And kidnap the prisoner?
Duo Long!
You're right! I betrayed you again!
You haven't changed a bit
Yes!
Frankly, Your Majesty
I have supreme power now
None of your people
Can stop me from doing anything?
Anything?
Including killing you
But I can't find a reason
To kill a beloved Emperor like you
Will you be so generous
And go easy on me and my family?
Please let us go!
- Rise!
- Thank you!
Again?
I've heard about your supreme power
I just want proof
You are indeed tougher than before
I have killed the rebel Bond
His accomplices have fled
He no longer exists
Be good to Jian Ning
Thanks for the Imperial squeeze!
- Don't let anyone bully her!
- Yes!
We'll always be good friends!
I agree!
- Take care!
- Bye!
Bye!
I bluffed him! My dear wives. . .
Let's go!
Don't care about right or wrong
My legend will pass on via songs
All I want is to have fun
Don't are what's mine and what's not
Just be happy
Be happy when you can
Have fun when you can
Everything is just a game
Life is just a game
Whether it's true or false
It's just a play
Such a waste