Come in, have a game and win!
Sir, you've won give me some tip?
What's the matter with you?
That's my money
Get lost!
Your money would've been robbed by the rascals
Th ank you
Remember, don't show off your money
Time has changed, a rascal becomes a good doer
You r mea| sir
Mister, Mister
Get lost!
Stop th ere
Damn kid... stealing rice
l'll teach you...
I've done nothing
Waiter
Th ank you
Let me go!
Hey, why are you treating a child so badly
l'm treating him badly’? He was stealing my rice
Ok, let me compensate for it
Let's go
Sorry, I'm sorry
Take out the money, quickly
You listening?
You'd better release me! Stop harassing me!
And what if I don't release you?
l'll beat you down
You trying to hit me or what?
Give it back to him, Hsiao Wen
What now?
Come on
Line up!
Boss, I only brought back a little bit
That's useless to me, no treats for you
But...
Next!
I've never seen this kind of paper money before
What's this?
l have done as you said
I stole it from that old man from America
Oh, then it's us. Dollars, great! You can have anything
you want.
Thanks boss
Next!
We made use of what you taught us and stole this
I stole it from a countryman
Now we can loosen our belts and eat till we're full.
Are you blind?
There are many traders and businessmen about, yet you
chose a countryman, It smells.
It's no surprise you've become so fat
you make the children steal, while you sit down all day
Then you reap all the benefits
What are you here for?
Give me back my money
What money?
You've got it in your hand
Do you have any proof?
Give it back, or I'll force you to
Out of the way now, let me deal with him
Let me show you some Kung fu today
Whoever learns, may have a chance to be my successor
I don't think you can compare with me
What do you mean by that?
l'll teach him a lesson, then you'll know for sure
You mean to insult me now?
Yes, I do
Your Kung Fu is not bad
Afraid now? Then give me the money
Me afraid? I've never known the feeling
Now watch!
What do you call that, boss?
It's called the Growling Tiger
Hey, careful of any damages
l'll smash everything up
You're pretty powerful
Well of course I am
No, you've missed me
You're pretty good, all you need now is a good teacher
Alright, I'll be the teacher
Look, Master is so great
So you like my Kung fu?
Look behind you Master!
What?
Boss has won again
How about that... powerful right?
Get up...
You won't accept my kindness?
Ok you don't need to give me my money
Don't smash up my placejust because you've lost?
You really mean it...
No no...
You...
That one is of precious value to my family, please don't
break it
You know what to do
l'll hand the money over
Pass it then
lt's shameful to do it in front of the children
What about the rest?
Oh, sorry I forgot
Is that all?
What more do you want?
How about the interest?
You want interest from me?
Alright, 2.5 °/o interest, is that enough
Master, you made an agreement with him?
He was afraid of me
Wh at!?
I said... you and..
Oh, it's all right never mind
This way...
Come back and visit when you want
You you payed him off
What?
You're saying I payed him? You must bejoking
You gave back the money that we got
Hey, you think I'm stupid
Look I have it here
Business hasn't been as quiet as today in years
What's going on, don't people cook?
Please miss, please
Come in for some rice
Hey there, if you buy rice at the new shop, you get free
lottery tickets
Really?
Yes, who'd miss that opportunity?
Miss, it's quite early, where are you off to?
I'm going to buy some fresh rice
I can get some for you here, and deliver it to your home!
Don't even bother, the new rice shop is offering free lottery
tickets
What are you offering?
Come on, come on, this is a one day offer
Buy 10 catties and you get one free lottery ticket
The more you buy, the more tickets you'll get
Try your luck
This is high quality rice too
Come on now, quickly
Thank you very much, come again
Here's you chance to get rich
You get one lottery ticket for every ten cattied of rice
First prize is two Gold bars
Second prize, you get one gold bar
Third prize, you get some barbecued pork
Forth prize, you get a bottle of Ginseng wine
This may be your lucky day so come and try your luck
Your big chance to get rich
Tell me, what's going on?
They're offering lottery tickets
This is ruining our business
This can't happen to me. What is it that they're offering?
The tickets are for ginseng, bars of gold, barbecue pork..
They're putting us out of business
I know what to do!
We'll mix their rice with sand
We could never do that
What is this?
Why is there so little?
What do you think, boss?
Stop there, I'll weigh it for you
Calm down
This is the wrong weight, they've cheated you
Go and get your money back
We want our money back...
Boss... My reward..
Oh, sorry, come in, welcome
Hi sir, come inside
Come on...
Come on then...
Take a seat, I'll bring you a girl
Quickly, you can'tjust stand around
You're supposed to be working
Get inside!
And where did they find you?
Are you going to just stand still?
Can I come closer?
Fist let me know if you have money
I wouldn't be here if I didn't have any
Let's see it then
There's no need to be looking down at me
Look at this!
I'm quite rich
In time, I'll be co-owner of the Wen Li Rice shop
Is that so? How could you be the co-owner?
That new Hang Chang rice shop will go out of business
since I played some tricks on them
So you'd better treat me well, and I'll treat you well
If not, I'll use my tricks on this place and put you out of
business too
You couldn't
What's going on?
You bastard, you tricked us
How dare you try to ruin our business
Stop that, you'll kill me
Sir
Yes, wait your tu rn
Excuse me, where's Ah Chu?
Don't even ask, I have no idea
If he has any money, he's probably at the brothel
He'll pick up a disease if he isn't careful
There you go
Sorryjust a minute
Sorry sir, but who is Ah Chu to you?
He's my broth er-inlaw
Oh, good that you came
You can help me out
Boss! Boss! You've got to help!
Sister!
Broth er!
What's happening?
Ah Chu is being bullied, you have to help him
Help me, help me
Someone get me down
Help me! Get me down...
Ah Chu, are you alright?
Get that man! Stop him fast!
Get out of here!
Go!
Brother, are you alright?
Wh ere's Ah Chu ?
He's sleeping in the room
Well we have to wake him up
Brother, what's the matter?
l have to question him
What is he doing fooling around when he has a nice wife
like you?
Don't say that brother, he's not like that
You should ask what he was doing yesterday?
He comes back late due to work at the shop
He has lots of work to do, but he's always at the brothel
What's th e matter?
Isn't it normal for a man to go to the brothel sometimes?
Don't be stupid
You're supposed to make sure he remains a good man
No need, I won't do it again
Brother, Ah Chu has admitted it
Will you forgive him?
Tell him you're sorry
Broth er, I apologise
You won't do it again...
Get up, brother has forgiven you
Brother, aren't you teaching Kung Fu in town?
How did you find the time to come and see us?
I haven't been teaching for months now
I had to close down
If you'd like, you can stay here with us
Thanks a lot, though I'll have to find ajob
For a strong young guy like you, you'd get ajob easily
You can find a job anywhere
Very good, th anks
Get them!
You'll push me out of business
What are you trying to do?
Stop there, we can discuss this
We'll get him too
What now?
Don't worry, I'm here
Come, let's go
Let them run away
I'm asking to tell me... Is there anyone who is eloquent,
active and can never lose a fight?
Yes
Who?
Thejudge is very Eloquent
The fists of Jackie Chan
The Legs of Bruce Lee
That's enough, where are they now?
Some have died, some have gone away
Nonsense, I'm asking you who we can use to beat the guy
Go and ask Uncle Hsien, his Kung fu is Marvelous
Where can we find him?
We can find him at the brothel
Please sit down, who do you want, sir?
Do you have someone you know?
Uncle Hsien? He's inside
Be quick
I'm coming
What are you looking at?
Go and get him
No way, I can't disturb him, he'll kill me
You shouldn't go in
Why?
There's a lady inside
Don't be impatient, just sit down and wait
Let's go in
You mustn't go in... Just wait a minute, there's one more
lady
Still another? He'll be weak, how can hefight?
He's coming out
You're uncle Hsien?
Yes, what's the matter?
I've come to ask for your help
Alright, fighting down others is a trade of mine
That's good, how much do you want?
You've come to visit me, we'll be friends from now on. I'll
take as much as you give me
That's good, I won't disappoint you
Wait!
Are you Uncle Hsien, sir?
Yes, I am
Nice to meet you
Hey, why did you hit me?
Who cares? I just did
You dare offend me? I'm Uncle Hsien
You're called Uncle Hsien too?
I'm called Hsien Ha, though I'm known as Uncle Hsien
Now who are you?
Tell me!
I'm called Hsien Ten, l'm known as Uncle Hsien too
What do you do?
What do you do then?
Just get out of here! Leave!
I've found you at last
I need your help
Shut up, I've heard the whole case
For cutting off a limb, Three Thousand
Six thousand for destroying his martial ability
Ten Thousand for his life
Alright, make him meet his end then
Brother, the Hang Chang restaurant has invited you to
come to dinner
They invited me to dinner?
Brother, you'd better be careful
Where is it?
In the Tai Pai Restaurant
Be careful, they may have made a plan
I think he's too scared to come anyway
Sorry, it has been reserved, come tomorrow
Sorry, you are...
Hang Chang invited me here
Here comes the guest
You're on time
I came as invited, so of course I'm on time
You're bold, please sit
We don't know each other
Why have you invited me?
I'm just here for money
Since you're here already, let's have a drink
Please
Cheers!
You think highly of me?
You're the guest and I'm the host, I have to make the toast
Th en thank you
Too bad, it's too bad
You don't think the wine is good enough?
It's too bad we have wine and no meal
What would you like to eat then?
It depends on the Host's preferences
Ok, we'll have snake first
How do you like the taste of this snake fist?
Not bad, but it should be left to cook for longer
Thank you for your snake fist
You let him go so easily
How about my money, give it back to me
Damnit, who'd give it back to you?
You guys, why are you still standing here?
What's that?
Give it back to me
I've told you many times, I don't mind if you couldn't catch
anything
But don't steal from me
Why won't you listen?
Boss, I didn't disobey you
lt's roasted pigeon
Roasted Pigeon?
It's fine
Delicious
Kid, you're young, but pretty fast
My bird!
You dirty brats!
That bird meant a lot to me but now you've killed it
l'll teach you!
Come here boy!
Master, I've got something for you so please don't punish
me as well
I didn't mean you...
Where did you get this?
A fat goat
That's no fat goat, the guy is a tiger
lt's ready, go ahead
Take it out
I haven't got it
Do you want to die?
Don't hurt him
Uncle 33
Feng I may, he's your kid?
How come my kid is... with you?
He stole my snuff bottle
You lost your snuff?
No one would dare to steal my things except you
You should have evidence before you accuse others
You work together, one plans and the other steals
You mean that l have your snuff?
I'm a man of experience, you can't deceive me
l've travelled around to a lot of places, and I've never let
anyone uncover a theft
That'd be shameful
There's an exception, right?
Let's make it clear, if you can't uncover it you must give
me face and let my kid go
How about if I find out?
If you find it, I'd submit totally and give this up forever
If I can't, we'll forget this ever happened
You said it yourself
I mean it, we're men
Come on
You'll lose face now
Too bad, it's not there
You're amazing, Fen I May
You've lost your thing, and now you've retrieved it
We made an agreement, you must give me face
Wait a minute
That was risky
Not so salty, it's delicious
That was a big risk since you were nearly caught
Why?
Don't you know? He's Uncle 33, since he killed 33 people
Although he's given up his trade, his character surely
hasn't changed
If it was uncovered, you'd have become the 34th ghost
Master
No need to say, I know it all already
Why did you make trouble again?
l was paid to get rid of someone
But he defeated me
Do you know the consequence of your dealings?
If you cause trouble outside, you'll disrupt my plans
I fear that he'll interfere with us again
So I think you should deal with him your self
Wh o's there?
Who do you want?
What are you doing?
Release me!
Where's Wang Cheng?
I don't know
Tell me
If you don't want to tell me, I'll make you tell me
Oh, my hand! My hand!
I'll tell you, I'll tell you
lt's you
l have to go to the toilet, excuse me
You haven't died yet, that's good
What are you doing?
Lesve now
But I have to use the bathroom first
Hey, do I have to beat you up for you to leave?
What are you saying?
You've already caused enough trouble beating up the last
QUV
Be smart and leave town, otherwise you'll die
It'd be difficult to settle down elsewhere
Why do I have to leave?
I'm just telling you the truth
Don't say I didn't warn you
You stay if you want, now let me use the toilet
Wait
You dogs!
Bastards, let go of me
Ah Chuan
Ah Chuan, Ah Chuan, why be so foolish?
Chuan, Ah Chuan! Ah Chuan...
Hey you, come out if you dare
It's this guy
You dare come here
Nobody dares to offend me in this town
But you've offended me, I'm Uncle 33
How did I offend you?
You've brought trouble to me
Let's see whether you caused it or I did
You're pretty bold to fight with me
Can you even beat me?
Don't get excited, it'sjust my clothes
Watch out, or I'll take your life
You're just scratching my itchy spots
I can kill you easily
Hey, we'll see how long you can stand
Watch my deadly Vital Eagle's Claw
Pretty cosy
Don't interfere this time, or I'll regard you as an enemy
When a monk eats dog meat, it doesn't make a difference
if it's once or twice
Stop thinking you're so skillful
We're both higly experienced
Fen, I know you're very capable
Though I have power on many levels
Either one or the other will lose in a battle, stop the talking
Give him one more chance and I'll never interfere again
Ok, but I have a condition
What kind of condition?
He has to leave immediately and he can never come back
Why do I have to leave?
Because of my Eagle's Claw
I won't leave, even if I can't beat you
You'll die if you fight
Why notjust leave?
I promise I'll tackle this problem
Fen, I'll give you face once more
If I see him next time, I won't let him escape
Go!
Stop that! You may be tough, but your Kung Fu isn't very
good at all
I don't think he's invincible
I won't leave just because he said
It's better avoid problems
Be patient, it'll save you trouble
Did you really think I came to go to the toilet?
I came to test your Kung Fu
If I didn't come, you would have died
Listen to me, just jeave quickly and don't try to be a hero
l have no relatives, where can I go?
Take this letter to Fen Yu Teng
In the Ching Ching Mountain, call for Monk Chio Wu, he'll
look after you
Let me say goodbye to my sister
No, you'll bump into Uncle 33 again
Go, go, leave quickly
l have to say goodbye face to face
Don't worry, l'll inform her of everything
What do you want? Say it quickly
l'm Wang Cheng, I've come to see Monk Chio
Are you the master?
I'm just a minor monk
But today I'm the outdoor supervisor
Supervisor?
I mean the guard
Understand ?
Do you have a diploma?
Diploma?
If you haven't, then sorry, you can't go in
l have to go in, I don't need permission
Stop th ere!
I warn you, you need my permission to get in
Even if you're the King, you can't get in no matter what
l have a letter
Supervisor, please take me to see the Abbot
Are you deaf?
Don't you hear the chanting?
The Abbot is busy now, come later
I won't leave until I've seen the abbot
Come on, he's busy right now
A good deed a day will take you to heaven
Ok, let me take you there
Stand here, wait till I come back
Stay back
They know I haven't permitted you
If you run in and the guards catch you, you'll be sorry
Master
Master, Master...
This is the temple, you can't yell here
I came to visit and he said he'll take me around
But hejust came here to eat instead
Hsuan Chi
Brother
Is it true what he said?
Dinner was laid out already
l was going to do it after I finished
The Abbot said that since you're alone
And you have no place to stay, we must be kind
You can stay here if you want
Don't get too excited, pay attention
Buddhist monks are never violent
So if you break the rules and fight, you must leave
Merciful Buddha
l'm responsible for all your actions from now on, so you'd
better obey me
Listen!
It's time for you to show your abilities
This should be the easy part
Hurry up
I'll put you to the test now
But we won't be doing Kung Fu for now
Drop this here
You're going to have to distribute the seeds
If the birds make a mess, you'll have to clean it all up
What about you?
It depends on how you cope
What?
You dare to argue with me?
You w on't obey?
Want to rule me?
Get moving!
Why?
There's a cloud... Nothing to see!
Get moving!
Stan d th ere
Is that comfortable?
Ok
The cloud is here, come over
Wait, the wind is blowing, move this way
You can never move me no matter how hard you try
Wait till there's no wind
Dry it in the sun
Look at you
The top of your the is heavy and the lower is light
If you your legs aren't firm, then of course you'll fall down
Why do you strike the bell?
You're mad, why are you striking it
Let it go, you can't strike the bell as you please
You've made a big mistake, wait and see
Brother, you'd better tell him
Release him
I've been here for three months, yet I haven't seen the
Abbot yet
He has been secluded since the day you came
I don't care, I must see the Abbot
Has he obeyed the regulations since he came?
He was striking the bell just a little earlier
He doesn't behave like a monk
But his legs get stronger everyday
Strengthening my legs...
You can never move me no matter how hard you try
Master, should we put him to the test now?
No, it's not the right time, he still needs improvement
What should we do in the next step Master?
Developing one's Kung Fu requires many practices
Watch
Reach out the arms
Attack the vital points
Defend
Stren gth en your arms
Strengthen your legs too
Why would he need to do that?
It's better to use one powerful kick than 10 weak ones
I understand now
You must take advantage of others' weak points
We stop here today
Master, you've practiced the Monkey Pole for very long
now
Why don't you show us?
Merciful Buddha
Learning Kung Fu requires patience, we'll do more
practice tomorrow
Buddha's name be praised
Please
You're not dead yet?
I won't die until you do
You want to die then, get him
I told you to kick him out
Why is he still here, tell him to go!
He has no relatives out there, it's pitiful
Uncle Hsien, you're generous, please let him be
Careful you fool, I won't be so merciful next time
You're still making trouble here, get away!
Please sit down Uncle Hsien
Wait a while, Ah Lien will be free soon
Ok, it's alright
Please relax, make yourselves at home
Ah Chiu
Lien, what's the matter?
What's the matter... Go change the water
What's the matter... you feel ashamed?
You deal with the water to make a living
Why aren't you listening?
Want to hit me now?
Why don't you try?
Such a fool
He should measure his ability first
Don't pay attention to him
He can't do anything anyway
Release him
With your behavior, you deserve this
You want to mess up my business?
If you're not willing to work then leave
Get out! Just get out!
I'll get you today
Ok, I'll deal with you today
The Monkey Stick
The Elephant strike
Back to the centre
Holding at bay
Th e sn ake attack
The bee sting
Turning aside
Turn back and grasp
I caught you this time
Practicin g Ku ng Fu
go back
Brother, you've gone far
Come back with me to see the abbot
You dare to beat me?
You'll regret it this time
You told lies about taking me to the abbot
Do you want to be the Uncle 32?
Uncle 32?
The one who dies before Uncle 33
Help! Help Master!
Help!
Stop Wan g Ch eng!
You're rude
You've forgotten our regulations
l have to put an end to this game played on me
You've destroyed the game of chess
Buddha will be angry
Give me the pole
Yes
Master, why didn't you see me until now?
You still can't read any Buddhist sutras
I haven't come here for ungodliness
There are just many villains out there for me to deal with
I must punish Hsuan Chi first, give way, Master
It's the attitude of the common man
To beat anyone that interrupts him
Come on, just fight me as if I was Uncle 33
l un derstand
That just means you don't understand
Master, here's the pole, beat him
You've learnt much of my Kung Fu
Though you may not be able to beat Uncle 33's Plum
Blossom Pole
Be careful, he uses the pole very well
He endures many fights
Even if wounded he wouldn't lose
Plum Blossom and the Dragon comes
From the eastern sea
The Mon key Stick!
The Elephant strike!
Friends meet in the cold weather
The cotton is revealed
Turn back and grasp
Gust of wind blows away the leaves
lncense facing the sky
Silly fool, avoid the heavy part and concentrate on the
lighter
Avoid the heavy part and concentrate on the light side?
Thanks!
Prodigal doesn't return, there's no way for him to get home
Ask for rain in the mountain
Turn back and kill the dragon
lnvite th e Goddess
The aftermath of a disaster
The flowers fade and fall
You deserve what you have in life
And don't ask for what you don't deserve
I don't intend to keep you here...
Since you have no interest in our teachings
You have learned my Kung fu but you have no relation to
Buddha, you can leave
Master, thank you for your kindness
Merciful Buddha
Master Hsuan Chi
Th ank you
NEIL BATEMAN
ls Chiu here?
No Chiu here, but there's eggs... How many do you want?
Sorry
Currently, the food trade business on depends on four
main figures
I want to talk with them myself
I'll come back in half a month
I'll leave everything to you
Master, don't worry, even the Heng Chuan shop is ours
Once we've taken over these other four businesses
We'd have monopolized the market
How about guy with the mill in the east village?
He's difficult to tackle
He says he won't let anything go
How much stock is there?
400 bags of grain. 100 bags of Barely, 90 bags of rice. 100
bags of wheat, about 700 bags in total
Tell the men to call for him immediately
If he doesn't sell at the price I give, then deal with him like
we did with the Heng Chuan
Force him to close
Boss...
So you did come back
Don't leave yet!
I need to go somewhere, wait till I come back
Don't fight, there's enough
Come now, there's enough for everyone
Why did you come back again?
Did Monk Chio Wu treat you badly?
No, he treated me kindly
Do you know where my sister and my brother-in-law is?
Your sister, sh e...
What happened to her?
She's dead
Dead? How did she die?
It was said that Uncle 33 and his disciple made her
commit suicide
How about my brother-in-law?
I haven't seen him in a long time
lt's you
So you finally came back to die?
We'll see whether it's you or me who dies
Don't forget that my Master has already beaten you
Who got my sister killed?
Was it you that forced her to die?
No, not me
Go
Go!
Did you kill my sister?
It wasn't me, It was my master's doing
Where's your master now
Why did you get my sister killed?
It's not my business, ask my Master
Wh ere's your Master?
I don't know
You don't know?
Do you know now?
Where is he?
I don't know
What are you doing?
Release me! Release me!
Release me!
Lets see if you'll talk or not
Will you talk?
I'll tell you... I'll tell you... I'll tell you...
My Master has gone down town
Wait! Let me down! Let me down!
I'll let you have a slow death
Release me! Release me!
Master, help me, help me!
Help you?
That was a big mistake you just made
You're my disciple, you should know I don't tolerate failure
And you even told him where l was going?
You've actually given me a helping hand here
At least I've seen his Kung Fu
And I know why he's looking for me
Alright, you're clever, but I'm not foolish
You never expected me to come back, did you?
You don't like your life?
You've already helped change my title to Uncle 34
Now you'll give me the title Uncle 35
Before you become Uncle 35, I think you'll be dead
You have your Plum Blossom Pole
But I have my Monkey Pole
Let me see your Monkey Pole then
My pole will destroy your vital points
Avoid the heavy part and concentrate on the light side
Alright, I'll do it
You know the Eagle's Claw?
You killed my sister, now you'll pay for it
How did you learn my Eagles Claw?
It's called an Eye for an Eye, a tooth for a tooth
Root up the stone of 1000 catties
Is that all?
No, there's more
You really think you can beat me?
You think you're invincible, but you're just another rascal
If you want to die, that's fine
Captu ring Tiger!
Grasping like a flying dragon
Capture of the blowing wind
Ambushing eagle draws close
Hungry tiger doesn't leave
You must bear it
Those men beat your brother-in-law to death
Take advantage of his weaknesses
You learnt from Ohio Wu to take advantage of
weaknesses
Too late to realize now!
Wait there