ðŸš« Please do not delete translation rights ðŸš«
â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸â¬‡ï¸
ðŸŽ¬ Translation and preparation: (Ahmed Artak) ðŸŽ¬
ðŸ“¢ To follow new works, join the official channel on Telegram ðŸ“¢
https://t.me/artaq12
â¤ï¸Ø¨Ø¯Ø¹Ù…ÙƒÙ… We continue to provide the best alwaysâ¤ï¸
Day 34
From monitoring Onsu through the smart home system
and psychological behavioral surveillance cameras.
The cause of Onsu's symptoms dates back
five years ago, after the death of her only mother
After a long battle with cancer.
where she exhibited symptoms of panic disorder.
She later moved
to an isolated country house with a strange environment.
and the stress of preparing for exams
All day alone at home
It seems to have caused a cumulative
that led to her condition.
Holy Night: Demon Hunters
Okay, I'm done.
(Kim) Manager.
- (Choi) Captain, is he here?
- (Sharon).
(Paw) here, right?
Yes, it exists.
You have a visitor.
Hello.
Yes.
Yes, you can enter.
Okay.
Sir, (Choi) the captain has arrived.
Yes?
Yes.
A few days ago, my daughter
(Sujin) suddenly disappeared, and she seems to have disappeared.
(Sujin is not the kind of person who would ever do that.
Something must have gone wrong.
Three of our men were harmed
during the search, by a suspicious group.
Two of them were killed, and the third is in the intensive care unit.
As always, I think
we need your help, Director Kang.
Since the investigators themselves
were involved in an accident, it does sound dangerous.
That's why I asked Choi
Captain to come with me, and I came to you like this.
Yes. Don't worry too much, we'll
check it out more thoroughly.
(Kim) Manager, can you get something to drink?
Yes. Just one moment.
It's okay.
One moment, damn it...
I apologize.
Have you found anything yet?
We were able to pinpoint the location
from the image we immediately obtained.
We moved immediately.
but our men were all hurt.
We couldn't save Sujin.
Here you go, (Sharon).
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Yes.
Get in.
Would you like some water?
Don't worry too much. We'll do our best.
(Choi) Captain...
Can I trust these people...?
Yes, you can trust us.
We may seem a little weird.
But we are professional experts.
Please take good care of Sujin.
We will do everything we can.
Yes, yes.
Yes.
I brought cash this time too.
You didn't take anything away from it like you did
you did last time, did you?
Are you suspicious of a cop?
Do you know how many clients
I've brought you so far?
Here, give this to the boys.
Do you think I'm not trustworthy?
What's the matter? Are you refusing?
The situation is very serious now.
A lot of people are being killed.
Okay, I get it.
Come on
Guys.
Let's get going.
Recently, there have been murders by
in Seoul and other parts of the country.
These violent incidents continue to increase.
It has terrorized the hearts of many citizens.
Police suspect an
of an unknown organization behind these crimes.
Gangs are believed to be
are also believed to be involved.
A special unit has been formed to investigate the matter.
But criminals continue to defy
authorities and brutally kill police officers...
In my thirty years as a police officer
I have not witnessed such violent cases.
People talk about demons
evil spirits, and unbelievable things happening all the time.
This is completely beyond the capabilities of the police, Father.
These people worship a high priest who summons Satan.
They draw supernatural power from Satan's medicines and dark energy.
Ordinary people can't keep up with them or beat them.
So, we need that kid.
(Mysterious words from witchcraft rituals)
You cursed evil spirit!
I command you... In the name of light!
Go back to the hell you came out of!
In the name of light... Your name has been revealed.
You are Baal, supreme commander of the armies of Hell!
Go right back to hell, motherfucker!
Go back to hell!
I command you... In the name of light!
Go back to the hell you came out of!
Go right back to hell, you son of a bitch!
I command you... Get out of this body!
To hell!
Go right back to hell, motherfucker!
How is it going?
I'm fine.
No, I don't mean you. I mean this girl.
The evil spirit hasn't fully possessed her yet. She's fine.
This is reassuring.
Sir, I was a little confused earlier...
I couldn't film the last part. What should I do now?
What are we going to do, wake them all up again for this?
No, we can't do that.
but I think the ending needs to be documented.
You had to shoot well from the beginning.
True.
Is Captain Choi on his way?
Yes, it's coming now.
My condition has improved a lot thanks to you, Dr.
Even my shortness of breath is getting better, thank you very much.
That's good. But you have to keep taking the medication.
I will monitor your condition and gradually reduce the dosage.
Please check every two hours.
Well, I'll make sure he's stabilized.
Concept.
(Sister Catalina) Don't worry, I'm fine.
I'm earning money to build a new
for the church, nothing more.
No need to thank me, it's my duty.
Okay, okay, I got it, (Catalina). Okay, okay.
Sir, we found out who
these people belonged to yesterday.
Really?
Who are they?
(Beelzeboth).
Who is the leader of these scoundrels?
We haven't found the High Priest yet, but I...
I have planted a number of undercover agents, and we will get to him soon.
Recently, several
first division demons such as Beelzeboth.
This is cause for concern.
because a bigger crisis may be on its way.
Even though I've encountered them repeatedly.
I still feel afraid of them.
We, too, are afraid.
They move with the power of Satan.
They are very dangerous.
So don't lose your focus, and always be careful.
Your future is promising, Kim, as a manager.
And what about me?
What about me?
Does this mean my future is dark?
It's hot, damn...
Excuse me!
Get out of my way.
I apologize.
Who are you?
What brings you here?
Can I see the manager?
Yes, I'm the manager.
What is it?
My sister is very sick.
I found no other way but to come here.
Did Captain Choi send you?
No, I... (Mar...)
Did Father Marco send you?
Sorry, but I don't deal with those people.
I apologize.
My sister is in danger.
I will do anything if you help me.
I brought the money too.
No, the thing is...
No, if your sister is sick.
it's best to take her to the hospital immediately.
Seek a psychiatrist or neurologist.
I'm a psychiatrist.
What the hell is this...
Wait a minute...
This is a recording of my sister.
Please hand it to him.
Please.
Uh, okay.
A safe haven for Onni and Onsu.
The garden, Ansu's safe haven.
Let's live here happily.
Don't fight, please.
Yes, no fights.
- And don't wear Onni's clothes.
And you, don't use my products.
As long as we don't fight, we'll live happily.
happily.
Thank you, Onni.
Goodbye.
Like it?
Yes.
The air here is very clean.
I'm also a doctor, and I didn't believe
what's happening to your sister until I saw it myself.
The Church officially bans exorcism rituals.
So I sent you to him instead of me.
I know that as a doctor you weren't comfortable with it either.
I don't know much about demons
or exorcism rituals and such.
I just... I want to save my sister, Father.
Yes?
Where did Sharon go?
I think she's in her room.
Sir, would you like to watch the video
that beautiful doctor sent yesterday?
No, no need. What the hell...
But if Father Marco
was the one who sent it, it must be important.
Don't mention Father Marco's name in front of me again, okay?
I apologize.
Where is Sharon? I have to give her this.
I'm here.
Oh my God! You scared me! When did you come?
Always enter with a voice, don't surprise me like this! Hey, these...
Here, here.
Here.
It's your paycheck.
Thank you.
Well done.
This is yours too, take it.
But why is my salary so much lower?
(Sharon) takes on more tasks.
and take on the hard work.
She even rides
the sword in the ritual, she's busy
Who said I ride a sword? When?
After all, it's hard work, so that's normal.
Here.
Thank you.
Take it, take it.
How greedy of you...
Just a moment, the number of demons and their followers is growing rapidly.
They became bolder, more public, didn't they?
They walked around the city center without fear.
And people are dying in increasing numbers, right?
So, our tasks have also increased, right? Right?
So, don't you think it's time to increase our salaries?
Oh my God...
It's been a long time. It's been ten years.
I'm still the same as I was then.
Of course, my appearance
hasn't changed since I was nineteen.
Your humor hasn't changed either.
(Han Jung Won) visited you recently, didn't she?
I know you said no because of what happened to me, but her sister...
I don't want anything to do with you anymore, Father.
I know you still blame me.
Many people lost their lives in that incident.
I suffered a lot because of it as well.
But I couldn't believe that Yusuf really did it.
(The Yusuf we know no longer exists.
He became a demon named Lucifer.
He killed all the innocent children.
and even nuns.
That's the demon you raised yourself.
I prayed for a long time with regret and tears.
asking: Is this really God's will?
Our children, all dead, and you say it's God's will?
Even if you don't forgive me, can't you help that girl?
I came to thank you myself.
If it wasn't for you (Sharon), I wouldn't have been able to see my son's face for the last time.
to see my son's face for the last time.
If only we had arrived a little earlier...
It's okay. I'm grateful that we were able to find his body.
and to give rest to his soul. I will not forget this favor.
to turn it off
This is Sharon.
Seven years ago.
The director saved us from a demon that almost killed us.
That day, he saved us from Lucifer, me and Sharon.
and even Sister Catalina.
If the manager hadn't helped us that day.
we would have been dead by now.
If we have someone to help us, we don't have to be afraid.
Let's help Dr. Onsu.
I also really want to help that doctor.
Thirty-fourth day of monitoring Unsu.
Unsu's symptoms were caused by
A panic attack following the death of her only mother
After a long battle with cancer.
where she exhibited symptoms of panic disorder.
In addition to later moving to a
an isolated country house with a strange environment.
and the stress of preparing for exams
All day alone at home
It seems to have caused a cumulative
that led to her condition.
(Unsu), it's time to eat.
(Unsu)...
(Forget)? Don't forget too quickly!
(Sister), I have a good feeling this time.
something beautiful.
Package receipt
I'll put it here.
(Forget it)!
Full lighting.
Where are you now?
(Forget it)!
Yes, this is Emergency 119, go ahead.
I apologize.
(Forget it)!
What are you doing there?
Are you okay?
(Forget it)!
(Forget it)! No, no
Recently, the
damage caused by an unidentified group
So far, more than thirty policemen have been killed.
(Kim), office manager.
Yes, sir.
Let me see that clip.
Infernal Fire falls from the sky! These demons
My sister...
Despite multiple treatment attempts, the
It's my fault, because I couldn't
to come back like I should have to save my sister.
See here.
I found another clip, but it shows an even bigger issue.
I am very grateful to you.
The homeowner has to make this effort
if he wants to rent it out. (Capso is not the neglected type.
We cleaned most of the stuff.
but the really big stuff
We put it in storage
Are you done?
Yes. We checked the cameras
surveillance cameras and the entire smart security system.
Look at this.
It seems that what happened to Unsu
has something to do with Bishop Lucifer again.
(Yusuf)...
We had a boy named Yusuf with us at the orphanage.
Three years younger than Pau.
The late nun (Angela) raised them as if they were her own children.
They were among the chosen few from a young age.
(Bao) had a physical strength
As his name implies, he was tough as nails.
As for Joseph, he had the ability to
exorcise demons from people's bodies and save them.
The other children feared and shunned him.
But Bao always protected him.
They were as close as real brothers.
(Yusuf chose the path of the priesthood to exorcize spirits.
while Bao, after leaving the house
He worked in the underworld using his fist
to make money, and still took care of Yusuf and the house.
He used to visit the home every Christmas, but...
Fifteen years ago, on that day, Yusuf
He summoned a demon and caused the death of the nun (Angela)
and all the children, and then he disappeared.
Everyone thought that Bao
had died, but he came back in a miraculous way.
He came back to life, and from then on, Bao felt guilty that he couldn't save those who were like family to him.
With his guilt and desire for revenge.
He started chasing the disappeared Yusuf.
and eliminated the demons one by one.
Back then, Yusuf was
trying to absorb people's souls
to strengthen the forces of evil in him, but I was stupid
I didn't want to believe that Yusuf had become like that.
Therefore, I could not tell the
the group the truth about that incident.
Meanwhile, Yusuf disappeared.
and when Bao later learned of this.
I think the reason he rejected your request was because of me.
Hello?
Yes.
I am Kang Bao, director of the Holy Night Foundation.
Can you meet with me for a bit if your time permits?
The exorcism ritual will be performed by Sharon here.
She (Kim) will be assisted by the office manager during the weather.
I apologize for not informing you earlier, but in such
In some cases, so-called demons and their followers may appear
anytime and anywhere around Onsu.
so I have to be ready to deal with them.
These possess
a special ability to detect the presence of demons.
She knows how to fight them better than anyone.
Please just show them your eyes shift for a moment.
Show us, even if only for a moment.
I will, but not now.
Okay.
It's a very dangerous job.
so Unsu and the doctor may be in danger.
We are, after all, always risking our lives in this business.
Are you willing to try though?
Yes. If it saves my sister's life, I will.
Our lives are also at risk...
Anyway, Kim, prepare the briefing.
What we know for sure
is that a demon is inhabiting Onsu's body.
Why is all this happening to Unsu in particular?
Have you let any strangers into the house recently?
No, we live in an isolated place, almost no one comes here.
Look.
It looks like someone summoned a demon through Onsu.
We also can't
confirm their identity until we see the mark ourselves.
They appear as normal people among us all the time.
We call them "worshippers." They worship the devil.
They submit to it, and spread mischief and evil among the people.
Especially the so-called guards among them, they are trained like soldiers
to mercilessly kill anyone who gets in their way.
Those who are called demons
They are like bishops who rule each region.
They are no longer human, but more like demons.
They are the ones who choose the offerings and conduct
all satanic rituals at the behest of their elder.
But why Unsu?
For thousands of years, they have been targeting
pure and wounded souls like Unsu
to summon demons through it, and build their own dark world.
Anyone can be victimized.
We have to meet Unsu.
(Unsu)...
Have you regained consciousness a little?
Do you hear my voice?
Yes.
Sister came to help you.
Can you talk to me for a bit?
Yes.
Is anyone else talking to you right now?
Who is that person?
I don't know.
I may not say.
Can I talk to him for a bit?
No, it is not allowed.
Why not?
Because it's scary.
If I talk to him and he talks back.
It will leave your body.
Isn't that what you wish for too?
I...
I'm so scared...
I'll start now.
Who are you?
Answer me.
Answer me!
Don't hide behind the child, answer me.
Who are you?
Why are you doing this to me?
I didn't do anything wrong!
You damned devil!
State your name now!
Go back to hell!
You evil demon!
Reveal your name immediately!
Go back to hell, right now!
No!
You evil demon!
Reveal your name now
Go back to hell.
You evil demon!
Reveal your name now
Go back to hell, right now!
Reveal your name immediately!
To hell
(Unsu) is here, but where are you now?
We are at the entrance.
What do we do now?
It looks like she's trying to get out.
â˜  Cryptic words from witchcraft rituals â˜
Back off! Back off!
Get out!
Run away!
(Zhongxin)!
Uncle!
(Forget it)!
My sister!
(Unsu)!
(Unsu)! (Unsu)!
(Unsu), there is danger!
(Unsu), no! I'm coming, just wait a bit!
My sister... I'm so scared...
My sister!
(Forget it)!
(Zhongxin)!
Uncle!
(Zhongxin)! Are you okay?
Sir, are you hurt?
No.
The devil inside Unsu has settled very deeply.
We cannot identify him.
I think we should end
in the house where it all began.
If I stay in the hospital.
Unsu and the others will be in danger.
Yes. We will do it.
Let's hurry up. We don't have time.
(Unsu).
Let's hang in there a little longer, okay?
Damn...
We don't know where these bastards will show up from...
No matter what you do, it won't work.
(Forget it)!
Save me!
I will save you no matter what.
The exorcism ritual consists of six stages.
At every stage, the goal
is to force the demon to reveal its name
so that we can expel it from Unsu's body.
You must follow my instructions precisely at every stage.
Once the weather starts, there's no stopping.
If we stop, Unsu's life
and all of our lives will be in danger.
The first stage: Existence.
We show the existence of evil.
My sister...
I'm so scared...
Fire them all...
I'm scared, sister...
(Forget it), it's okay.
(Joonwon), don't answer.
(Kim), have you finished your preparations?
Yes.
(Joon Won)...
(Joon Won)?
If I call you, you have to answer.
Yes?
Start the devices.
Okay.
Vital signs are within normal range.
Let's get started.
From now on, answer
every question I ask. Otherwise, you will be in pain
Don't touch my body! Don't touch me! Don't touch me!
State your name!
Say your name!
What happened?
We have now entered the camouflage phase.
From now on, Satan will try to deceive us.
My sister...
I'm so scared... Please free me from this...
(Dongyong, a sacred mirror
carries within it the spirit of a spiritual priest.
(Mysterious words from witchcraft rituals)
(Taiju), from the Great Dynasty
He is known for his ability to convey the words
(god of the flesh) through the art of esoteric pronunciation
Oh my God...
Would you like to know my name?
Did he tell you?
The devil doesn't try to camouflage?
I was before the universe existed
I am... The first entity to exist
I am the One and Infinite Entity
I am the eternal... And I am the ultimate end
I'm inside you, too.
It's in your bones.
Why block the light?
Something strange is happening.
I'll go check, keep it up.
Okay.
Fuck!
(Mysterious words from witchcraft rituals)
I am everywhere... and I'm nowhere
You evil demon!
Reveal your name immediately!
Get out of the girl's body.
You're afraid of me and you don't even dare
to come in here? Come if you can! Come on!
Petty priests like these
will never be able to defeat us!
Devil inside the girl.
Leave the girl alone.
Exit immediately
Devil inside the girl.
Leave the girl alone.
Exit immediately
I... Me!
Sir, are you okay?
I'm fine... It's okay.
Sir, didn't I tell you earlier?
This is the powder they are spraying. You have to be careful.
It is completely paralyzing and can actually lead to death.
Well, come on, hurry up!
Yes.
Now we are in the third stage: Resistance phase.
(Joonwon), it's best to rest a bit now.
(Joon Won)...
(Joon Won), are you okay?
I command you in the name of the Supreme God and the Three Holy Gods
Now return immediately to your world
Go back now.
(Joon Won)! (Joon Won), wake up! (Joon Won)!
It's okay. You're okay now.
She was possessed by a demon for a moment.
During the ritual, the
to target family members as well.
There seems to be something else in the house.
(Mysterious words from witchcraft rituals)
Hey.
Yes.
Do not read them.
Okay.
What does it mean?
I'm not sure.
It's in an ancient language called Igbo.
Because of this, unexpected things started to happen.
The whole house is under a curse.
And what should we do?
We have to remove all those symbols.
(Cryptic words from witchcraft rituals)
What happened to me?
It felt like something had come out of my body.
(Unsu, are you okay?
Has she regained consciousness a little?
Wait...
My sister...
Please untie me...
Are you really Unsu? Do you know who I am?
Wait...
No matter what you do, this girl will eventually die.
Do you remember?
I made those poor kids die.
The sound stage has begun.
Uncle, please save me, please!
Save me, please!
(Yusuf) is the one who killed them?
No, you killed them.
Because you didn't feed Joseph, all the children died.
Come on, come with me to meet the Master.
Only then will you have eternal life.
If she doesn't, she dies... and so does this child.
She also killed your mother, the nun (Angela).
Read it!
Are you okay...
I'm fine.
Don't be fooled by them.
(Shindo, the divine sword
A sword that contains a faith that exorcizes evil spirits.
"Why are you on the side of the humans?"
Your ability to...
It didn't come from that asshole.
"Didn't you get that from my brother?"
That my ability originated from your brother...
This is proof that the bastard couldn't beat me.
Do you think you can
to withstand that power any longer?
She is here.
What is this thing?
Cover.
And why did you bring the lid?
Didn't you ask me to get it?
I said get a thick coat! Damn it, I said "coat".
And why is your life...important?
You're wasting it for these insignificant humans?!
Whenever you summon your invisible powers...
Your body is dying... Can't you feel it?
As you have tasted this torment before...
Greedy, corrupt humans... don't deserve your survival!
Are they worth sacrificing for?!
Join us... our sister.
Let's stay together...
I am not your sister. And I will not be!
Get out of my mind right now, motherfucker!
Say your name!
I will end this torment.
Tell me your name now!
Say it!
Hurry up, say the name! Name!
Say the name now!
What is my name?
Sister... Save me...
Stop! Enough of this!
Miss!
- Don't!
- No! Please don't!
(Mysterious words from witchcraft rituals)
What is this?
This girl is now mine.
Get out of my way!
It's a collision course now.
We need to find Unsu quickly.
(Sharon)...
(Mysterious words from witchcraft rituals)
The exit is blocked from there.
Move out of the way.
Damn... The house has been damaged a lot.
Sir!
What? What is it?
This door is automatic.
My sister...
(Unsu, are you there?
(Unsu)! My sister!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Is there a place we don't know about?
I got rid of most things.
The big stuff I temporarily put in storage.
pantry?
What is it?
(Unsah) gradually turns into a demon.
(Forget it)!
Come back to us! No, no!
So you're all gathered here.
Wounded... Why do you use
the power the devil gave you to petty humans?
Are you Korean?
If you interfere with us, the only thing for you is death.
Cryptic words from a witchcraft ritual
Nyatara...
- This cover is for you! - Tracta!
Fucking Niikara!
Now I know who you are... Only one more package left...
If this stage is over, I can save Unsa.
The hideous, filthy king of death, who devours children
as human sacrifices...
(Moloch)!
Your time is up.
"I am yours... I'm made for you alone
You are my destiny... You have no escape from me.
I am the path that leads you beyond the end...
My kingdom...
Built on the pure blood of children...
I will subdue you...
I will dominate every fiber of your being...
And now, the end... Banishment!
Once we finish the stage, we will save (Unsah).
You filthy, ugly...
who preys on children as sacrificial lambs!
Your time is up.
Go home to your cursed homeland!
I fire you, you...!
Go right back to hell, motherfucker!
Leave now, you...!
Go home to your cursed homeland!
Go back to hell, motherfucker!
Go back where you came from, you...!
I expel you from this body, Moloch!
Go back to where you were, motherfucker!
I expel you from this body, Moloch. I'm kicking you out of this body, Moloch.
(Forget it)!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
The demon is now leaving her body.
You are insignificant... And yet you beat me?!
There will come a day when I will tear you apart... until you perish!
And I'm taking this bitch to hell with me!
No one takes it... It's mine!
Sharon
You are the messenger of hell... And I'm kicking you out now!
Release the girl immediately!
I am the reincarnation of Palo... I command you now!
Go back to the hell you came from!
There's very little left for you...
If you want to stay... let the darkness in!
ðŸ”¥ Go back to hell, Moloch! ðŸ”¥
(Forget it)!
Are you okay.
My sister
Okay, I'll take the picture now.
Look over here... Smile.
Okay, one, two, three!
Boys, that's enough for now.
Next time.
If you have time, definitely come.
Let's go.
Okay.
Yes.