THE PUBLIC WOMAN
Do you like dogs, sweetheart?
- Is he yours?
- He's been following me all day.
Someday you'll have a dog
too. That's a fantastic animal.
What do you want?
Please.
Give this to the man with the dog.
But don't tell him how you got it.
Wow, that's his lucky day.
With all the money he owes.
Hey, what makes you so
sure I'll give him the money?
I have faith.
Lea, here girl.
Hey, you've got
money! You can pay me back!
No!
Stop it, guys!
I was working on the balcony
in the fresh air,
when I saw, walking
under the trees nearby...
When I saw, walking under
the trees nearby,
an elegant young man, who
humbly bowed as soon as he saw me.
Out of politeness, I
curtseyed back to him.
All of a sudden...
He bows again.
So do I.
He walks, approaches,
and goes, each time bowing.
And each time, I would curtsey
back, looking at him intensely.
If the night hadn't come, I
would still be standing there,
refusing that he might
think me less courteous than he.
Do you have any theater experience?
Or cinema?
Have you taken classes?
Yes. In Genevilliers.
- With General?
- Yes.
It's been a while
since he worked there.
My teacher was an actor. From Paris.
I don't have any pictures.
It doesn't matter.
We have your details.
We'll call you. Can you
follow me, please? Thank you.
I'm Lucas Kesling, the director.
- Can I walk you out?
- Why?
Because I want to, and I want
to talk to you about the film.
So we're being told that independent
cinema is dead.
It's more the end of an era,
because cinema accompanies everything else.
It is very difficult
to make a dumb film,
especially when you have a voice
inside, saying that cinema is better than that.
This is why I want to play Nicolas, the
main character of "The Possessed".
He is ice cold, he's
the vice, the cynicism,
the intelligence personified, and...
Do you understand?
Yes.
I don't like your hair.
Do you like how I bleached mine?
The Lithuanian
Archbishop arrived this afternoon.
His Grace was welcomed by a small committee
of Lithuanian expatriates.
Shit, shit...
His Grace has spent a month in Rome
and is about to return to the USSR,
where the Church has recently seen an unexpected
revival due to his influence.
The 75-year-old prelate previously
spent fifteen years in Siberian prisons.
The Russian authorities
consider him to be an increasing threat.
Not another one...
Will His Grace be able to follow
Polish Cardinal Woïtila's example-
Always late!
Hello.
There you go. Mr.
André arrived a little early.
You did choose
Miss Ethel, didn't you?
What are you waiting
for? Studio one is free.
With the composition, we
reach this sort of abstraction that...
Did I ask you anything?
Do you have an envelope?
What do you do to all those men?
I scare them.
You've come a long way.
Do you want to show me?
Here's my little girl!
We were waiting on you
yesterday at lunch time, but not today...
- I was modeling for Prisunic.
- And?
Nothing.
- How is he?
- He's fine. He's fine.
Do you want some soup?
I can reheat some soup if you want.
And some meatballs.
You like my meatballs, don't you?
It's pointless being a
model if you end up starving.
And don't stay alone,
with the hours you work.
Did you get your hair cut?
Don't you like it?
Salomon says it
makes me look younger.
And you put on weight, that's good.
Ethel!
I was about to go.
She's doing very
well. She's sleeping better.
Look what I made for my beauty
who's going to look like a Page!
- Can I try it on?
- Eat first.
How's the restaurant
going? Are you not too tired?
When he's not on night shift, he's
not going to bed before 2 a. m.
Salomon, your boss can wait
a minute. Take a picture of us.
It's not often she
comes to visit her mother.
He's not sick, is he?
You're the one who's sick.
Don't say that.
I've always been a
bit crazy, you know?
And Salomon?
At his age! He's in
love, just like a young man.
Thanks, darling. Thank you.
Why do you do that?
Did you speak to him this
time? Your father, I mean.
Sorry, it's the last time I ask you.
I didn't have the courage.
At least he'll be able to subsist.
Mom, stop it!
I don't want to go anymore.
Next time, I'll go.
Sure. And then you'll
call me to come and get you,
because you want to
live, live, live, and not die!
Has he changed?
Does he still send you
those letters, just to hurt you?
To make fun of you even more?
We are the ones who are
killing him, Ethel.
We're just repaying him in kind.
You're so violent!
He's the violent one!
He's...
disgusting, vicious, and crazy!
But do we have the right? Can we?
How can you answer that
question when someone's hurting you?
You know, don't
you? I don't, you know.
Or maybe nobody told me how. I've
always done what I'm told.
I've always listened to others!
Stop it, it's not your fault!
It's nobody's fault!
Miss, hold the elevator!
"SOLIDARITY WITH THE WORKERS OF"...
If you keep doing it, I'll
be able to feel pain.
Are you here to see me?
- Do you live nearby?
- Well, yes. Just here.
You know, my producer is
insane, but maybe not enough.
He's cutting the budget, he
doesn't give me enough days to shoot.
And in the end, he expects
this movie to be prestigious.
Pussyfooting as
usual. Goodbye, Miss...?
Ethel.
That's it.
I forgot to tell you.
I'd like you to read the
part I just told you about.
I don't believe in the traditional
auditioning process.
Tomorrow, we'll just
rehearse. Like in theater.
You'll see for yourself.
I'll call you.
Thank you.
"The Possessed".
No. Thank you.
Thanks.
This is a prophetic tale about those who
try to change the world through violence.
This is why Dostoyevsky's book was banned
in Eastern European countries.
That's why we live in the shadows
and in the continuity of what is there.
We bury our heads in the sand, like
ostriches, to remain ignorant.
Some of you are actors. Some
aren't. Just as in real life.
- Barbara.
- Yes.
Thank you. I hope you'll explain to
everyone that will see this film,
that it is a contemporary
story, not just a classic.
Shall we?
Read your scripts.
I don't care if you don't know your lines, I'm going to watch you
- live!
Put that cigarette out, please.
Thank you for
receiving me and my sister.
My sister, the Stranger!
What do you mean, "the Stranger"?
Madam, I wrote you a
letter about your son.
And the letter of a worm, of a rat,
of a bacillus even,
must be read like poetry!
Of a bacillus?
Your laugh. More insane!
More insane!
More insane, this laugh!
The sitting room is yours,
jump, twirl around! Quick, quick!
Go!
Everyone is here! It is
so wonderful... but...
What are you doing here,
Captain? Who let you in? With this idiot.
- Sir, my honor doesn't
allow me to- - Your what?
I said I would arrange
everything. And the money...
My dear, your son will arrive soon. If
only you knew what happened in Germany.
But he will tell you much better than
I! Do you know he traveled through Iceland?
The island of ice and
fire. Oh, Christian!
Your son's good soul is holding
the simple conscience of the world.
And my father, steeped in
pity, even in his very posture.
My son, I was expecting different
signs of affection.
Son? Son? Do you think
this is the right word?
Let me remind you
that I only met you twice,
when I was born and when
I went to University!
You don't have the
right! A writer can have...
Right, family,
duty, society: Literature!
This aristocracy where rottenness can
be found hidden behind the couch.
This joke will cease to be funny
when it turns to blood.
And I enter. I mean, Nicolas enters.
You all look at me. Attention.
Nicolas, my son...
More beautiful, more gifted,
more unique, more brilliant than ever!
Is it true that for a bet, you
legally and religiously married this idiot...
No...
Is that true, for a bet, you
legally and religiously married this idiot...
And who are you, Miss?
And now you look at him
and without expecting it,
all of a sudden, you
fall in love with him.
And he falls with you too.
- Well, thank you.
- By participating in this film, you are committing suicide...
Not bad. Tomorrow, don't forget to
use some white pencil above the eyelashes.
No powder on the temples, it makes
your eyes smaller, makes you look stubborn.
You need to project the light
towards us, not the other way around.
Yes, sir.
Inflexible... do you remember the
article I wrote about Sartre in 1962?
Yes, sir?
Can you come with me?
Yes.
That's it! Just create
goddamned chaos! Another attempt, comrade!
Where are we?
A hotel!
- Is there no reception?
- No!
Why shoot all your films
in Germany? You're French...
I'm not French.
Or even German.
My mom was French.
I shot my movies in Germany because it
was the only place I could do it my way.
Films "against"...
Against what?
Against... those who
no longer fear God.
- Hurry up, we're almost ready.
- Ready for what?
I told you several times, I
don't want this powder there.
Just like this.
Damn it, the dress!
Can't you see it's
useless? Pick another one, come on.
Are you stupid, or what?
Ethel! I need to speak to you.
Do you like it?
Scratch the sole. It
will be less slippery.
Listen, you don't look
like the son of a servant.
You studied with Nicolas,
you wear Nicolas' clothes,
but they are too short for you.
Give it to me.
Let's shoot!
Lights!
"The Possessed", Scene 32, Take 1.
Action.
Nicolas, is that true that,
for a stupid bet, you legally and
religiously married this idiot?
Pierre, would you accompany
this lady?
Of course, immediately. I told you
it was only a misunderstanding.
Being a generous man, Nicolas was being
charitable to those poor souls.
Leave, fool...
What do you mean, "fool"? "Fool"?
I have money, madam!
Leave.
What did I tell you? I'll
take care of everything.
And this is Lise. She is pretty,
isn't she? Young, intelligent, sensitive...
Pierre, your
behavior is unacceptable.
Speak, you intellectual, idiot...
Let me introduce you
to my fiancé, Maurice.
The problem is that if I had no
legs, we could not walk together...
You so tall and I so short.
Try again. More tensed. More
nervous. You're trying to be funny. Now!
You would come with me if I was
deformed, destitute and limping, with no legs.
The problem is that if I had no
legs we could not walk together.
Nicolas...
I demand an answer. I am your
mother. I want to know.
No, mother. I did not
marry this infortunate.
Liar... liar...
Why? Why?!
Cut!
Sorry, Lili. Everybody step
out of the lights, please.
Impressive!
Thanks, I didn't fall properly. I
wasn't thinking. I'd like to do another take.
3, 7, and 1.
Change of scene! Quicker!
That night, I
played my life for you.
I was happy to do it...
Because I love you.
Don't push me away.
Keep me with you.
When I see you like this, I think
that you are hiding something dark...
Or even have blood on your hands!
My head hurts... so much...
Congratulations my
friend, you are a widower.
We just found your wife and her
brother at home, their throats slit open.
Do you remember this servant that
my father lost at a card game?
Apparently he is the culprit.
He even tried to start a fire and got caught,
his pockets full of stolen money.
Lise, have you arrived
already? Perfect. A miracle, isn't it?
A godsend, if God exists.
I just saw your
fiancé. What's his name?
You knew!
Still as a statue...
You knew! You knew!
It was... I could have...
stayed with you... at the
price... of their lives...
What if all of this was so that we
can get married, and start a new life,
clean and proper?
All you want is to
imprison me. With you.
And show me that there is a
huge spider inside the wardrobe...
And we will spend
the rest of our lives,
staring at it, terrified,
and this spider would
be... it would be...
No, no! I don't want you to
snivel. I don't want you to faint.
The Virgin, the Innocent! Enough!
You gave yourself to me,
you loved me, you understood...
You know the truth.
All you can do is vomit when
facing the horror, the crime.
Playing each scene separately
isn't enough.
The weeping girl, the hysterical
girl, in love, the girl losing her charms...
I don't want you to play each scene,
I want you to act your part!
I've seen actors playing each scene amazingly,
like the branches of a tree.
"The tree-actors". At the end, all
you could hear was rustling of the leaves.
It's crap! What matters is
what's happening between the scenes,
the truthfulness of the character,
the heart of the role. The
perceptiveness of the role!
All that you carry within during
the movie, the destiny of the character.
I want you to know everything, I
want you to show me like X-rays would.
To find the truth, the
truth of what's right here!
Do you understand?
I don't understand what you
mean! I don't understand what you want!
Listen! If you think that
everything can be found in life, such as love,
lies, and cheating, then
you can't play your part.
Love isn't just physical, fear isn't
only being afraid of the big bad wolf!
Rebellion isn't just sticking
a needle in your veins!
Coming from the gutter doesn't mean you
have to act as if God doesn't exist!
I'm tired.
Fine, act the tiredness. At
least there'll be something there.
Let's try again. Enough! Let's go!
Action. Open up. Open up!
Pronounce each word.
You are growing
up, becoming an adult.
Go on... "all you want"...
"Is to imprison me here!"
"We will spend"
- "We will spend"...
Calm down... open up.
All you want is to
imprison me here with you...
And show me that there is a huge
spider inside the wardrobe, as big as a man.
And we will spend the rest of our
lives, staring at it, terrified.
And this spider would
be... It would be..
Cut.
It's not just me.
It's not just my movie you're
destroying. You're destroying yourself too.
OK, I get it.
Let's shoot a sex scene.
Yes, but which one?
We need to shoot something at least!
"No kidding, baby!"
This lady has been an ass.
It should be easy.
Come on, hurry up! Don't
you see we're waiting for her?
Hurry up, come on!
Well miss, would
you be kind enough...
Go away!
To lie there first, as
I will be on top of you!
If you want, I can go
with you. I'm OK with that.
If only you knew
how much I hate you...
So many gifted, deserving,
experienced girls... and you!
She won't do it!
She won't even do this!
"All you want is to imprison me,
and show me that there is a huge spider
as big as a man. And we will spend
the rest of our lives, staring at it.
And this spider would
be... it would be..."
Lucas. The producer
wants to know what's going on.
You have to make a decision.
Go away! I'll call you.
Let's walk and talk.
You know, I could easily take my
scissors and cut your part out!
I suck! There are some things
I just can't play...
An actress can keep nothing for
herself! She can't have her secret garden!
The sheep, the wolf,
and the grandmother!
And you were mistaken
- I'm not an actress!
I'm never mistaken. I
never make mistakes.
I can make mistakes about everything,
apart from that!
If you could do better, you'd be...
A star!
Don't give up on me! Don't leave me!
Where is it in you? Where?
Get out, just leave!
Leave me alone!
I told you to only come
visit when I tell you to.
Get out! Go away!
Go away!
Mlis-ka Elena...
Fifteen...
The corpse of a 30 year old woman
was discovered in the ourcq canal.
We are showing these
images, despite their brutality.
The woman was wearing gold
stilettos. She was not carrying ID
and was only wearing flesh-colored
tights and a beige T-shirt. She had auburn hair.
The police are asking that anyone-
That's it! Keep playing!
If a Judas happened to be spying
on me, he would find it difficult!
Nicolas was appointed by the
central committee, which I also belong to.
I am leaving to visit the other group
as soon as you have started.
How?
By any means possible!
First of all, accelerate the destruction
of this rotten society.
Second of all, run as fast
as possible through the shit.
Third, create a fair
society, based on equality and love.
- It will leave some marks.
- Exactly!
Murder,
blackmail, extortion, bombs...
organized lies!
We need a list of all those that
will be killed immediately
for being beyond redemption, and
those that we will have a temporary use for.
I came here to talk to you about the horrible
living conditions for students.
Do you have a
pair of small scissors?
- Pardon?
- I forgot to clean my nails.
Miss! A new religion is being born!
An absolute religion,
because of its absence of God!
My thinking brought me to understand
that freedom for all
can only be obtained through
slavery for all.
Those that want unlimited freedom
will only receive
unlimited despotism in the end.
There is my conclusion:
One tenth of society will rule,
and nine tenths will obey.
That's my despair.
Your despair is yours
alone. It's subjective.
Stop it! Nicolas is waiting!
- Are you ready to take action?
- Yes!
Christian.
Your departure would be dangerous for
us, or yourself, at this moment.
You heard it, Christian. You
know... if you don't agree with us...
Where are you going? To the police?
Can you see that,
Nicolas? Can you see it?
Your friend, did you
say? There he is, Judas!
And who do you work for? Who's destiny
are you preparing us for?
Yours!
Are you OK?
You're always in the way.
Kesling hasn't made
any decision regarding you.
I've always been against the
idea. But I'm only the wallet.
I really don't
understand what they see in you.
I came to give this back to you.
That's not mine.
I'm not completely gay...
but give it time.
It belongs to the woman
you were kissing that night.
- Her I.D. is in there.
- Why are you carrying it?
Because...
Because she's dead.
- Excuse me?
- I saw it on TV.
She had on the same shoes.
They said she was murdered.
So with your Z-list intelligence, you
decided that I kill actresses in Paris.
Actress?
She was an actress, but
she doesn't act any more.
And since I used to live with her,
you'll excuse me if I kiss my ex-girlfriends
where I want, when I
want, and how I want.
Especially when they become annoying
and live with assholes, have no money left.
She can't be dead, because I
walked her home, back to the asshole...
so you couldn't have seen her on TV.
I'll go to the police!
You won't go
anywhere! Only where I tell you!
You're fired! I'll show you this
big success, this faggot.
You're made for each other!
Get out! Get out!
Would you tell this young
lady the whereabouts of your...
Where's Elena?
She went back to Czechoslovakia.
Are you sure?
I took her to the
airport for her 12:00 flight.
How could she fly
if I had her passport?
She lost it a few days ago.
The embassy replaced it. Why?
Nothing.
You can check with the airline.
Did you know her?
You're an actress too, aren't you?
Yes.
She was a wonderful actress.
I was in love with
her since I was sixteen.
She could play anything.
She had been in plenty of films in
our country, before we went to Germany.
And she made
plenty of films there...
She could have kept going...
and she would have been as
famous as she was in Prague.
If she hadn't met this loser...
This loser who... who...
That's enough!
Me... not make same
mistake. Me... poor Czech immigrant.
Even if me look so
French, it just be imitation.
I hope you are single, miss.
And an actress.
Let's drink to actresses.
To Elena!
Long live Elena!
Bottoms up, an old Czech tradition!
Enough, enough!
Indeed. I don't
even need to be here...
Happy now?
You don't have the right to
humiliate people like this.
Even if you're the most powerful,
most intelligent,
even if you're always right.
Go away.
Go away!
His Grace, Archbishop Schlapas, had
a long talk with the Minister.
His Grace has always let known his
love and understanding of French culture.
As usual, His Grace Schlapas
refused to answer journalists' questions,
and to all of those concerning
his Elevation to Cardinal.
The Pope can name a prince to the Church
in the secret of his heart only,
in order to avoid any possible
retaliation from the Government,
after his visit to Paris
and his pilgrimage to Lourdes.
They stole the passport.
Elena Mliska...
Elena Mliska, fifteen, fifteen...
Sorry, I knocked.
Is it Mr. Kesling? Again?
No...
I didn't believe you.
I know just what it's
like to beg for a role...
So when you say that your... I
mean, that she, left the next morning...
My wife!
Come sit next to me.
Come, come.
What have you done
these last two days?
Since yesterday, you mean?
No, no...
You left two days ago. Two days ago!
You know I get sick
every time you leave.
When you leave, I put on those
beautiful clothes you bought me.
You're crazy!
Take this pretty scarf, the
one you brought back on Friday.
Put it on. It really suits you, and
it looks like it's going to rain.
- Where's your bag?
- What bag?
Your bag and the coat you left at
the hotel, where you go to screw Kesling!
Did you get into a fight? Did
he not give you what you wanted?
The hotel where Kesling
brings his whores, or his actresses...
Same difference!
Please, please...
I don't want to play that!
Why not?
Is that you?
I'm back.
You made the right choice.
I'm sure you're hungry.
Yes.
The day you left Kesling for me,
it was like a miracle.
For me too.
Come again?
I said, where was it again?
In Munich, you idiot! Munich!
Yes, in Munich...
And do you remember why
our door is never closed?
Because the last time you
left and I went looking for you,
someone broke in and
stole all the money we had left.
Where did you get those shoes from?
How much were they?
Did you turn tricks for the
money? How much do you charge?
Couldn't you spend the money
to sort out this shithole?
- That's not how it is!
- Where did you spend the night then?
At the Salvation
Army. It was horrible.
Some girl was screaming. She was either
going cold turkey or having DT.
I was scared of catching lice.
This morning, I washed in the fountain,
like homeless people do!
Why did you leave? Why?
I wanted to be alone! Alone! Free!
I don't want to be
with the people I love!
I can't love, I can't! Don't
you understand that?
I can.
- Promise me.
- I promise.
It's OK.
It's OK...
Keep me with you.
OK...
It suits you.
It always has.
I'll go back to
working in the kitchen.
I'll be home late tonight.
Me too, I'm going to look for a job.
As usual?
No.
You're not going to see him tonight?
I promise.
"When he holds me against him..."
You look different.
Don't you like it?
Take off your shoes. You
look silly in those.
I thought I'd relate
to you more with them on.
Today, you'll be against the wall.
Bastard...
Gertrude!
Shit...
Milan!
Are you home?
You scared me!
Did you get home early?
I quit. I got offered a better job.
There's money on the bed, count it.
That's great...
I have money, too.
I bought food. That way we can...
You promised!
It's an honest job.
I work in the cloakroom in
a club in Montparnasse.
I get fantastic tips...
just from selling cigarettes...
Ah, yes...
And how did you get this job?
Through my actress friend...
She's unemployed too...
Because of her age...
And her accent...
That's not a job for you.
You're a star.
An actress.
A fantastic actress!
A very good one.
You really think that all
actresses are whores, don't you? That's it?
All women, all girls... they
all have this inside of them...
Why are you still here?
I told you a thousand times already.
I don't love you anymore.
I don't want to pay what I owe you because
you ruined your career for me.
Just take your money ...
and fuck off!
Please, please, please...
I love you.
"When he holds me against him...
When he speaks softly to me...
I see life in pink..."
There was a new outburst of violence
in Lebanon. A car-bomb exploded in Beirut,
resulting in four
deaths and twenty injuries.
Struggle amongst the FCP for
the position of First Secretary.
Members seem to take a
more radical approach.
"our objective is this:
What we want is revolution!"
No lead for the murder of the
Archbishop, shot several times at point-blank range.
This amateur film was
filmed by one of the guests
outside a party
organized for the Archbishop.
Politicians, religious figures,
artists and fellow Czech citizens were present.
The camera operator was close enough
to capture the exact moment of the murder.
This footage makes it possible
to identify the murderer, who fled.
Watch carefully, we have studied
each frame and have enlarged the footage.
To the left, you can clearly see the
weapon and the murderer's hand.
Here...
And here is the side of his face.
The Police hope that
these blurred images
will help the investigation.
Some suggested that the group who took
over Lithuania in 1940 are responsible.
His Grace Schlapas was due to
return home the day after tomorrow.
If only I had guessed that you
were hiding here with this genius.
- Where is he?
- He killed a priest.
He's crazy. Sick and crazy.
I was there. Do you
know what he's done before?
He came to me and asked me to
give you this farewell letter.
- Are you going to the police?
- I don't fucking care.
He can kill all the priests, I don't care.
As long as he doesn't destroy you.
Why do you care?
You're mine. I made you. I can take
you back or send you back whenever I want.
Loser!
He won't steal another one from me.
It's only in my film that you
refuse to do what you're told.
Why did you dye your hair? For
that faggot? Why did you sleep with him?
Why did you sleep with his wife?
She sleeps with
everyone, just like you.
Now listen.
Denounce him or I will. If not, you
stay with me, and become my property.
Maybe, one day, I'll
give you another chance.
You'll never come back here.
What about the neighbors?
The neighbors are dead.
All of them are dead.
Taxi!
Why did you do that? It's horrible!
Is that you? Thanks for coming.
And your hair... it
suits you so much more!
This is my film!
Does this mean anything to you?
He's right. The most beautiful
film was directed by a sick producer!
I won't mention its name.
I just don't know anymore.
I knew he couldn't handle it. I knew
our arrangement would work out in the end.
I finally understand why
you wanted Christian dead.
To make a film about
this group of idiots.
You understand, you have to start
with the idiots and the greedy,
who bring everyone else,
the sheep, right behind them.
Later, the citizens
spy on each other.
Slaves have to be equal. I love
misery, alcoholism, fear, lies, and obedience!
Total servitude!
Happiness! All of them miserable!
Kill all talent!
From time to time, let them rest for
a while. Let them have a little idol.
So that they can believe that
they are improving society!
- You're crazy.
- Crazy? On the contrary!
I'd even give half the world to the
Pope. I'd only need the International to agree.
Does that sound crazy to you? The Pope
in Eastern Europe, and you here!
Because you are beautiful! I love
beauty. We need a leader, and you're beautiful.
You believe in
everything, except in yourself.
Do you know why you married this worm that
we now need to destroy at all cost?
Because you're
beautiful. Despite everything.
For the challenge...
Enough!
I love beauty. His
beauty and his genius!
Your only problem
is your desire to live!
But I will clear the
path to your destiny,
and you will become a leader
according to my expectations.
A murderer, a liar...
A worm!
Cut. Thank you.
- How long is it?
- 1 minute 23.
It's too long. I
can't shoot another one.
I can't take it
anymore. There's no time left.
Quiet!
I'd like to go home now.
He can't go there, he doesn't
know where I live.
OK.
Is it true that Elena
came to ask you for a part?
She wanted me to help
her go back to her country.
She had severed all links. She was
living with a political expatriate.
She was scared of retaliations.
How can you help her go back there,
when you're a director here?
I won a prize at the Karlovy
Vary Festival in Czechoslovakia.
I knew a member of the government.
Really...
- How did you know?
- I followed you.
To the studio. Everywhere.
What did you do?
I killed whoever they wanted me to kill
to keep my wife alive. That's the reason!
But... she's dead!
She's... she's...
She's here because you're here!
But she's over there because they
were meant to bring her back home.
They promised me that we would
be reunited right after.
They were sure she wouldn't go
to the police... to protect me.
But you know...
there's not much time left,
and when I went to the meeting
point, it was a trap.
But they didn't get me!
But why? Why all of this?
So that they can find me with a
letter, saying that I killed him for no reason!
But you can't
stay here, if Kesling...
This time, you can't deny it.
I saw you two go to
the hotel together.
You forgot I was his wife
before being yours.
You'll need money. You'll
take what you left me.
I can get more.
I have the details of where they're
going to shoot. Call me.
I can't,
sweetheart. See for yourself.
And you don't ever tell me anything.
People ask if you're available, but
you come and go as you please.
I didn't know miss
Ethel would be here today.
Do you want me to cancel Lisette?
I'll pay.
That will be 600 francs.
There you go. Everything's sorted.
Well, go on, move.
Don't you have your camera?
I don't need it. I paid
what you asked for, didn't I?
Is this what you want?
What took you so long? We've
been waiting for hours.
Can we not leave you alone
for five minutes?
I walked.
Give me your key.
I can't stand what
you did to your hair.
You look like an old Jewish woman.
Go for your make-up. We'll
dye it back to normal.
Is that OK with you?
Action!
That's it. Dig now!
I give you back the Press!
You can print whatever you want!
My wife is back.
She is pregnant.
I have changed.
I don't want to
write against my beliefs.
You forgave your wife for leaving
with another man and coming back pregnant?
- I believe in God.
- Bastard.
One, two, three!
I like it.
Catch her!
Be quiet!
Cut!
Is it the one?
The blood!
I'm shooting a
commercial about death.
If you don't put blood on the screen,
it will run more freely behind.
What do you think of Kesling's work?
It's fucked up, don't you think?
It's really theatrical.
Someone for you on the phone.
Yes, I'll be there.
I'll be there.
Get up! Come on, get up!
Sorry, I can't.
I'll show you karate!
Milan, I'm hurting!
Why are you laughing?
Because I'm happy!
Because you're here.
Milan, do you believe I'll always
be such a loser, a reject, a slut,
just because I have to live
and accept? To be able to make it!
It's not "Milan", it's "Mi-lann"...
Run!
They must have followed
me, I can't see you anymore!
It's never going to end!
Run!
Who's that?
Another lover?
Where did you find this?
In a letter you
didn't bother to open.
So?
You're different.
Solomon? Put mom on the phone!
Change a bit more...
When?
Why didn't you tell me? Why not?
I thought it'd be better.
They loved each
other a lot, you know.
They just didn't know...
how.
You're not going to faint, are you?
I was thinking about
giving you your role back,
but with
everything that just happened,
do you want me to drive you home?
You know, I'm so happy you're here.
I'll give you great make-up today!
Oh, I'm so stupid...
That happens all the time...
Hi! I'm glad you're here.
Today's will be easy for us.
We're playing corpses!
Kesling promised me that he'd
let me try for your part,
and now, that's not happening. Why?
I don't know.
But why? Why?
Leave me alone!
Lise! Stay there, don't go!
Out the way!
Get out of my way!
I love you!
One, two, three!
The smell of blood again!
Lise!
I am the one who killed them!
I... am... the one... killed...
I am... the one...
who killed them...
Go on!
I am... the one...
You whore!
Do you like the
smell of blood? Do you?
Whore!
Go away.
After this film, I'd like
you to make more with me.
I believe that together...
You do everything backwards.
In your films and in your life.
Why?
Do you know what
cinema is for me in the end?
To preserve the image of our Dead.
This is actually the only way we
have found to keep them alive.
Marilyn's dead, Gabin, Jouvet...
Vivien Leigh...
Raimu...
And me.
OK.
Are you hurt?
No.
You have to turn yourself in, Milan.
If I do that, I won't see you again.
It's no longer just
between the police and me,
it's now between me and what's
left of my conscience.
We have to call an ambulance!
Your family is poor.
You're doing well at
University thanks to a government bursary,
then one day, they
take it back and say,
"You need it... come on..."
"tell us about your friends
at university".
Then you realize that those
people are no longer welcome some places.
Some are sent to prison.
Then you are given a passport to leave,
because everyone knows you're the snitch.
They make you meet a woman...
And then you forget everything else.
You did everything for me.
Until the end.
Will you call me?
Are you hurt?
Are you?
Attention...
Here he comes...
Lise, there you are!
I saw your fiancé in the garden,
still like a statue, staring
at your window.
It's not that he is like a statue, just
that he is staring at your windows.
You understand the text, it's
got a wild beauty, and...
I just saw your fiancé
- what's his name?
As if he was in a trance,
still like a statue in the garden,
staring at your window.
I mean, the windows.
Isn't that strange?
Did you know?
It was at the price...
It was at the price of their
lives... that I could stay here...
All you want is to imprison me,
and show me that there is a huge
spider inside the wardrobe,
as big as a man. And we will spend the
rest of our lives, staring at it,
admiring it, knowing it...
And this spider would be...
God...
Good.
Ethel, can you try
to speak to Kesling?
He fired the continuity girl for
drinking too much, but there's still one day left!
Have you seen Kesling? You were very
good. Yesterday's rushes were amazing.
- Could I have an advance? - Of
course, where's my check-book...
The studio director has it, he left
and the accountant has closed access.
Can it wait until tomorrow?
It's OK. I'll find another way.
Being crazy isn't
cheap. Very well...
Gertrude?
There's nothing left for you here.
He's dead.
The most terrible thing...
is that I'm relieved.
Are you becoming part of my race?
What? What race? Did
you use him from the start?
Yes! Yes and no!
Me! Me! I was meant
to be the kingpin,
helping the ascension of a proletariat that
doesn't exist, like everything else.
And it just seemed so natural, a director
who is lonely but in love...
with the woman he made
fantastic films with.
And he finds her in
Paris with her loser.
Did you follow them?
No, I was merely there to remind Mr.
Mliska what was expected of him.
To help him get where he was meant
to be, at the right time.
And if he refused, I had to
help capture his wife, if need be...
Did she know?
She knew.
She was fucked... but not dumb.
She was trying to
convince you to leave Milan alone.
Tomorrow is my last shooting day. I
won't have any right over you anymore.
I made you. You'll be a star.
I don't give a
fuck. I'm not interested.
You're interested! You'll
make more and more films!
Cinema is like bubbles of
light in an ocean of shadows.
One has to prepare
its destiny to keep going.
There, our boat is sinking!
And you can hear the
chariots coming!
Ivan!
No...
It's just the garbage men.
I'm not crying for Milan.
I'm crying for you.
I love you.
Don't patronize me.
If you had any idea how
little I care about you...
To what extent...
I don't know...
I'll do anything so
that one day you'll know it.
Do it.
And now the creature is
going to devour its creator...
Isn't it?
Do you think I could handle it?
Are you going to go to the police?
Yes. I have to.
I could stop you.
Are you scared?
If you are, you
don't understand anything.
I can't hurt you.
You're my film.
I'm asking you to finish it.
Just one day...
Tomorrow.
Will you come?
I will.
Hello?
It's over, dear.
I never told you, but
I've got so much debt...
You can't come back.
I won't.
Let's not say
goodbye just like this.
Have you seen my apartment upstairs?
No.
Come in.
This is my daughter.
Are you going to say Hi to the lady?
Hello...
I was never able to
leave her. And it has cost me.
Now she'll go into an institution.
I'll try to find a job not
too far away from her...
Spectacular car
accident this morning in Paris.
A car drove into a
pylon on the highway.
It took firemen more than twenty
minutes to extract the body of the driver,
who was killed instantly.
This incident is bringing new light
on the investigation into the murder
of His Grace Schlapas, which
took place a few days ago in Paris.
The victim of the car accident
is a Czech dissident, Milan Mliska.
A note was found on his body,
claiming that he was the Archbishop's murderer.
This would make investigators
reconsider their previous theory of a conspiracy.
The letter is leading them to
consider that Mliska had mental health issues.
It appears that he was trying to
bring attention to prisoner conditions.
You were on the cover of P. Match, Jours
de France and Elle. Did Kesling tell you?
- Ethel, can I have an interview?
- Later, sure.
There's my competitor, who
wants to steal you from me.
Pleased to meet you, I brought a
script. It would be nice if you would read it.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
Ethel, we've not had much time to
talk, but I'm working on my first film
and I'd like - what I mean - it's going
to be completely different from this one.
Look, we've all helped buy this for him. It's solid gold
- do you like it?
I do.
- Hey, have they paid you?
- No.
Listen, I have an
idea. Sign the box!
You'll be everyone's favorite.
Or a flash in the pan.
What's wrong, Ethel?
It's just as if I was
suddenly all alone in this world...
"Modern and unexpected, the new revelation
of young French cinema".
"'I Have Met a Star'
by Lucas Kesling".
"Pros and Cons: Touching,
serious and unusual, the new beauty"...
"Young woman: Actress or object?"
"All three, answers Lucas Kesling, the
flamboyant director of 'The Possessed"'.
"The Unusual Life"...
Forgive me, bless
me, love me, remember me...
Always go where life is...
Don't turn back, believe
in yourself.
You're the most beautiful
gift God could give a man.
A man would need to be...
as proper...
and humble as you
are, to deserve you.
Go!
Then he walks past the
building, inside, two guys are arguing.
Those two guys were producers, and
he didn't even know that cinema exists...
And half an hour
later, these two guys ask him...
Oh my God, no!
Shit. He hung himself for real.