PATHÉ and The Criterion Collection present
a 2022 restoration
Le Samouraï was restored in 4K
from the original camera negative,
which included some internegative parts.
Also and interpositive was used.
The sound was restored
from the 35mm magnetic track.
The color correction
was supervised by Bruno Nuytten.
THE SAMURAI
THERE IS NO GREATER SOLITUDE
THAN THAT OF THE SAMURAI,
UNLESS IT IS THAT
OF THE TIGER IN THE JUNGLE...
PERHAPS...
BUSHIDO (BOOK OF THE SAMURAI)
SATURDAY, APRIL 4
6:00 P.M.
Jef?
Tonight I got here at 7:15
and left at 2:00 a.m.
Impossible. Wiener just got back.
He phoned to say he's coming at 2:O0.
Then I was here
from 7:15 to 1:45.
I like when you come here,
because you need me.
Call.
How long will you be here?
We rented the room for the night.
I'll be here at 2:00.
Save me a seat.
Bring cash, in case you lose.
I never lose.
Not really.
- Who are you?
- It doesn't matter.
What do you want?
To kill you.
General alert.
Routine round up.
Identity checks all night.
The killer is described as tall,
young, wearing a raincoat and a hat.
I want at least 20 suspects
from every precinct.
What's 400 suspects
in a city of 10 million?
Get a move on.
In an hour it'll be too late.
Police. Open up.
Identity check.
Your papers, gentlemen.
Your papers, sir.
How long have you been here?
Since 19:00.
Thank you.
Papers, please.
And you?
Since 21 :00... 21:15.
Your livelihood?
I get a full pension, sir.
I'm a disabled veteran.
Your papers, sir.
When did you get here?
At 2:00... 2:15.
Come with us for a routine check.
If you make a legitimate living,
you'll be released at once.
Let's move it.
Silence!
Damolini, Ange Sėraphin.
Gros Caillou precinct. Age 41.
Picked up in a bar
on Ave Bosquet,
with a .32 automatic.
Take off your glasses.
What have you got to say?
Me? Nothing at all.
You were carrying a gun.
For what purpose?
Next.
This way.
Garcia, Juan, age 47,
and Delbarre, Jeanne, age 51.
Picked up near Austerlitz station.
Man carrying a .32 automatic.
Take off your hat.
- You're not married?
- No.
Living together?
Yes.
Why the gun?
Paris streets ain't safe at night.
It's just for self-defense.
I'll read your record:
"1945, six-month prison sentence
for inciting a minor to debauchery.
1950, 12-month sentence
for drug trafficking.
1952, attempted burglary.
1955, new sentence for procuring.
1958, attempted murder.
1960, manslaughter.
Given the benefit of the doubt."
Well?
Next.
Costello, Jef. Age 30.
No criminal record.
Fits the description.
Not carrying any firearms.
The man wore a hat.
Put on your hat.
It wasn't a hat like that.
The hat he wore...
...was darker.
No, it was a light hat.
But he had a mustache.
I think.
Why'd you shave your mustache off?
I've never had a mustache.
I don't think it's him.
No, it's certainly not him.
Excuse me, but I say it's him.
I distinctly remember the silhouette.
And you?
Yes, of course,
it could be him.
Where were you
between 12:00 and 2:00?
At my girlfriend's.
The lucky lady's name
and phone number?
Is it necessary?
Asuspect without an alibi
stays here.
Jane Lagrange,
11 Avenue Amiral Bruix.
- Phone number?
- MacMahon 91-73.
Miss Lagrange, please.
Miss Lagrange alone.
Apart from the man outside
whom we found at your apartment,
did you have
another visitor last night?
We're not investigating
your private life.
You can see whom you like,
when you like.
That's not an offense.
I just want to know if, before
Mr. Wiener arrived at 2:00 a.m.,
you had another visitor.
Yes.
Until what time and who?
Until 1:45. A man.
So I understood.
Same age as Mr. Wiener?
No, younger.
Thirtyish?
Yes, thirtyish.
From what time to what time?
From about 7:15 until 1:45.
How did you know it was 1:45?
I made him leave.
I expected Mr. Wiener at 2:00.
I understand.
And now one last verification.
The man's name?
Must I answer?
Yes, you must.
Jef Costello.
Excuse me a moment, please.
He didn't say he knew the victim?
- Why didn't you mention that?
- It's not true.
You'll have to prove that.
No, it's up to you
to prove the contrary.
What you can't deny...
for very long anyway...
are your regular visits
to his club.
I never set foot in there.
What exactly are you after?
Jef Costello's confession
to a crime he didn't commit?
Isn't that going too far?
I'm about to make
you change your tune.
Call you back.
Bring Wiener straight in here.
You arrived at Miss Lagrange's
apartment at 2:00 or 2:15?
That's right.
Think carefully before you answer.
Did you have the feeling
upon entering her apartment
that someone had just left?
Forgive me for being so blunt,
but didn't you feel your spot
was still warm?
Excuse me?
I have to insist.
I'm not very observant.
That's everyone's loss.
But I do remember something.
As I entered the building,
someone turned on the light.
I saw a man on his way out.
He walked past me.
Come to think of it, he was
a few feet from Miss Lagrange's door.
He might've been coming out.
Could you recognize him?
No, I don't think so.
Let me try something.
Put on your coats and hats
and line up in three rows.
Come with me.
Stand over there.
Switch coats with him.
And you switch hats.
Come this way, please.
Do you recognize the man you saw
at 2:00 a.m. in Miss Lagrange's lobby?
Do you recognize anyone?
I have a composite image
of the man I passed.
A trench coat like that one.
A hat like this one,
or that one.
And a face like his.
Just imagine
if you were observant!
Come with me, please.
That's it.
I must ask you both to forgive me.
Our job leaves no room for etiquette.
Can I go now?
Of course.
So much for people's private lives!
I'm investigating a homicide.
I have no choice when dealing
with a suspect. Every minute counts.
Can I go now too?
Of course.
Take the lady home.
I'd like you to take
one more look at Costello.
Try to be certain.
No "maybe" or "I think."
"Yes, it's him,"
or "No, it's not him." Understood?
Bring him in.
Do you recognize this man?
Did you see him come out
of the office hallway?
Yes or no.
No, absolutely not.
Thank you.
Step into my office.
Sir?
Do you still recognize him as the man
who came out of the hallway?
I can answer unequivocally.
That's what I'm asking you to do.
The answer is yes.
Step into my office.
Do you recognize this man?
No. Frankly, I don't think so.
Step into my office.
Same question.
I'm not sure now.
I didn't see the man long enough.
Step into my office.
Miss?
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
I can't give you
a definitive answer.
Thank you.
Step into my office.
Now, ma'am,
you're the only witness
who actually saw Martey's killer.
You were a few feet from him.
I can hold him and destroy his alibi,
since he was formally
recognized by a witness,
or he walks out of here
a free man on your word...
and that's the end of it.
There's not the slightest doubt
in my mind.
It's definitely not him.
Thank you, ma'am.
It's the least I can do.
Thank you, miss.
Gentlemen, step outside.
SUNDAY, 5:45 A.M.
Can I go now?
I'm afraid so.
- How many suspects left?
- Nine.
Same procedure for the nine.
That'll take care of our Sunday.
What do you think about Costello?
I never think.
1 Lord Byron Street.
He just entered 1 Lord Byron St.
I'll drive around
to the Champs-Elysėes side,
then circle back here
to see if he comes out.
Careful now:
1 Lord Byron St. has two exits.
The Champs-Elysėes exit
is at 116b.
- I'll pass it.
- Stay there.
I'll double-park.
He just went into the metro.
Tail him. Try, anyway.
He got away.
What do I do?
As usual when this happens,
report back here.
It's done.
I know.
But you were arrested.
It was nothing.
Fine. A promise made...
We can't leave him on the loose.
He was picked up and held
several hours by Homicide.
The fact they released him
proves nothing.
He might still be a suspect.
I doubt it.
He came up with a terrific alibi.
- And if it doesn't hold up?
- No way it won't.
It's a two-part alibi.
They don't connect.
I admit they don't come
any smarter.
That's why we hired him.
He carried out the contract:
to kill Martey without a trace.
He's a lone wolf.
Awounded wolf.
He'll leave a trace now.
No, we have to get rid of him,
and quick.
Since the police
won't find the killer,
they won't let him off the hook.
Despite his alibi,
he's their main witness,
by which I mean
their main suspect.
We'll keep on his trail as well.
Make sure he doesn't
give you the slip again.
Not a single clue,
and yet something doesn't fit.
What's that?
I don't know.
He's not normal.
I can keep the other suspects
for 48 hours,
but him, no way.
- His alibi is airtight.
- Too airtight.
Wiener's absolutely sincere,
but I'm sure the girl's lying.
We have to break her
so she talks.
Then the DAcan slap
a perjury charge on her.
And little Jef Costello
will be sitting in this chair.
He'll just laugh in our faces.
I doubt it.
Ever see a guy stay handcuffed
for 48 hours and not open his mouth?
I haven't seen many.
Stick with the girl,
but don't lose his trail.
SUNDAY, 10:00 P.M.
- What will you have?
- A whiskey.
If you were the man
wanted by the police,
you could say the criminal always
returns to the scene of the crime.
May I get in?
Why did you say
you didn't recognize me?
Why did you kill Martey?
I was told I'd be paid.
What did he do to you?
Nothing at all.
I didn't even know him.
The first and last time I saw him
was 24 hours ago.
What kind of man are you?
But you knew Martey. Not having
an alibi makes it worse for you.
I was driving back to Paris.
Without witnesses.
You'll have to prove it.
Over here.
- The others?
- Nothing.
- You'd think informers were on strike.
- Bite your tongue!
Something new.
A package Costello dropped
in the gutter.
- What's in it?
- Bloody gauze and cotton.
He's wounded.
- Know where he is now?
- Naturally.
I have to know who hated Martey
enough to kill him.
Why should you care?
At the payoff,
they tried to kill me.
To make sure
it won't happen again,
I have to find them
before they find me.
The blond guy I was to meet
on the overpass
didn't leave me much time to think.
I'd like to contact him
and his employer.
You know them.
They hired you.
No, I only saw a go-between.
You didn't identify me
for one of two reasons.
Either you enjoyed playing
with the police...
or you were told
not to recognize me.
Arrested, I'm a threat
to the go-between.
Thus, indirectly, to the man
who ordered the murder.
And?
If he's a friend of yours,
I'll find him through you.
It's 6:10.
Call me here in two hours.
MONDAY, 7:OOA.M.
Jef?
Yes.
They're just awful.
I can't keep them
from being overzealous.
What do you expect?
In the police, promotion means a lot.
When I was young,
I was overzealous.
- While now you're a fatalist.
- Exactly.
Things go your way or you give up.
I don't want to get a confession
or a testimony by strong-arm tactics.
- You don't say.
- I'm very tolerant.
I'm all for individual freedom.
Live and let live.
Provided the way one lives
doesn't cause harm to others,
doesn't disturb the peace,
and can in no way be considered
an offense against public decency.
- Isn't that so?
- Sure. What are you driving at?
Simply this:
You declared under oath
that Jef Costello
was here the night of the murder,
from about 7:15 p.m.
until 1:45 a.m.
- Is that right?
- Quite right.
Let's suppose Costello
wasn't here during those six hours,
and I find out.
You'll be indicted for perjury,
contempt of court,
obstruction of justice
and accessory to murder.
You'll get at least five years.
Five years is a long time.
Especially for a girl your age.
If I tell you this,
it's because...
I have a daughter your age,
and I'd feel really bad.
Would you now?
I would.
You're wrong not to believe me.
I think you're a nice girl.
Avery nice girl.
Your behavior
in this proves one thing:
You've got pluck.
Not many girls would've done
what you did for a friend.
Sorry.
A boyfriend.
You're above reproach.
But compared with you,
he's no good at all.
- You seen him since?
- No.
I figured as much.
That little louse!
- Know where he is now?
- No.
Want to know?
No.
I'll tell you anyway.
He's at that pianist's place
from the club.
They've been inseparable
since that night.
Seems like true romance.
You don't look too concerned.
Don't you love him?
Well, well.
I thought you did.
What with all the risks
you took for him,
I thought you must really love him.
You're not much of a psychologist.
That must be it.
Yet I figured he was your...
What's the word?
Your "soul mate."
While the gentleman...
Wiener...
was there to pay the bills.
It's strange. Girls like you
are virtually prostitutes.
Ever give it any thought?
You should.
It could blow up in your face.
If the vice squad
starts in after you...
Those boys mean business.
You need to be covered.
No pun intended.
And you want to cover me?
Even better.
I want to help you,
get you out of this.
Your statement.
If you tell me now,
without witnesses,
that Costello wasn't here
the night of the murder,
I tear it up and we forget it.
No perjury charge. Nothing.
And you won't have
to make a new statement.
And the vice squad?
You have my word.
Nothing will happen.
I knew you were a smart girl.
In other words,
you want me to perjure myself,
in return for which
I'll be left alone.
But if I stick to the truth
and get in your way,
then I won't heart he end of it.
Is that it?
Not quite.
The truth is not what you say.
It's what I say.
Whatever the methods I use
to get to it.
So then...
is it yes?
It's no.
As you like.
But we'll meet again.
Hang it up.
We made two mistakes.
First was to think
your arrest was a police trap.
Second was to worry
you'd be a threat to us.
That's why I tried to kill you.
But we think we need
to make a fresh start.
Here's the remainder
of the two million for Martey.
Remember the deal said
no problems.
Imagine how we felt
when you were picked up.
Now we want something else.
Here's another two million,
in advance this time.
For the same kind of operation.
Another contract.
No answer?
I never talk
to a man holding a gun.
Is that a rule?
A habit.
On your feet.
I'll answer you with a question:
Who sent you?
I'm not free to tell you that.
You were free
to kill me on the overpass.
Look at me.
I won't ask you a third time:
Who? Name and address.
It's nobody you know.
He isn't someone like us.
Don't try my patience.
Olivier Rey.
Address?
73 Boulevard Montmorency.
That's how you end up out of work.
Now about this new contract.
Well...
He found the bug.
He'll be on his guard even more.
When he leaves his place,
you're to stick to him like glue.
Our plan of attack is ready.
He knows the metro
like the back of his hand.
I want flawless surveillance this time.
You're in charge of surface vehicles.
You cover the metro. I'll give you
50 men and 20 auxiliaries.
You'll all wear
a gallium arsenide transmitter.
When you see Costello,
switch to this position.
When you lose contact,
this position.
If you pick up contact,
switch it back. And so on.
I'll stay here as liaison between
the vehicles and the metro unit.
Dismissed.
Car 11 ready.
Car 13 ready.
Car 38 ready.
Car 41 ready.
Here we go.
Contact established.
Contact broken.
He got off at Jourdain.
Reestablish contact
at all costs!
Acarto Place des Fëtes,
another to Botzaris,
a third to Prė-St-Gervais.
Message received.
We're on it.
Car 167 to Botzaris.
Car 16 to Place des Fëtes.
Car 39 to Pré-St-Gervais.
I was on the wrong side.
- What happened?
- Boss!
- What?
- We lost him.
- How?
- On the moving walkway.
He can't have come up yet.
I have a man at each exit.
Got enough men?
No, I'm waiting,
but the other cars aren't here yet.
I hope he uses
an exit we have covered.
- And the platform?
- Covered.
I'm warning you, Jef.
This is the last time.
Okay.
You heard me?
I think I did.
Well, I had a feeling.
Maybe it was just because
I wanted you to come.
You in trouble?
No.
Because of me?
I've never been in trouble
because of you.
They hassled you?
No.
But what about you?
Don't you need me?
- No.
- Yes, you do.
What can I do?
What can I do, Jef?
Nothing.
Don't worry.
I'll work it all out.
What do you want?
You got the four million?
Yes.
You accept the new contract?
You shouldn't have come.
I'm leaving.
Don't stay here.
Why, Jef?
I was paid to.
You had a close call.
If it weren't for us,
you'd be dead.
Wrong.
Acknowledgments
4K restoration carried out by
L'lmage Retrouvėe, Paris-Bologna