Presented by Prosperity Film Company
Executive Producer: WONG Cheuk-hon
Presented by King HU
LEGEND OF THE MOUNTAIN
Starring: HSU Feng
Sylvia CHANG, SHIH Chun
TUNG Lin, TIEN Feng
NG Ming-choi, Rainbow HSU
Also starring:
CHEN Hui-lou, SUN Yueh, WU Chia-hsiang
Director of Photography:
Henry CHAN
Music:
WU Ta-chiang
Producers: SUN Chia-wen, Robert CHAN
Editors: King HU, SIU Nam
Martial Arts Choreographer: NG Ming-choi
Production Design: King HU
Assistant Directors:
TUNG Lin, Fred TAN
Written by
CHUNG Ling
Directed by King HU
In the olden days,
there were a lot of Chinese legends.
Some are about spirits and monks,
while others are about
ghosts and fairies.
These legends were popular
with all audiences.
One of the legends
is set in the Song dynasty,
maybe in the 11th century.
A scholar failed the imperial exam.
All he knew how to do was study,
but he couldn't find a decent job,
so he started working as a copyist.
It was a living.
One day he got a letter
from a monk at the Ocean Mudra Temple
asking him to copy a Buddhist sutra.
Well, he wasn't a Buddhist,
nor did he believe in a spirit world.
But then he thought it over
and could hardly say no to the money.
It was merely another job, after all.
OCEAN MUDRA TEMPLE AT GAYA MOUNTAIN
Wait here for the sutra and the prayer beads.
What about the mudra?
The old master will show you.
Remember not to speak.
Just listen to what he says.
Yes, of course.
So later...
Will you...?
Me? I'm not allowed to go in.
Master Pujing in the capital
needs this sutra for a ritual.
I see.
It's a ritual to release lost souls
who died on the frontier.
It will be a great meritorious act.
So copy the sutra as fast as you can.
I shall.
I've found you a quiet place to copy it.
This is a letter of introduction.
Tsui Hung-chih?
Tsui is an adviser to General Han.
I haven't seen him in over a year.
Here's a money order
to cover your expenses.
What's Mr Tsui like?
He's a good friend of mine.
He's mild-mannered, widely read,
but uninterested in an official career.
His current position is a sinecure,
so he doesn't have much to do.
He spends his days enjoying
wine, poetry and nature.
Mr Tsui and I are birds of a feather.
Just make sure to keep yourself in line:
spending too much time in
nature will delay the work.
Don't worry.
Sir.
Where is Qinfeng Road?
Go through the gate, go straight,
cross the bridge and turn left.
Thanks.
BAMBOO ISLAND PAVILION
Sir, I hope you don't mind my asking,
but how do I get to North Fort?
How far is it?
Why do you want to go there?
To see a friend.
You'd better not go.
Why not?
Nobody lives there.
Great, I'm looking for peace and quiet.
How do I get there?
Go downhill and cross the river.
There's no bridge, but it's not deep.
You can cross on the rocks.
Sir.
Sir, wait!
I have a question.
I'd like to ask you...
Be careful.
Sir!
What are you doing?
Stop it.
Old Chang, let him go!
What's gotten into you?
Be gone.
Leave!
Sorry, my old subordinate is deranged.
If he has offended you,
please accept my apology.
No, it's my fault.
I kept pestering him,
hoping to ask for directions.
He probably thought
I was up to no good.
No, that's not it.
He gets confused when he sees strangers.
Maybe you can tell me the way.
How do I get to the General's Mansion
on Qinfeng Road?
It's right up ahead.
I'll take you.
Great! Please.
- Let me show you the way.
- Thank you.
This way.
I've got something else to ask you.
Oh, I'm no expert.
The road's been so desolate since the pass.
I didn't see any soldiers in the fort.
Did they transfer somewhere else?
The rest transferred back.
- The rest?
- Yes.
There were only a few left.
Did they lose control of the area?
You don't know what happened here.
I heard there was a conflict.
We battled Xixia bitterly
for three years,
but the imperial court was irresolute.
The Xixia king saw a weakness,
and launched a massive assault.
Almost all our soldiers were slaughtered.
The court signed a humiliating treaty,
so that neither side can station troops.
The area is now a no man's land.
Then what happened to General Han?
He died defending his country.
He's dead?
Oh no!
What, did you know him?
No, I didn't.
I want to ask you about someone.
Who?
One of his advisers, a Mr Tsui.
I am Tsui Hung-chih.
What a coincidence!
Huiming at Ocean Mudra Temple
sent me with a letter for you.
Sorry.
Here it is.
Oh! Mr Ho.
You're here to find a quiet place
so you can copy a sutra.
Yes, but given the situation here,
I don't know if it's convenient or not.
No inconvenience at all.
It's quiet here if nothing else.
I left my pack in the pavilion.
I'll tell Old Chang to get it for you.
Old Chang?
That man just now.
GENERAL HAN'S MANSION, QINFENG ROAD
So this is the General's Mansion.
- Mr Ho, let's go inside.
- Yes.
This is where General Han gave orders
and reviewed the troops of his armies.
In his letter Huiming said
you're going to copy a sutra.
Which sutra are you going to copy?
The Great Mudra Sutra.
Has it been translated?
Yes, it took Master Fayuan
ten years to translate.
I heard whoever owns this esoteric sutra
can navigate the realms of life and death.
I don't know too much about it.
Monk Huiming said, of all the sutras from India,
only it can grant release to lost souls.
I hear the hardest part is the mudra.
I know a thing or two about it.
- How reassuring!
- Why?
To think that lost souls can get
release from suffering.
Mr Tsui, do you believe in all this?
I believe. What about you?
I didn't used to believe.
But now more and more I do.
Why?
I've seen so many strange things lately.
Really?
I'll tell you some other time.
Mr Ho, about the mudras...
Did Master Fayuan pass them
on to you personally?
Yes, when I got there,
the venerable sir taught them to me,
especially the art of subduing demons.
He worried demons might harass me on the way.
But I don't know if it really works.
Mr Ho, after you.
Thanks.
It will work if your heart is true.
- Good point!
- Please.
Here it is.
- It's fairly plain.
- No, it's perfect.
Once the abode of
the General's favourite concubine,
it's now a guest house.
Make yourself at home.
This is the bedroom.
You'll find everything you need.
If you need anything else let me know.
No, I'll be fine.
It's really comfortable and quiet.
It may be, but you have to be careful.
What you mean? It's not safe here?
You won't get robbed,
but I'm worried about the sutra.
Really?
This is a gazebo.
And there's a lotus pond over there.
Wonderful.
You said you're worried about the sutra?
I heard that if
evil sorcerers got hold of it,
they could enslave fiends and do evil.
Does the sutra really have such power?
So I hear.
Better safe than sorry.
I think it would be safest
not to tell anyone you're copying the sutra.
One more thing:
I'll tell Old Chang
to bring your meals every day
and take care of your laundry.
Old Chang? I can cook my own meals.
And I always wash my own clothes.
Don't worry about such trivialities.
Really, it's fine.
There's no need to trouble Old Chang.
Mr Tsui, Mr Tsui...
Oh no! That old lady
is rather trying.
You are really something.
Old Chang is useless, too clumsy.
How can he serve anyone?
Madame Wang, what are you doing here?
I heard Old Chang say you have a guest.
I knew he'd be staying here.
Mr Tsui, when will you introduce me?
This is Madame Wang,
General Han's chief housekeeper.
And this is Mr Ho.
Hello Madame Wang.
Let's talk inside.
Mr Ho, cooking and cleaning
is for old ladies.
You leave everything to me.
Mr Tsui, Old Chang's not up to it.
He's deaf and mute, and inefficient.
Put it here, Old Chang.
Madame Wang, how could we impose on...
Don't treat me like a stranger.
Mr Ho, is there any laundry in here?
I will wash it while I am at it.
No, I don't have any laundry.
All I carry in my pack is books.
Don't be afraid to ask for help.
I know how hard it is
to be away from home.
Old Chang, take his pack into the room.
Madame Wang,
please don't go to the trouble of...
Don't interrupt me while I'm working.
Mr Ho, I'll tell you the truth,
I'm bored out of my skull.
Don't worry, I don't want your money.
I can take it myself.
I don't want to impose.
I've got an idea: I have a child.
You teach my child for free,
and I will cook and clean for you.
Is it a deal? What do you say?
Well, I...
Madame Wang,
Mr Ho has a lot of things to do.
Tutoring won't take much of my time.
Good, it's a deal!
Mr Ho, you must be tired.
Mr Tsui, let's go.
Madame Wang, I'm going to
invite Mr Ho to dinner.
You go first.
Right! Tonight I'll make a few dishes
to welcome Mr Ho here on your behalf.
- No...
- Let's go, I don't want to hear it.
Mr Ho's been on the road for days.
At least let him take a nap.
Let's go! Old Chang...
Let me go!
This evening I'll send someone for you.
Mr Tsui, let's go to the market.
To the market?
- Mr Tsui...
- We'd better just go along with her.
- No need to send me off.
- Bye.
Old Chang, let's go.
See you later.
All right, see you later.
Thanks in advance.
Thanks for what? See you this evening.
See you this evening.
All right.
Quiet now. Let's go.
What?
Old Chang!
Mr Ho.
Mr Ho, the person I'll send
is my maid, Qing.
All right.
Mr Ho, remember, don't be late.
All right, thanks.
Who is it?
Me.
Madame Wang sent me to escort you.
Please come in.
You are?
I'm Qing, Madame Wang's maid.
Great, let's go.
Were you scared to come alone just now?
I hear this area is haunted.
Look! Over there!
What is it?
Don't be afraid.
It's just a Lama. Let's go.
Hurry up.
Here we are.
I'm coming.
- Mr Ho, you're here.
- Madame.
- Please come in.
- All right.
- Mr Ho, over here.
Sit inside.
- You made it!
- Mr Tsui.
Please sit down.
You two!
- I'll do what you say then.
- Sit yourself down!
- Sit down, you two...
- All right.
- Sit...
- After you.
I'm grateful to you both
for your hospitality.
- Sorry for all the trouble.
- Here we go again.
Mr Tsui and I want to welcome you.
Make yourself at home.
With Madame's delicious wine,
a toast to you.
Thanks.
- A toast to you too.
- All right.
Good wine.
To be honest,
I brewed this herbal wine myself
over ten years ago.
- No wonder.
- Here it comes.
The hot pot is served.
What an amazing meal!
Just simple country dishes.
Madame Wang is famous for her cooking.
If it weren't for you,
I wouldn't be here to enjoy it.
Just listen to yourself!
Yunqing, there's no
such thing as a free meal.
Really?
Why do you say that?
Mr Ho, didn't I mention
I don't want my child
sitting around all day.
I want to hire a tutor.
If you're not too busy,
then why don't you take a pupil?
I don't have what it takes.
Mr Ho, don't belittle yourself.
Yes, Yunqing, don't put yourself down.
Just see if you have the time...
I have the time, but I've never...
Mr Ho,
You can be straight with me.
Just name your tutoring fee.
No,
that's not what I meant.
I've never been a tutor.
I'm afraid I'll do a bad job.
You learn by doing.
My child isn't slow,
just a bit naughty.
Naughty is normal.
Children will be children.
But has he been taught before?
For a couple of years.
The zither, chess, poetry, and painting.
How old is your son?
My son? Oh, here she is.
All grown up!
That's her.
This is that child of mine.
Please sit down.
Come over.
All grown up and still so shy?
Meet Mr Ho.
- Yes.
- Go over.
Come, sit by Mr Ho.
Mr Ho, her name is Melody.
We've already talked it over.
Mr Ho will be your tutor.
Madame Wang, this will not do.
I didn't know you meant a girl.
Mr Ho, you can't go back on your word.
Come, bow to your teacher.
Sir.
I'm not a teacher!
Mr Ho, please sit down.
Clumsy girl! You splashed the wine.
No, it's my fault.
Young lady, get up.
- I don't deserve it.
- Quick, wipe the wine off.
- No!
- I'm sorry, sir!
It was my fault.
Refill Mr Ho's cup.
I'm fine, no need.
She's kowtowed to you,
so you must take her as your pupil.
Mr Tsui, am I right?
Mr Tsui...
You'll have to make the best of it.
It'd be inappropriate to teach a girl.
But we can study together...
Study what together?
She'll take lessons from you.
Madame Wang...
Mr Ho, you've agreed.
- Hurry up and toast your teacher.
- I...
Mr Ho, a toast to you.
All right.
Then it's settled.
All right, Yunqing.
Now you've got a beautiful disciple.
Come, a toast to you.
- I shouldn't drink.
- Melody, refill Mr Ho's cup.
All right, thank you.
Yunqing, Melody is a good student,
and a talented musician.
She plays lots of different instruments,
and excels in percussion.
- Uncle Tsui!
- Then you should teach me instead.
- Mr Ho, you're not serious!
- I mean it.
Don't listen to Uncle Tsui,
I don't deserve his praise.
- Drink some more!
- I don't hold my liquor well.
You've barely drunk anything.
Come.
Very well.
Please.
Madame! Miss!
You won't believe it.
Come quickly!
What are you making such a fuss over?
Come here.
You keep drinking.
There is a Lama begging for alms.
I'll take a look.
What's the matter?
Lamas often come begging for alms.
Amitabha Buddha!
What do you want?
We don't give out alms here.
Get out!
Mother has a bad temper,
I'll go and see.
All right, go ahead.
Do you hear me? Get out!
Yunqing, a toast.
What's the matter with you?
You just said Lamas often come here.
I'm going to see for myself.
No need, Yunqing.
No, on the way here,
I was followed by a Lama.
He did not look friendly.
I will go and see if it is him.
Are you looking for trouble?
Why are you being difficult?
I think it's him. I'll go for a closer look.
No need, Madame Wang can handle him.
Are you drunk?
Leave!
Go!
Away with you!
Next time, don't make a fuss.
Shut the door!
Now let's all sit down again.
Sir, I hope it hasn't ruined your evening.
What just happened?
That Lama was probably drunk.
He insisted on coming in for a drink.
What nerve!
Yes, sit.
Please.
Mr Tsui, just now...
- Another drink.
- I can't.
Since...
Uncle Tsui just praised my drumming,
let me perform to the best of my ability
to entertain both of you.
- All right.
- Wonderful!
Not bad.
Mr Tsui, look.
It's Old Chang.
Old Chang, you've come just in time.
There is a Lama outside making trouble.
Go and get rid of him.
- Please sit over there.
- Mother's over there, go quickly.
Yunqing, have another drink.
- Yunqing...
- Uncle Tsui!
Let Mr Ho enjoy himself.
Very... good... wine...
The Lama's here.
You're awake?
I'll pour you a cup of tea.
Please don't bother.
Miss, when did you come?
Me? I brought you back with Old Chang.
Thank you...
I'm really sorry.
Sorry?
You said I had to take you home,
or you wouldn't leave.
Did I say that?
I was really drunk last night.
Then... after you brought me back...
So you did spent the night here...
What happened last night?
Ask yourself.
Ask myself? Miss...
Please don't call me "Miss".
All right... then...
Mi...
Melody.
Did you sleep here last night?
Were you really drunk last night?
Or just pretending?
I think I was really drunk.
What about everything that happened?
You don't remember anything?
I don't remember a thing.
Maybe you're forgetting on purpose.
Me?
Oh, I see, you regret what happened.
You men are always playing around.
It doesn't mean a thing to you.
Melody, you...
Fatherless girls and widows
are easy to take advantage of.
What are you talking about?
Should I tell you everything?
Yes...
I told you everything last night.
Having been sold to General Han
to be an entertainer,
I'm like used goods,
not worthy of your love.
But last night you pledged
to spend your life with me.
I pledged to spend my life with you?
So I gave you my body,
not realising...
...everything you said was facetious.
How could this be a laughing matter?
Melody, listen to me...
Mr Ho.
Karma arranged for us to meet!
At least we had last night!
Goodbye!
Melody!
Don't worry, I won't cling to you.
Melody, listen to me.
What?
How could I be that kind of man?
What kind of man are you then?
Melody, if what you said was true,
I'd be afraid I don't deserve you.
You mean I was lying?
Of course not, I just never thought
I could win you over.
You already got what you wanted.
I...
These pills will ease your hangover.
Take one when you get a headache.
And this is the pledge of your love,
which I am now returning to you.
I'm not a heartless man.
But... I still don't get it.
Last night, right here,
you played the flute, I the drums,
and you whispered sweet nothings.
Was it the wine talking?
I'll marry you, no matter what.
I...
But there's something
I'm too embarrassed to mention.
Embarrassed?
I can't tell you what it is yet.
What's so embarrassing?
Yes, what's so embarrassing? Let's talk it over.
- Madame Wang.
- Mother.
Mr Tsui.
You rotten girl.
How can you get engaged
without letting me know?
Cavorting in broad daylight! Shameless!
- Mother!
- Ah... I...
Don't worry, she won't run away.
I will wait for you at the lotus pond.
But later...
All right.
It's been only two days,
and you're stuck together like honey.
- Sit down.
- No, I'm afraid she...
What are you afraid of?
If you're already hen-pecked now,
what will you do after getting married?
Sit, we have something to discuss.
- Please sit.
- All right.
- Last night, you proposed.
- I proposed what?
You said you and Melody were meant to meet.
It was love at first sight,
and you had to marry her.
Mr Tsui, did I say so?
Listen to Madame Wang.
Did you mention something embarrassing?
I... Oh, that...
You are my future son-in-law.
Your business is my business.
Tell me.
I...
Mr Tsui, it's hard to say.
Just say it.
All right, Mr Tsui, to tell the truth,
I'm just a free-spirited wanderer,
and I've never been more
impecunious than I am now.
"Impecunious"?
Mr Ho means he is not a rich man.
Well, I wasn't expecting you to be rich.
What's embarrassing about that?
- The bridal gift? The wedding expenses?
- No need. It's her second marriage.
You have no friends or relations here.
We don't need a wedding.
All that matters is that you're in love.
Then what about the future?
To tell the truth,
she has some savings.
You won't have
anything to worry about.
Mr Tsui, is it really all right?
It's for the rest of your life.
You have to make up your own mind.
That goes without saying! He's already decided.
In that case you can be the matchmaker.
Right! The 5th is an auspicious day.
Madame Wang,
- 5th of next month it is!
- No, Madame Wang...
Come, I will take you to the lotus pond.
I have to discuss this with her...
Take your time.
Go and talk to her yourself.
- Mr Tsui, I'll talk to you later.
- All right.
What do you need
to talk to him about?
- We have to talk things over.
- No need for that.
Hurry.
Hurry up.
Get a move on.
Come.
Go.
Go!
Last night I was drunk and said things I...
Here are some medicinal fungi.
Two sets should be enough.
Give it to me.
Son-in-law.
Son-in-law, are you any better?
Mother.
I'm much better, but still a bit weak.
No problem, I've brought a tonic.
This one is really great.
What did you bring, Mother?
Turtle stew.
- It's restorative, if you drink it hot.
- Turtle stew?
Madame.
How many red dates
should I cook with the chicken?
Wait for me, I'm coming.
Oh, that maid of mine!
Come, drink it hot.
I'll fetch a ladle.
All right, I know.
Mother, what are you doing?
I am... taking the sutra to you.
To me?
As if I can't get it myself!
Leave it.
You are up to your old tricks.
I was going to get a monk to read it.
And then we could...
Stop dreaming!
That's not what I meant.
Melody, I'm afraid Tsui
will strike first.
Not to mention...
Listen to me!
The sutra is useless by itself.
The sutra has to be copied,
and you need his amber beads,
and it has to be read 180 times.
So when will he finish copying it?
Don't you worry about that.
Don't move.
You rotten girl!
No more tricks.
- Melody...
- Mother!
- There's something I need you to do.
- What?
Keep your eye on that Lama.
All right.
Master, I can't discuss that sutra with you.
Reverend.
I can't do anything about Melody.
Reverend...
Reverend!
Well played.
All right, I lost.
Fine.
Master, don't bring trouble on yourself.
Yes, Reverend. You're right.
- Sit down.
- Yes.
I've still got two pages to do.
Tired?
I'm all right.
I'll make you ginseng stew.
Thanks.
Melody.
Melody!
You won't believe it.
Just now I saw that Lama
studying drumming with your master.
Did they see you?
They caught me.
And the Lama told me to tell you
you are not to touch that sutra
or he will tell Mr Ho that you are...
He's here. What do we do?
It's all right, come with me.
Don't be afraid.
You and Qling go intercept the Lama.
Whatever you do, don't let him in.
- Do you know how to use these?
- I do.
Then go.
I...
Oh! You were playing your drum.
Listen.
Not bad at all!
In the rear garden, I think.
Oh, at the lotus pond.
The ginseng still needs to stew.
Let's go and join the drummer.
All right.
Miss.
Miss, come here.
You go first.
All right.
What are you doing?
What a pain you are.
Put the spells up on the door.
Hurry up!
What's wrong?
Mr Tsui came this morning.
He wanted to take you to the market.
Really?
Om mani padme hum...
Om mani padme hum.
Don't mind me.
What's that sound?
Xixia soldiers are testing the cannons.
Oh...
How is my playing?
Wonderful.
Look!
Wow!
Let's go.
They must have fired another shot.
Madame, Madame! They're coming.
They're all here.
They? My son-in-law too?
Yes.
Don't forget to tell Melody about this.
Oh.
I'm coming.
Mr Ho, Mr Tsui.
Please.
Now you're my guest, you first.
Qing.
Where is the Madame?
The Madame... has taken ill.
- Madame Wang.
- Mother.
You're all here.
What's wrong with you?
I had another asthma attack.
- What's wrong?
- My eyelid's been twitching.
So I knew that you all would come.
- All your rules!
- Sit.
Shall we call the doctor?
- No!
- No need...
My mother has a ready made remedy.
Yes, it's ready made.
There's a late market today.
Yunqing and Uncle Tsui want
to buy copying supplies.
I thought I'd drop in
to see how you're doing.
I didn't know you'd be sick.
We don't have to rush to the market.
Let's stay here with Mother.
I am all right.
My things...
In that case
I'll stay with my mother.
You two go and buy supplies.
Mr Tsui, what do you say?
I'm all right either way.
But if we go the earlier the better.
No, those things can wait.
I can buy them any time.
You almost finished copying.
You go home first.
I'll get Old Chang
to take me back in the morning.
- No.
- You go, first things first.
Yunqing, let's go,
or we won't make it in time.
Come with me.
Mr Tsui...
Is it really all right?
What?
Go with him.
- All right, I'll pick you up tomorrow.
- No need.
- Mother, see you in a few days.
- All right.
- After you.
- No, after you.
- Actually...
- Let's go or we'll be late.
All right.
Qing, open the door.
I have to tell you...
What's wrong?
In that box of his prayer beads...
Why did you touch his prayer beads?
Didn't you say they were precious?
I didn't tell you to take them!
- Did Ho Yunqing know?
- No.
What's up with the Lama?
He's trouble.
Oh no!
Yunqing, what's on your mind?
The house where they live
is strange.
Let's go.
Cloud!
Who is that?
The lady proprietor's daughter.
There's a tavern here?
The customers are all regulars.
They didn't used to run this tavern.
The girl's father
was a frontier magistrate.
He was martyred in the war.
His widow and daughter
opened this tavern.
Hello Uncle Tsui.
Cloud, how are you?
Fine, now that you're here.
Is your mother home?
Yes, she misses you.
Why haven't you come?
I've been busy lately.
This is my friend, Mr Ho.
Hello, Mr Ho.
And she is Miss Chuang.
Hello, Miss Chuang.
Let's go.
You didn't come to see us?
We're going to the market.
I'll tell my mother
you didn't stop.
We're off, see you
on the way back.
Let's go.
The market? Uncle Tsui...
What?
I just came from the market.
It's already winding down.
Ah, we were too slow.
Yes.
There's still a long way to go!
We won't make it.
Didn't I tell you?
I can buy those things any time.
Let's go back.
Fine.
Uncle Tsui, you're not coming in?
Yunqing, care for a couple of drinks?
All right.
How is business?
What business?
You only sell vegetarian food?
We can get meat dishes if you want.
No, I prefer to eat light.
Why did you close the gate?
Now that you're here,
we're temporarily closed.
What for?
I'll warm up the wine.
Please.
Mother, look who's here.
Who's here?
This is Mr Ho.
Hello, Mr Ho.
This is Mrs Chuang.
Hello, Mrs Chuang.
Please.
- Please.
- Mr Tsui, please.
Yunqing, please.
Please.
Mr Tsui, please take your seat.
- No, after you.
- You are my elder.
This place is
just like home to me.
Make yourself at home.
Come, sit.
You sit, too.
What do you think of this place?
It's elegant.
We came a long way and
ended up having a drink here.
If my mother-in-law knew
she would be livid.
I can't stand your mother-in-law.
She is a bit talkative.
Mrs Chuang would be
a great mother-in-law,
so quiet and pleasant.
Don't make such a crass joke.
I'll take a drink as a punishment.
The wine here is better by the bowl.
Here's the bowl.
Oh, thank you.
Mr Ho, will you drink from a bowl?
No, I can't.
Thank you.
What about that Taoist on the hill?
Has he moved back?
The Taoist?
The one that knows some magic.
Have you forgotten?
He used to do seances.
But then he harassed some woman
and people here drove him out.
Now he lives up on the hill.
Mother, can you go
and have a look?
Oh, I remember,
I'll go and have a look.
Cloud, attend Mr Ho for me.
Please go ahead.
What's wrong?
Nothing, just a pesky Taoist priest.
Come, drain your glass.
Miss Chuang,
have you been to North Fort lately?
Not for over half a year.
Have a drink.
All right.
He's left.
Where was I?
- Illusions.
- Yes, illusions.
Mr Tsui, do you believe in
the arts of invisibility and illusion?
I don't understand black magic.
No, I really...
Come, some wine.
I can't drink.
Come, pour the wine.
You have had a lot to drink.
If you won't serve me, I'll help myself.
I didn't mean that.
Mr Tsui, Mr Tsui.
Mr Tsui, you're in a good mood today.
You know who knows black magic?
Your wife.
My Wife?
Mr Tsui is drunk.
Oh, that's quite enough.
Mr Tsui, don't drink any more.
There you go again.
Eat something first.
Don't mind me.
Eat something? I can get it myself!
Mother...
- You bully me like all the rest.
- Nobody bullies you.
Who bullies you, Mr Tsui?
Go to hell!
Your wife bullies me.
What are you talking about?
- Are you all right?
- I'm OK.
Your wife, she is a devil!
You've said quite enough.
She'll get you, sooner or later.
All right, go inside and rest.
He doesn't know what's going on.
You have to tell him...
What is this all about?
My wife's been nice to him.
- It's all right.
- He's drunk, don't be angry.
Strange.
Why did he suddenly mention my wife?
Drunk people talk nonsense. Sit.
No, in vino veritas.
There's some truth in what he said.
I want to ask him.
Wait till he wakes up.
- Cloud?
- What?
Go for a climb to pick herbs for
Mr Tsui's hangover...
- Listen to me, you tell him...
- All right...
Why don't you take
Mr Ho for a walk?
The view there is lovely.
I will take you up.
Strange, when I got married,
he was the matchmaker.
- How could he...
- There's no telling why right now.
- Let me help you up.
- I can get up myself.
You two hurry up and go.
- Let me tell you...
- Let's go!
I don't know what's
gotten into him.
Mr Tsui has a bad temper.
The wine must have upset him.
He seems to have
something on his mind.
People here all do.
Is there something on your mind too?
Quite a bit, actually.
Can you tell me about it?
No, I can't.
Mr Ho, is there something on your mind?
Yes, there is.
Would you like to hear about it?
All right.
I think I've seen you somewhere before.
Really?
I've seen you before.
Maybe...
Sometimes I meet a stranger,
and feel like
I have seen them before.
But in fact I never have.
Yes.
Sometimes I go somewhere new
and meet someone,
and feel that the scene
has happened to me before.
This must be Buddhist karma.
Karma?
Right, karma brought us together, no?
No...
I really have seen you before.
It was when I first got here.
I saw you many times.
I even waved to you.
And then you were gone.
You were probably seeing things.
I thought you were a fairy.
I never expected you would be real.
Real, but like a dream.
What could be better?
Miss Chuang,
can you make yourself invisible?
Don't be silly.
Look!
That's the hangover herb.
I can't get at it.
Let me help you up.
Would that be proper?
It's OK.
You shouldn't...
Hurry up and pick it.
I'll come down myself.
Are you all right?
I'm scared.
Don't be afraid.
Hello, Mother.
Mother.
You're back.
Where's Mr Ho?
Ah...
Sorry, sorry.
Mr Tsui just fell asleep.
Please ask Mr Ho to wait.
Take this medicinal fungus to
the Taoist on the hill.
I've already let him know.
He'll stew medicine for us in a bit.
I'm afraid to see him.
Then leave it in the doorway for him.
Cloud?
What?
Your skirt is dirty.
I have to go out again. Mr Ho,
do you want to go for a walk?
All right.
I'll go and get changed.
OK.
Mr Ho, what are you looking for?
Nothing. I just saw a Taoist priest.
There are a lot of Taoists around.
Let's go.
Mr Ho, what's on your mind?
I came here for peace and quiet,
not expecting all these eerie things.
All you have to fear is fear itself.
Look, that's our home.
What place is that?
It's going to rain. Let's take shelter inside.
No.
It is scary in there.
It's all right, I know a mudra.
As if demons would bother me!
You wait here, I'll have a look.
Cloud Chuang, come here.
The mushroom you brought
is very helpful.
Thank you.
But as for Melody,
I cannot help you.
She has acquired powerful magic.
I can no longer subdue her.
Hurry up and leave Mr Ho.
If you don't,
you might never find release.
Lama, I...
Cloud, it's nice inside.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Come in.
What's wrong with you?
I'm afraid.
Yunqing?
Yunqing.
- Good morning, Mr Tsui.
- Uncle Tsui, you've sobered up?
You hurry back.
If Melody gets mad,
you'll be in trouble.
Mr Ho...
You two can talk tomorrow.
I won't see you in.
- Goodbye.
- You're back.
- Yes.
What are you doing?
It's windy outside,
you can copy the sutra here.
I'll take a nap before I start again.
Where were you last night?
I was drinking with Mr Tsui
at a friend's house.
At the Chuang house?
Yes.
Did you meet Cloud?
That woman has always
been against me.
How has she been against you?
By seducing you!
What are you talking about?
Don't be so small-minded.
Don't move!
Oh, so I am small-minded,
and that wretch is big-hearted?
Well, then.
I'll show you how small-minded I can be!
Kneel!
What a thing to say!
My legs!
Melody, what's wrong with my legs?
Hurry up and finish copying the sutra.
When I return, your legs will return to normal.
Melody!
Melody, where are you going?
To settle the score
with that woman.
Melody, wait!
Melody!
Melody, Melody...
Mister Ho!
Mister! Mister!
- Mister!
- Cloud, my legs...
I know, don't worry. I'm coming.
- Cloud, my legs!
- Give me your hands.
- What are you doing?
- Close your eyes, don't speak.
- My legs...
- Sh!
Close your eyes.
Rise.
What dark art did Melody use to...?
- Your life is in danger.
- My life?
You've got to get away.
Get away?
When did you learn to do magic?
After you finish copying the sutra,
Melody will kill you.
Why?
Because she is a demon.
Let's hurry.
Mr Tsui might be able to help.
Mother!
- Mr Tsui!
- Yunqing, your life is in danger.
Find that Lama
at the East Gate Temple.
- Mother.
- Cloud, take him.
Cloud!
What about my mother?
Don't worry, I'm here.
Hurry or it'll be too late.
No...
What's wrong?
- What's that?
- Don't move.
Qing!
Let's split up. You go that way...
Don't look back, whatever you do.
Mr Ho! Come home with me.
- Run!
- What about you?
Hurry.
Don't move!
Use the mudra!
Cloud...
Cloud!
Cloud, what's wrong?
Don't worry about me,
just get out of here.
Go!
What are you doing?
Old Chang, what are you doing?
Mister, stop using your mudra!
Old Chang, we're not your enemy.
Why are you doing this?
Old Chang?
Why are you abetting her?
Hasn't she hurt you enough?
Let's find that Lama
and get him to release you.
Run!
EAST GATE TEMPLE
Hurry over!
Yunqing, come with me.
Come!
Let go!
Demon, if you keep haunting Mr Ho,
you'll be doomed to Hell forever.
Lama, Buddhists believe in compassion.
Why are you breaking up our marriage?
What marriage?
You only married him for the sutra.
Go!
How dare you. Qing!
Melody, look!
See the evil you have wrought?
Melody, it's not too late to repent.
Stop bothering Mr Ho!
If you repent,
you might attain release.
If you don't,
I'll turn you over to the ghost warden,
and let him deal with you.
- All right.
- Go now!
Magic gourd!
Look!
General Han.
General, there's a new entertainer.
Want to give her a chance?
If you make a decision now...
General, this decision has to be made.
Good.
Halt.
I've come to see the General.
That's right.
CLOUD CHUANG'S TOMB
She's confessed everything, General.
Choke her to death!
Wait!
General Han.
If this gets out,
it wouldn't be good
for your reputation.
Then exile her.
Master!
Master, save me.
Your life on earth is over,
I can't save you.
But I won't be at rest.
What unfinished business do you have?
I want to become a powerful demon
to settle a score with someone.
All right.
Rise.
Om mani padme hum.
Look!
Om mani padme hum. Look!
Master.
Tiger!
Tiger? Where?
In the gazebo.
Master, it was just a cat...
I know, I was seeing things.
Master...
Let me rest.
Yes, she's a ghost too.
You should have known.
They were both after the sutra.
Lama, I was once in it for the sutra,
but now...
I know.
But you must not bother Yunqing again.
But Lama, I...
I understand.
You're not going to hurt him.
But an affair between a man
and a ghost will never work out.
Go.
Damn monk! Let's fight it out.
Stop right there!
Master.
Reverend.
Go back with me.
Master, save me!
All right, I'll save you.
But you have to go with me.
What about Ho Yunqing?
It's over.
And the Great Mudra Sutra?
You can't ever mention it again.
Then hasn't it all been a waste?
Come with me!
Master, don't you want that sutra?
Come!
Ho Yunqing, hurry back
and bring the sutra here.
I'll find you a place to finish copying.
Watch out!
Ho Yunqing, hurry back
for your prayer beads.
Lama...
Old Chang...
What?
Old Chang!
Danger?
Quiet! Wardens, bring Ho Yunqing here.
All right.
Innkeeper!
Innkeeper, a pot of huadiao wine.
And a bowl of hot noodle soup.
Are they asleep?
Innkeeper!
Innkeeper, wake up!
Wake up!
A pot of huadiao, a bowl of hot noodles.
The wine should be on the hot side.
We don't have anything hot here.
All right.
Then at least let the soup be hot.
Everything here is cold.
Innkeeper, this won't do.
How can I eat cold soup noodles?
Mister!
Hurry up and copy the sutra.
Cloud?
Cloud!
Mister, stay there.
Cloud, are you all right?
Mister, don't come in. I'll be OK soon.
Old Chang.
What are you doing?
Old Chang!
- Ah!
Mr Tsui.
Yunqing, the Lama told me to tell you
to finish copying as soon as possible.
- Now?
- Immediately.
What about Old Chang?
How can I copy with him here?
Old Chang, please leave.
I know, just leave.
Yunqing, hurry.
Mr Tsui,
what's the rush?
There's no time to waste.
Mr Tsui, you...
No, you sit, sit down.
Melody has been locked in Hell.
With her power, it's only a matter of time
before she escapes.
But what's the point of copying now?
The Lama said, once you finish copying,
you can use the mudra at will.
Though you might not overcome Melody,
you can at least protect yourself.
I can't focus if I copy it here.
Look, there he goes again.
Old Chang!
Yunqing, don't be afraid.
He's basically kind, he won't harm you.
But he's tried to choke me to death.
Not of his own volition.
He's under Melody's control.
Why does he listen to Melody?
Old Chang!
Three years ago, he came under her spell
and ended up like this.
Why did Melody do such a thing to him?
If I tell you Old Chang's story,
maybe you can focus your mind.
He was a loyal officer to General Han.
After the rout, he took
a few men to guard the pass.
Who's there?
Who is it?
Who are you?
Get up, will you?
Get up!
What are you doing?
You bitch!
From that time he became...
a half-man, half-ghost.
The Lama told me
Melody wanted to turn you
into another Old Chang.
Cloud and I were so worried!
I rushed here with your implements.
Then Old Chang...
I brought him here to help.
- Mr Tsui?
- No problem, don't move.
Mr Tsui...
Fear not...
Don't be scared.
Melody has escaped.
Hurry and finish copying.
My mind is a mess!
You have to copy no matter what.
Cloud...
Mr Ho, if not for yourself,
do it for the fallen soldiers.
You should do it for them.
- I'm dizzy.
- Mister!
- You can even copy it for me.
- I...
You heard the Lama:
it'll be the end of me if I see you again...
But I... I've come to see you anyway.
All right... I know...
The Lama has intercepted Melody.
Just relax and copy the sutra.
Cloud, get some mushrooms
and herbs for Yunqing.
Let's go.
- I'm not hungry.
- I'll be back in a minute.
What's wrong?
Nothing, the Lama must have subdued her.
Nothing's the matter? All right.
Are you almost done?
I'm finally done.
Yunqing, you've done
a meritorious deed.
It's worth celebrating!
Heaven will bestow you with long life,
prosperity, and progeny.
I don't care about such things.
If I'm warm and well-fed,
I'll be satisfied.
I know what I want to do.
What?
Leave this nest of ghosts
and sleep for three days.
Yunqing,
you should eat something
before you go to sleep.
I'm really not hungry.
Mister.
I couldn't find any herbs,
but I did find a few mushrooms.
You're back.
Have you finished copying?
The great deed is finally done.
Eat it while it's fresh.
I don't like to eat mushrooms.
- Let's sit down and talk it over.
- Sit.
You haven't slept in days.
You must be drained.
Eat some to replenish your energy.
Do I eat it like this?
Yes, eat it while it's fresh.
You have to eat something.
Mister!
- Don't eat it!
- That's Melody in disguise!
Old Chang, go and restrain her.
Mister!
Mister, don't eat it, it's poison.
- Get the beads!
- Take the sutra and run!
Get lost!
Come here.
Mr Tsui, why did you...?
Mister, come with me.
Come back.
Don't go over.
Old Chang, let her go!
Go get her.
She's Melody, don't move.
Old Chang, go get her!
Hurry!
Old Chang, what are you doing?
Uncle Tsui! Mr Ho!
Save me!
Mr Tsui, which one is the real Cloud?
Oh no! She's dead!
Old Chang, let go!
Mister.
Get the beads and run.
Tsui, which is the real...
That's odd. Neither of them
should be afraid of Old Chang.
Uncle Tsui,
Melody's poisoned me.
Save yourselves!
- Get the beads.
- Ah?
Hurry!
What are you doing?
Let go!
Mr Tsui!
Toss the beads at her.
Go.
Old Chang, don't toss the beads!
Toss the beads at her!
Don't toss the beads.
Old Chang...
Yunqing, get the beads!
Aim at her!
Mr Tsui!
"Adviser Tsui's... Spirit Tablet..."
Lama!
Old Chang!
Old Chang...
The sutra!
Ho Yunqing...
You haven't left yet?
I've already been.
You've already been?
I...
I'm going now.
Ah...
THE END