Four, as usual?
Yeah, four.
Four it is.
Thanks. There you go.
Nothing else?
I got K, speed, coke, MDMA...
No, I'm good. I'll stick with this.
- You're bleeding.
- What?
You're bleeding.
Fuck!
What's in this?
I dunno, I don't cook it up.
- I won't be here next week.
- What?
I'm not here next week.
Tell everyone.
I'm going on vacation, anyway.
Where you going?
I dunno. My dad's surprising me.
Yeah? I don't like surprises.
See you, then.
- Can I finish this off?
- Yeah, it's on me.
Great.
I'm outta here.
- You know the way.
- Yeah, of course.
- See you.
- Yeah.
Hello.
- Have you scored?
- Not on the phone, Ana!
Don't be so paranoid!
Do we take something to the party?
No, I dunno.
A bottle of something.
But I think we're good.
You gonna keep me
hanging around again?
No, I'll be there in five.
- Okay, I'm waiting for you.
- Yeah, kiss-kiss!
Shit!
Fuck!
Fucking shit!
The fucking car!
Shit!
I don't believe this!
Fuck!
What's that?
Calm down! What are you doing?
What?
Calm down, calm down.
Can I help you? Do you need help?
Emergency services?
I'll call them.
What can I do for you?
- Yes, hello...
- Speak slowly and clearly.
I've found a woman by the roadside...
- Is she hurt? Is she breathing?
- She's in a bad way.
Wait there.
We'll send an ambulance and the police.
- What?
- We'll send the police.
- Where are you?
- No, no, no.
Okay, okay.
I'll drop you off.
What?
Ma'am...
Ma'am... what's going on?
Ma'am, are you okay?
I'll drop you off.
Okay? It's not far.
Just up here, okay?
Less than ten minutes.
We're almost there.
We're really close.
It'll be all right, okay?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Do you speak French?
Did someone hurt you?
Where have you come from?
What happened?
Are you hurt?
What?
Stop it! Sit back down, please!
What are you doing?
It's dangerous, sit down!
Overtake!
Overtake, asshole!
Ma'am, please sit back down.
Ma'am.
Stop it!
Calm down and sit down.
Sit down!
Be careful!
Calm down, please.
Sit down!
Subject C39,
female, aged between 20 and 25.
What?
Nationality unknown.
Blond hair, blue eyes,
height 1.77 meters...
I don't understand.
I'm taking you to the hospital, okay?
The hospital is just...
just a bit farther.
Extraction of teeth and excision
of tongue and salivary glands
as a safety measure.
I don't understand.
Contamination achieved after injections
with retrovirus-infected blood.
I'm taking you to the hospital.
They'll help you there.
Yes, they'll fix you up!
What?
Stop it for fuck's sake! Stop it!
Let go, let go!
Stop it, stop it!
Calm the fuck down!
What are you doing?
What the hell? Stop it!
Stop it, stop it!
Fuck!
You are through to the Gendarmerie...
What the hell are you gonna say?
Hold the line.
You're fucking stoned!
Calm down.
You are in communication
with the Gendarmerie Nationale.
Hold the line, we will take your call.
Gendarmerie emergency line. Hello.
Fuck!
What the hell is this shit?
Wake up!
Fuck!
The fucking car!
What am I gonna tell him?
Oh, no! Not him!
Not him, not him...
Romain!
I came to see you earlier,
you weren't there.
- You coming later?
- No, not tonight, Philippe.
Not tonight. I can't.
I'll come round tomorrow.
Yeah, if you like.
Wake up!
Yeah, Dad?
I've called three times.
What's wrong, is it the Mustang ?
No, it's fine.
- Are you at home?
- Yeah.
Go in the kitchen,
find my flight reservation number.
It starts PI... something like that.
When do you get back?
My flight gets in at 9,
so I can be there for midday.
I'll get changed,
then we can go for lunch.
To the restaurant
we went to last time, yeah?
Yeah, great.
Are you okay?
You sound odd.
I'm getting dressed.
- Where did you say?
- I just told you, in the kitchen.
Whereabouts?
With all the Post-its.
Are you doing this on purpose?
Have you been drinking?
Did you go out last night?
No way.
Okay, I get it.
We'll talk about it later.
KP, then lots of figures?
Can you send it to me?
I'll send you the photo.
- There, got it?
- Yes.
- Bye.
- Happy birthday, son.
Okay? Why haven't you been answering?
- How did you get in?
- I dunno, it was open.
I'm pissed.
I lost the 100 euros my dad gave me
for the summer break.
All that cash he gave me,
I got nothing.
I don't know what I can do.
I can't pay. Can you spot me?
You don't mind?
- We'll do a line in your bedroom.
- What?
We'll do a line in your bedroom.
Yeah... No!
Wait here, I'll go get it.
- Why?
- No, stay here.
Stay here! I'll be right back.
Idiot!
Yeah, Ryan, a quick voice note
to tell you not to pick us up.
If that's okay.
I dunno, I think we'll walk.
Baby, if you get this,
call me back or text me.
We're going to walk, it's real close,
so don't come.
We have stuff to do.
Well, I want to talk to him. Okay?
See you later.
Ana.
- Ana, come here.
- No, you come here.
No, come here.
I want to talk to you.
I don't have time, come here.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
What are you doing?
I told you not to smoke in here.
What's happened?
Why are you being all weird?
It's nothing. There.
It's all wet.
Did you have a shower with it?
I'm staying here.
- No, don't.
- Yes.
- Don't you want to anymore?
- What?
- Is that why you ignored my calls?
- No.
Tell me. Come on!
Fucking leave me alone!
What the hell is that?
Fuck, I told them not to come!
Turn that off!
Turn that light off!
And stop sounding your horn!
Stop it, turn it off.
Turn that light off.
Stop sounding the horn!
- What's going on?
- Stop it!
Your neighbor's a pain.
Come with us, there'll be lots of pussy!
Don't give me your lip!
Don't talk like that.
Stop it. Turn it off, turn it off!
Romain, shall I call your dad?
It's okay, chill!
Stop that.
Guys, guys...
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Be quiet! I'm gonna call the cops!
Sir, why not come with us?
There's drink...
Turn it off, I'm coming.
He's always doing it!
No intrusion detected.
The house alarm is now activated.
- His other woman?
- It was his other woman.
Basically, it was another woman,
but it's like it was you.
They're just being pricks.
They need to chill out.
But actually,
she wasn't his other woman.
Who was she, then?
- Nah, she was his mom.
- She's a bitch.
His mom is mine!
Are you serious?
You're an embarrassment.
Take your shit and pay me.
I'm sick of it.
Probably next week.
Give me one. I gave you three.
Good shit.
Romain, you're acting weird.
Are you serious?
Is it because of last time?
Is it me?
What's wrong?
Yeah, we share everything.
No one among us gets jealous.
Yeah, we share.
No, sorry, not me.
Can you say something?
You're acting weird, what is it?
Romain!
Don't I turn you on anymore?
Tell me I'm the most beautiful girl
you've ever seen.
Subject C39...
Contamination achieved...
Same as usual, okay? We're buddies.
Whose house is this?
Whose house is it?
Where the hell are we?
Come on. Come with me.
Romain, they all wanna blow you!
He's being so weird. What is it?
- Everyone wants to blow him.
- Shut up! No one wants to blow him!
Come in the bathroom.
Hi, Romain!
Okay, bro? Happy birthday!
Happy birthday!
Hi, Romain, you okay?
Romain, where are you going?
Hey, Romain, how's it going?
- You wanna toke?
- Come for a swim.
Hey, Romain, come over here.
I got something to show you. Magic!
It'll blow your mind.
Look, look, look!
One!
Two!
Three!
Hey, hot guy, wanna line?
- No, thanks.
- A birthday shot?
I'll be right back.
- You're acting all weird.
- No, it's just that...
Stop it!
Are you sure you're okay?
- I'm good.
- You're sure?
- We'll be in the kitchen.
- I'm coming.
Fucking leave me alone!
What the fuck...?
It's always the same.
Like I might suffocate if I fall asleep.
I really gotta pee.
Pee, then.
- Here.
- What's that?
Chop it on your phone.
Hey, girls, what you doing?
- It's occupied.
- Get out!
They're like kids.
I'll watch the door.
- So?
- I couldn't turn the light off.
I'd never freaked out that bad
in my life before.
We gotta calm down a bit this year.
Says she, chopping up some lines!
Shit, this is all wet.
- Never mind, it's okay.
- We don't care.
That's okay.
- I don't know what it is.
- Okay, after you.
Wait...
This is lit!
I'm not flushing.
What's this? Why have you got a...
Juju?
Juju, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Just kidding.
Get outta here!
- Sorry.
- That's not funny.
- What's this?
- I'm sorry.
Why you got a pregnancy test?
That's gross.
- Why you got a pregnancy test?
- 'Cos I'm late.
But you don't fuck.
I have fucked!
You haven't fucked anyone for a year.
Why you got a pregnancy test?
Or you've not been truthful
with your BFF.
I fucked Romain.
Cool!
Shit, they're such kids!
Cut it out!
You asshole!
Wait! She's downstairs.
What?
Your eyes.
What about them?
What's wrong with my eyes?
Yeah, Dad.
Where are you?
The alarm just went off.
You have to enter the code.
Yes, I'm on my way now.
Aren't you at home?
I'm on my way.
I'll be there in two seconds.
I'm going now.
What's moving? I can see something
on the camera on my phone.
There's someone in the house!
Sonofabitch!
Let me go!
Get off me!
You okay, Julia?
Alphasecure, good evening.
Did you request
an emergency intervention?
No... that's why I'm calling you.
It's why I'm calling you!
Enter your four-figure code
to deactivate the alarm.
1324. 1324!
You must enter the code yourself.
I cannot deactivate it remotely.
Are you by the panel?
No, I'm not there.
Sir?
Unless the system is deactivated
I have to request police intervention.
No, don't call the fucking cops!
Sir, please be polite.
This call may be recorded.
Please enter your four-figure code.
I'm doing it, I'm doing it now.
I'll put you on hold
while you carry that out.
Alphasecure, the best remote surveillance
since 1995.
With Alphasecure,
leave home feeling secure.
With our "intrusion alert" package,
your home is protected 24/7...
You haven't entered your code.
Can you repeat the operation?
Sir, are you by the panel?
Yes, of course,
but don't call the police.
I'll put you on hold
while you complete the operation.
Hello?
You haven't entered the code correctly.
Please make a third attempt.
I'm there, I tell you!
- Are you by the panel?
- Yes.
Well, almost.
Sir...
I'm there, I tell you!
Sir, are you by the panel?
What?
Are you at this moment by the panel?
I'm there!
Good. Please complete the operation.
House alarm deactivated.
Okay? Okay?
Your alarm has been deactivated.
Alphasecure wishes you
an excellent evening.
You can call us 24/7
for the slightest problem.
Good evening.
Mistaken intrusion alert deleted.
Are you there, Romain?
Yeah.
What have they stolen?
Nothing, everything's here.
Romain.
What?
- Romain.
- Yes.
Body temperature stable
and incredibly low at 33.5°.
Pulse well below average at 38.
Pupils extremely dilated.
I shall proceed with eye tests.
I have observed in the subject
spectacular strength
when exposed to light.
The emission of photons seems
to provoke a physiological response,
stimulating increased adrenaline production.
This response could be attributed
to neuroendocrine modulation.
Fucking stop that!
Come on!
Come on, then!
Fuck! You sonofabitch!
Seriously?
Romain.
Why did you do that?
You bust his jaw, okay?
You could go to prison for this,
you left him for dead.
Where are you?
I went to your place,
there's no one there, there's no answer.
Please...
Calm down!
I'm calm.
You know you can talk to me.
Where are you?
I just told you!
I went to your house, Romain.
Where are you?
Romain,
why are you talking like that?
Where?
Romain, why did you do that?
Why did you sleep with her?
She's fucking pregnant!
She's pregnant!
Hello.
How are you?
Sorry, I got the address totally wrong.
We'll be there in seven minutes.
No problem.
Take some candy if you want.
Do you have water?
Water? Yes, of course.
- There.
- Thanks.
If there's anything you need,
just say.
I'm a bit cold.
Can you turn down the A/C, please?
I'll turn it off if you like.
Thanks.
Shut up!
What do you want?
Ana, where are you?
I don't want
to talk to you right now, Julia.
- I'm sorry.
- Listen to me.
It's not you, we'll talk tomorrow.
I'm freaking out,
I don't know what's going on.
I feel bad. I'm seeing scary stuff,
scary people, everywhere.
Why should I care?
What is this shit?
What was it we took?
It wasn't me. It was Romain.
I'm having a really bad trip.
I gotta see you.
Where are you? I gotta see you, Ana.
I can't breathe.
Look! I'm in a bad way too, okay?
I'm in a bad way too, so shut up!
Shut your mouth, you fucking whore!
Are you okay?
- Someone's following us.
- What does he want?
- I don't like it.
- He's been there for a while.
Just a minute, sorry.
- Don't get out!
- He's busting my balls!
What's your problem? Why...
What the...
I'm having a bad trip!
Chill, chill!
There's no one behind!
Critical loss of pressure
in rear left tire.
Stop the vehicle as soon as possible.
Hello.
Police?
Hold the line, we will take your call.
You are in communication
with the Gendarmerie Nationale.
Hold the line, we will take your call.
Pick up, please!
You are in communication
with the Gendarmerie Nationale.
Police?
I don't wanna go home
I don't wanna go home all alone
Call the police.
Call the police!
And lock that door. They're coming!
Give me the keys to your fucking bar.
Give me the keys!
I'm begging you! They're coming!
The keys.
The bathroom?
Why?
My poor body!
Romain, Julia, Romain...
I'm not crazy.
Yes, I'm crazy.
I'm dead.
Mom...
Mom!
- Can you hear me?
- Julia...
I got my scooter.
These guys are everywhere.
No, listen to me...
No! You listen to me!
Ana, what was that?
What the fuck was that noise?
Ana, answer me!
- Julia!
- Ana!
- Meet me by the station bridge!
- What did you say?
By the station bridge!
Okay, I'll head to the center.
I'll be there in five minutes.
Ana, do you hear me?
Stop it, no way!
I don't wanna go home
I don't wanna go home all alone...
Excuse me, can I take your bike?
What are you doing?
Leave that, it's not yours!
Cut it out! Let go!
Fuck!
Shit!
Sorry.
Sorry!
You lunatic!
Forgive me!
It's not me, it's not me!
Sorry.
Why? Why?
It's not me, it's not me.
Sorry.
Julia!
Anaïs!
Ana, what's happened to you?
What the fuck's happened to you?
Anaïs!
I'll get you to the hospital, okay?
I'll get you to the hospital.
Do you hear me?
Get on.
Hold on tight,
I'll get you to the hospital.
Hold on.
Shit!
Anaïs, hold on!
You're gonna be okay. Shit!
What are you doing, Ana?
Shit, they've blocked all the roads!
Hold on.
What's wrong with you? It's all right.
It's okay.
How do I get through?
They've blocked all the roads!
Where do I go?
Stop it!
What are you doing?
Hold on tight!
Stop it, and hold on tight!
Hold on!
It's gonna be all right, okay?
Stop it!
What are you doing?
Ana, what are you doing?
Stop it!
What's wrong with you?
What's happened to you?
You're scaring me.
Stop it, please.
Look at me.
Stop, please.
Ana, why are you acting like that?
Why are you doing that?
Stop it!
Ana, I'll go get help, okay?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
- Mom.
- Something's happening in town.
- Mom, what's wrong?
- Alice has left me on my own.
Mom, calm down.
I'm close to home, I'll be right there.
My wheelchair's stuck.
Mom, I know!
Sorry. I know, okay?
I'll be right there. I'm close to home.
¡No me puedo mover!
Julia!
Help me!
Please!
Forgive me!
Forgive me, Julia !
I'm scared!
I'm gonna eat your fucking face!
Julia!
Wait for me!
Wait for me, Julia!
First floor.
Door closing.
Stay calm, a problem has arisen.
An operator will contact you.
What's going on?
Why have the lights gone out?
Is anybody there?
Victor, that you?
Can you hear me?
I'm stuck in the elevator!
Can someone see downstairs?
Hello!
Okay, I'm going down.
Is anybody there?
Stay calm, a problem has arisen.
An operator will contact you.
What are you doing here?
Do you know
where my friend Julia lives?
Get out or I'll call the cops!
You smell good. Can I smell you?
What?
No, I don't believe it!
It's a nightmare!
Stay calm, a problem has arisen.
An operator will contact you.
Is anybody there?
- Alice!
- Is someone in there?
Alice, can you hear me?
It's Julia, I'm stuck in the elevator.
Alice, have you seen Mom?
You can't stay,
you gotta go, do you hear me?
No, listen to me!
There's no one to help Mom!
Open this fucking door!
Sir?
Alice!
Sir, please help me.
They've killed everyone.
Please.
Please...
Stay calm, a problem has arisen.
An operator will contact you.
Is anyone in there?
I know you're there.
If you've been in contact
with an infected person,
turn yourself in immediately.
You're in danger.
We can help you, we can protect you.
Do you hear me?
Come out of the elevator.
15th floor.
Door opening.
Mom! Mom, I'm here!
You see me?
Here!
Come here!
Julia, Julia...
Open your mouth and you're dead.
Come here.
Turn that off, it attracts them.
Open your eyes wide.
Show me your eyes.
Don't make any noise.
Stay here.
Whatever you do, don't move.
Sir...
Keep your distance!
Keep your distance, I said!
Sir...
Tell me none of this is happening.
You have to leave.
Quick.
Listen to me.
Listen to me!
We have orders to kill all those
who've had direct contact.
Listen to me.
This life no longer exists.
How do you feel?
Is your head spinning?
Are you hearing voices?
Are you drawn to the light?
If you haven't ingested
any of their blood, you're okay.
Stay in the dark.
Use as little light as possible.
It makes them stronger.
What's your name?
I'm Julia.
Julia.
In a few minutes I'll no longer
be able to control myself.
Julia, get away from here.
Before I hurt you.
This is crazy shit!
Go.
I don't believe this.
Julia, turn around.
Turn around.
Wake up!
Subtitles by Howard Bonsor
Subtitling
TransPerfect Media France