Through books,
one comes to possess...
The road of life
The road to beautiful dreams
is a long one
The wind blows
and frost covers the road
Wind and frost dries out the plain face
In this mortal world
How many different directions
can beautiful dreams take
To find the love
one cannot stop dreaming of
The road follows the man frantically
Mortal life is
Beautiful dreams
and passionate aspirations
Vaguely in one's dreams
A dim glimmer of tears
Going from place to place
My shoes!
To find the direction
my heart wants to go
In the dream the wind seems to
sigh lightly once in a while
How come it's so torn?!
GUOBEI COUNTY
"Walk five miles to the south..."
But which direction is south?
Good heavens!
Just as the sun breaks through,
suddenly it pours with rain!
Can't you take pity
on lonely travellers in a hurry?
This has not been one of my better days.
At least I haven't run into thieves.
Don't run! Don't run, thief!
Don't run away!
Let's stand against him!
Sir, please forgive us
I'll return your money to you.
You dare steal my money!
You deserve to die!
The road in the mortal realm
Happy young man
The road is rocky
It's rocky and sunlight
does not penetrate
In the dust and mud
How many different directions
does happiness take
Fragments of the dreams
are like the wind and rain
The road follows
the man frantically
Fragments of the dreams
are like the wind and rain
The road follows the man frantically
Don't run! Let's see if
he's the wanted criminal!
-What? What?
-Is it him?
-Drag him over to that side!
-Lee's take a look!
Get out of the way!
Get out of the way
-Don't go
-Don't go!
Let's see if it's you
No! Let's go!
Thank you, sir.
Hey! Come here!
Not him!
Get out of our way!
Don't interfere
in my accumulation of wealth!
Hey, don't run!
It's not him! Move!
Don't run!
-Don't go! Don't go!
-Don't go? It's coming from over there!
-Don't go?
-Don't go!
Don't go! Don't go!
If they don't run,
then they are not wanted criminals!
-Did someone say "Don't run"?
-Criminal!
-Wow! Is it a festival?
-You!
You've money for the dead stuck to you!
Trying to take advantage of me?
Sir, you're got to be joking!
I don't spend this kind of money.
You'll be able to spend it
sooner or later.
Thank you.
Hello, sir.
Are you looking for a room?
-Ah Gan, help him with his luggage.
-Coming!
-We have a nice room...
-I'm here for what you owe Jaap Bou Jaai.
-It's all for nothing
-Hey! How rude!
-Why a different debt collector every time?
-The last one was murdered.
As you'll be murdered anyway, why don't
you do me a favour, and not collect it?
Please don't joke.
Sir, can I take a look at your bills,
please? New rules.
New rules? Let me see!
-You can't look at them!
-You can't
-The book of accounts...
The ink has run!
How will you collect the money?
If I can't collect the money, then
I won't have money to return. Please...
As there's no record in the accounts,
that means I don't owe any money.
You still hanging around?
If you don't leave, I'll have you arrested
Sir, where can I get
free shelter for one night?
-Free lodgings?
-Yes.
Go to the Lan Yeuk Temple!
Madam,
I'm not lying to you this time...
Where is Lan Yeuk Temple?
Lan Yeuk Temple?
Go east for three and a half miles.
When you see a creepy-looking
old temple, that will be it.
What's the matter?
-What's with him?
-Thank you.
-How brave..
Sorry. Excuse me.
-I wonder what's..-
-Madame, buy this.
He's going to die..
-Let him go..
-We shouldn't let him go...
That painting was painted beautifully!
Sir, you have a lot of taste.
Name a price.
I don't even have a container to boil water.
How can I buy a painting?
High class taste, low status. Go away.
Hey, what are you doing?
I also stock coffins. By the time
yours is made, your time will be up.
-Thank you.
-Hey I forgot to tell you.
The wolves in the forest
have been hungry for a long time.
Once it gets dark,
you won't be able to avoid them!
Move it
Hey, don't eat me! If you eat me,
then I'll be dead.
LAN YEUK TEMPLE
Is anyone there?
I gather your fight is over.
Brother Hah Hau, you've been fighting me
for seven years, and lost for seven years.
But I must say you have patience.
Wherever I go into hiding,
you're hard on my trail.
Yin Chik Ha, in only six months at Lan
Yeuk Temple, your rusty sword is sharper.
No. It's only because
you wasted your youth.
Your ambitions were too grand,
and you didn't try to improve yourself.
In the name of the superficial title of
world's best swordsman,
you show off your abilities too often,
and you harbour ill intentions.
Your moves are not clean,
and you're too hot-tempered.
You strike quickly but inaccurately.
Even if you were to win,
it would mean you were just lucky.
Yin Chik Ha, I came to fight you,
not listen to you preach. You, you...
you're right.
You are totally right.
Really, you should know better.
you're already a better fighter. By pointing
out his faults, you're making him lose face.
You too. The bearded man is already
avoiding you. Why are still following him?
Why not put down your swords,
and be nice to each other?
You have to know that the universe
is infinite, and true love lasts forever.
We must love each other,
and not slaughter each other,
because love is
the strongest weapon of all.
You've got even more to say than him!
Hey, I'm not following you.
-Part of it came off!
-So, go love it!
Scholar, if you're in need of love,
go to a bordello. Don't wait here.
-I just need a place to stay.
-Out of the question!
Why is it out of the question?
-Do you have a brave heart?
-Of course.
Look over there.
If you hear a shout,
you hide behind me.
If a tiger appears,
you'll probably want to hide in my trousers!
There are tigers around here?
There aren't any tigers here, but there's
something even scarier than tigers here.
Why speak so close to me?
Because I have bad breath, and I don't
want to listen to your nonsense.
Leave here immediately!
Otherwise,
no amount of love will save you!
-I understand. I'll leave.
-Me too!
Damn!
Brother Hah Hau,
you were so ambitious alive, yet in death,
you're still a smelly old husk.
So what was the paint of
being so competitive?
I won't stand by and let your corpse
be exposed to the elements.
Still tip to your old tricks! Even when
you're dead, you still want to fight me!
Prajna Pararnita!
Luckily the water was shallow, or else
I would have splashed water on myself!
The monsters and spirits
are causing trouble again!
Darn! The scholar didn't leave
I have no bad intentions towards you.
I'm just passing by.
If you're afraid, I'll throw it away!
What's the matter?
Oh! My stole!
I'll go get it for you!
The water is really deep!
Why don't you come out of the water,
before you drown?
Get out quickly!
Thank you.
As it's dark right now, it'll be difficult
to find it. I'll get it for you tomorrow.
I'm freezing.
How come your hand
is colder than mine?
Because you're warmer than me.
Miss, your complexion is pasty,
you must be ill.
You'd better go and see a doctor.
As long as you give me some warmth,
then I'll be fine.
I'm sorry I pushed you away,
but if I hadn't, I'd have spit all over you.
I'm in pain,...
I shouldn't have
pushed you away.
I'm really cold.
I'm completely soaked. If you lean on me,
you'll be even colder.
-Are you cold or in pain?
-It's really windy. Carry me instead.
You even want me to carry you?
you're really heavy.
I can't carry you on my own.
Why don't I get someone to help...?
you seem rather kind. It's a shame
you came to the wrong place,
or else you wouldn't have to die
such a wrongful death.
How come I'm still in the water?
Miss You forgot your qin!
Why are you following me?
Hey! What's the matter with you?
There's a bad person around!
If I don't run, I'll die!
A bad person? Who?
Why can't I see him?
Wait...
Die, die!
I'll squash you till you're dead!
I'll squash you till you're dead
Die! Why are you still here?
Oh! The snake!
What about the snake?
don't speak so loudly.
That bad person just passed us.
Which, bad person?
That bearded man who lives in Lan Yeuk
Temple. If he sees us, were dead.
Oh... you mean the bearded man
who lives next door to me.
I knew he wasn't a good person.
Its too dangerous for you to be alone.
Shall I accompany you back?
Don't! My family doesn't like it
when I consort with strangers.
-They're very strict!
-Miss
How about this?
Why don't I act as a decoy,
so when the bearded man
catches me, you're off the hook.
Let's just go with this plan...
Don't let him see you!
Miss,
allow me to return your qin to you.
What's your name?
Ling Choi San.
What's yours?
I'm called Nip Siu Shin.
Nip Siu Sihn. Tomorrow night...
I'll see you at the little pavilion
tomorrow night.
you're still trying to escape?!
You're in danger!
Now that you're shown yourself,
you won't be able to escape!
You think you're the only one
who can shout?! I can shout too!
Darn Daoist monk
We're only looking for a place
to call our own.
The people I kill
deserve to die anyway.
Why do you persist in not letting
bygones be bygones?
I spit on you Who says I have
anything to do with you?
I avoid the complications of the martial
ails by hiding in this haunted place!
As we bath want to reduce
the criminality of mortals,
and bless mankind,
upon reflection,
our intentions are as one!
Were the same?! I'll be damned
if lye anything in common with you!
If you play with fire,
that means you're toying with me.
Sooner or later, you'll get yourself in a lot of
trouble! And that's when I'll destroy you!
you're a good person. don't ever come
to look for me again. Siu Sihn.'
It's the bearded man...
You who are filled with love...
did you run into something last night?
I've experienced
everything in this room.
Then did you see anything strange?
Does that include you?
How dare you!
I'm talking about serious matters,
but you're joking around with me!
How can I tell when you're serious
and when you're joking?
you're always smiling.
I advise you to leave immediately!
There are ghosts here!
I dare you to call them
all out to see me
You stupid scholar!
If it were easy to spot a ghost,
there wouldn't be so many around!
They won't appear during the day,
you stupid boy!
Bearded man,
you don't have to try to scare me.
If they don't appear during the day,
have them come and get me tonight!
If you see them, then its too late already.
Why won't you listen to me?
Damn you!
If I see you here again,
I'll throw you out!
I'm not afraid of being thrown out!
No? OK, then. I'll kill you!
Better that I scare him away
before the ghosts scare him to death.
I hope I can save him.
There are ghosts here?
Maybe he's just trying to scare me.
What happened to the bottom half
of my garment?
Hey, bearded man!
What happened to my bottom half?
The bottom half?
It's attached to your top half!
I don't know what you mean
Keep it!
He doesn't talk sense. It won't make
a difference whether I save him or not!
As there's no proof one way or
the other, why don't I just make it up?
You really stayed
at Lan Yeuk Temple?
-The records show that you owe 70 taels.
-He stayed at Lan Yeuk Temple..
-You should pay up.
-Take them.
-Thank you, sir.
-Ah....
Let's follow him and see..
Boss.
You scared me to death
What do you want with me?
You scared me so much, I forgot.
Excuse me.
Siu Sihn!
Can't you hear me calling you?
don't go!
-Lets go!
-If you can hear me, then don't go!
Don't go!
Who shouted "Don't go"?
Who was it?
Let me take a good look at you!
Let me see who's the wanted criminal?
Why are you still running away?
The man with high class taste
and low status is passing by again.
-Owner.
-What are you doing here again?
Owner, where's the painting
from yesterday?
Money, which means you have status.
Let me find it for you immediately.
Owner, what are you doing?
This doesn't make sense!
No one's wanted it for a year.
I should be able to find it.
Come back tomorrow,
and I'll definitely have found it!
Fine. I'll come back tomorrow.
The wind shouldn't be able
to blow out three lanterns.
If wolves appear,
they'll be taken care of!
"See how the Yellow River
moves out of heaven."
"Entering the sea never to return."
"See how much
it looks like bright mirrors."
"Silken black in the morning,
changed by night to snow."
"Oh, let a man of spirit
venture where..."
"See how the Yellow River moves out of
heaven. Entering the sea never to return."
"See how much
it looks like bright mirrors."
"Silken black in the morning..."
"Oh, let a man venture..."
"And never tip his golden cup
empty towards the moon!"
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7
"The Six Classics are stored
in my heart."
"A branch grows above
the almond bud."
"If you don't run away, I'll run away!'
I've ran myself out of breath!
Why don't I see wolves?
The wolves are coming!
THE WATER RESIDENCE
Nip Siu Sihn!
Siu Sihn!
Siu Sihn! Open the door!
Why did you come here?
-I heard the sound of qin music...
-Hurry up and come in first!
-I told you not to come for me.
-I'm leaving tomorrow.
-I came to say goodbye.
-Tomorrow?
-Yes. But I'll come to see you again.
-Don't ever do that!
Darn! Someone's coming!
The Old Dame will smell your presence,
but not if you're in the water.
I have to get wet again?
Sister Siu Sihn.
Ski Ching. I know that the Old Dame
is waiting impatiently.
I'll come out
after finishing my make-up.
You worthless creature!
You dare hide another man
behind my back!
I didn't do that!
You know ft not true!
I already have proof!
Look at it yourself!
I can't believe
you would write such things!
You're obviously
working against me!
I need to teach you a lesson!
You worthless creature!
Have you forgotten
how I punished you before?!
If you don't behave yourself, I'll destroy
your ashes so that your soul will be lost!
Tonight,
you must find a live one for me,
so that I can replenish my chi,
and extend my life.
As its the first time you're done wrong,
I'll give you another chance.
Siu Ching, get some medicine
for your sister's wounds.
Yes.
I've already arranged for you to marry
the Lord of the Black Mountain.
you're getting married
in three days.
Although this old fool has a wasted body,
he's not easy to deal with.
When he gets mad,
even we aren't able to deal with him.
When you become his, don't even
think about coming back to us.
-Siu Sihn.
-Yes.
Come and try on the dress.
Its your bridal outfit.
Come and help me.
What is that smell?
It smells like a mortal.
My garment got torn,.
How come you're so clumsy?
My hands are dirty.
I'll wash my hands.
Siu Ching. I'll help you.
-You don't have to be so polite.
-I should.
-Why did you splash water on me?
-I was just careless.
-Siu Ching, don't argue with your sister.
-OK
You haven't finished cleaning yourself.
You did it deliberately
I'm not washing any more!
Siu Sihn, disrobe.
I'll help you mend it.
-Siu Sihn. What are you doing?
-In, preparing to bathe.
I'll dress tip a bit,
then I'll be ready to go out.
It's almost dawn. If I don't go soon,
there won't be time to get you a live one.
See how obedient your sister is, Siu Ching.
You have to learn to be more like her.
Madame, rest assured.
I won't disappoint you again tonight.
Come on.
Hurry up!
What's the hurry? In three days time,
after I get married, this room will be yours.
Put your clothes back on.
I won't look.
Come over here.
-your Old Dame...
-Hurry up and go!
But I have so much to discuss!
Lets talk at the little pavilion.
-Then I'll wait for you there!
-OK!
Master Ling.
How did you get here so quickly?
It's quicker when travelling
on the road higher up.
Are you OK?
Do you like this painting?
I'll give it to you.
The painting...
Why do you have it?
A year ago, my father
commissioned this painting.
I only managed to recover it
during the Festival of Hungry Ghosts.
The woman in the painting is me.
When you look at the painting,
it'll be as if you're looking at me.
It sounds like you're asking me
never to see you again.
I have to marry
the Lord of the Black Mountain.
I have to get married in three days.
I know you're not
a willing party to this.
If you're in trouble,
I'll take you away from here.
Its almost dawn, let me return.
Dawn is good.
We can leave immediately!
Let go!
If you won't come with me,
I won't let go.
Let me go!
Siu Sihn.
you impoverished scholar!
Stop dreaming impossible dreams.
you just want my wealth! lye seen
many like you. I won't be tricked by you!
Why are you saying such things?
If you don't leave now,
I'll have someone arrest you!
Fine! I'll leave.
Take care of yourself!
Master, I can't find the painting of
the beautiful woman washing her hair.
How about another painting?
I've seen that woman.
She's too heartless
She's also been dead for over a year.
Forget her! Lets take shelter over there.
You don't have to be so harsh
and curse her to death!
Don't stand so close,
you'll only get wet!
Master,
stop being so superstitious!
Hey, don't go!
Who called out "don't go"?
You dare cry wolf?!
Damn you!
I'm not a wanted criminal.
I don't care. Whoever shouts,
I'll chase him!
You won't get any reward
for arresting me.
Just chase him We won't lose
anything by doing that!
This world is a heartless world.
Lau Yat Dou?
The bearded man is a murderer?
That means
Ski Sihn is in great danger.
Help me down slowly.
Be careful don't get my clothes wet
You can't afford to replace them!
Siu Sihn! I'm coming to save you!
My clothes are soaked
My mother will kill me!
The Dao in the mortal realm
Dao, Dao, Dao.. Dao!
The Dao that can be followed
is not the eternal Dec
The Dao of Heaven
The Dao of Earth
The Dao of Man
The Dao of the Sword
Evil Dao, Good Dao,
Yellow Dao, Whatever Dao
Dao of Dao
My own Daoist place is very Dao
I spit, I spit, I spit, I spit, I spit
I speak nonsense
Here and there, where's the road
The Way of Ikebana,
the Way of sado, ha!
The Dao of Yin.
the Dao of Yang
Zero degrees blandness
Blinding brightness
A ghost cries
Evil cults
Fornicating dogs
Your place, his place
Wolf in sheep s clothing, hey
I'm seeking my own Dao
I seek...
My own Dao
Why are you leaving so soon?
Siu Sihn.
How come the wind
is blowing so strong?
Master Ling!
What happened to your eye?
-I got hit by a dummy.
-Which dummy?
Lie down!
Why do we have to lie down?
Its going to rain.
Even if we shelter, well still get rained on.
I'm getting used to being wet.
Let's go to the little pavilion
to take shelter.
Siu Sihn, you're in great danger.
The bearded man is a murderer.
Lets talk when we get inside.
I rushed back on purpose
to tell you to be careful.
Even the roof of the pavilion
is leaking.
Did you really
come back to save me?
I really wanted to see you.
The art dealer said the woman
in the painting died a long time ago.
Let's not talk about
such things right now.
Don't you remember that I have to
get married in a few days?
Dawn, please don't come
Tonight, let dreams and fantasies
Be alive forever
Retaining the truth of the moment
To accompany this outpouring of love
Ordering the soul to enter
Please ask dawn not to come again
The romantic feelings I have now
Take me out of the world
And the warm aroma of
the clear breeze
Delivers hot love in the cold rain
Silently allowing the undying love
to overcome obstacles
Don't allow the daylight
To separate us
Don't let the long sweet night pass
Please ask dawn
not to show its colours
This enjoyable dreamscape
Will be impossible to replace...
I've seen it in the painting.
-Give it back to me!
-The chimes are pleasing to the ear!
Give it to me!
-You know qinggong?
-Leave immediately!
Why are you losing your temper?
Why haven't you left yet?
I didn't know the anklet was so
important to you. Don't be angry.
That's not what I mean. Let me
be honest with you. I'm not a mortal!
You can't say that!
I won't allow you to talk like that!
You say you're not mortal.
What does that make me?
I will take responsibility
for what I did just now.
Don't follow me
Go and find the bearded man.
He's a murderer. By asking me to find him,
you're sending me to death.
If you follow me,
you'll die even sooner!
Siu Sihn!
-I told you not to follow m&
-You can't leave!
Where's Siu Sihn?
Siu Sihn!
I'm not looking for you.
Heaven and earth are inexhaustible!
A rite borrowed from heaven and earth!
Master Ling!
That man killed your sister.
We have to report him!
I can't go with you!
I don't care. I'm taking
you away from here!
Siu Sihn!
Damn! Siu Sihn's disappeared!
GUOBEI COUNTRY COURTHOUSE
SILENCE IN COURT
BRIGHT MIRROR
HANGING HIGH
The court is in session!
-A crime was reported.
-Yes.
-Did you collect the fee yet?
-Not yet, sir. You're missed your seat.
The magistrate is seated.
-Have a gargle, sir.
-Wash your face, sir.
Magistrate!
You have me in session and you
haven't paid any of the registration fee!
-You're getting 30 strokes of the rod first
-Double! 60 strokes!
Magistrate, please don't beat me.
If you do, I'll forget everything!
Have you collected the fee yet?
If we don't beat him up,
how can we get the money?
That won't do! Beat him!
Magistrate, I just found
the murderer Lau Yat Dou!
Lau Yat Dou?
-Who in the world is he?
-Magistrate...
Yau Yat DOU is a wanted man
with 1000 taels of gold on his head,
but we arrested him six hours ago.
This is infuriating! I'm the one
with the money-hungry reputation!
How can you be
more greedy than me?
Do you want to close me down
and cheat me out of my reward money?
I'll have you beaten
till your backside catches fire!
Beat him
-I did see Lou Yat Dou
-You've seen Lau Yat Dou?
Then I ask you,
who's the person I arrested?
-Of course it's Lau Yat Dou.
-Your crime is doubly serious!
Beat him
I'm innocent!
You're arrested the wrong person!
Magistrate, our men often
arrest the wrong man!
-Really?
-Really.
-Fine. We call for Lau Yat Dou!
-Call for Lau Yat Dou!
We call for Lau Yat Dou!
Official, if it really is Lau Yat Dou,
we have to cough up the reward money.
Let's deny it.
We'll have him beaten anyway.
you're light.
Beat him
I still have to be beaten?
Hold your rods!
An assassin!
Its Lau Yat Dou!
Lau Yat Dou? Don't rob me!
I really don't have any money!
Official Chiu.
It's Mandarin Yim.
Mandarin?
You're all cowards.
I'm reducing all your salaries!
You don't even recognize Mandarin Yin?
Mandarin Yin
is renowned in 26 districts
and Guangdong and Guangxi provinces
for being a ruthless judge.
He hated corrupt mandarins
ruling the courts so he retired.
Mandarin Yin, you didn't come to arrest
greedy officials, did you?
I don't get involved in the law any more.
I just came to see my young brother.
Don't listen to him
He's not my brother!
Slow down.
Maybe we made a mistake again.
Reporting, sir.
Lau Yat Dou is here!
Sir, the man in the jail
really is Lau Yat Dow
If it's true, then take him away.
Don't create a fuss!
-Go back, go back!
-Yes!
Get down!
Sir, you have to protect me.
He's a murderer!
How dare you!
you're not making sense.
This case is too complicated.
If we continue this case,
you have to pay three times more.
-Fine!
-Then who's the murderer?
It's him!
I didn't kill anyone. In this case,
no-one has been killed.
Official, this magistrate
is exhausted by this case.
What is it, magistrate?
The case is serious.
You decide what the increase in fees is.
Listen up, if no one's been killed,
then there is no case.
Why make mountains out of molehills?
But if you want us to put on a good show,
you should give us more money.
Why are you being silly?
Hurry up and bribe me.
I'm the magistrate'
-Increase the fee!
-I want to bribe you, but I'm poor.
You can go and steal
or commit robbery!
Magistrate, why don't you
quickly process the case?
As the magistrate
is selling his services cheaply,
why not hand over the money
to process the case?
It's pointless discussing this further.
Where exactly is the crime scene?
-Tell us.
-It was Lan Yeuk Temple.
Brother Ling, the person who died
tonight wasn't a mortal.
I saw you chop up the woman!
Not a woman, but a female ghost!
A female ghost?
As this is not a mortal matter,
it has nothing to do with me.
-Right.
-Then we won't take your money.
you're right.
-Adjourn the court!
-Court adjourned! Court adjourned!
Adjourn the cowl.
I don't believe you.
I know that girl.
-She lives behind Lan Yeuk Temple.
-No-one lives there any more.
Behind Lan Yeuk Temple
is an abandoned graveyard.
An abandoned graveyard?
There has been much unrest lately.
All the temple residents left.
At night the long pitiful sighs
and cries that you hear
are actually the cries of
solitary ghosts and wild spirits!
Solitary ghosts and wild spirits?
I don't believe you!
Fine. If you don't believe me,
then I'll take you to see the ghosts.
Look for yourself!
BELOVED DAUGHTER
NIP SIU SIHN
Now do you believe me?
She's a ghost?
Then why didn't she kill me?
I don't understand either.
Maybe you're still useful to her.
I didn't realize I was useful enough
to be used by someone.
Only ghosts would know.
Anyhow, ghosts and mortals are the same.
They use each other to get ahead.
Brother Ling, before it gets dark,
leave here quickly.
Then what about you?
I'm not leaving.
The mortal world is too complex.
It isn't easy to separate truth from lies.
With ghosts and spirits though,
matters are black and white, very distinct.
I'm staying.
Hurry up and leave!
I¡¯ve thought it over.
You had better stay.
Stay here? Then Siu Sihn
will come looking for me.
I want to use you as bait to get the female
ghost and the monster to come out.
I want to completely destroy them!
If you stay,
shell definitely come to find you.
When that happens, if you ring the bell,
then I'll come and save you.
You want to use me to kill Siu Sihn?
You're correct. Recently
they're been very displeased with me.
It seems that the forces of
evil and goad cannot co-exist.
This monster's magic is very strong.
Then are you able to defeat it?
Don't worry. Evil will definitely not
overcame Goad.
Only use this Diamond Sutra
when absolutely necessary.
-What language is this?
-Sanskrit.
You have to remember,
if you're calm, you'll find Buddha.
Then,
how you do pronounce the first line?
Prajna Paramita!
-You know Sanskrit?
-I don't.
Just remember that if you're calm,
you'll find Buddha, and you'll be fine.
Also, don't forget to ring the bell
v/hen you see the monster.
Prajna Paramita! Prajna Paramita!
-Prajna Paramita!
-I forbid you to chant!
If you chant, how are the monsters
supposed to come out and get you?
Who is it? Who is it?
If you don't answer, I'll open the door!
Why did you still come back?
The Old Dame already
knows of your presence.
Are you really a ghost?
-Yes.
So you killed
all the people in the old temple?
I didn't want to.
I was forced into it.
Ling Choi San.
Don't come near me
If you come near me, I'll get nasty!
Did you hurt yourself in the fall?
Don't be afraid of me.
I won't harm you.
Why don't you believe me?
Think, have I ever harmed you?
All ghosts harm mortals. You're a ghost.
How can you ask me to believe in you?
You think that ghosts are scary,
but mortals are even scarier.
Sometimes people are much
more cruel to each other than ghosts are.
In addition, some ghosts aren't allowed
to reincarnate into mortal life,
as they have not righted
the wrongs and injustices done.
That's why they wander around. Some
ghosts are actually kinder than people.
Then why do you harm people?
I was forced to by the Old Dame.
She is the spirit of
the millennium-old tree here.
I was born into a family of
magistrates and officials,
but I was killed by corrupt people
while travelling.
My father temporarily buried me under an
old tree, but he was murdered soon after.
So the Old Dame took control of my corpse
to seduce men to take their energy.
She even arranged a marriage between me
and the old monster of Black Mountain!
-I'll leave now!
-Don't go!
Siu Sihn!
They're coming.
How come
he hasn't ringed the bell yet?
Now you're not afraid of me?
No. I'll definitely save you
from the Old Dame.
Really? Then before sundown
the day after tomorrow,
You must deliver my bones and ashes
to be buried by a family in my village.
-Its my only chance for reincarnation.
-don't worry.
Early tomorrow morning,
I'll unearth your ashes and bones.
Before sundown the day after tomorrow,
I'll have you back at your village.
Darn! Leave now!
The bearded man is a Daoist priest.
He's waiting for a chance to destroy you!
The Old Dame asked me to harm you, but
she's lost faith in me, and she's here herself
You'd better leave
Don't be afraid! Remain calm.
Buddha will save us.
Prajna Paramita, Prajna Paramita,
Prajna Paramita...
Why hasn't that damn
Daoist priest come out yet?
Prajna Paramita...
Its useless! Let's run for it!
You said that I'd find Buddha
if I'm calm in my heart. You were lying!
-What is that?
-The Old Dame's tongue!
-Ling Choi San!
-Siu Sihn
Ling Choi San!
What is it?
Siu Sihn!
Be careful!
Don't let her tongue enter your mouth!
Let's go this way!
-Siu Sihn!
-Don't worry about me!
Ling Choi San!
Follow this silk ribbon!
Don't come back!
-Siu Sihn I...
-Why haven't you left?!
Ling Choi San!
Siu Sihn!
The Old Dame?
-You, damn Daoist priest!
-Stupid idiot! Of course its me!
Where did you go?
Why did you show up so late?
I told you to ring the bell, but you had
to resist, which almost killed me!
Damn Daoist priest, you're interfering
with my feeding habits!
I don't care if you kill bad people,
but look at this scholar!
He's tall and long-limbed.
He's weak, doesn't use what he's learnt,
and has done nothing in his life!
What other good points do you have?
I'm not as good as you've described!
If I don't make it up,
I won't be able to win the argument!
If you kill him, that means
you don't give me face!
Then when you killed my female servant,
did you think about giving me face?
Old bag
We won't discuss the matter of face!
Fine, Lets discuss our martial arts
background! Let's see who's better!
Make your move!
-Her tongue is longer than yours!
-Move it!
Prajna Paramita!
"Let the deity
be manifested as a sword!" Go!
"Heaven and earth are inexhaustible.
A rite borrowed from heaven and earth!"
Siu Sihn!
Ling Choi San!
Don't go over there!
Now, the needle!
Don't hurt her! SW Sihn!
Idiot! Come back over here!
Quickly! Help the priest
deal with the Old Dame!
Where should I stick it?
Wherever! Just stick it in
-What do I do after I stick it in?
-Just stick it in!
Not my backside!
The tongue is coming again!
Hurry up and run
Are you waiting to die?
Siu Sihn!
Lookout!
Now you are mine!
With one cut...!
Siu Sihn!
Siu Sihn Siu Sihn!
Have you lost your mind?
You know she harms mortals,
and still you follow?
She was forced into it!
Have you no pity?!
The mortals have the mortal world,
ghosts have their own dimension!
We mortals most not interfere with
the matters of ghosts and spirits!
I broke this monster¡¯s magic already!
Although her magic lies deep in her roots,
she won't be able to harm anyone
for 100 years!
As long as the status quo is maintained,
you shouldn't interfere with, them!
I can't. I promised Siu Sihn I'd bring her
bones and ashes back to her village
so that she may reincarnate into
the mortal world, and live a new life!
Swordsman Yin,
although mortal matters don't concern you,
there are many bandits in Qinghua county.
Without you, I'm afraid I won't
be able to bring Siu Sihn back.
Swordsman Yin,
I beg you to be generous-hearted,
and make an exception!
Help me deliver Siu Sihn's
remains to her village
so she may have a chance
to be a mortal! I beg of you!
Get up!
I retired because I got so sick of
people's power struggles and hypocrisies,
so that's why I hid in the old temple
and the wilderness.
In front of people,
I pretended to be a ghost.
In front of ghosts,
I thought of myself as a mortal.
The end result is that
I'm neither a ghost or a mortal!
Now,
I don't even know what I am!
-Swordsman
-How funny!
Why is it funny?
I'm mortal, yet I took myself away
from the world.
But Siu Sihn is a ghost,
and wants to become mortal again!
Swordsman, don't analyse
the situation too much.
The most important thing is
to take Siu Sihn away from here!
Why is the world such a ridiculous place?
I'm a walking mockery!
OK, I agree to do what you ask.
We found it
-Why are there so many here?
-That's strange!
Which one shall we take?
-Its sundown soon! We'll take them all!
-OK!
Where is the Diamond Sutra?
-I put it in my backpack.
-Carry it on you,
-or else the ghosts won't come with us.
-OK
Follow me closely!
You're going so fast,
how am I supposed to follow you?
We're running out of time!
Its almost sundown!
We're been riding
for half a day and we're still here!
-It must be the monster's doing!
-Then what should we do?
We have to get out of this forest
before sundown!
Prajna Paramita!
There's a path out! Follow me!
TAM LOI INN
It seems like there's going to be
a wedding celebration.
-Innkeeper!
-How come there's no-one around?
-What if everyone's dead?
-Who's dead? What are you doing here?
We want to stay at the inn.
Follow me.
That's fine. That will be all.
If we don't call for you, don't come out.
Siu Sihn, if you're one of them,
please show yourself!
Master, are you looking for me?
Master, are you looking for us?
Damn! Siu Sihn isn't among them!
These are the wrong ones!
Be quiet! Take your own burial urn,
and forever disappear!
-You may not harm mortals ever again!
-Thank you for your kind act.
Disappear!
don't worry.
We still have one last chance.
there's only one left. Siu Sihn,
if its you, please show yourself!
Hurry up and show yourself.
Hurry up and show yourself!
Master, are you looking for me?
Its a male voice.
Damn, we've taken a man's burial urn!
Look!
Why did you keep on asking me
to came out?
Oh, it was you, the inn's servant.
-You scared me to death!
-We didn't call for you!
Sneaking up to talk to us like this, you
could have scared us to death! Leave us
Siu Sihn?
-Siu Sihn!
-Ling Choi San!
Siu Sihn!
Thank you, swordsman,
for your princely act of saving my life!
That was nothing! Get up, get up!
Yes, no need for heirs and graces.
We're all friends here.
You two stay here and waste time.
I'll go and get a change of horses.
We have to prepare to leave
in a hurry tomorrow!
Crazy man and persistent woman!
Yuck!
Heroes are like that. They have to say
a few words of advice before leaving.
"A frozen lake ten miles wide,
snow falling in the sky."
"Silken threads of hair,
dreading the arrival of the winter of life."
"Facing the moon alone,
longing to be together."
"Envious of mandarin ducks eternal love
rather than, the immortality of gods."
This painting is the only valuable I'm leaving
behind. You must always keep it with you.
We must get to Qinghua County
before sundown tomorrow,
or else I won't make it on time
to reincarnate as a mortal.
Then you should be happy. It's rare to get
another chance to live as a mortal again.
When dawn comes,
we'll be separated forever!
We won't ever have a chance
to see each other again!
I hope that dawn won't come too soon.
Prajna Pararnita!
The aura of evil!
Head soup?
Ghosts getting married...
What are you doing here?
There is a stench of evil in this inn.
Quickly pack tip
and leave immediately!
Let's get your burial urn first!
Hurry up!
-I forgot the painting!
-Retrieve it after dawn!
Ling Choi San!
Today is a day of good fortune
for the underworld.
Siu Sihn must have been
kidnapped by them.
The old monster's come
to steal his bride?!
We have to force our way
into the underworld!
-We have to save Siu Sihn!
-Hold this!
We have the duration of a burning
incense stick to save Siu Sihn!
When dawn arrives,
we won't be able to return!
Remember to keep your eyes closed!
Prajna Pararnita!
Follow me!
Can I open my eyes yet?
If you don't open your eyes,
how are we supposed to find her?
Siu Sihn is inside.
Siu Sihn!
Ling Choi San!
-How come I can't touch her?
-Ling Choi San!
Siu Sihn Siu Sihn!
In the mortal plane, people can't see ghosts.
In the spirit plane, ghosts can't see people.
Prajna Pararnita!
This way, Siu Sihn
will be able to see you! Lets go!
They have entered the underworld!
Leave quickly!
Siu Sihn!
What shall we do?
Run and hide!
-Hurry up and go save Ski Sihn!
-Me?
Go!
Prajna Paramita!
"Heaven and earth are inexhaustible,
a rite borrowed from heaven and earth!"
-Where am I?
-Forget me, leave now!
I've come to save you!
I'll help you chop off the iron chains!
Lets go!
Cops!
I¡¯ve bit off more than I can chew
Swordsman Yin!
Catch the sward
You two get out of here!
I'll follow!
We have to find another way out!
Prajna Pararnita!
-Swordsman Yin
-Why did you come back?!
-We can't get out!
-The old monster has sealed the way out!
You won't be able to leave!
-Get my arrow!
-OK!
Pull the bow!
Release the arrows!
Prajna Paramita!
We're no match for him!
Hold on tight! He's a 1000-year old monster.
He'll steal your souls!
Swordsman Yin!
Don't loose concentration Recite the
Buddhist Sutras! Prajna Paramita!
Old lord of the Black Mountain
I beg you to release them!
I want you to break your burial urn so that
you stay with me in the underworld.
Siu Sihn! don't listen to him!
Don't get distracted!
Recite the Buddhist Sutras!
-Prajna Paramita, Prajna Paramita...
Don't!
I'll come and save you!
Siu Sihn.
Yin Chik Ha, Ling Choi San,
now you will die!
Don't!
What is this? Diamond Sutra?
You're been evil long enough!
Now I'm going to destroy you, old monster!
Damn old monster,
I guess you're finally willing to die!
Swordsman Yin!
The exit has been opened!
Take Swordsman Yin and leave now!
Swordsman Yin!
Swordsman Yin, we've returned
to the mortal world.
Darn! The sun's rising Siu Sihn's
been left behind! Quickly pull her out!
Swordsman Yin! Quickly come
and give us a hand!
Siu Sihn!
don't let the sunlight touch her!
If the sunlight touches her, her soul
will disperse, and she won't reincarnate!
Siu Sihn, quickly go back
into your burial urn!
The sun has already risen. I now must
leave even though I don't want to.
Siu Sihn, you have to be a good mortal.
I shall always remember you!
I never thought I wouldn't be able to see
you one more time before we separated.
You have to take care of yourself!
She's already left.
Don't allow the daylight..
-Siu Sihn
To separate us
Don't let the long sweet night
Siu Sihn!
Pass us by..
Siu Sihn! don't worry,
I'll definitely take you home.
I wonder if Siu Sihn has reincarnated
as a mortal yet?
As a mortal, you can't choose when
to be born. Its worse than being a ghost.
Look up there!
Lets stall on our journey!
The road of life
The road to beautiful dreams
is a long one
The wind blows
and frost covers the road
In this mortal world
How many different directions
can beautiful dreams take
To find the love
one cannot stop dreaming of
The road
follows the man frantically
Mortal life is
Beautiful dreams
and passionate aspirations
Vaguely in one's dreams
A dim glimmer of fears
Going from place to place
To find the direction
my heart wants to go
In the dream the wind seems
to sigh lightly once in a while
The road and the man are frantic