It's my head?
We'll know more tomorrow.
Those are nicer than my images.
Nature changes if we get too close.
- That's just charm.
- I'm charming.
- Lucas...
- I love to talk.
Words are my thing.
So my head...
...is affected.
- How badly?
Nature changes when observed.
It's minor.
A minor problem?
It's neither dead nor alive.
I'm not kidding.
A mystery, like an orgasm?
Not for long.
Sure.
Nature's secrets throw us off.
I'm handsome, so I'm a problem.
Oh no, it's only a virus.
Only its progression is known.
We've seen it recently
with electroscopes.
It kills 400 a year.
It changes part of the brain...
- Night falls...
- Fast?
- Balanchine, the dancer.
- I don't dance.
- I'll call tomorrow.
- I better hurry.
- Don't stay alone.
- Tonight?
Stop it, asshole!
She'll turn her back,
like every other night.
Funny, aren't they?
No, I think they're pretty happy.
You're the funny one.
They'll go home tired,
others cruise on their Hondas.
- Leave me alone!
- Bitch!
You son of a bitch!
I'm fed up!
- Asshole!
- May I...
Stop it, you lazy fuck!
They're poor
and they shouldn't have it so bad.
I love you!
- You see?
- They're drunks.
- You're a drunk.
- Fly face!
Horse's ass!
I got most of the press.
You're famous!
"Soir de Paris."
We got Vogue, VSD
and, get ready...
The cover of Paris Match!
Wow, great, Mom!
François did a great job.
They're all fags in the press.
Mom!
He did it for you.
What's this crap?
They say Dad's still a truck driver...
Crap. Yes!
This is all bullshit.
Who cares? At least we're in it.
In it, out of it, right.
It's ok, we can be proud.
My compliments. C-c-c-ompliments.
- Excuse me.
- What's wrong?
Ladies, want a drink on me?
I'm Lucas
de blah blah...
Why not? He's polite.
I said no!
That's ok.
The color of your drink goes with...
- With what?
- Everything. Your mom's mouth.
Your mouth is black.
- I told you.
- He's sick!
How right you are.
Women are frightening.
I was looking for you!
Saw your bike. Can I sit?
Chair.
- So, old buddy!
- Who's old?
They called. They love it.
You can't imagine
their enthusiasm.
- No, can't imagine.
- Cross our fingers.
There's a 100% chance
- the language 'll be adopted.
- You can only adopt orphans.
Lucas...
I don't feel like joking.
I want to cry.
6 years! You're a genius.
Europe is using your language.
- Me too.
- You too?
I feel like crying too.
I'll get the news out.
But there are
some lovely items in the paper.
What's that?
I'll go call.
- What's her name?
- Who?
- The girl you slept with.
- We slept with.
She never said.
Phone's downstairs?
I was afraid I'd forget her name.
I have to go to the ladies' room.
Wait here.
Stay standing. Don't be scared.
The bait.
No bait, no bite.
How about another drink?
"'No' goes without saying."
- Someone said that.
- Someone dumb.
- There's a glare.
- No, a shadow.
Take off those eclipse glasses.
Eclipse?
I'd like a drink.
My heart's beating.
If it didn't, you'd be dead.
It's too late to drink.
Too late?
It's dinnertime.
I just had a cheeseburger.
Cheese.
You can also say "please."
Are you a joker or what?
Please give me your hand.
Your hand.
Huh?
You always say that.
What should I say?
Not "huh," nothing.
Ok, I'll stop talking.
I say, "How about dinner?"
That's the name of a play.
I don't know.
I do.
I wasn't coming on to you.
Why'd you throw it?
I was upset.
Don't ever hide that again.
Day people become night people.
People meet,
drink and have dinner.
You'll be hungry soon.
What else can we do?
- Go to a movie!
- We can't talk.
I don't talk with my mouth full.
I'll keep it.
Why'd you do that?
What's this?
A foot.
And this?
A butt.
And...
A gut.
And this?
Those are your shoes.
- And that?
- Let's go, come on!
- That's a slut?
- No, that's Mom.
- Is this table suitable?
- Even better.
- Would you like a drink, Miss?
- Yes, a Ricard.
No, champagne for her.
- My scotch's outside.
- It's on its way.
Who was that guy?
My assistant,
a promising mathematician.
And who are you?
Who am I?
I am Adventure.
- I don't eat meat.
- You mean dead cows?
I hate oysters,
and whiskey makes me sick.
What's "swimming fish?"
It can't walk.
- "Veal in a pocket?"
- Cow embryo.
No way.
Right, no way.
That'd be disgusting.
We can go if you want.
I just got really sad.
It's a heavy load.
We have to be patient.
- Do you have lovers?
- I'm very careful.
No one's careful at 20.
I feel like I can't,
it's too much.
- What is?
- Living, understanding.
You can be so intense.
- I want to cry.
- I'm that intense?
It all happens at once.
I got here too late.
- I wouldn't have noticed you before.
- Before what?
When I was dating younger guys,
you would've seemed too old.
"Would have seemed,"
that's good grammar.
My grammar's bad?
- We talk like we think.
- So bad?
- Risky.
- I never say what I think.
- Think pink.
- I can't talk, I'm vulgar,
because I don't eat fish
swimming in whiskey?
Ready to order?
Ok, whatever.
I don't want to cry.
What should we do?
Forget the order.
That's too embarrassing.
Oysters and veal for the lady,
- with Pastis sauce.
- Pardon me?
Alright, Miss?
That's Mrs.
Ok, right.
That's it.
That's what?!
I hate weddings, couples, betrayals,
people tearing each other apart.
It's not that simple!
It's all simple,
you just have to realize it.
Simple, no one wants anything!
- You don't love anyone.
- No.
- I could love you.
- Me?!
That'd be a huge mistake.
I use people,
I'm totally self-centered!
I want a pear!
One pear.
- And you, sir?
- Brains, please.
Yes, sir.
Care for some wine?
I don't care, I want.
- Wine?
- Beer and lemonade.
Tequila, sake, vodka,
and caipiroska in a tall glass,
with a piece of asparagus.
Yes, sir.
I'm leaving.
You won.
- Your husband will console you.
- This was a faux pas.
Faux pas,
pas de deux, Broadway!
Shut up!
No, I'll forget what I'm saying.
My words string along like pearls.
Then talk to yourself.
Sir, your check!
You ordered, you drank.
Settle the bill!
Bill, will, spill.
- Money.
- Sir, that hardly covers it.
C-c-covers it.
Cover, smother, other.
- Fork it over!
- Fork god's sake!
Pay!
Move over.
There you are.
I thought I'd never find you.
"The Everlasting Return,"
a fine work.
The phone's ringing off the hook.
There was a party.
I didn't know that.
- You like gum?
- Love it.
You feeling up?
Down, in hell.
- Got a hangover?
- Hungry, cold.
- How can I say it?
- Say what?
- I love you, sir.
- Why so polite?
I don't love you as a friend.
You've been helpful, tough.
You've always been rich.
You're amazing.
- You'll hurt me when it's over.
- It's not over.
When we sign,
you'll have it made.
- IBM will take notice.
- You'll take off.
- Because of her?
- Because of her.
This is yours.
- Hello, Miss.
- That's hello, Ma'am.
I'll wait for you.
I'll wait for you?
I'm leaving.
Already?
I came to say I'm leaving.
I wanted to check.
I didn't know.
Me neither.
I'm glad you didn't.
Now I'm sure.
All the taste is gone.
- I chewed it.
- That explains it.
- Forgive me.
- My fault.
I said such stupid things yesterday.
I stopped listening to you.
I have to keep talking.
I'm like a bathtub,
letting the water run out.
Let it run out on me.
Now it hurts even more.
They're picking me up.
- You know where you're going?
- Not with you.
- Where?
- I'm working.
- 3 days. Casino.
Casino, the supermarket?
- No, a real one.
- Gambling?
No, I'd be terrible.
I never lie.
Will I see you again?
I don't know.
I might get a contract.
I came looking for you
because you touched my heart.
I wasn't prepared,
I tried to be like Mom.
What's going on?
What's your address?
We're late!
Are you the husband?
Are you the clown?
- Stop that!
- I'll kick his ass.
- Don't cry.
- It won't help anyway.
Orly airport.
- That's where you're going?
- It's in the papers!
I'll let you go.
It's my big day.
I invented a language
for computer images.
I invented a computer language...
It has more of a future than I do...
It's in Biarritz, sir.
You be careful.
Don't hurt my Blanche.
What're you doing?
I'm asking dumb questions.
Don't use the front stairs.
I thought now that...
we're successful, you owe me...
I only owe myself.
Really nice of you!
Nice, mice, twice, thrice.
- What's that?
- A tuxedo.
Tuxedo, casino, ok!
You're leaving?
Don't you realize?!
Yes, realize... fate, dreams.
- Air France phone number?
- 45-44-32-32.
Call Orly.
You're leaving from Orly?
- What's that?
- I told you.
It was your party.
- You mean there are more?
- Have a look.
I don't want those floozies here!
- My place is too small.
- Take mine, it's big.
- What?
- Big, wig, room for a pig.
...confusion about departures.
The only available flights
are to Metz, Biarritz and Lyons.
No more... damn!
Impossible.
Hello?
- Credit card, check book...
- It's your doctor.
He's not in. Is it urgent?
Rabbit.
Say that again?
Lucas!
Rabbit, pause...
doctor, me.
"I, Lucas de B., sane and voracious,
leave my apartment, clothes,
earthly belongings and glory
to Michel Durand, signed Tintin."
Bastard!
Cold, mist,
sky, clouds, wind.
Pretty landscape. France.
France: My country.
Language: French.
Husband: François.
Coca-cola.
Easy, it's written out.
But then there's...
Mac...
Mac... ac... McDonald's.
Makavejev, Yugoslavian filmmaker.
McLaren Formula One.
What's the formula?
If I formulate, I get lost.
My name's Lucas de Bonneval,
and I have a rabbit.
My folks left me in the rabbit hole...
one fine spring morning.
Gabriel!
Arthur, are you coming?
My rabbit!
Whoopee!
Wait for me!
Come on!
Can rabbits swim, Daddy?
I know that child.
His name is Lucas.
Urgency makes his heart dance.
He must find Blanche.
And now, the star of our show.
The one you've all been waiting for.
She's triumphed all over the country.
We're very proud
to have her here tonight.
Let's all bask in her glory...
Miss Rika Halliday!
I love it... Lucas, Rika,
rocky, rococo, hara kiri...
Hare krishna!
...man who raised her...
Maniac!
...the bewitching, inexplicable
gift of nature...
I'm talking about Raj de Pondichéry!
Go, mon chéri!
This is gonna be good.
- I'm falling asleep!
- Her too.
Follow my finger, follow my finger...
- Up her ass!
- Will you shut up?
As long as he's not touching her.
Watch it, will you?
Bitch!
Stop it!
Are you ready, Rika?
What's this woman's name?
Solange.
And that man in the balcony?
Cohen.
His wife died during the war.
Taken to a German camp.
The number she bore...
603221.
He's wearing 2 wedding rings.
She's the second,
I can tell.
A love like yours
makes my heart swell.
Is that correct, Ma'am?
Yes.
It's a hoax.
They must have a drugstore...
I mean a data base.
We're late.
- We almost missed our flight.
- There she is!
I'm never wrong.
...lying to her husband,
she took cash for the wedding band.
Her husband is gone.
Her sad days are done!
She rhymes!
- Why'd she say that?
- She's hot. Right, Inès?
And I'm chopped liver?
I'm hot, I'm in.
And she is in.
She's a knockout, a bomb!
Our daughter.
She's of age but lives with us.
We'd like to know why she doesn't...
why she can't have...
a husband and family.
Because when she was 12,
she was raped, it was hell.
She never mentioned...
By whom, dammit?
Who was it?!
The man who's your partner
is also her lover!
Sad secrets run wild
in the mind of a child!
My love, my life,
when I'm lost, I find you,
my speech is nourished by you.
Images like words dancing along,
a simple song.
What did I say?
- Whatever you think, Edwige.
- I'm never wrong.
Will you shut up!
Hey, what about me?
Inès, you've been married a lot,
using men to put money in the pot.
Like the great door of Istanbul.
At least you're not evil,
you give life to these people.
But I see suffering.
Go on.
You want
to learn of the world's cruelty?
Yes. P.R. is my business.
So be it.
Cancer will soon strike you down,
and you'll be all alone.
You'll never mend it,
you'll try 20 times,
but you're too strong to end it.
Did you know?
Don't believe her.
Rika! Where's my car?
Carefully hidden by a good friend.
Near a cliff 'round the bend.
That's my girl! She's great!
For redheaded Joëlle,
who works at the hotel!
He's gonna knock her up!
Think you're slick?
Watch your son's dick.
The redhead is funny,
she'll give him a run for his money.
- Let me through.
- No way!
I can't let her do it, go through it.
Blanche, don't show yourself
to these pigs, cads, jerks!
- At least explain to me how it works!
- I knew he was trouble!
You have a perfect life,
you love your kids and wife.
Your latest joy is a pretty girl.
You gave her a pretty name: Pearl.
Hey, that's true! Did you tell her?
The hotel. A rendez-vous!
I'd like a room.
We have no rooms free, sir.
- No vacancy.
- Are you sure?
Positive, sir.
But my cousin the Baroness
promised me.
- Baroness?
- I stopped at the bank.
We only have a suite left for you, sir,
the Imperial Suite.
- How much, roughly?
- Pardon?
Imperial Suite, royalty,
aristocrats don't count money.
I couldn't go backstage,
and now I have to freshen up.
Freshen up?
Bathroom. Price?
For what?
Ten minutes.
It's 3,500 francs a night.
Sold.
The rest is for you.
I love the smartest
and most beautiful girl.
How unusual.
The bedroom.
The key.
The light switch.
The Atlantic.
Next light switch.
Next... and next light switch.
Water.
Tip.
I got a heart condition.
- Dying soon?
- They don't know.
I look ok, but I'm not young.
Excuse me, sir.
Drink to your health.
I never drink.
Where's the master?
And where's Pips?
The ferret.
I have to look presentable,
when I'm introduced.
That'll work.
Introduce only me.
The water's hot.
It must have been hot then,
weather like this.
Dizzy.
If I close my eyes,
the ceiling will fall.
Fatigue, traveling.
I'm drunk with waiting.
I was afraid of that.
Even as a boy,
Lucas was obsessed with cleanliness.
- How was it, alright?
- Alright? It was cosmic!
I'm so happy!
- Great!
- Were you... was she there?
The Paris Match photo was better.
We can do even better, believe me!
See? She doesn't remember,
just like me!
Living in the present.
- Did I say something?
- No.
We'll tour that much?
- It's the path...
- The path... of wrath... exit...
Anger... erupting...
...new disguise, new dress...
...not that...
New York is next, then the moon!
We've got it made!
- Yes, Ma'am.
- Edwige, it is, I insist!
Tokyo, La Baule, Frisco...
we'll see from there!
We'll see!
Look who's here.
Who's that?
- None of your business.
- That jerk!
- You little...
- Let me help.
Take this.
It'll calm your nerves.
- You came!
- We're all here.
- You're all wet.
- I swam here.
"Swimming fish."
I don't believe you.
We're not really here.
- Just talk.
- I'm not lying.
You talk well onstage.
Paranomasia...
You liked it?
What's that?
My heart beating.
Let's go.
- Lucas.
- Stay here.
I have to talk about the contract...
We have a whole lifetime.
Time... is passing away.
- Like you.
- Huh?
I... like you.
- I've got to go.
- Can I come?
- No one will understand.
- Later?
Yeah, maybe later.
- How?
- I'll find a way.
- You won't lie?
- I will... for you.
Which room?
The Imperial Suite.
Wow, nothing but the best!
Yes, nothing.
Suburban idiot.
Sweet swimming swami.
No, that's not it.
Are you crazy?!
He's out of his mind!
There it is...
"Somewhere, beyond the sea..."
To leave?
Or not to leave?
That is the question.
The sea comes, goes, flows...
Waves of alabaster...
Master.
Master of cruel fate and solitude,
master of solicitude, anxiety.
Dreadful here.
Goddamn meeting.
All I need's a silk cravat,
champagne, strawberries,
some music, and bam!
Vulgar. Not like my Madame.
What can I do?
Wreak havoc, spread confusion!
The organized mind
must work in reverse.
Leave nothing in place,
of order I will leave no trace.
And so I...
turn upside down...
I lost my degree,
and all faith in me.
Should I order a great big meal?
She may be eating now.
Turn on the TV.
But how? I don't see.
A silent show, a musical hit,
something clean and fun.
I never liked it.
After you, my dear!
- Watch your step.
- Now for the next step!
Private consultations.
Only for a select few, you know?
The upper crust.
But she can only do it once a day.
Hypnosis is tiring.
- You don't hypnotize.
- No, I command.
- You're full of yourself.
- No, full of life!
- I'm going to sleep.
- I'll wake you tomorrow.
You have make-up
and hair appointments.
- Stop fighting and love me!
- Sink or swim,
strike while the iron's hot!
That will make or break you!
- I'll take you to your room.
- I'll go alone.
Whatever.
Too early to sleep.
- Come on, girls.
- You're ready to dance!
It's me.
Sir, a lady's looking
for your suite.
- Pretty?
- Wow.
Send her up, or I'll come down.
Isn't she the loveliest in town?
She keeps saying,
"I'm sick of this shit!"
That's her!
It's not nice enough here.
Throw some water?
Make a lake?
It's too late.
My sweet flower,
crying at this late hour!
You took forever.
I never...
It was unbearable.
My fault.
No, mine.
I never know what to do.
I could do better.
It takes me awhile
to come out of it.
We'll figure it out.
Shit!
That's my word.
The door.
The door to what?
Close it.
Tired.
At last.
At peace.
Yes.
Want nothing.
Must nothing.
We'll see?
The sea.
Not asleep?
I was cold.
You could close the window.
If I moved,
it'd be ruined.
- What?
- Sleeping together.
All night.
That's right.
Crossing a bridge.
Huh?
Playing bridge.
I don't know.
What's it like onstage?
It's something.
I knew it.
Not something... nothing.
A black hole...
I'm there, but not really.
Where then?
- In a kitchen.
- Huh?
- You said, "Huh"!
- And I chew gum.
You got some?
Always, in my bag.
Are you mad at me?
Because we should've done it?
It's the law.
That's Paris...
bad literature, de luxe Parisianism,
gossip and storytelling...
vita brevis, ars lunga...
- Life is short, art is long.
- Huh?
- I've got a hard-on.
- Me too.
Impossible.
When I have to pee,
I get hard.
- "When I see Fernande..."
- My mom's name!
Don't be mad.
You do it with your husband?
When I have to.
- You don't have to.
- I do what I have to.
Do what you want to!
Why are you here?
That's a good one.
I love you.
I think I do too.
I do it when I'm unhappy.
I threw the lighter at you
when my Mom picked up that guy.
Otherwise...
I wanted to be different.
Let's not do it anymore.
Which one of us will be bored?
Your dick?
- My instincts.
- I'm starving!
Let's eat!
We're not doing it,
because you're happy? It's that simple.
- Let me order.
- Yes, master.
- That's my college degree.
- Master?
Croissants? Tea?
- Hot chocolate?
- Toast! Where's the bathroom?
Out of sight, as Dad said.
- What'd he do?
- Owned land.
- Phone?
- Out of reach.
- Your dad?
- A slave, O master.
- His name was Sir Cumference.
- A knight?
Your high hat.
Your Highness.
Your Thickness.
Your Brilliance.
Hey, you're big!
Is that Dick speaking?
Dick the prick!
Downstairs.
My friend!
One breakfast tray
with bread, eggs, fruit,
hot chocolate,
- tea... the best.
- I should think so.
Thank you, sir.
- My friend!
- You should've called.
And wake the lady?
Sleeping beauty.
There's a phone in the bathroom.
It's vulgar to call from the john.
- Your syntax is divine.
- And it's all mine.
- No one gets it.
- How does it go?
To and fro. It's intense.
If you want intensity, let me know.
But I'm in love.
With a precious gem.
Enough banter...
She's almost hysterical
when she's in a trance.
The brain, cells, waves...
- Like claws.
- No, the signals are weak,
- the sensors blind.
- Leaving us breathless.
Breathing life into the lifeless.
What poetry!
You're a new man, sir!
- I've got to call the Baroness...
- Done, sir.
Huh?
I called her,
so she wouldn't worry.
Was she happy?
Delighted, Mr. Bonneval.
Breakfast is on its way.
Don't let me down.
Where's the bellboy,
I haven't seen him?
No one knows.
He hasn't shown up.
Sometime soon
I'll have to own up.
They came in late.
Him with a lass,
her with a bloke.
They have words,
he looks for her,
mother looks for daughter...
Vampire face!
I hope his gaze finds no trace.
Excuse me!
François! He's here!
He's here, François!
You didn't say he was here.
I would never
betray the aristocracy.
I'm not used to this.
You can take anything.
Room service, Imperial Suite.
Two breakfasts.
You figure it out.
- Why are you running?
- I'm being followed.
Cops?!
Pack your trunk.
- I don't have one.
- Your dress and clippers.
When we run,
our shoes go "clip clip."
- What about breakfast?
- I'm hungry.
Mom says I'm still growing.
Watch out, they're crazy.
We looked for you all night.
We were worried sick.
Afraid I'd leave?
What'd that creep do to you?
- Lazy losers.
- Loser!
You think I'm a loser?
- Nothing happened!
- What'll I do?
- "Blanche" means white like snow?
- Cold?
White like nothing?
They're changing my costumes!
- I can't stand it.
- Give me that.
I'm gonna look stupid
with dyed hair!
You're handsome, François!
Calm down.
He said my ring was an eyesore.
But it's gold
and has my initials on it.
- What's your name?
- François, like everyone else.
Pathetic.
Remember the Cergy supermarket?
- I sure do.
- So funny.
- My sales pitch.
- "In the cheese section:
Fresh camembert
that all you ladies will love.
It'll remind your men
to wash their feet before dinner."
I got fired for that.
- I loved it!
- You were so young.
I was working.
- In the cafeteria.
- You defended me.
- Your father came...
- To beat me, for money.
- I hit him with some honey.
- I don't know.
You cried so hard,
like a fountain.
It's easy.
No, it's not easy.
He said: A birthmark I had,
so I knew he was my dad.
Dads have no value.
They beat you.
- Then I lose you.
- Not true.
You see?
Come here.
You've got a photo session today...
I'll be there.
He's handsome, classy.
- It was good for you.
- Right, Mom.
Tablets...
All 3 of us got laid.
- You too, Mom?
- Edwige's guy.
Get the lead out, François,
she'll catch up.
What're you doing?
Going through your bag.
- Looking for something?
- Gum.
Did you find it?
I don't like this.
Will these things protect me?
From what?
From you.
When'd you last have one?
While you slept. Why?
No reason.
The Mrs. Will sign,
if she can write.
Blanche Filthy von Slut!
You don't like my family?
Not hungry?
Yeah, more than ever.
Pass the sugar.
No, the sugar.
Are you joking?
Joking.
King.
King Midas.
Midas touch.
Soft touch.
Velvet touch.
Blue velvet.
Velvet blue.
Blue rabbit.
Rabbit.
Wounded.
Left by the others.
Shit.
Empty.
Tragedy.
Want to drive me crazy?
Crazy...
Me.
Fuck off, Lucas.
My rabbit!
- She's on drugs.
- They all are.
Can I get her autograph?
Oops, I got carried away.
- What'd I do?
- Want another?
Stay away from such people!
Stay away... path...
Don't beat me.
Child.
Love me.
Teach me.
I need...
so badly.
That girl looks sick.
Don't go there. She's throwing up.
Maybe it's indigestion?
That hotel food...
See that?
She's eating sand.
No silly, she's lost her senses.
Those women!
Take my hat, Miss.
You're all wet.
- No, thanks.
- Let me help.
- Poor girl.
- Adrienne!
Your name's Adrienne?
Look after her, she's not well.
I didn't do anything.
Go drown yourself.
What?!
Got some lotion?
The sun makes my nose peel.
Have a nice swim?
My mother always had lotion.
- Can I look?
- You already did.
Don't you remember?
Vaguely.
I brought your towel.
I'm sorry.
I saw you swimming.
- You're not so tall in the water.
- No.
- We should never argue.
It tears my heart out.
This is really it, this time.
Even if we're different,
together we're whole.
You're long, and round.
- With swimmer's thighs.
- From the pool in Cergy.
- You love swimming?
- I love you.
Let's make the most of that.
- Your back's freezing.
- My fingers too?
No, stop...
- We might drown.
- I want you.
I...
want...
you!
Get out... of here get out.
The sheets are wet.
Doesn't matter, pitter patter,
go now, scatter, heathens,
I'm not afraid of water.
Let me redecorate.
It feels like the first time.
It's hot in here.
It's cool in here.
Be proud of me.
Tonight...
I'm having an...
eclipse.
Talk to me,
like you're in a trance.
Need... so much love.
Give!
I can't.
Open!
There's a little person
inside the big one.
Yes...
body...
intelli...
gence.
They put Blanche
in the black closet without food.
Words...
and body...
Women...
The kitty...
is dead.
Not dead!
Alive!
That night, he remembers,
we were wandering...
and you, you?!
And you?!
The water!
I don't want to cry!
- Don't cry!
- Don't!
Love!
Cry, love! Pain!
Does it hurt?
Or are you suffering?
I understand.
Love means pain, lots of pain.
Your parents died in a pond at night.
Your parents drowned in a pond.
Heads up!
Head's in, warm inside.
I can feel you.
King Arthur's putting the sword
in the stone.
Guenevere
is showing him the way home.
We're no more alone.
Give.
Open.
There it is!
Correct.
Excuse me.
We went fast.
You think so?
Believe me,
wave...
came...
from deep inside.
Cannot.
What's that?
I asked for room service, to buy...
some shoes,
and tops and bottoms.
- You don't know my size.
- I measured like this.
It's gorgeous!
Wanna help me?
They got any old thing.
It looks good on me.
Excuse the delay.
They had to go to town.
You wanted them alive,
the market's closed today.
You did want big ones?
She's a big girl.
Not too big.
Too big? Big enough?
Hope that'll do it.
What's that?!
- For your breasts.
- Crabs?
I lost the word.
Brassière?
I forgot the "-ssière."
They need water.
The bathtub, maybe?
No, the sea's better,
while I'm away.
- You're going?
- Got a lunch.
- Lunchbox?
- Restaurant.
- Soup kitchen?
- No, a fancy place.
You shouldn't go!
What's wrong?
It's going down the toilet!
What?
Words. Don't ruin them!
But I have a meeting...
In that pathetic casino,
why do you show them your ass,
and crack?
I...
The faucet's on,
the water's running...
No, turned off it is.
Leave together.
Bad, bad, bad for you.
It's my last show in France.
Will you be back?
Yes, I know I will.
Do you still want me?
You talk in rhymes.
Did they tell you?
Because I pity
that little person, I do.
We need a computer
that can hurt others.
What compassion!
I walked barefoot
all over France, in the war.
Which one, honey?
Wow, you're stunning!
I love it, don't you?
Is that the little turd in Paris Match?
You mean "blurb."
- Turd, blurb, who gives a shit?
- It was the first time!
They colored my hair.
I'd say they discolored it.
I'll leave Blanche
to your decadence... I mean wisdom.
- It's nice.
- If you ask me...
I'm in charge here!
Don't touch the girl.
Give her a beer.
Stop butting in!
"Haley" is classier than "Halliday,"
or use your real name, "Blanche..."
Did I say you could use my name?
Blanche!
It's ok, François.
I used to be like that.
Wild.
Right, Barnaby?
Incorrigible.
Always right. Really moody.
I manage 400 people.
Guy knows.
Haley... like the comet.
- I am really...
- What?
- Sick of it.
- Want me to take care of it?
Call me Blanche Haley, Haley Blanche,
I want to see Mom, alright?
What the hell are you doing?
It's good to stand up to her.
I need you.
- Oh, it's you!
- Who else?
Waiting for another one?
See you later.
Why stop? Give it your all.
Just like when I was small.
He drank. He couldn't.
He was unable, you were unstable.
Instead of your vulgar ways,
he needed
calm tenderness in his days.
You're rhyming, dear.
At age one I saw you,
the tears, the escapes,
screaming with a lover above you.
I also imagined
that love would be suffering.
I hoped it would change,
but I can't understand,
it's still too strange!
These people
are taking over our lives!
We're making a fortune.
We'll work something out,
so I won't suffer.
You said you were unconscious?
To make you happy,
to save your conscience.
Was that his maid?
I called her.
It's risky taking a lover.
It's my first time.
Had enough?
Got any more of that stuff?
Screw 'em... and get the hell out!
Compassion, compassion,
come on, passion!
Pass it on, play along, Baroness.
Let's find a way...
Your cousin the Baroness is here.
Does she need a brassiere?
Including the "-ssière."
I couldn't say.
One male, one female.
I better hide them.
My deepest respects
to your Highness.
Arthur and Adrienne
are their names.
Lucas learned about love that day.
When you're tired of loving,
you throw each other away.
One goes, then the other.
All traitors!
Here to knife me in the back?
I didn't know. Her mom told me.
Reminds me
of a film about loyalty.
- Buñuel, I think.
- Why think when you can go?
- You have to go home.
- House, home,
sell my place and roam.
Find another
with a pretty kitchen.
About your condition...
Be a sad husband...
Words are your friend.
- Open up to language...
- Your own.
The doctor's waiting!
I'm so lucky.
Medical advances left and right!
- Doctor says every day...
- Worse gets worse.
Please...
I kissed your ass for 7 years.
You replaced my name with yours.
Wait... I can still write...
and spell my name right.
It's not my fault.
It's just that I really want her.
My language is yours.
That's right. Thanks.
Now I can go home...
and enjoy life.
Now you can die!
Where's the porter?
Napping.
And you?
Waiting for you.
He helps me
when I'm missing a word.
What's missing?
Elevator.
That's a tough one.
I'll take you there.
You can't charge 20,000 an hour!
Believe me, I'm never wrong.
If you don't like it, lump it!
L'chaim.
Know the Jewish Connection?
If you don't want 2 armed guys
at your place...
Get the picture?
Always taking us for a ride!
What do you think?
A star is born!
The Biarritz beauty.
You need to learn English.
- Dummkopf.
- Dumb ass!
- My tailor is rich.
- How are you, sweetie?
- I wanna screw you!
- My turn!
- I can't get enough.
- Leave us alone!
- Or you?
- Who do you think you are?!
You better watch out!
Watch your filthy habits, old man!
- I do look old.
- No, distinguished.
Anyway, you're so pretty,
you intimidate me.
My god, you're gorgeous!
- How about some music?
- I look ok?
She'll marry a prince!
Like I always wanted.
No artists!
Her dress keeps folding.
Tighten the curve of the breast.
Michel said your friend's not well.
Damn... how does it work?
Are you crazy?!
Leave me alone!
Thank you so much.
Biarritz! I am never wrong.
That's right, you got it!
Even in Moscow,
they'll need psychics.
I've got to go.
But not for long.
Blanche not here?
No.
- Then I'll go to her.
- Really?
Add grease to the fire.
Lots of grease, please.
Your kitchen!
"Baucet?"
Nitty gritty... pretty!
I know.
House, pond, noise...
I love you!
We ate like sad boys.
Fighter!
The spider... is sad.
Time, I know.
Don't go.
I need better hands, give me some.
No.
Come.
- You must.
- Move not.
- Love.
- Cold in here.
- Stay near.
- Like me best, how I'm dressed?
- Your jewels, your gown?
- Don't let me down.
Is one woman too much?
Ecstasy again?
Talk.
Come...
Oh, come.
Suffer, then.
I'm coming!
When I go,
don't forget the love of Blanche,
it'll stay with you
long after tonight.
With or without her, empty space
without words.
One last vision she'll have for you.
Turn away and you'll forget.
Was she here?
No, sir.
So I must go.
It's time.
A big blue rabbit!
Your ticket, sir.
Your software.
My soft wear.
It's heaven-sent.
Certainly, sir.
For your ten cents.
Glad to be of service.
Tonight, the lady
has become a true princess.
It's you... and what you do.
She smells the sweet smell of love.
- Gum?
- Got some.
This extraordinary woman
needs no introduction.
The divine Blanche Haley!
Bravo!
You're back, Mr. Le Comte...
you're not going to...
Love is a pond that can drown you.
You think so?
The porter told me
about your credits as a scientist.
It'd be wise to keep quiet.
Mark my words.
And her guru, François.
That makes it even tougher.
Watch my finger, Blanche.
Words...
and body.
This gentleman!
This little man,
I can't really use him,
he always needs
something new to amuse him.
Paying for love,
a slave to perversion,
he gets off in his armchair
and thinks he knows passion.
He smells, likes porno,
has no wife,
I should give him my skin,
as a balm
for his sorry excuse for a life.
This man has the power
to kill the artist.
The artist must bow down,
not go too far.
This man can do everything,
wreak havoc.
The enlightening child
must be corrupted,
the pathetic spirit must run wild.
We must flatter fate,
raise praise as directed, not hate.
Sir, please excuse me.
You were chosen from many.
There are others here,
far worse than you.
And others who are honest, kind,
sentimental and sweet,
the kind of people
I'm touched to meet.
They think that life
is more than just lies.
And some are innocent.
Can we trade words for innocence?
You've got to go,
quietly, discreetly.
Expect nothing from me.
Me, Lucas, them.
If you don't go, Lucas,
I'll speak no more.
You've got just a few hours,
you won't see the dawn,
I won't cry like before.
I won't cry for you.
It's best to go
when it's really good.
You're killing my act,
killing me.
I'm making up poems
to make you happy.
The child is dying to speak...
Tell him!
I have to be honest in what I say.
Merchandise wins,
the blade cuts the foreskin at the end.
Her, there!
Her child won a word contest.
In her bag?
A checkbook, of course.
- Number?
- 792832000.
- Is that correct, Ma'am?
- It is.
Just in case,
she's got one big condom.
Looking for love
with a black stallion.
You, Lucas, me, Blanche.
Want to see me dance?
Will I finish school?
With top honors,
you'll be the best.
You'll get married
but she won't pass the test.
Now that I've loved,
I don't have the ears
for your little secrets
or deepest fears.
You have no power over me.
I may one day miss
the gift of my talent,
the glory
of expressing myself to you.
Glory, in the sea's luster,
appears lackluster.
And all that's left...
is charm.
The charm of a short life.
Blanche, what's wrong?
You'll die alone
in a retirement home,
dirty, poor, forgotten.
A triumph! Call the press!
I'm never wrong!
My life's a waste.
No matter what you think.
Even if I know now...
that I take and give of my soul,
out of pity for that small person.
That person in so much pain.
The person who makes me whole!
Why don't you lose your mind
now, Lucas? Why wait?
Ladies and gentlemen,
her powers rain on us like showers!
Power play, tower of power, flower!
We are crushing this flower!
- Mr. Le Comte!
- This way.
Must you depart and despair?
Just before dawn,
we'll say good-bye. I'll be there.
What did you say to her?
That dove is a bond
in which you can clown.
If there's a pure soul here,
please raise your hand high.
I'll look for the good.
No one?
Ok, let's see.
You're 5 years old.
As one often does,
you miss the way it was.
You want to see
your grandparents less.
Your first love will last
all your life.
Because that's the way...
of happiness without strife.
I forgot, your Granddad
has a surprise:
A doll outfit.
Today is your name day.
It's at home on your pillow.
What a recovery,
she saved the show!
Nantes was almost a no-go.
I'm never wrong.
Bunch of vultures!
The lining, right.
Smoother now.
Time to tango, mamba!
Incredible!
Wait 'till she hits the gay clubs.
Then François can strip, right?
Alter this!
Photographers coming!
I want to find Lucas.
Don't forget, your contract!
Was that true?
I don't know.
If so, I'll do it!
Go ahead.
The guy is crazy!
I'm a star.
- Will you stop?
- The truth hurts.
Now get the hell out,
you filthy bastards!
All this will soon be superfluous.
Lucky for you, lesbian.
That's right, I'm lucky.
You were always clean, pretty.
You had everything.
Not now!
You said I'd be happy
with you here.
Only love yourself.
No danger in that.
To love yourself,
you need a mirror.
An insurmountable, obscene
same-sex image.
What do I do onstage?
Beautiful things, great things,
definitive things.
I've got to go, Inès.
Lucas hurts me so, it stings.
Can I come with you?
Not tonight.
Mr. Le Comte,
you have to get ready!
I am ready.
Look, white gloves
and a fancy pop hat.
You see,
sometimes words pass me by.
Words are strange...
Sartre was inspired
to write about them all.
Sometimes I feel
I'm against a wall.
Another of Sartre's pieces,
he couldn't write at all.
I want to have my final moment.
Set up in a room.
A fine idea!
The porter will help us.
Not too much trouble?
I died 2 days ago.
Nothing more will harm us.
Impeccable style!
Style running wild.
It really flows!
It's the water.
I came to say good-bye.
Maybe... water... too much...
No talk.
No moving.
Sleep.
My flight's leaving.
- When?
- Before dawn.
Man wants to change woman.
She'll never change.
Ok, there!
Talk, please...
- One last time!
- That hurts!
Help me, please.
You shouldn't do that!
You shouldn't
hurt the little person!
When it's all over, you'll die.
Men die by the sword,
you'll die by your brain.
But you'll die happy.
Kind, stupid,
you'll end your pain.
Cold intelligence
makes a person seem wild,
but the only true justice
is that of a child.
I hate you now.
Pain!
Help me.
Love me.
Love.
Didn't know.
Know...
we can't.
Use the verb "to smurf,"
it's easier.
I'll smurf the lights,
you smurf the lady in your arms.
I'll smurf her onto your back.
Love...
or misery.
We must learn to share.
At our age!
Rabbit!
Thank you...
but they're all anxious, waiting.
That way, Mr. Le Comte.
No charge to your account.
If I may say so.
The lady is drunk...
with success, right?
She's sleeping.
Aren't we all?
Don't let me go.
The motorcycle
is waiting outside.
Don't worry about the bill.
Your Highness the Baroness...
He'll thank his cousin later.
You even have a voucher.
- Here.
- It's all yours.
For buying the gum.
Are you making fun?
He who chews...
cannot laugh.
Come on, sir! Gas, clutch,
gears... it's child’s' play!
No, I can't smurf.
Smurf the metal from my cotton.
You can pipe it.
Just like I always wanted.
Good-fly, guy.
My diversion
will save the artists from detection!
My love... shall we so?
Like the current
flowing into the river,
like Blanche, awakening,
in love with her lover.
By accident,
not knowing where or when,
they'll complete the circle
as children again.
I kept this for you.