DAIEI MOTION PICTURE CO., LTD.
BLIND BEAST
PRODUCED BY KAZUMASA NAKANO
ORIGINAL STORY BY EDOGAWA RANPO
SCREENPLAY BY YOSHIO SHIRASAKA
CINEMATOGRAPHY BY
SETSUO KOBAYASHI
ART DIRECTION BY SHIGEO MANO
MUSIC BY HIKARU HAYASHI
ASST. DIRECTOR: YUKIO SASAKI
CAST:
EIJI FUNAKOSHI,
MAKO MIDORI, NORIKO SENGOKU
DIRECTED BY YASUZO MASUMURA
My name is Aki Shima.
I was never very popular
as a fashion model.
But I was very moved by the artistic sense
of the photographer Mr. Yamana,
and I was quite willing to let him
take such pictures of me.
The exhibition created quite a sensation.
I went to the gallery one morning
for an early meeting
to discuss our next project.
At such an early hour,
there was only one visitor.
He didn't take any notice
of the photographs.
He was crouched at the foot
of the featured statue.
It was a nude study of me,
sculpted by one of Mr. Yamana's friends.
This visitor's whole demeanor
was very strange.
What happened next was unexpected.
It felt as if the statue and my body
were somehow one.
I felt his hands
as he pawed at the statue,
as if he was running them
over my body.
It sent shivers down my back.
I ran out of the gallery.
Several days later,
I worked for Mr. Yamana again.
I woke up at four in the morning
and drove down to the studio.
Mr. Yamana was very demanding.
Working for him was hard.
I was exhausted,
but still had to drive back
to my apartment in Tokyo.
Once home, I called a local masseur
to relieve my fatigue.
It's open. Come in.
I'm from Sakura Massage.
They've never sent you before.
Yes... that's correct.
Your usual masseur
Is otherwise occupied.
They sent me instead.
- Do you mind?
- I guess not.
I only moved here three days ago.
I beg your favor.
Hurry up and start.
With your permission...
Put some effort into it. I like it hard.
If it doesn't hurt, it doesn't satisfy me.
Like this?
No! Harder than that!
Your body is quite stiff.
Massage is good
for younger women, too.
It stimulates the circulation
so your skin looks more beautiful.
More so for someone
in your line of work.
How do you know what I do?
You're Aki Shima.
Famous for those sensational photos.
And very famous among we masseurs.
Sometimes I really appreciate my work.
I get to talk to famous people like you.
And besides, I get to touch you.
I'm not famous.
You're very beautiful.
Don't flatter me. My looks are average.
Not at all.
To the blind, faces don't really matter.
It's your body and the silkiness
of your skin that are important.
You really are quite exceptional.
Stop that! What the hell?
I'm terribly sorry.
The blind have eyes in our fingertips.
I know your body better
than someone who can see.
From top to bottom.
The feel of the blind man's fingers
on my body
was exactly like the man
stroking the statue.
Could it be him?
Maybe cold clay wasn't enough.
The thought of that made me angry.
I said no! Don't you understand?
I'm sorry.
That's enough. You can leave.
But I've just started.
Forget it. I'm very tired,
I need to get some rest.
I'll pay you anyway.
700 yen, isn't it?
What are you doing?
It is you! I knew it!
- Well done.
- My coat.
Finally, you're awake!
It's you, isn't it?
Where are you?
Where?
I'm here!
What is this place? Where am I?
This is my studio.
Your studio?
It looks just like a warehouse
from outside.
What are you?
I'm an amateur sculptor.
A sculptor?
I'm blind.
I was born with damaged optic nerves.
I'm totally blind.
Being blind is miserable.
From listening to people
and Braille books,
I can picture much of the world's beauty.
The sunlight,
the color of clouds,
splendid scenery,
and the beauty of works of art,
plays, movies, even TV.
But I cannot see a thing.
I hate my parents for this.
However... that doesn't achieve
a single thing.
All that is left for the blind
is sound, smell, taste
and our sense of touch.
Sounds are like the wind,
no satisfaction.
Smells are also useless.
Human noses aren't sensitive
like dogs' noses.
Food merely serves to fill our bellies.
But what I have discovered is that
touch is the only way to amuse us.
Our one tactile satisfaction.
Touch is the only sense
worth anything to me.
I've touched everything I can.
I liked the feeling
of touching animals best.
They're so warm and soft.
I've had dogs and cats to stroke.
I've been to a farm
to play with sheep and horses.
However, no animal can compare
with human flesh.
Especially the feel of women's bodies.
After finishing school,
I took a course in massage.
Every night, I went to inns,
hotels and apartments to work.
But not for the money.
I wanted to feel the women's skin.
Like faces,
every woman's skin is different,
each with its own shape and feel.
So many women,
I became totally fixated.
Around then, I sold some land
that I'd inherited from my father.
I made a fortune out of it.
But a blind man like me
could find no use for money.
So I bought this warehouse
and took up sculpture.
Recalling all of those women,
I reproduced their body parts from memory.
Now I can caress them at any time.
It took six years to build the studio.
I spent most of my inheritance.
When it was finally completed,
I was so happy.
And now,
I spend most of my time here.
Days and nights here in the darkness.
I amuse myself by caressing
their bodies at will.
Be careful.
I'll put the lights on.
This is my studio.
What do you think?
You're insane!
But I've got bored with the studio.
Real bodies are nothing like this.
Not like the soft bodies
of beautiful women with luscious skin.
When I finally realized
that's what I needed,
I heard schoolboys on the train
talking about you.
What did they say?
They were discussing
your photos and statue.
I went to the exhibition space
and ran my hands over the sculpture.
I registered at your massage agency
and finally got to touch you.
Those boys were right.
Your body is the finest I've ever known.
Your shape, your skin texture
are exactly what I want.
- Get away from me!
- Please don't worry, I'd never hurt you.
What do you plan to do with me?
I want you to stay a while
and be a model for my sculpture.
- That's why you kidnapped me?
- You would never have agreed.
I had no choice.
- Will you be my model?
- No way! I refuse!
I'll pay you very generously.
I don't want money.
With you as my model,
I'll create a wonderful work of art.
There are many kinds of art
in our world.
Art for amusing the eye,
the ear and the mind.
- Why can't touching be an art form?
- That's not my problem!
Every day we use touch.
We touch bowls, vases,
desks and chairs.
Clothes and furs, too.
Art is more than color and shape,
what about touch?
- What about it?
- I want to pioneer the art of touching.
An art only the blind can appreciate.
A new art form, by and for the blind.
That is my life's mission.
I beg you, please be my model!
No way!
Go on, you can beat me, kick me.
I'll be your slave.
You can do anything to me.
Just let me touch your body.
Help me create a totally new genre of art.
No! You're wasting your time!
Why?
You stripped naked
for that photographer Yamana!
So why not for me?
That's obvious.
Mr. Yamana is a great artist.
He depicted me as
The New Woman Of Our Age.
That's why I posed for him!
But I also create art!
What? That's crap and you're crazy.
You just want to feel me up.
- Why do you say that?
- Just stop!
In that case...
But I won't give up.
I'll wait,
no matter how long it takes.
I won't let you go until you agree.
You intend to lock me up in here?
Fine! The police will come
and find me all the sooner.
No, the police won't come.
Why not?
I used a false identity
when I registered as a masseur.
Nobody saw us bringing you here.
Besides, we changed taxis many times.
And we walked the last few blocks.
Even a massive search
wouldn't find you.
You're insane!
You can't open it. It's locked.
Help!
Somebody help me!
There's no use screaming.
They're double doors of sheet iron.
It's futile to try and escape.
I can follow your scent,
and the sound of your breath.
I can soon find you.
If you keep this up,
you'll collapse from exhaustion.
Looks like I've got you.
Stop it right now, or you'll regret it!
You've got goose bumps.
Why are you so scared?
Let go of me!
You give me no choice
I'll have to use this again.
- How was your breakfast?
- She hasn't touched a thing.
If you don't eat, you'll get sick.
I want to talk. Come here.
Talk about what?
I sat up all night
thinking about my position.
If you continue to lock me up here,
I won't be able to eat or sleep.
I'll go insane and I'll die.
So?
I'll do as you say...
I'll be your model.
Really?
But once the sculpture's finished,
you'll let me go, right?
Naturally.
After thinking about it,
I realized that the art of touching
is really quite an interesting concept.
A bold experiment.
It didn't take long to change your mind,
just one night.
I was so scared, I could hardly think.
In these circumstances,
I think anybody would be the same.
But once I calmed down,
I realized you're not insane at all.
You're a pioneer artist
in a brand-new genre.
Do you really think so?
The energy and passion that
you've shown in creating this studio
proves you're truly unique.
I want to work with you
to pioneer the art of touching.
I'm so pleased that
you finally understand.
Thank you.
Let's start right away.
I want your best work.
Indeed!
You're one in a million.
I searched long and hard for a body
such as yours. I love this body.
Is it okay if I take a break?
But we've barely started.
- I don't feel well.
- What's wrong?
My stomach really hurts.
Where? Where does it hurt?
You won't call a doctor, will you?
No, of course not.
I've caught a chill,
but I'll just have to bear it.
Shall I turn up the heating for you?
Do you have any painkillers?
Normal aspirin will do.
I'll go and have a look.
If not, can you buy me some?
I want to get well
and get back to modelling.
I understand.
Where are you going?
Let go! Let go of me!
Michio, she's trying to escape!
Come quickly!
Was she really trying to escape,
Mother?
If I'd been any later, she'd be long gone.
Is that right?
So you lied to me
with your fancy stories.
Let me go! Please! Let me go!
You can't leave
until Michio finishes his work.
No! I'll go crazy!
Let me out! Let me go!
Quieten down.
I'll keep watch over her.
You concentrate on your art,
it's your only pleasure in life.
Thank you.
I couldn't do anything without you,
Mother.
Don't be silly.
You know I'd do anything for you.
Any mother would.
Now get back to your work.
Hey!
How long will it take you to finish it?
This will be the pinnacle of my art,
so I can't really say.
Really?
If that's the case,
maybe we should try to be friends.
If not, this oppressive atmosphere
will drive me crazy.
It's your fault, you tried to trick me.
I'm very hungry.
Mother will bring lunch soon.
Will you eat here together with me?
Together?
I don't have much appetite
eating on my own.
I'll lose weight and my skin will suffer.
- I won't be much of a model.
- That simply won't do.
That's why I want us to dine together.
What do you think?
Or would you prefer to eat
with your mommy?
What mischief are you planning now?
Do you love your mother?
Of course I do.
She raised a blind boy all by herself.
She taught me to read and write,
to live as a human.
I couldn't do without her in my life.
Was it always just the two of you?
Where's your father?
He died of an illness
soon after I was born.
Any friends, any lovers?
Not one.
So you've never had a woman?
You poor thing.
That's why you built this studio.
You prefer cold clay
to a living, breathing woman.
Mother is the only woman I know.
Now I know why you make
such gigantic figures.
They're from a baby's perspective.
You love to nestle in their arms
like a baby.
I wonder...
But a real woman is totally different.
If you had a lover, you'd know.
It's so much more fun.
Is that right?
Well? What will you do,
eat with me or with Mommy?
I'll eat with you.
I'm thrilled!
- I'd like a drink, too.
- Alcohol?
You like a drink, don't you?
It gives you an appetite.
No. I've never tried alcohol.
Eh? You've never tasted alcohol?
You poor thing.
It's sublimely delicious!
Really?
I love wine. Go buy some.
Is this another trick?
You get me drunk and then run away?
You're so suspicious.
Your mother wouldn't let me past.
I've given up trying to escape.
Is that true?
Will your mother get angry
if you dine with me?
Not at all.
She'll do anything I ask her to.
I wonder
I'll bring you some dinner and a drink.
That was an excellent meal.
I've eaten every scrap.
Alcohol tastes wonderful, doesn't it?
Is my face flushed?
It has a lovely glow!
Other than my mother,
you're the first person I've dined with.
Was it fun?
Shall we continue doing it?
Yes.
- Are you still angry?
- No.
So, shall we get back to work?
Well, I'll put these away first.
Just leave them.
Your mother will do it anyway.
Carry me up there.
You've finished the arms and legs.
What's bit's next?
- I want to do your breasts.
- Right...
Go on, touch them.
Your fingers are very delicate,
but ever so masculine.
- It feels wonderful.
- So why did you object to being my model?
At first, I didn't like the idea.
But I've gradually grown to like you.
I didn't realize just how gentle you are.
I can hardly believe it.
There's not another man
who worships my body like you.
What about that photographer Yamana?
No, it's different with him.
I'm just another model to him.
But I'm your one and only.
We women are conceited, we need
to dominate. I'm very, very lucky.
I really love you.
It's another trick! You're lying!
Don't you believe me?
I'll show you proof.
Do you still doubt me?
I'll keep going
until you change your mind.
No, I believe you.
I really do.
I always thought being blind
would repel most women.
Do you love me?
Of course I do.
- Was that your first ever kiss?
- Yes.
Did you enjoy it?
Tongues are far more sensitive
than fingers.
So warm, soft and sweet.
Right, you try it this time.
Michio!
What is it, Mother?
Stop playing around
and get back to your work!
Your mother seems angry.
I wonder why.
She's shocked.
It's the first time she's seen me
in a woman's arms.
There's so much I can teach you.
Things only a lover knows
and a mother cannot do.
Michio! It's almost dawn.
You need your sleep.
Don't overtax yourself.
I want to keep going.
Be happy for me, she's helping me
make a unique work of art.
Really? That's wonderful.
And she loves me.
- She actually loves me.
- Nonsense!
It sounds unlikely,
but it's the honest truth.
You idiot!
Can't you see she's fooling you?
When you let your guard down,
she'll escape.
I really have fallen in love with him.
I could stay here forever.
Don't be ridiculous!
No flighty young thing like you
would ever fall for a man like Michio!
What's that supposed to mean?
Am I so repellent?
I know very well what she's up to.
She's making a fool
of a blind country bumpkin!
- Is that right?
- Oh, I get it now.
Your mother's jealous.
She's bad-mouthing me
for stealing her precious son.
Jealous? Mother's jealous?
Yes!
You're more than a son to her,
you know.
She's substituted you
for her husband or a lover.
So she sees me as her rival.
Shut up!
I can understand it, but it disgusts me.
Especially at her age.
Is she right, Mother?
I won't stand by and watch her
make a total fool out of you!
Mother, I'm an adult.
I want you to stop being jealous.
I'm free to fall in love, aren't I?
Oh, really?
Then do as you please!
You're free to go.
- What did you say?
- Get dressed and get out of here.
- I can leave?
- Yes!
If you go to the police, I'll get you back.
If it takes my whole life, I swear.
I understand.
There's money in your bag.
Go and hail a taxi.
Hurry up.
Mother?
Where are you going?
It's snowing, and we're freezing,
so I'm just going to get some coal.
Out of my way.
Why aren't you going alone?
Why do you have to take her with you?
Mother?
Alright, I'll tell you straight.
- I'm getting rid of her.
- But why?
The sculpture isn't finished yet.
You can find another girl.
I'll help you find one.
Don't you understand?
It has to be her.
Her type are a dime a dozen!
She's unique.
I'll never find another like her.
Michio, please!
Forget all about her!
No!
What are you doing, Mother?
Michio, listen to me.
I've done everything
you've ever asked for.
I helped you buy
and then build the studio.
Just once, do this one thing for me!
Please, get rid of her!
No, never!
- Mother...
- How dare you do this to me?
Have you forgotten how I sacrificed
everything to raise you?
It wasn't easy to raise a blind child!
And who was it who gave birth
to a blind child?
It was you!
Don't you ever forget, Michio,
that I did my utmost
to raise you properly.
This girl's the exact opposite!
She loves only herself,
she has no feelings for you.
If you don't get rid of her now,
you'll suffer for it.
She's not like that.
She's sweet and kind.
You have no idea
about the outside world.
And you know absolutely nothing
about women!
A slut like her is nothing but trouble!
- A slut, am I?
- Of course!
That's what we call women
who bare their bodies for money.
You call it "art", but it's just greed
and grasping for fame.
I'm not like that.
I'm a virgin,
I've lead a good, honest life.
Don't make me laugh!
How did you fool Michio?
Go on, tell me!
What kind of mother
humiliates her son's lover?
I know what you're trying to do.
You want your little boy to stay forever.
You want to sleep with him.
What did you say?
I feel sorry for Michio.
With a mother like you,
he can never find love.
Always alone, Mommy's little plaything.
Shut your mouth!
Is that what you want?
To never experience physical love?
Always a boy, never a real man?
I love you!
I want to be with you.
Is she more important to you
than me?
How could you?
I want to save you from her.
I'll even marry you.
On the one condition
that you cut all ties to her.
Any real mother would be pleased
to raise a son and send him into the world.
Don't you agree?
You bitch!
Mother!
What are you doing?
Please stop it!
Mother!
Please, Mother!
Stop it!
Help me!
I'll kill you! Die, you bitch!
I can't breathe!
Help me!
Mother, stop it!
I can't breathe!
Let her go!
She's killing me!
Mother, will you stop it?
Are you alright? Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
Something's wrong with your mother.
What's that?
She's dead.
Dead?
Mother! What's happened?
Mother!
She fell against the pillar.
She must've hit her head.
Mother...
What have I done to you?
You loved me so much.
You took such care of me!
How could I go and kill you?
Mother, please forgive me!
It was my fault!
I was so stupid.
Please forgive me!
You will stay, won't you?
You're running away?
Let me go, please!
She was right.
You lied about loving me.
Let me go! I'm sick of this!
You deliberately provoked my mother.
Didn't you?
All you want is to escape.
Of course!
How can I possibly stay here?
Let me go!
You despicable woman,
deceiving a blind man.
It was you who killed my mother!
It's no use fighting back.
You're coming with me!
Kill me! Just kill me!
I'd rather be dead than suffer this!
You won't get away now.
I won't let you go.
In place of Mother,
you'll be here till you die! I.
You said I was a mama's boy,
not a man, didn't you?
You laughed and said my work
is a poor substitute for a real woman.
Right... I'll prove to you I'm a man.
I'll take your virginity!
You animal!
Yes, the beast who killed his mother.
I can do anything now!
You're all mine, and I'll have you.
You'll be my woman.
I'd rather die!
No, you don't.
You'll make a man of me.
I'll show you love.
Then you'll know.
Several days passed.
We buried his mother
under the dirt floor of the old warehouse.
In the studio, with total disregard
for day or night,
he made love to me repeatedly.
By the time he had finished
the sculpture,
I'd started to develop
a slight affection for him.
Do you still want to leave here?
To leave me and go back
to the outside world?
Not now.
It's strange, but I seem
to have forgotten that world.
Have you given up
because you can't escape?
That's not it.
I don't hate you anymore.
Why is that?
Making love with you has been wonderful.
You're so strong, yet so gentle.
You've shown me
the true beauty of a woman.
Sculptures are inanimate.
They can never match the feel
of a real woman.
You are far superior.
At the same time
as I was falling in love with him,
I, too, began to go blind.
Darling.
I'm going blind.
Here, in constant darkness,
only feeling and caressing your body,
my eyes have atrophied,
and I've started to go blind.
So, you're like me now.
Is it a disability? Are you sad?
Quite the opposite.
People pity the blind.
What a big mistake.
I pity those who have sight.
They can never know
the tactile ecstasy of our caresses.
You finally understand.
I do.
My sense of touch is so acute.
So sweet, so deep, yet so certain.
Shape, form and color can't even approach
our tactile level of artistic expression.
So I'm not crazy, am I?
You're not insane, you're amazing.
Your sense of touch
is almost not human.
I envy you.
Someday, you shall reach
the same level as me.
How I wish that day would come.
The sensation at the tip of my fingers
has become so acute
I can almost "taste".
As sensitive as insect feelers
and animal whiskers.
Like the lower orders of life,
without eyes, only able to feel.
Like an amoeba, or a jellyfish,
at the dawn of life.
The same sensations
as the most primeval creature.
As if going back to the womb
of human creation,
so dark, so sweet
and so pervadingly familiar.
When I look with my eyes,
you're a different man
from the one I feel.
How different?
You look normal,
but to the touch, you're divine.
These small depressions,
the large curves and projections.
As I caress your body,
I perceive constant variations.
Like the flow of a musical masterpiece.
- Delicious fun!
- Is that right?
Again, days flew by.
We both explored
the innermost secrets of our bodies.
The most subtle and shaded nuance
of each other's flesh.
But in our tactile world
of touch and feeling,
we discovered unwritten,
unrelenting, natural laws.
So much pleasure only spurred an
ever-increasing demand for more sensation,
seeking greater satisfaction,
an unquenchable desire
for ever more pleasure.
More!
Harder!
Like this?
Not enough.
Bite me, bite me hard!
Like this?
Even harder.
Make me bleed.
More?
Harder!
That feels so good!
Now it's my turn. You bite me.
That was the beginning.
We began to take our pleasure
through biting, clawing,
and beating our bodies
in a rage of sensation.
The pain-pleasure from nails, teeth
and fists gradually declined in intensity.
We began using various devices
to stimulate each other.
Whip me!
The more I suffered,
the more I craved.
What is it within
that brings forth such ecstasy?
Does it mean that I was born
with masochistic tendencies?
Had I arrived at the point
where natural law
and the sensations of pleasure collide?
We couldn't stop ourselves.
We escalated
from innocuous devices of pleasure
until we turned to knives
to extract our ecstasy.
You really want me to cut you?
Go ahead.
Where?
Anywhere.
Wherever you want.
Here?
Cut me. Cut me. Hurry.
Does it hurt?
It's agony,
but exquisite!
Hurt me more!
Cover me with scars!
How's that?
More. I don't care if I die.
Give it everything.
You want me to cut you up?
You like that pain?
Cut me deeper.
Cut deep into me and twist the knife.
Are you alright?
It's so good!
Drink more of my blood!
Now... it's your turn.
That's when we began the inhuman rite
of drinking each other's blood.
The ecstasy of it marked our descent
into a nonhuman abyss.
But constant bliss, such as we felt,
was never destined to last for long.
The stench of his mother's corpse
began to fill the studio.
Our bodies cut and scarred
as if from battle,
the loss of blood and constant pain
began to sap our vitality.
We won't last much longer, will we?
I can barely muster the strength to stand.
All we have left is
to wait for death to claim us.
Do you regret it now?
Why should I?
I've feasted on a bliss
that most people
never even know exists.
- I'm ready to die any time.
- Are you?
Listen... I've got a good idea.
What is it?
If we're to die anyway
make it an ecstatic death for me.
Bring me to tears of joy!
But how?
Cut my arms off.
And my legs as well.
Cut this body of mine into pieces.
Why?
I'm sure it will be agony,
but also the ultimate ecstasy.
As I reach that climax,
make it my moment of death.
You prefer that
to a slow, lingering death?
Of course.
I beg you!
I understand.
I'll die with you.
To have my arms and legs
cut from my body.
What a fitting punishment
for our sybaritic descent
into a world where touch was bliss.
I gave myself a death sentence.
I'll start to cut.
Good.
Are you happy?
Now the other arm.
Don't stop now. My legs.
Quickly.
The world of touch...
The world of insects...
The lower orders
such as the jellyfish...
Those who venture
to the edge of such worlds
can expect only a dark, dank death
to envelope them.
THE END