Dubey!
- Not here.
Not here yet?
He's an impossible fellow!
Nearly 1 1:00. How to fix this?
He wants money
but doesn't want to work.
Dubeyji? Lalit Verma, who else?
Very kind of you to answer.
What's going on? No sign of anyone.
Fry the pakoras.
Tea for the master. Hurry!
God forbid it!
The wedding is so soon.
Hundreds of things to get tense about.
The marigold gate is falling apart.
The flowers are everywhere.
What's going on?
No need to get so upset, sir.
Flowers? What's a few flowers?
For you, I'll bring Kashmir's Mughal garden.
Just say the word.
I'm stranded in a traffic jam.
Enough! Get here on the double.
Ten minutes, exactly and approximately.
I can't phone and drive.
What's the idiot up to?
Where were you?
You're incredible.
The guests are on their way.
Did you? Out with the truth!
These are our laws.
Change the constitution,
then censorship will follow.
What do you think?
Let's hear some dialogue
from the new script.
Go ahead, please.
Give it to me.
Come on.
More, big boy. More.
I like it like that.
Big boy, I like it.
Give me more.
Come inside me.
Give it to me.
Come!
If he wants the works,
then he must get the cash out.
The one-rupee era is over.
Tea anyone?
Four teas.
- King Dubey!
- At your service.
Gracing us with your presence?
Your daughter is my daughter.
Why worry?
The wedding is in four days.
Today, the engagement.
The groom is on his way.
Want me to lose face?
- Important call.
Call my pager, damn it!
More important things to do?
Now you're an event manager.
Fix this now!
- Yadav!
Tameez-ud-Din!
Lottery!
Get down. Fix it!
Insolent bums!
Want tea, do you? To work!
Right away!
Hi, Uncle!
King Dubey, move your van.
Move the van!
Where have you been?
How lovely!
Take it easy.
No, Ma.
I'll stop at the temple.
It may get late.
No, I won't eat at home.
I'll come late.
You can pack the food in the tiffin.
Forgive me.
Ma, leave the worrying
about the stock market to me.
I can deal with it.
Twelve rupees a minute
calling me on the mobile.
Hang up.
I saw cousin Aditi naked,
and I almost saw you naked too.
Enough.
Get dressed for the engagement.
What is it, my child?
In God's name,
what on earth is written here?
There is no such word, my child.
It's a spelling mistake.
There should be an L here.
It's "luxurious."
Brought the whiskey?
Anyone about?
Let's take the whiskey in.
Australian idiot-you!
We're hardly late.
You get tense for nothing.
Talk fast.
Can't catch the network.
Let me come down.
One minute!
Speak. No, no, no.
Yes, I'll be there.
That's correct. Take the advance.
Life's such a comedy.
No signal up there.
But there's one down here.
The virtuous virgin look
really suits me.
Breasts like baby mangoes.
The groom!
The groom's here!
Congratulations, Mr. Rai!
Pay your respects to Grandmother.
Look what I have for you.
Know why God arranged
your marriage in a hurry?
I told him I had to see
a great-grandson before dying.
He heard me!
How beautiful!
So fair and lovely.
Say hello to Hemant.
Enough!
I met C.L. only once,
and we got married right away!
Don't you feel like getting married?
Sweeten your mouths, my dears.
Just in time!
My dear brother-in-law!
Look at him.
What a complete idiot!
Calls my son an idiot,
then calls him a duffer.
Who does he think he is?
I'm not coming back to India.
My naughty niece,
couldn't you wait?
The motherfucker doesn't have
a dime to his name,
and he wants the White House theme
for his daughter's wedding!
How the fuck will that happen?
The swine hasn't any shit in him,
and he invites other pigs for dinner!
What?
- We need more ice.
- What?
I've told them once.
I've told them a thousand times
they'll need ice.
They never listen.
Now what?
Do you need some water?
Water?
Okay.
Fridge water or tap water?
Fridge water.
Our eyes made the right signal
And I found a partner for life
Shut up, you assholes!
I quit.
America makes everyone quit smoking.
The Rais are so cultured.
Speak a little English and you become
a very cultured family.
Rai!
Make her understand.
Lots of money in writing these days.
That girl who won the Booker Prize
became an overnight millionaire!
Two weddings in one!
I have anotherjoke.
Nonvegetarian!
Let me start rehearsing, then.
I won't listen to you
or to Ria's mother.
I can still work.
This is India's big problem.
Alice, has the fuse blown?
Alice! Get the phone.
When are you arriving?
Yes, yes. She's here,
swinging on my shoulders.
The line's cut.
Sisterfucker, what a pain!
All the fuses have blown.
Pardon?
Which is the house fuse?
This one?
I'll fix it right away.
The light, a little closer, please.
A little to this side, please.
A little lower.
Your shadow is in the way.
A little closer.
Trying to say something?
It's hot today.
Switch it on. The power is back.
What a silly asshole I am.
Eat, Son, eat!
What is it?
Some gratitude.
We are so grateful, dear Pimmi.
This wedding is driving me crazy!
Today will be a long day.
It's hot, too, after all that rain.
May I have...
a glass ofwater?
I'm very thirsty.
What is your good name?
It's an English name.
Where are you from?
- Bihar.
What's your name?
Parbatlal Kanhaiyalal Dubey.
But I've changed it to P.K. Dubey.
But it makes people laugh.
In the city, they call me Dubeyji.
Parbatlal is a nice name.
They're newly printed.
I'm into event management.
It has the address to send mail
through the computer.
You know about it? Yes.
Keep it. Take some more.
This is fine.
Tell me you love me.
Have you seen the movie
Tell Me You Love Me?
Yes.
What happened?
Nothing happened.
I must be going.
Tell me something.
How many weddings
have I organized so far?
At least 150 or 175.
How come I'm not married yet?
My poor mother has grown old saying,
"Son, get me a daughter-in-law."
Now I've done my thinking.
I'll put an end
to my lonesome, vagabond life.
I'll find myself a decent, simple girl
and begin life as a family man.
The hope now is that
the next tent Dubey puts up
has Dubey entering as the groom.
Bravo!
I swear, pure genius!
Motherfucker.
Do I pay you to sit on your ass?
Get to work!
Coming, sir.
Not a minute of peace.
This is the limit. A white tent?
A white tent?
- Yes, sir.
- What's this "yes, sir"?
What's with the white tent?
This is the fashion these days.
Millennium style. Y2K dot.
Smart-ass!
A white tent!
Is this a wedding or a funeral?
I only have one daughter.
I don't want a white tent.
Put up a colorful tent.
Red, yellow, green, blue.
Okay. Yadav!
Get this down. It's not wanted.
He wants the old look.
Get it down.
What about the waterproofing?
It was never discussed.
What do you mean, Dubey?
The peacocks have stopped dancing.
It won't rain.
Peacocks? You've been smoking pot?
Okay, sir. Advance.
In foreign countries, deal is deal.
Look, sir.
See, everything in foreign style.
In writing.
The number of plates and spoons.
But no waterproofing.
You want more? Pay more.
How much?
$5,000.
I'm not a nonresident Indian.
Your garden is huge.
Well, your daughter is my daughter.
Advance, sir.
Today we work. Tomorrow, holiday.
Strike, day after.
Then our wedding.
- This is all I have now.
I'll give you the rest later.
This won't pay for a thing.
You'll fall sick.
A Popsicle, now?
This one's for Hemant's sister.
You bought one
for his cousin in Bangalore?
So many cousins!
Look at this silk sari.
So smooth,
even a fly could slide on it.
Once your eyes behold its beauty,
the fly has gone.
It's too gaudy.
- Who's the bride?
- She's having a Popsicle outside.
Come!
Put them properly.
Over there.
All right.
Not a single flower in place yet.
I knew it. She's a thief!
Mother fucker.
Mother fuckers!
She's not stealing. Fucking ass holes!
You don't come to golf these days.
I'm busy with my daughter's wedding.
How much do you need, pal?
$1 2,000.
A daughter's wedding,
that's what happens.
Or I'd be wiped out.
O women of the house
Decorate me with henna
Make these fair hands
beautiful with henna
Madhorama asks
Which one shall we marry
Madhorama says
The Fat One
The Fat One needs
too large a bed to sleep on
- Let's drop her by the wayside
- Right on
- We want another
We are fancy gentlemen
Brimming with lust and desire
Life intoxicates us
Do I lie
- No way
Madhorama asks
Which one shall we marry
Madhorama says
The Fair One
The Fair One has the color of butter
She sleeps alone on the roof
as her lover pines for her below
This is the one we'll have
This is the one we like
We will marry her
Shashi, remember
when we were newly weds?
Lalit and my brother would sleep.
You'd come to my room
and tell me dirty jokes.
Your Lalit may have gone to sleep,
but my C.L. would never sleep,
nor would he let me sleep!
Go! No men allowed!
Stick with me.
You'll have fun with me!
Cash in on the pleasures of life with me.
I'm giving birth!
Lemon juice. The henna's drying.
As I leave
for my father-in-law's house
I will take your dreams with me
The gift of bracelets
Binds me in marriage