Daiei Co., Ltd.
A Daiei / Nippon Television Network /
/ Hakuhodo / Imagica Production
Change course.
Direction, 120 degrees.
Roger, hard to port.
Hard to port.
I need navigational information.
It all began one day...
without warning...
like this...
Still no answer at Taguchi's?
No.
It's been a week.
He must have his reasons.
It shouldn't take a whole week
to work on that disk.
No...
Something's wrong.
Maybe I should see if he's okay.
I just got the creeps.
What?
I don't know, I just feel
like something's wrong.
Like something's... horribly wrong.
What's up with Taguchi?
I don't know.
If we don't get that disk now,
we're in real trouble.
The deadline's tomorrow.
I know that.
What am I supposed to do?
We haven't heard a thing.
I think I'd better go see
how he's doing.
A KUROSAWA Kiyoshi film
Taguchi?
PULSE
(Kairo)
Hey, you are here.
Hey, Michi...
I was worried about you.
You haven't called.
Right, sorry.
Did you finish working on that disk?
Yeah, it's somewhere in that pile.
You okay? Are you sick?
No...
What have you been up to,
all on your lonesome? We're friends.
Yeah... Stuff...
Help yourself to the disk.
You ought to label your disks.
This it?
The one marked Work File?
Taguchi?
Michi.
Oh, Junco.
You okay? Was it awful?
I'm fine.
I'd say it's break time.
Oh, I forgot. Here.
Thanks.
It's so upsetting.
I don't know what he was
so depressed about.
He never said anything,
so what could we have done?
Maybe...
he suddenly just wanted to die.
I get that way sometimes.
It's so easy to hang yourself.
Hey! Why so gloomy?
Oh, sorry.
About Taguchi?
It's just... If only I'd...
He seemed like the Taguchi I know.
I never imagined
he'd do something like that.
Time to put it behind us.
Besides, it wasn't your fault.
Yeah...
Say... Would you take a look?
At what?
Taguchi's disk.
What is it?
It's Taguchi's place.
Is that Taguchi?
Yeah, I think so.
Look.
What's going on?
Isn't that the same scene?
I can't tell.
Hey, look.
That's a face...
A reflection.
You're right.
Can you blow it up?
Let me see...
That was Taguchi, wasn't it?
Sure seems like it.
What's going on?
Maybe something strange is going on.
Strange?
I don't know.
I don't even care anymore.
Something's definitely not right.
A message in a bottle
launched 10 years ago
by a boy
on Tanegashima Island
was recently discovered
on a beach in Malaysia
some 4,000 kms away.
Hikono Koichi was
a 4th grader when
he sent off his message.
Members of a local group,
cleaning up the beach,
a sea turtle habitat,
discovered the bottle by accident.
I never imagined it would find its way
to some foreign country.
I was shocked to get an answer
after 10 years.
The group located Hikono
through his former
elementary school.
Next, the National Weather Service
forecasts another unseasonably
hot summer, it's the 3rd
for eastern Japan...
for western Japan...
Northern Japan... will...
"Welcome to the Internet."
No, this way, here.
Okay.
Next, okay.
Next.
"Have Fun."
Okay, I'll have fun.
Done. "Okay."
What's this crap?
Yes, I agree.
Next...
What? I guess that's okay.
Next again, huh?
What?
What the... oh, well...
What the hell...
Hey... this...
Who's... what's...
Would you like to meet a ghost?
Stupid crap!
What the...
Maybe you should change
the size on this batch file.
Using the variable?
Yeah.
So you'll find its property, right?
Oh, conventional memory.
Right.
See.
So that's how you do it.
Say...
Can the internet dial you up itself?
You in computer science?
No, economics.
No relation.
Huh... Sounds like a hacker.
A hacker...
Huh...
It said,
"Do you want to meet a ghost?"
Some website like that.
A ghost, huh...
Which website was that?
What?
Something about meeting ghosts?
I don't really know.
It just appeared last night.
Know the address?
What? Um... address?
I see.
Windows?
Yeah.
Open the Explorer log...
Oh, no, no, I really don't know
anything about computers.
The next time the site shows up,
click on it to bookmark it.
Not so fast.
Click...
Can you repeat that?
Click on it.
Click... on... it...
To bookmark it.
To...
bookmark it.
If that doesn't work,
you know the print screen key?
Yeah, this one?
Try pressing it.
If it doesn't work...
Print screen key.
Press the...
Print screen...
Got it.
Let me know?
Sure.
See you.
Don't bother with that, Mom.
What? Sure.
Are you eating this junk again?
It's not good for you.
I'm going now.
Have you called your father?
Nope.
I see...
but what if you get in trouble?
I can't rush over.
It's awkward for me to see him,
but you should.
Forget it.
He's out of the picture.
He lives here in Tokyo.
But Tokyo's huge.
I know, but...
I'm fine. I've got my friends.
You sure?
I guess you'll be all right then.
You're so trusting
and get carried away...
Hello.
Help...
Who's this?
What is this...
The Forbidden Room
Taguchi?
What happened, Taguchi...
What?
What am I saying?
What happened to Yabe?
Try his house?
No answer.
Huh...
I hope nothing's wrong.
Oh, no. What's he up to?
I've got to go see him.
No! Don't go!
He'll turn up. He'll come if we wait!
Nothing strange has happened yet.
Yeah...
Let's just act normal.
Yeah, at least for today.
Sorry, I'm late.
Sure, sure.
Where were you? Why didn't you call?
Hey!
Can you believe, he's ignoring us!
What's going on?
Who cares...
What do I do now?
Click it...
and bookmark it.
Doesn't work.
If that doesn't work,
press the print screen key.
There.
Hi.
You're the one...
Um...
Kawashima.
Yeah, Kawashima.
I'm Karasawa Harue.
Harue-san, Harue-san.
How'd it go?
Well, it came back again.
Really?
Yeah.
And...
I pressed that print screen key...
Right.
Can I come over and check it out?
Yeah, sure, absolutely fine.
I just need a minute.
Um...
What's this?
That? Something we programmed here.
If two dots get too close, they die,
but if they get too far apart,
they're drawn closer.
Huh... what's it for?
A miniature model of our world...
But only the grad student
who designed it understands it.
I wouldn't...
suggest staring at it for too long.
Sorry, it's a mess.
Thank you.
There you go.
Getting the data?
Yeah, almost set.
What got you started on the internet?
Nothing in particular...
You don't like computers, right?
No.
Wanted to connect with other people?
Maybe... I don't know.
Everybody else is into it.
People don't really connect, you know.
What?
Like those dots simulating humans.
We all live totally separately.
That's how it seems to me.
Oh... Huh...
I wonder...
Yabe...
Kudo-san.
Yes.
Can you move these orchids
into the greenhouse?
Yes.
Um, boss...
Yes?
Isn't Yabe acting strange?
You think so?
Can I go check on him?
Fine, but...
It might be a waste of time.
Words said in friendship with
the best of intentions...
always wind up
hurting your friends deeply.
And then you wind up getting hurt.
Is friendship always that way?
If that's so, what's left?
If I were you...
Who needs friends like that?
A courageous choice in itself.
Are you okay?
Did something happen?
If something happened,
let's talk about it.
Both Junco and I ...
are really worried.
I saw...
A face...
What?
A horrible face...
I've never seen anything like it...
What are you saying?
What did you see?
The Forbidden Room.
Forbidden Room? What's that?
Is that...
the room with the red tape?
Don't dare go in there!
Please...
tell me.
What happened?
I'm cold.
Yabe...
Are you okay?
Exit
Harue.
Hi.
I don't really use the library much.
Couldn't find the way out.
Phantoms
You reading this?
Yeah.
Is it related to your
work in the lab?
Yeah.
Huh...
Do you have a minute?
What? Sure.
Come.
Isn't it strange?
Yeah... sort of...
Almost like ghosts, right?
You're right, they're like ghosts.
Sometimes, these turn up.
At first, they look
like the other dots.
What are they?
I don't know.
A bug?
No.
That website...
What?
Oh, what happened with that?
Nothing... yet...
Huh...
But I think they're related
I'm sure they're related.
You think?
Let me know if anything happens.
Yeah, sure.
Karasawa-san.
I need you to check this.
Yes.
And you are?
My friend, Kawashima.
Huh...
The grad student, Yoshizaki-san.
Hello.
I forgot to give you my number.
Oh, right.
Call me, okay?
Right.
Anytime, okay?
Yeah.
Thank you.
"Everyone dies, therefore there's no
logical reason for ghosts not to exist.
"How many ghosts have...
"existed since prehistoric times..."
Do you see it too?
Sure you do, because it's really there.
Who is that?
You'll have to catch him to find out.
Start right now and you might succeed.
Have a go?
What?
Why don't you, right now?
He disappeared.
I see.
He must be a student...
I don't know him.
Maybe you're right.
Sorry I encouraged you.
See you.
Wait a minute.
Just what was that?
I'm cold...
The spirit...
Or consciousness, the soul,
whatever you want to call it,
it turns out the realm they
inhabit has a finite capacity.
Whether that capacity
accommodates billions or trillions...
eventually, it will run out of space.
Once it's filled to the brim...
it's got to overflow somehow, somewhere.
But where?
The souls have no choice
but to ooze into another realm,
that is to say, our world.
Maybe, at first...
it started with something really simple
Once that realm reached critical mass...
any device would have sufficed.
Thrown it together with
the means and materials at hand.
That's how I see it.
Excuse me, do you have any tape?
Anything'll do, some tape.
How's this?
Thank you.
After many hours or days...
or many weeks, it finally happens.
Through that process,
it spread around the world.
But now they're no longer
the faint presence they began as.
You saw one yourself.
I don't believe your stories.
Right, sorry, it's all hypothetical.
Thanks for the tea.
Are you okay?
Just fine.
But if this really happened,
there's no turning back.
No matter how simple the device,
once the system's complete,
it'll function on its own...
and become permanent.
In other words...
the passage is now open...
that's how it looks.
Hello.
Oh, I see, our boss isn't there?
Yes, I understand.
If he does stop by,
will you please ask him to call us?
Yes, thank you very much.
Michi...
what do you think's going on?
Why's everyone disappearing?
Oh, hello.
This is Sunny Plant Sales calling.
Thank you for your business.
Is our boss there with you
by any chance?
Oh, I see... Thank you, and excuse me.
I'll go look for him.
Wait, Junco, wait.
Yes, hello...
Boss?
Help.
Yabe!
Are you Yabe?
Help me...
Help...
Junco...
Junco!
Junco, no!
Are you okay?
Junco.
Help me...
Junco!
Look, I'm right here.
I'm right here, it's okay.
Excuse me.
Karasawa Harue
tel. : 090-4079-2677
What are you doing, Harue!
You're dripping wet!
They went away...
They've all disappeared...
They always do...
I have to run away...
Run away somewhere...
Harue!
Hey, Harue!
Listen, Harue!
Harue!
Calm down! Harue!
Thank you...
I always wondered
what it's like to die...
From when I was really little...
I was always alone.
Any parents or family?
Sure, but they're irrelevant.
Right...
That after death...
you live happily with
everyone over there.
Can we stop talking about this?
But it may be true.
Sure, but...
Then in high school it dawned on me...
you might be all alone
after death, too.
There's no way to know.
How could you?
The idea was so terrifying.
I couldn't even bear it.
That nothing changes with death,
just right now, forever.
Is that what becoming
a ghost is about?
You can't mess with that.
It's really bad.
What have ghosts got to do with us?
Besides, we're alive.
Then, who are they?
Are they really alive?
How are they different from ghosts?
In fact...
ghosts and people are the same...
whether they're dead or alive.
It's not right. It's wrong.
They're all crazy.
Nobody knows what happens
when you die.
All this about ghosts, but I won't
believe in them, even if I see one.
But I do know...
that I'm definitely alive
and so are you, Harue.
That's for sure, right?
So I don't want to think about
the fact we'll die someday.
Just maybe...
in 10 years, or at least
while we're still alive...
they'll invent a drug
that prevents death.
Then, we could live forever and ever.
Of course you might think
I'm crazy to say that, but...
I'd rather bet on that.
You want to live forever?
Yeah.
That sounds like fun?
Yeah... That's what I think.
Huh... Maybe I've got it all wrong.
No...
It'll turn out just like you say.
I'm sure.
What?
Ghosts won't kill people.
Because that would just
make more ghosts.
Isn't that right?
Instead, they'll try
to make people immortal.
By quietly...
trapping them in their own loneliness.
Help...
Junco, it'll be okay.
It'll be okay.
Okay...
I fell asleep...
How do you feel?
Yeah.
Something to drink?
How about some coffee?
Michi...
What?
Am I just going to die like this?
Of course not.
That's right...
I'll just keep on living, all alone...
What?
No.
Junco!
Junco.
Why! Why!
Junco, don't go!
Junco.
Mother?
Mother!
I'll be right there.
Harue...
Harue! Hey...
Kawashima... take me with you.
I'm scared to be alone.
Take me somewhere.
Okay, sure.
Where to?
Somewhere far away.
Out of Order
Shit, let's just go!
There's no one...
No...
Where did everyone go?
I'm here.
I'm here beside you.
Even if...
there's no one else,
it doesn't matter.
We are both definitely here.
Guess that's true...
What happened!
I've got to go back!
What? No! We've come this far!
But this is the end of the line.
That's not true.
It'll start moving.
I'll go check with the driver.
Come with me.
Okay, but promise
you'll wait right here.
I'll be right back.
Promise.
Harue!
The Forbidden Room
Construction Materials - red tape
I'm...
Not alone...
Harue,
it's me, Kawashima.
Harue! Listen!
Listen, what do you say to this...
The two of us live together.
That way, we can always be together.
If we keep living alone,
we'll get worse and worse
because we're weak.
We'll balance each other out.
How 'bout living that way?
Would you try it with me?
What do you think, Harue? Listen!
Harue!
Tokyo: Missing
Sakai Mitsuo
Yamazaki Naoko
Kanagawa: Missing
Hirayama Michio
Kawahara Takumi
Saitama: Missing
Tomioka Shigeki
Tokyo: Missing
Yoshida Tomoko
Nakajima Kumi
Kanagawa: Missing
Kitaoka Eri
Tokyo: Missing
Fukuda Tatsuya
Um... are you okay?
Breakdown?
Yeah.
Want some?
You are?
Oh, me? Um...
What are you doing here?
What am I doing here...
You?
So neither your dad nor your mum...
made it through...
No...
So many things happened at once...
it's impossible to sort them all out.
Yeah.
Me too. My head's all messed up.
So you're a student, Kawashima?
Yeah.
Lucky you.
I don't think so.
Here.
Oh, thanks...
And you?
I had a job.
Wow, amazing.
Nothing amazing.
Did you have any friends?
Friends?
Maybe one, I guess.
What was she like?
What? I don't really know...
I never really found out...
Where is she?
Somewhere...
Okay, try starting it.
Okay, good.
Why don't you look for her?
What?
She's still somewhere, right?
You've got to help her then.
But...
Let's go find her. I'll help you.
This is the last stop...
After that we go as far as we can.
I can sort of see...
The future...
Help Help Help Help Help
Look over there.
An abandoned factory?
I wonder...
Shall we try it?
Listen, even if you see
a door sealed with red tape,
don't go near it, okay?
I know.
You okay?
Look... at this.
Look... over there.
Kawashima.
Harue!
Watch out!
What happened, Harue!
What are you doing with that?
Let's get out of this place together.
Together?
Yeah.
C'mon, hand it over.
Harue! Harue!
Oh, no, a hospital...
Harue! Don't die!
C'mon! Please!
Help me!
Harue!
We couldn't save her...
No...
We're out of gas...
I'll get some, there was gas back there.
You'll be okay?
Wait for me. I'll be okay.
Forever...
Death was...
Eternal loneliness...
Help.
Don't ask me!
What's that got to do with me!
Forever...
Death was...
Eternal loneliness...
You're not real.
I refuse to acknowledge... Never...
I refuse to acknowledge death!
I know.
I'll catch you.
Then you'll disappear.
That's it, right! Right!
You can't beat me!
I am...
Real...
Kawashima!
What is it?
Forget it... Let's go...
It's too much...
What... are you doing?
You went in there...
Me?
Yeah, I did, but I'm fine.
Don't cry.
You want to go back?
To what's left of Harue?
That make you feel better?
I that's what you want,
I'll go with you.
No...
Let's go...
As far as we can go.
Are you sure about that?
Yeah.
Can you get out?
You okay?
Be careful.
Wait here, okay?
Death comes to us all...
If so, maybe we would've been happier
if we had gone with the rest.
But we chose to keep going...
into the future...
We'll head for Latin America.
We're still getting signals there.
Though they're pretty weak.
We've got to give it a try...
no matter what we find.
If anyone's survived...
we can head out again...
and go as far as we can.
C'mon, be strong.
Have I done the right thing?
Yes.
Are you sure?
You're doing the right thing.
Now, alone with my
last friend in the world...
I have found happiness.
CAST
Kawashima: KATO Haruhiko
Michi: ASO Kumiko
Harue: KO YUKl
Junco: ARISAKA Kurume
Yabe: MATSUO Masatoshi
The Boss: SUGATA Shun
Taguchi: MIZUHASH I Keniji
The Ghost: SHIONOYA Masayuki
The Worker: AIKAWA Show
Michi's mother: FUBUKI Jun
Yoshizaki: TAKEDA Shiniji
The Captain: YAKUSHO Koji
Executive Producer:
TOKUMA Yasuyoshi
Producers: SH IM IZU Shun
OKUDA Seiji
Producers: INOUE Ken
SH IMODA Atsuyuki
Director of Photography:
HAYASHI Junichiro
Lighting Director:
TOM IYAMA Meicho
Production Designer:
MARUO Tomoyuki
Sound: IKA Makio
Editor: KIKUCHI Junichi
Music Producer: WADA Toru
Composer: HAKETA Takefumi
Theme Song by: Cocco
"Wings ~ lay down my arms ~"
Visual Effects: ASANO Shuji
Written and Directed by:
KUROSAWA Kiyoshi