Get out.
Step up and state your name, loud!
My name is Yeh Ming.
Yeh Ming, 37 years old. 7 years
for armed robbery and assault.
Go over!
Go over there!
Next, quickly!
Sir!
My name is Li Shan!
Li Shan, 28 years old.
5 years for embezzlement.
Go!
Stand over there.
Next!
Ricky Ho.
Step up!
Ricky Ho, 21 years old.
10 years for manslaughter and assault.
I didn't say you could go.
Carrying weapons?
Sir!
Let him go now.
Why not let a doctor
extract the 5 bullets from you?
They're souvenirs.
Give the three the initiation lecture.
Go!
The warden is at the top.
The second in command
is the assistant warden.
The four cells are controlled
by the Gang of Four.
You're new
and ineligible the see the warden,
but you must learn the rules.
Damn, getting up so early?
Captain, that towel's mine.
What?
You're confronting me over a towel?
Wild Cat is bullying again.
He's head of the underworld and the cell too.
He's a crony of the cell guards.
He's taking the law into his own hands.
Down on your knees and kowtow to him.
This car really is cute.
I assembled it
with wooden scraps as a toy.
So it's for your children.
I hear your application
for probation has been fixed.
Is that so?
But you can't get it without my okay!
Behave or you'll suffer!
Wild Cat, you bastard!
What's up?
Sir, Ma's getting old and clumsy.
He ran and fell on a blade.
He's whining like a pig.
What a nuisance.
Stop screaming! You're blind!
Don't run wild.
Captain,
we haven't brushed our teeth yet.
Use them as brushes.
Big brother!
What now?
Bastard, going to hell?
Are you speaking to me?
Have breakfast!
Captain, drink your milk.
Without a straw, I can't!
To hell with you!
Damn.
Ricky doesn't give a damn about me!
I must teach him a lesson or lose
my North Cell Killer title forever!
Captain, why not have
Silly Lung finish him off?
Silly Lung?
Yeah! He was hungry
and ate a horse the other day.
He's still in solitary.
When will he be out?
Tomorrow!
Take my allowance for this month.
Great, I need money.
Watch out. Silly Lung
makes trouble each time he's out.
No one dares to take
responsibility for anything serious.
Take it easy.
Me?
What? My probation
was rejected from above?
The captain promised...
Did you write home secretly?
No, sir, I'm innocent.
I really am innocent, sir!
Innocent?
You lie!
I didn't lie, sir. Believe me.
I'm dying to see my wife
and children at home, sir.
I've yearned to see them
from the day I got jailed.
Stop it!
Don't...
You're unlucky.
Don't, sir!
Ma's hanging himself to death!
Wild Cat bad-mouthed him.
And the warden canceled his probation.
Ma really is unlucky.
He was a model citizen.
He ran down someone while
rushing his wife to the hospital.
It should have just
been a traffic offense,
but he faced more charges
because the victim was a police officer.
So he got sent over here.
Ricky, what are you doing?
Take off his handcuffs.
He's already dead.
Ricky, don't do anything foolish!
Off...
Hurry up!
Next shift!
Shower, clean your laundry,
and use the toilet within 15 minutes.
Ricky!
Someone gave me 30 kgs
of rice to bump you off
and to mince you into meat pies.
Can you make it?
Silly Lung, come on,
I bet heavy on you.
Stop fighting!
One move and
those two are down.
Another move and I'll knock
you down. Come with me.
Making trouble already...
I want to have
a word with that kid, sir!
You really have guts.
I've never seen you before.
Nor have I seen you.
I'm the north cell's leader,
and your big brother.
After the assistant warden punishes you,
you'll be disciplined by our family rules.
I'll take you to the assistant
warden tomorrow. What a nuisance.
Are you Mr. Ho's son, Ricky?
You are...
I'm Uncle Shan Kuei.
Your original name was Rick.
But you were as strong
as a bull at 7 or 8,
so I called you Ricky.
Have you grown up as strong?
Stronger, of course.
Let me see!
Good!
Uncle!
I'm coming.
Ricky, you're as strong
as when you were a child.
So Uncle knows focus and breath control.
I want to learn it
to be a martial artist and help the weak.
Breath control requires a mild temper.
It accumulates energy
in the human body
and turns it into an inestimable
power against attacks.
The accumulation of energy
should be made freely.
Break this stone with your limbs.
See how I do it.
Now, ounces prevailing over tons.
Ricky, learn how to borrow strength.
Get stronger when
facing strength. Try it.
Okay!
I'll take you to the assistant warden.
Sir!
The prisoner is here.
Tell him to come in.
Stop!
Read me that file.
Yes, sir!
Ricky Ho, 21, blood type AB.
Parents unknown,
brought up in an orphanage.
He didn't do well
in primary and middle schools.
He joined a music college
to learn the flute.
He suddenly
disappeared as a senior.
He disappeared for two years and
fought triad members in major cities.
Then he was found
guilty for killing a man.
He was found by the court
to be a serious criminal.
That's all.
Where were you for those two years?
What did you do?
What? Turning a deaf ear?
How come you have scars
from five bullets on your chest?
You'll be in jail for quite some time.
You'll confess sooner or later.
We received a letter
for you this morning.
It contains a photograph.
Come have a look.
Don't take me for a fool.
Let me show you something.
Let me see how good the man who
killed Silly Lung and Wild Cat is.
You can take pain.
Are you a trained killer?
Speak up!
Ricky, are you
a special agent or CID?
If you're on
a special mission, I can help you.
I once arranged the accidental death
of a prisoner suspected of espionage.
Dumb bastard, you'll hurt
the moment you open your mouth.
Bet I'll finish you off.
Or have a taste of your bird.
She's a beautiful bird.
Let me take off her clothing.
You won't give up until I fight back!
Easy!
The warden's not here.
I'm number one!
Lay hands on me
and you'll be a corpse!
Ricky!
You're good. You threatening me?
Don't poke your nose
into my private affairs!
The punch hurts,
even without touching me.
What kind of demon are you?
Let me fly it!
Let's fly it together.
I'd rather do it alone.
Ying, look!
Ying is the incarnation of two fireflies.
Come on...
Why play the trumpet at this hour?
A playboy keeps going to the toilet,
not knowing if he needs to or not.
Buddy, why so serious?
Stop acting. How many
have you destroyed as a fink?
I'm not a fink!
You even hurt Ma, you bastard!
I didn't do it!
Kuang, this kid is crazy.
Buddy, vent your feelings.
Do what you want to me.
Kid, listen.
Eat a bowl of shit now.
Then lick our shoes clean.
Then...
Kuang, what do you want?
I'll chop you
into 18 pieces and offer you to Ma.
Kuang, do you mean it?
Kuang, don't!
Kuang!
Hai!
Brother, help!
Keep away!
Kuang, don't go too far!
The assistant warden
won't let you go if you kill him.
Hai, he killed many
as a fink. We can't tolerate that.
But you know who can
enforce the family rules here.
Kuang,
repeat the north-cell
rules to the youngsters.
Only Hai can enforce the family rules.
Let Centipede go
and forget the Ma incident.
Hai, if I were to forget this and that,
what good are the family rules?
You can't lead us
if you're not reasonable.
Not respecting a superior.
That's breaking a family rule!
Hai, you really are good.
Leave Kuang to me.
To hell with you, Kuang!
How are you going to handle Kuang?
By using him as bait to lure Ricky out.
I don't follow you.
Show something
to those prisoners in the north cell.
I'd be in trouble
if everybody was like Ricky.
Hai!
Use this knife
to enforce the family rules.
Care for some mints?
Hai, show me your specialty.
You're friendly,
but you don't know the rules.
I thought you were brave,
but for the Gang of Four's reputation,
I must finish you off today.
Why don't you fight back?
Now, be fair.
Let Kuang go before fighting me.
I'm enforcing the family rules.
Hai kills when he shows
his tattoos. Just escape!
Ricky, Kuang's finished if you don't
fight back now. Come on, Ricky!
Come on, don't be afraid of him.
The broken glass
comes from the assistant warden.
See if you're as strong
after being blinded.
Blind, with cut tendons...
Ricky, you're finished.
Ricky, you're tops!
Go on, Ricky!
There's a fight in the north cell.
They say Hai is
challenging Ricky to a duel!
Did anyone get killed?
Go and have a look!
Great...
You can see
your right arm's
crippled like a sandbag.
What's he doing?
He tied his tendons?
Ricky, you're great!
Hai, don't try anything foolish!
At worst, we die together!
Great, you're undoubtedly
one of the Gang of Four.
Seems you won't
give up until you die.
Great...
Ricky's great! Ricky's superb!
Kuang's dead!
Ricky, Kuang's dead!
He's dead?
Kuang!
Today's mints are bitter.
Assistant warden, you got him killed.
We must kill him to avenge Kuang.
Finish him off!
Bump him off!
What are you doing?
Turning against me?
Aren't you afraid of the Gang of Four?
With Ricky here,
we're afraid of no one.
Not even you. I'll kill you too.
Ricky, let me introduce
west cell's Huang Chuan,
east cell's Taizan, and south cell's god.
Finish off these three
if you've got the guts.
Ricky, don't worry!
Let's join forces to finish him off!
Ricky, come on!
Ricky!
Ricky, do in those bastards!
Kill them to avenge Kuang and Ma.
Go back.
We want no more death
after Kuang and Hai.
Ricky, do you want to become
one of the Gang of Four?
Sha? Hai's godson.
He must be sad
over his godfather's death.
Lighter, not so hard,
and roll your tongue.
Hai's dead. Aren't you sad?
Your tongue got cut off?
Hey! Try to play this.
It has a better sound.
How could you have
gotten poppy leaves?
In the west cell?
What happened, Huang Chuan?
Sha told Ricky about the poppy leaves.
What? A mute exposed it?
You think I lied?
Sha defected
to Ricky and betrayed us.
And you're in the dark about it.
We need evidence to do anything.
If Sha did become a fink
even a revived Hai couldn't protect him.
Sha!
Damn it, keep cool!
Sha, this is Hai's weapon!
Kin can avenge the deceased,
according to the family law.
Use this to get rid of Ricky.
Look, Hai died a tragic death.
Aren't you, a youngster,
going to avenge him?
Traitor!
This time we won't
only cut off your tongue.
Isn't it Sha? What's become of him?
Yes, it's Sha.
Almost all of his skin
has been peeled off.
Huang Chuan must've done it.
Sha really is unlucky.
He was new and witnessed "that."
He had half of his tongue
cut off by Huang Chuan,
and now he died a tragic death.
What do you mean by "that"?
Ricky, forget it.
Don't antagonize Huang Chuan.
But Sha knew full well.
After Hai's death,
he wouldn't live long either.
Devil!
What? Ricky knows
about the poppies?
What's wrong with you three?
A fire in the west cell?
How come? Damn it!
Must be arson!
Damn, it really is burning!
You bastards,
you grow opium in the cells?
So you are the arsonist.
I'll kill you for Sha's sake!
Now it's the west cell that's in trouble.
A fire for no reason!
Why's there a sour smell?
Huang Chuan grew
opium in the greenhouse.
You squeezed poppies into juice,
and dried it to make opium.
You traded this juice for human blood.
Bastard, you burned up my lifeblood.
I won't let you go!
Huang Chuan
knows unorthodox kung fu.
I've hit your heart muscle
in a fatal spot. You'll die soon.
We can leave once
this cell is burned down.
Lock up those criminals.
Yes!
Go now!
Sir, the fire brigade
called to ask what happened.
Tell them we're burning rubbish.
Sir!
A call from the police station now?
No, a call from the warden saying
he's returning from Hawaii tomorrow.
What? Why so serious?
He's coming back ahead of schedule?
Raise the zero alarm!
Zero? Huang Chuan
and Ricky are outside.
Just do as I say.
Yes!
One looks beautiful before dying,
especially a man.
I won't let you off easy
for burning the poppies.
Nor will the master!
Ricky, prepare yourself
and be a messenger for hell.
You've even broken my technique.
No wonder they call you a demon.
But you can't
live through tonight.
Huang Chuan, catch!
Now I'm going to cremate you.
Ricky can't die till
I've had a duel with him alone.
Taizan, you're out of your mind!
Zero alarm.
All men back to the cells in one
minute or you'll be shot on sight.
We must beat Ricky quickly
and get back to the cells.
Damn, keep away,
or you'll be done in too!
Creep, you're really vexing me!
Ricky, I'll stay
for a duel with you here.
You really are hell-bent.
I have to show
the poppies to everybody.
Once the cement on him dries,
he won't even be able to lift a toe.
The proof's gone forever then!
Break Taizan's cement.
Let me handle the warden,
then I'll take care of Ricky.
With me here, it's going to be okay.
The warden's back. Open up!
Open up!
Open up! The warden is back!
The warden is back!
Get up...
Stand still!
Warden, you're back!
Young master,
had a good time in Hawaii?
Young master.
Did you get hurt? Seriously?
It's all right.
Who rolled out the carpet?
I didn't do it!
This prisoner did, sir!
You did?
It's not my fault, warden! Let me go!
Why didn't you check to see
if the carpet was all right?
Have you got eyes?
If you can't see clearly,
have one eye less!
What happened during my absence?
Some prisoners disobeyed.
Some died.
Several criminals died
in a month. What's wrong?
Since the prison was privatized,
the prisoners have become
the cheapest and best labor force.
Take good care of them to avoid
death from hunger or illness.
Young master, eating a candle?
Keep a close eye on those prisoners.
It's sugar.
Anything else?
The poppy field was
burned down last night.
What? Why...
Bring medicine, quick!
Yes!
My medicine!
Warden, it was him!
Don't worry!
I waited for you the whole night.
Kill him! Kill him quick!
Ricky, want to get killed?
Is the poppy field yours?
Ricky, let's have a hand-to-hand fight!
Warden, sit down for a while.
Taizan is the best kung fu
fighter in the Gang of Four.
Ricky's finished for sure.
I haven't okayed his death yet.
Warden, have it your way.
You really have guts.
You put your hands on the warden.
Bravo...
One, two, three, four, five, six. Six!
How is it? Tastes good!
That's all?
Have some more, if that's not enough.
Warden, it's his "Open Coconut" technique.
It could burst Ricky's head.
Get up quick, Taizan!
You're good for nothing!
You're finished so soon!
Shut up. We're people, not insects.
You really are okay.
No wonder you made trouble in the cells.
Scum, you grew
opium and killed many!
Ricky, what do you want?
He won't tell!
But once the metal plate crushes him...
Great, Ricky Ho,
your conditioning is good.
Let me help you.
This is the latest taser
with 100,000 volts.
You'll turn into a dried persimmon.
Taizan, you're still alive?
Warden, you forgot I was inside?
Rubbish!
I've always been loyal.
Loyal? You're a heap
of scraps to be cleaned up!
Taizan, come out quick!
Ricky, I can't hold on.
Mommy, I'll have to leave you...
Each prisoner has relatives
awaiting their release!
You can't throw them away
like some dirty tablecloth!
You can't get out anyway, idiot.
Summon all prisoners
to the compound tomorrow.
Yes, sir!
Warden, please!
I must seriously punish Ricky Ho.
Everybody, throw a spade of clay in!
Are we to bury Ricky alive?
Yes. You want us to do
the dirty work, don't you?
Don't you?
Tell them to start.
Burly and Breakdown, you start now.
Everyone else goes after them!
Ricky, what shall we do now?
Do as he orders. You're no match.
Are you going to die?
What?
Say it when you visit his grave.
Ricky, hold on!
Next!
Keep away!
Ricky, hold on!
Listen, everybody.
I'll let Ricky go if he lasts a week!
Great!
Hold on...
This oxygen tube
can last you seven days.
Come over quickly. Pack him in.
Can Ricky last seven days?
Let's wish him luck!
If he dies, it's our fault!
Ricky!
Ricky?
He's still alive!
Good, he keeps going
even when buried alive.
Huang Chuan, you really are terrific!
Your windpipe is clogging up.
Brother, she saw us selling powder.
We brought her back for your pleasure.
Then let's decide how to dispose of her.
No way! If an old woman should see,
would you bring her
to me all the same?
Brother, take your time.
Sword of the Green Dragon clan.
Damn, how dare he call my name?
Keep away!
Seven days of rain
makes the earth cold and wet.
If he's alive, he must be a superman.
Ricky!
He's dead!
What a tragedy!
Ricky!
He's moving.
He's still alive, just asleep!
What? Asleep in such a situation?
Ricky's great!
Move him quickly!
Ricky, you're the stoutest
kid I have ever seen.
Let's be friends, okay?
A wolf and a pig can't be friends.
You destroyed many people
by growing opium in the cells!
I must settle this with you.
Don't talk so much.
You bastards!
Let's be enemies then.
What else did you do besides
investigating the opium case?
Shorty, come on!
Okay!
You disappeared for two years,
according to the files. Where were you?
So long as you live,
I'll beat the truth out of you.
Let me.
You lured me out.
What else do you want?
You must answer
my question before you die!
Warden, are you okay?
The day you know my secret
is the day of your death.
Assistant warden.
Warden!
Bring the medicine, quick!
Ricky!
Ricky, I've brought
something for you to eat.
You haven't eaten for a whole week!
You're our savior.
Ricky, eat now, eat!
The warden's tough.
Watch your back, Ricky!
Be strong
I'll come back tomorrow.
Why's that creep here?
Fa!
Centipede is backbiting again.
Ricky, I have a present for you.
You'll die mutilated today.
Now it's your turn.
Ricky, don't try anything foolish!
Emergency.
Mobilize the task force.
Emergency, over!
They'll arrive in one minute, over.
- Over!
- Fa!
Ricky, Fa can't hold on.
Fa!
Ricky, are you all right?
Thanks for bringing me some food.
Fa!
Assistant warden!
You killed Fa. Don't run away!
You killed Fa!
You murderer!
Punch him!
We'll take your life today.
You cockroaches want to die, don't you?
Cockroaches? Bastard!
Sock him!
Take me to the warden.
Warden, tomorrow's menu
for the prisoners is ready.
Your instructions, please.
Preserved beans, vegetables,
and meat pies for tomorrow's lunch.
Don't you think
there are too many dishes?
Halve the vegetables
and preserved beans.
Keep the meat pies for supper.
Be good.
The prisoners won't die of hunger.
Right!
You get fish and meat
and feed the dog steak too.
Not enough food?
Let me give you some more.
Enough now?
We're humans, not beasts!
If criminals are human, then flies
and cockroaches are human too.
Ricky!
What is it?
Warden, riots. Central control has been
disrupted, and the alarm's not working.
Let's see how tough
you cockroaches can be.
Warden, don't shoot!
They rioted only due
to your mismanagement.
You asked for it.
Warden, help!
My gun's for shooting elephants only.
Ricky, your turn.
After you die, the prisoners will
return to their cells themselves.
Bastard, Ricky won't die.
Who wants to die now?
You bastards trying to turn against me?
Warden, I'll go and bring some men in.
Bastard, I'll fight you!
Go through the back.
Young master,
push this button. It's fun.
You two, help me fix Ricky.
Huang Chuan, it's not
a tournament. Finish him off quickly!
I'll cripple you
so you can never kill again.
Don't...
Don't kill me...
I nearly forgot
you can even stand bullets.
Come here!
Take him back to his room. If those
cockroaches get in the way, shoot them.
Ricky, see if you can kill me now.
You still have power?
I mean what I say.
A warden must be a master of kung fu.
Now, see for yourself!
Ricky, use what you've got.