TOHO CO., LTD.
ALL MONSTERS ATTACK
Produced by
TOMOYUKI TANAKA
Screenplay by
SHINICHI SEKIZAWA
Cinematography by
MOTOTAKA TOMIOKA
Production Design by
TAKEO KITA
Music by
KUNIO MIYAUCHI
Theme Song GENDAI
KANO SHINICHI SEKIZAWA
Edited by
MASAHISA HIMI
It's the march of the monsters!
An awesome juggernaut
destroying everything in its path!
Go-Go-Godzilla fires his atomic breath
Starring
KENJI SAHARA
MACHIKO NAKA
TOMONORI YAZAKI
HIDEYO AMAMOTO
Wham! Bang! Crash!
They pulverize everything!
SACHIO SAKAI
KAZUO SUZUKI
YOSHIBUMI TAJIMA CHOTARO
TOGIN YUTAKA NAKAYAMA
JUNICHI ITO
KOBITO NO MACHAN
YASUHIKO KAKUKO, HARUO NAKAJIMA
Voice of Minilla: MIDORI UCHIYAMA
But it ain't easy being a monster
Special Effects Supervisor
EIJI TSUBURAYA
Directed by
ISHIRO HONDA
Move!
- That sounds like Minilla!
- Minilla?
Yeah, Minilla makes that sound.
“Kee kee kee.”
Liar! You've never seen him.
No, but it's true.
The monsters are crying
Why is Earth such a hard place to live?
Go-Go-Godzilla is shocked
Mi-Mi-Minilla is trembling too
Wham! Bang! Crash!
They pulverize everything!
But megaton smog
And exhaust are worse
They're the real monsters!
- Ichiro, you going home?
- Hi, Dad!
I'm working tonight.
Be good till your mom gets home.
I Will.
What's that?
A vacuum tube.
Put it down. It's dirty.
The next train's gonna be a bit late.
Your boy feeling okay?
Why?
A lot of kids get asthma.
You should be careful.
He looked pale.
Nah.
But I wish he were more assertive.
He tends to keep to himself.
He needs someone around,
but my wife works too.
A latchkey kid, huh?
We want to save up
and move to where the air's clean...
but when?
Damn! “Police find getaway car
used in 50-million-yen heist.”
What good is finding the car?
The robbers probably
already stole another one.
Fifty million yen...
Sachiko, let's go in there.
We can't. It's all fenced off.
I know a way in.
We'll get in trouble.
No one's watching.
Lots of kids play there.
No, my mom's waiting for me.
Rats!
Don't go in there.
It's okay.
Ichiro, it's Gabara!
Come out quick!
Sachiko, what are you doing there?
Mommy!
You shouldn't play around here.
Ichiro, go on home.
Your mother worries about you.
Good-bye.
Ichiro!
You found that vacuum tube here, right?
No, I found it over there.
- Liar!
- It's true.
Give it here.
But I -
Give it here!
We did it, baby!
I really did find it there.
If you want it back,
go honk that motorcycle horn.
It'll startle that guy.
That's why it's fun.
Do it.
Don't you want this back?
No!
Scaredy-cat! Chicken!
All patrol cars...
the two men involved
in the 50-million-yen heist
may steal another car to get away.
Keep an eye on parked cars too.
Car 11 here. Roger.
Ichiro, just getting home?
Is that Ichiro?
The key's in the usual place.
What's that?
This? A new toy.
A "kiddy computer."
- Kiddy computer?
- That's right.
Can it do stuff like my homework?
Keep dreaming.
But watch this.
Push this button and -
Apollo 11 has landed on the moon.
Don't you want to visit there too?
What do you think?
The moon is great,
but there's somewhere else
I'd rather go.
Where?
- Monster Island.
- Monster Island?
Yeah. Minilla, Godzilla,
Rodan, Kumonga,
and lots of other monsters are there.
They're all stronger than Gabara.
Gabara?
Never heard of that monster.
I mean Sanko, the bully.
That brat is called Gabara?
He bullies you, huh?
Today he took a vacuum tube I found.
Why didn't you take it back?
He's stronger than me.
You never know till you try.
I'd just make it worse.
It would be cool to record
monsters' roars with this.
See you.
Monsters' roars, huh?
Whose roar was that?
Mine!
Too bad!
Ichiro, finish your homework
before you play.
Your snack's in the usual place.
I'll make dinner when I get home. Mom.
He said,
"The crazy behavior of young people
that we're seeing all over the world
today is creating problems."
Next up:
Police investigating
the 50-miiiion-yen heist
announced today
that the robbers may still be hiding
near where
their getaway car was found.
Police are searching the area carefully.
Ichiro, this means good-bye for us.
No, I'll come back for you, I promise.
I could never forget you.
This is a test of our love.
Ichiro!
Yuck!
Computer, computer...
take me to Monster Island.
tell me the location of Monster Island.
Over.
I forgot the antenna.
Where is Monster Island?
Computer, do you read?
Roger that!
A jetliner from Haneda Airport!
Ladies and gentlemen...
thank you for flying Pan American.
Today's first flight to Monster Island
departed Haneda Airport on schedule.
Calling Monster Island.
This is Monster 001
approaching for landing.
It's Godzilla!
Kamacuras!
Gorosaurus!
Manda!
Anguirus!
Giant Condor!
It's Kamacuras!
Ouch!
I'll give it a try.
What's this?
It's Minilla!
Come here. I won't hurt you.
You sure?
We don't lie like humans.
Thanks for saving me.
What brings you here?
I wanted to see you guys.
Won't your mother and father be worried?
They work all day.
I'm all alone after school.
It's Gabara!
Come on!
That's Gabara?
Yeah. He's really mean.
You ever fight him?
No, he's really strong.
- It's just like my situation.
- Your situation?
With the Gabara I know.
Mommy!
Hello? Minami Toy Makers.
Who? Ah, Ichiro's mother!
Sorry to impose on you again,
but could you please
give Ichiro a message?
Sure. I think he's napping.
What's the message?
I won't be home tonight.
A coworker got sick, and I have to cover.
Sorry to bother you, and thanks again.
- Those men are detectives.
- Is there trouble?
They say the men
who stole the 50 million yen
are hiding in this area.
Wake up.
Hey, wake up!
Where did you go?
Where are you?
I'm not going anywhere.
You're still half asleep.
- Why did you wake me up?
- Sorry.
He was going to take me to Godzilla.
Who?
Minilla. We became friends.
Going back to your dream?
Your mother just called to say
she won't be home tonight.
Really?
Rats! This happens all the time!
Stop complaining.
Your mom and dad work really hard.
Tell you what:
Let's have dinner together.
Hey, cheer up.
I'll call you when it's ready.
Minilla, come back...
It's not working.
I got a bite!
It got away!
Hey, Ichiro!
Come here!
He ran away. What a wimp!
Anyone there?
I've got an idea.
I won't let Gabara have these,
but I could give one to Sachiko.
SECOND FLOOR
I'm not afraid of Gabara!
A police car!
Cool! Let's follow it!
A headset! What a find!
THIRD FLOOR
Bonehead!
- Idiot! Now you've done it!
- Done what?
When you looked through that hole,
your driver's license
fell out of your pocket.
Get down!
Go find out where that kid's going.
"For sale at a great price."
Don't play with that. You'll break it.
It's already a junker.
Any worse and we'll never sell it.
Shinpei should have
gotten rid of it sooner.
I have a driver's license.
Stop it!
A fake license isn't good for much.
Rats!
Monster Island.
Monster Island, come in.
Can I help you?
Interested in buying this car?
No, I was just -
It looks like junk, but it runs great.
I'll give you a good price.
Is it yours?
No, I'm just looking after it.
Want to take a look?
Maybe some other time.
Wait!
Damn Iooky-loo!
Ichiro, dinner's ready!
Coming!
What's wrong?
You haven't touched the meat.
- I feel bad.
- Why?
I'm worried you'll go broke.
A little beef won't break the bank!
Did you sell that new toy?
I might have a buyer.
I want you to be a play tester.
A play tester?
I want a kid's honest opinion.
So you're paying me with sukiyaki?
You could say that.
Great!
Hey, slow down there.
You'll get sleepy if you stuff yourself.
That reminds me.
Don't wake me up next time.
I'm going to see Godzilla.
Godzilla? Where?
Monster Island.
Minilla's going to take me to him.
Sorry to interrupt your dinner.
You are...?
Police. We wanted
to give you a heads-up.
That car down there
belongs to you, right?
Yes.
It's not parked illegally, is it?
No, nothing like that.
You may have heard
about the 50-million-yen heist.
The robbers may try to steal a car,
so be careful.
Really? Thanks for telling me.
Sorry to bother you.
Let's go.
Thief!
Police!
Good night.
What are we gonna do?
Smoking's no cure for hunger.
I'm starving!
We're loaded, right?
Forget about food.
Think about how to get out of here.
Did you find out where that kid lives?
Yeah.
Second floor,
third apartment from the right.
Good.
Put this away and let's go.
Minilla!
It's Gabara!
Finally lost him!
Oh, it's you.
What are you doing?
Nothing. I have no friends.
Then you're just like me.
Why did you come back?
You said you'd help me
climb up on Godzilla's back.
Oh, right.
I wonder where he is now.
- You're not with him all the time?
- No, he gets mad.
Why?
Godzilla says I have to learn
to fight my own battles.
He's tough on you, huh?
There he is! Come on!
They're fighting.
Go on!
Let him have it!
Get back!
Will Godzilla be okay underwater?
Yeah, he's really tough.
He won!
He's going that way.
Let's follow him.
It's Kumonga!
Godzilla got it in the eye!
We'll see about that!
Come back, quick!
Run!
You're still not ready for that.
Yeah...
but even Godzilla
couldn't do it at first.
He had to practice a lot.
Look! He's amazing!
Godzilla fell down.
Hooray! He won!
- What's wrong?
- It's Gabara!
What should we do?
You gonna fight him?
We should run.
If I always run,
Godzilla will think I'm a coward.
No, don't!
Here goes nothing.
Go, Minilla!
Let him have it!
Minilla, run!
You better run!
You're right. Let's run.
We're safe here.
He's scarier than the Gabara I know.
Fighter jets!
Humans are coming
to invade our island again.
Hooray!
No, I don't want to!
I guess Minilla has to learn too.
Attaboy, Minilla!
Keep still!
Make a sound and you'll get it!
See if the coast is clear.
Put your shoes on.
Ichiro!
What were you gonna do
with my license, kid?
Forget that. Go find us a car.
Keep quiet, you hear?
Shut up! Stop crying!
Don't be a sissy.
Boys get scared too.
Quiet!
Sake, please.
We meet again.
Still on the job?
They work you hard!
It's been a wild goose chase.
Recharging your batteries?
Can't stand the thought
of going back empty-handed.
We'll warm up
and then make another round.
Officer, what does
50 million yen look like?
It would fill a bag like this.
Damn it!
Why's it taking so long
just to steal a car!
Fall in, bad man!
- It's Minilla.
- What?
Minilla's in danger.
We're the ones in danger!
Minilla...
Minilla, hang in there!
Don't let him beat you!
That's it!
Minilla!
Up here!
Come up here!
Quick! I have an idea.
Quick!
When Gabara steps on that tree trunk,
jump on this end.
Can I beat him then?
You'll send him flying.
Here he comes!
Okay.
Here I go.
Now!
You did it, baby!
Go, Godzilla!
Hooray! He won!
Godzilla's really strong!
Gabara limps away
with his tail between his legs!
No, I'm your friend! Don't!
Minilla, help!
Help me!
You're having a bad dream, kid.
Wake up!
Pipe down!
It's me!
Idiot! What took you so long?
Don't blame me. The car had a flat.
I've never had to change a -
Where's the car now?
Just outside.
Give me your handkerchief.
You bringing the kid?
Kidnapping's a serious crime.
Not his legs! His hands!
We're not gonna kill him.
There's no point.
But if he's safe, we're safe.
He's our ticket to freedom, huh?
Shut up and get the bag.
Keep quiet, you hear?
Hurry up!
Quiet!
Stupid piece of junk!
Hurry it up!
Keep quiet, you hear?
What's wrong?
- Let me handle this!
- Just get it moving.
Godzilla says I have to learn
to fight my own battles.
The kid!
Hold it right there!
Stop it!
Little brat! Hold it!
Be careful!
I've had it with that damn kid.
But he's trapped like a rat now.
Go look in that room.
Idiot!
Be careful, idiot!
You tripped over yourself!
Don't blame me!
Just go look over there.
Any sign of him?
Nope.
Damn it! Where'd he go?
It's like he vanished.
Go watch the entrance.
I'll search the second floor again.
Damn brat!
What is it?
- He's on the third floor.
- All right.
I've seen this car somewhere before.
Where was it?
Wait, this is my car!
What's my car doing here?
Very strange.
What's this? This isn't mine.
The robbers!
There's a big bag of cash in my car!
Yes, cash!
Huge wads of it!
Damn you!
There's nowhere to run now!
I found him!
What happened?
Where'd you go?
- Down here.
- Where?
I fell through the hole!
You blockhead!
Damn it!
It's not broken. Where's the kid?
- Upstairs.
- Why didn't you say so?
Hey, kid!
Stop!
Hold it!
Hold it, you brat!
Son of a bitch!
You little -
Stop it!
Goddamn it!
Come back, you little weasel!
Right here!
The money's right here.
- Mr. Shinpei!
- Ichiro!
Mr. Shinpei!
Get back!
Don't move or I'll shoot!
- Drop the knife!
- Now!
I'm sorry.
Take him away!
Get out here!
You can't run now!
Come out now!
- I'm sorry.
- Let's go.
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
You fought those two all by yourself?
I had to...
It's all right now.
Let's go home.
Well done, son.
We'll take you home.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I'll never work again at night
no matter what.
But don't we need the money?
Of course I wish you and Dad
were home all the time,
but I can take care of myself.
I'm done.
Bye, Mom!
Bye, and be careful!
Here he comes!
Hey, sonny.
Weren't you scared all alone?
I wasn't alone.
Was someone with you?
Who was with you?
Minilla.
That's right. Gotta go!
Let him go.
He means Minilla the monster.
I think I understand.
He's like a higher power.
- A higher power?
- That's right.
Adults believe in gods,
so why can't kids have
their own gods too, like Minilla?
That's true.
Sachiko!
Did you buy
this month's manga magazine?
- No.
- You can read mine.
Ichiro, wanna join us?
No!
What?
You're just a bully, Gabara!
You little -
I hate bullies!
Stop that!
I said stop it! Leave that alone!
All right, baby!
You really did it!
He looks like a monster!
Damn kids!
Run!
Come back here!
Damn it!
Come back here, damn it!
Daddy!
- Ichiro!
Please apologize for me.
What did you do?
It's all my fault.
Come back here!
Where are your parents?
You did that?
- Thanks, Dad!
- Wait!
Stop, you brat!
I'm sorry. That's my son.
Look what he did to me!
I'll pay your laundry bill.
This paint won't come out!
I'm really sorry.
Sorry, Mr. Painter!
THE END