What are you so scared of?
If you move, you'll
get stabbed in the face.
P-Please stop this!
Dumb-ass. Stop crying.
As punishment, we'll all
throw our knives at once.
Ready, set...
Cut that out!
What if that kid gets
stabbed by your knives?
Who are you?
This is none of your business.
Unfortunately, it is my business.
You remember, don't you?
Yu Hyuga. My little brother.
You bullied him to death.
I have no idea who that is.
Oh, really?
Even if you don't remember him,
he's waiting for you in hell!
I'm gonna kill you!
Stop screaming so pathetically.
You're a man, aren't you?
You won't die from
getting your hand cut off.
After all...
I only have one arm too!
I'll blast you to pieces!
That thing is real! NO fair!
So what?
Hey!
Are you okay?
You're safe now.
Murderer... Murderer...
Murderer!
That's right. I am a murderer.
But until a half year ago, I was
a normal high schooler who was able...
...to hold her little
brother with her left arm.
Here we go, Yoshie.
All right!
Wait up!
Wait, Ami!
Wait! Wait!
Nice shot! You're amazing, Ami!
You're really something. So cool.
If you were a boy,
I might have fallen for you.
Stop it.
I don't want a girl
to have a crush on me.
But it looks like
it's not that way after all.
How so?
Because it looks
like you have a young fan.
You're so popular!
And he's so cute. I'm jealous.
Dummy. That's my little brother, Yu.
I'm impressed, Sis. I had no idea
you were so good at basketball.
You're always lying around the house.
Quiet, you.
So Why'd you stop by today?
There's always something going on
when you come visit me like that.
I'll pay you back, so please lend
me money to buy a new game!
I knew it.
No way.
We don't have that
kind of money to spend.
Sis, please. I really want it.
I'll clean up every day,
even wash the dishes.
Sis. Come on, Sis.
Really?
Yu.
Takeshi, how much did you bring?
I took 10,000 yen from my mom.
I see. Me too.
They're not gonna be happy.
Hello, it's Yu.
It's Takeshi.
Excuse us.
You're late.
I'm sorry.
Where's the money?
Hurry up and hand it over.
This isn't even half
of what we agreed on.
Hey!
Hey, Yu...
How'd you get that money?
I borrowed it from my sister.
Then I expect you to get
more by tomorrow. 200,000 yen.
If you can't, then I'll make your
sister work at my dad's whorehouse.
She has nothing to do with this!
Who do you think you are?
Don't get me wrong.
I don't really want your money.
I just wanna have fun
by seeing you guys suffer.
Teppei...
He's a peon, but he's cunning.
Ryota Fujii... He's just a coward.
But the one I hate most
is the leader, Sho Kimura.
It's morning! Wake...
Oh, you got up early.
We're having fried chicken for
breakfast. They're still hot and tasty.
Hot!
Hey, what happened to your face?
I fell.
That can't be.
Come back here.
Yu, tell me the truth.
Okay, I got into
a fight and got pummeled.
You weren't bullied?
NO, I'm not that hopeless. I hit
a classmate who pissed me off.
Watch it.
You've done it now.
I won't go easy on you.
You shouldn't use violence like that.
Remember what Dad used to say'?
Jeez.
Violence doesn't solve anything.
It only hurts people.
You and I fully understand that.
When Mom and Dad killed
themselves over murder allegations...
We promised then.
Not to lose loved ones.
To always be there for each other.
NO matter what happens,
I'm going to protect you.
Sis...
Listen, Sho.
Whatever you do, do not ever bring
shame to our Hanzo Hattori clan.
I know, Dad.
We may be yakuza now,
but never lose your ninja pride.
Never let your guard down.
Never!
Everyone except
yourself is an enemy!
Think of them as slaves, right?
That's right!
Do not fear blades.
Use them to destroy your enemy!
Destroy! Destroy!
Very good.
You are my flesh and blood.
I will make our bond even greater.
A cup of my own blood.
Drink it to strengthen our bond.
Drink it...
Drink more...
She...
As long as you're around,
our clan will never die.
You are my treasure!
Master, your breakfast is ready.
Hey.
You must be new.
How dare you interrupt our sacred
ritual between father and son?
You!
Young master, have a good day.
Good morning, Mom.
What are you doing?
Oh, good morning.
This maid's been messing
up a lot, so I'm punishing her.
Have a nice day.
Have a nice day!
She was a terrible maid.
Bye-bye.
Have a nice day.
Where are you going?
School's the other way.
Where's the money?
Wait! Come back!
What the hell?
Watch where you're going!
Come here, you! Come on!
You open?
Hello.
Excuse me! Is Takeshi here?
Hey! Wait! Who are you?
What's wrong with kids these days?
They don't even say hello.
Miki, do you know that kid?
Miki?
What was that?
I'm scared... I'm scared...
Those guys are... It's me.
We're in trouble. Run for it.
What should we do?
What do you want with Takeshi?
Sorry...
Ma, this is my friend, Yu Hyuga.
You're the son of
those alleged murderers.
That's not true! My dad
was framed and killed himself.
I don't care.
Just stay away from my son.
GO home!
Takeshi? Takeshi!
Takeshi, where are you going?
Takeshi!
Ready?
Okay.
Go for it!
You're amazing!
Nice shot! Just as I expected!
I'm jealous of you. Seeing you
and Yu get along like that.
He seems like a nice kid.
He must be easy to deal with.
That's not true.
He's very selfish.
I don't know what to do with him.
This is bad!
Y-Yoshie, excuse me.
W-Wait, Ami!
Where are you going? Jeez...
Hold it!
Where do you think you're going?
Stop running away, man!
Sorry...
Hey.
Where to, girl?
I'm in a rush.
What's the rush?
Where are you going?
Stop!
Who do you think you are?
No! No! Stop!
No!
Stop...
No! Stop!
What are you thinking?
You broke your promise.
Do you know how embarrassing
this is for a yakuza's son'?
Stop!
Beating on you two isn't much fun.
I think I want Yu's sister to be my toy.
I hear she's got big tits,
and she's cute. GO find her.
Don't you dare lay
a finger on my sister!
You sissies. You pissed me off.
I won't take it easy on you!
What the hell?
Yu!
You're pretty strong.
Is your sister strong too?
She's much stronger!
Then she should've trained you better.
Takeshi"
Are you okay?
Yu, I'm scared...
Shut up!
Takeshi
See ya.
Sis...
Yu?
Yu...
Yu!
This is some kind of joke, right?
Sugihara Motors
Takeshi"
Why did you have to go?
Excuse me.
Who are you?
I'm Yu's older sister.
I'm so sorry about Takeshi...
What do you want?
The police are trying
to call it a suicide.
But I know someone was
responsible for their deaths.
If only I had a lead...
Stop it.
I don't want you playing the victim.
Look.
If it weren't for your brother,
Takeshi would still be alive!
But...
You people are murderers.
Your family brings misfortune
to everyone around you!
Stop it!
Get out of here!
MM .
Neither Yu, Dad, nor 1
would ever kill anyone...
There's no way Yu would kill himself.
No way.
Someone forced him into it.
Someone must've killed him!
"People I want to kill."
What is this?
Why didn't I find out sooner?
Yu...
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
I'm not sure about tempura
in the morning. Is it okay?
The incident with your
brother breaks my heart.
I'm sad since I was his friend.
Ryota, who's the leader of the group?
Ryota needs to get to school, so...
Wait.
Well, I'm going.
Make yourself at home.
So...
Are you saying that our
Ryota bullied your brother?
This diary is proof.
I'd like you to come to
the police precinct with me.
You're an idiot!
We've been in the police business
ever since my grandfather's time.
You're Hyuga, right?
I know that your father is a murderer.
Trying to falsely accuse my son...
What do you want?
Murderer!
What?
If he was being bullied...
...maybe it was because something
was wrong with your brother.
I don't want you blaming us
for your brother's problems.
Please stop.
I want to talk calmly.
I can't talk to you.
A minx like you should be arrested!
Stop!
There's no need for this violence!
I'm doing this to protect my son!
Please stop!
It's hot!
Oh, it fried up very nicely.
Such tasty tempura.
Hot! Hot! Hot!
Damn it!
H-Honey!
Honey, are you okay?
Don't call the cops.
I'll find her and finish her off!
It stings.
Oh, it stings...
L4tsflngs™.
Ow...
Stop.
If you make a noise, I'll slit your throat.
Now apologize to Yu
and tell me who your leader is.
I don't know.
I'll tell you. The leader is
a yakuza's son, Sho Kimura!
Sho Kimura?
I can't breathe... Murderer...
I always believed that it was
wrong to kill no matter what.
But I learned from your parents...
...that there's a time and place for it!
A blackout?
Ryota!
I hope you rot in hell together!
Mother, there's no conditioner.
Can you get some?
Sir, how about
an unusual conditioner?
It can't be... you!
Ryota!
Wash your hair with your son's blood!
RYOTA??
Please, God!
Serves you right.
I'm a demon! I turned into a demon!
I'll remain a demon until I kill
every last one of Yu's enemies!
Delicious.
Here are your noodles and soup...
Hot!
Hey! What do you think you're doing?
What'll you do
about the master's leg?
I don't like that look on your face!
Hey!
Keep it down.
Sorry about that.
You must be the new chef, right?
Yes...
Got kids?
No.
Kids are great.
I did a lot of bad things in
my life, but my kids need me.
Sho means everything to me.
I live because of him.
And you caused him great pain...
Cut off a finger as an apology!
Please forgive me!
Honey, that's not right.
You always do this.
I'm really sorry about all this.
You're too soft!
Even all five fingers wouldn't
be enough to make it up to Sho!
I am formerly of the Kanto Beasts!
Don't fuck with me!
No!
If you don't want to die...
...then at least apologize like
the true chef you are, huh?
Excuse me. I want
to ask you for directions.
Where do you need to go?
Where's Sho Kimura?
Take me to him!
Now, eat some sushi...
Eat as much as you want...
GO ahead and eat.
If you say so...
How do your fingers taste?
We need a new
chef starting tomorrow.
I'm going to the bathroom.
You're Sho Kimura?
Who the hell are you?
What was that sound?
Sho!
Who the hell are you?
Stay back or I'll slit his throat.
I'm not afraid to die.
I just want to kill him.
NO way. You can't kill me.
What's that?
You won't get away! Someone!
Right!
She's good.
You...
You killed my Yu!
GO through!
You did pretty good for a girl.
But it's over now.
I'm sure you know what's
going to happen to you, right?
Yu's sister, I feel sorry for you.
You were so close.
Wounds from burns and a katana.
Your arm is a mess, girl.
We, the Hattori clan, won't kill
our enemy after they're captured.
We give them a taste
of hell before killing them.
I thought your stupid
son was the crazy one...
...but you're all insane!
You have pretty fingers...
I can't believe these belong
to such a strong girl like you...
Slice, slice, slice these fingers off...
O great Hanzo Hattori.
Provide this girl with
great pain and suffering.
It hurts!
That was for all three of us.
But we're not done yet.
Now this is from the great Hanzo!
It looks pretty nice without any fingers.
I think that's enough for today.
One minute.
Wait.
You should keep going, honey!
Torture isn't fun unless
you do it a little bit at a time.
That's why you're too soft.
You should finish her off at once!
You shut up and let me do my job!
I'm gonna give you a painkiller.
The boss is being kind.
It's a shame you're
gonna be hacked up tomorrow.
Such a nice body.
Give me the key
to unlock this chain! Now!
What is this?
Shit. She escaped.
Hey! Someone!
What's wrong?
That girl...
That bitch... Where did she go?
Like I said,
you were too easy on her!
Find her and kill her.
Yu...
Where are you taking me?
Don't overdo it.
You won't be able to work
efficiently even if you work overtime.
I'll take over.
Don't.
I want to keep working.
If I stop working for even a bit,
I start to think about Takeshi.
I see...
Hey, Miki!
Someone's collapsed outside!
Hey! Are you okay?
Hey!Hey!Hey!
Hey, Miki...
Are you okay? Hey!
Hey!
This girl...
Are you sure you
know what you're doing?
Yeah. Don't worry.
I'm the son of a doctor.
When I was in the biker gang, I fixed
up buddies who got hurt in fights.
Including you.
Hey, you're going to throw her
out when she wakes up, right?
I don't want to get
dragged into anything.
Even if it has something
to do with Takeshi's death?
I'm sure she's like this
because she discovered the truth.
It's not safe for her out there.
So you want to keep her here?
No way.
You have nothing against her, right?
Hey, are you okay?
You...
I'm home.
NO! Who are you people?
NO! Get off of me!
Sorry to barge in.
We hear that you're
best friends with Ami Hyuga.
Is she here?
I don't know what you're
talking about. She's not here!
I'm not involved with anything!
I don't know any Ami.
I don't know her!
I see.
I apologize then.
She wasn't here after all, huh?
Then we have to keep
you quiet about all this.
Hey, why don't you do it with her?
Right.
It's not often that
you get to do a college girl.
Where the hell did she go?
You can eat a rice ball
with one hand, right? Here.
So what you told us is true?
Takeshi was killed by a yakuza's son?
I wouldn't have lost
my arm if it weren't true.
Who and where is he? Tell me!
Shut up. I thought you didn't want
to have anything to do with me.
Is that how you talk
to people who saved your life?
You told me once
not to play the victim.
Well, right back at you!
Now you did it.
I don't give a damn
if you only have one arm!
Hey... What are you doing, Miki?
She hasn't recovered yet.
Please don't stop us.
No matter what shape I'm in,
I just want to settle this.
It's a battle between those
who've lost loved ones.
The loser will be covered in blood.
I cant lose.
NO matter what happens to my body,
I have to seek revenge for Yu's sake!
Me too.
I'm furious with myself for not
being able to protect Takeshi!
Ow!
Are you okay?
Ami, you're pretty good
even if you only have one arm.
You came at me
with everything you had.
I like that.
Mind if I join you
in getting your revenge?
You'll be with a murderer.
Are you sure?
They're my enemies too.
Besides, if there's a way to get
revenge by not killing people...
...then I'd like to know it.
It's kill, kill, kill.
Ami, it must be hard
to fight with that kind of body.
I'll make you a new arm.
One made of steel.
You think you can
avenge your brother like that?
He won't be able
to rest in peace, you idiot!
It's tough!
This training is for moving forward!
You didn't even move a millimeter.
Come on! Keep going!
Cute face.
Those are the eyes. Remember that!
Can I help you?
The Kimuras moved away recently.
Where?
How should I know?
But I'm glad the yakuza are gone.
Thank you.
.
Oh, Ami.
I'm almost done.
Thank you... for everything.
I hope you'll stay friends with my wife.
She can't have any more kids.
I wasn't able to understand her pain.
But, Arm...
She was saved by meeting you.
So please take good care of her.
I Will.
Ami! We have a problem!
The Kimura family's gone.
What?
They're up to something.
Hey, do you hear a strange noise?
The machine gun...
Okay!
All right, calm down... Calm down...
We are...
...the Junior High Shuriken Gang!
Whoa.
Takeshi's house is really dirty.
Excuse me, but could
you stop wandering around?
Your family members
died on their own...
...so don't hold a grudge against us.
Honestly, it's disturbing.
I'm going to kill that bastard!
You stupid brat.
You're gonna get it!
We might get killed first!
The wire...
Honey, is that
machine gun finished yet?
Hang on! I just have
to attach the trigger!
Aw, looks like it's over now.
Damn it...
It went in! Yes! It's done!
I'm finished...
Ami! Take it!
Honey!
Honey! Honey!
Shit...
She's pretty good...
I'm hit!
Mommy...
Honey! Honey...
Honey...
No!
Honey! Honey!
Honey...
Suguru...
.
Damn it... Who killed my son?
I'll never forgive... Who killed him?
I'm sorry about your loss.
I know who killed your sons.
Do you want me to help you'?
There's no point hiding here.
My boss will find you two
and send out an assassin.
I'm not running away.
I'm just waiting for
my chance for revenge.
Stop bluffing and
give me something to eat.
I'm hungry. I'm really hungry.
If I kill you, then I won't know
where to find the Kimuras.
So I'll let you live for now!
Here's a rice ball.
Eat it.
Come on.
Thanks.
But that kindness
happens to be your weakness.
Thank you for coming.
I know that you have all lost
your children for no good reason.
Your enemies will surely come here.
I want to help you get your revenge!
We're going to kill those women!
Ryota!
Damn...
I can't believe I screwed up...
Ami.
Did you find out
where the Kimuras are?
I really want to kill them.
Miki?
Miki, let me take a look.
No...
It looks bad...
Her wound is getting infected.
She'll die if you don't
get her to a hospital.
Miki... You can't fight like this.
Let's go to the nearest
hospital to get you fixed up.
Wait a minute...
You want to go without me?
You've gotta be kidding me.
I can't just relax without
getting my revenge!
No!
Miki?
'ZZZ
I don't want you to die.
I'll be the one to die
after getting our revenge.
So I don't want you to die.
I lost everyone I loved.
I have no more hope left.
But after I met you...
...was able to understand
what it's like to protect someone.
MM .
You're the only one who
means something to me now.
Thanks, Ami.
But I lost my husband and Takeshi.
I'm as good as dead.
If I don't crush the Kimuras,
then they'll never rest in peace.
Ami...
Ami, I'm begging YO"-
Please let me die in peace.
Miki...
Come on.
We don't have much time.
Tell me where the Kimuras are hiding.
I'm not going to tell you
even if you bash my head in!
I see.
Hey, what are you doing?
Stop messing around...
Stop! Stop!
Stop it...
You nailed me!
Using a nail isn't fair!
Stop complaining.
We're risking our lives, you know!
Miki, let's go.
Let's go on a journey to hell
in order to kill the Kimuras!
It's time to get your revenge.
This is too much! NO more!
The Kimuras have
a hideout at Ichinooka Shrine.
Ichinooka Shrine?
This is the way
to Ichinooka Shrine, right?
Ami, if you can't use your machine
gun, use the weapons in this bag.
We're running short
on machine-gun bullets.
You can use...
This.
These bullets are very powerful.
It's nothing like the other ones.
Use it to finish your opponent.
It's got too much power and might
just destroy your machine gun.
Think of it as
a last present from Suguru.
Okay.
Even with a weapon like that,
the two of you are gonna get killed.
But it's impressive that
you got the boss all fired up.
Shut up.
Come on, Arm.
Let's go!
What? You actually came?
My parents are angry.
Why don't you just die
before you complicate things?
What? You little punk!
Huh? What's this?
H v U
Tomokazu...
Takeshi"
Yoshio...
H v U
Tomokazu...
Takeshi"
I'll give you credit for coming this far.
I'll do whatever
it takes to protect our son!
You're not the only ones who can
become demons for your families.
Listen!
We have gathered to punish
you for our sons' deaths.
We're the Super Mourner Gang!
Shit... You bastards...
Feel the wrath of my son!
Am".!
You killed my son!
Give him back!
NO way.
Bulletproof vests under the pictures...
.
Tomokazu! I'm sorry!
I'm out of bullets.
Wrong target.
Thanks for waiting, Ami.
Do you think you can kill me?
My most deadly ninja weapon.
The executioner's blade. Take this!
Takeshi"
Ami.
Here we go! Take this!
Miki!
Ami...
Don't worry about me...
Kill the Kimuras.
You have to kill them for me!
I've chopped off such a useless thing.
In a matter of minutes, you will die.
Then you won't be able
to hold a grudge against me.
But if you still want to kill me...
...then come this way!
How dare you do this to Miki...
Miki...
GO...
Die in front of our great Hanzo's spirit!
You will perish.
Apologize to the great
Hanzo in the afterlife!
She...
I couldn't protect you...
Take that, you brutal yakuza.
Ami...Ami...
I-I... I'm coming...
You're not going anywhere!
Ryota!
Am".!
Don't let them beat you!
MM ...
Miki, I wish I could join you...
But I want you to wait for me...
Sho Kimura's still in the main hall...
I can't die until I take his head.
Missy, I'm over here.
L-I'm scared... I'm scared...
I'm using these three as my shield.
If you want to kill me, go ahead.
But they're going to die too.
You're such a coward.
A ninja does whatever
it takes to survive.
Sho is much more of
a ninja than his father was.
That's because I raised him right.
You stupid bitch.
A person without love
can't possibly love their child!
NO way...
The chainsaw was deflected?
I'm sorry.
I'm wearing a special bra.
A steel one.
A drill bra.
It can't be...
Yes, it can be.
What do you think of it?
Enjoy my drill.
Well?
How do you like my drill bra?
Now I'll drill your face.
I'm scared... I'm scared...
.
Sho!
Are you okay?
This is for the ones you killed!
Your love turned out to be harmful...
I hope you both rot in hell!
Listen up. GO down
the mountain and get some help.
Find the police and tell them
that lots of people have been killed...
...and that a girl
named Ami Hyuga did it.
GO on.
Even if you get bullied,
don't let them win.
Promise?
Yeah, I'll be strong like you one day.
.
I'm such a stupid sister.
You probably have nothing
but contempt for me now.
Yu...