Good luck, general yin
A man must do or die
Mr. ho, before I left
lord zheng is concerned about you
if he can strike back with his army
and defeat the tartars
credit for canton will be yours
one must sacrifice for one's country
the six brothers arrested by tartars
were tortured but have so far
refused to make a confession
this is most admirable
if I failed
I wouldn't even get arrested
general yin
Mr. ho, please
Sirs
when inspector-general and general tien ta
arrive, please say a good word for me
don't worry, Mr. magistrate
general tien ta ordered us
to capture the six traitors
the inspector-general is specially
invited to supervise the execution
yes, yes...
Tang San-yao, it's almost 12:30
don't forget the general's command
the inspector-general is here
make way...
Make way...
We're trapped
general yin, I knew you'd be here
to "welcome" the inspector-general
But he has not yet reached canton
Stop
your skill is comparable to a general
let's have a fair fight
a general to a general
let me try you out
good, I need a substitute
Let me fight you single-handedly
Quiet down
the teacher's here
the teacher's here, hurry up...
Mr. ho
What's it? What's happened to Mr. ho?
Please have tea, Mr. ho
Mr. ho, why are you so late?
Did you go to see the execution?
Leave me alone!
Executions should be interesting
lin zhen, it depends on who it is
if it is the tartars who invaded us
of course it is interesting
but today's convicts are patriots
they are all han's martyrs
do you still think it is interesting?
Yesterday, I taught you sacrifice
for the sake of a righteous cause
do you all understand?
Yes
hurry up...
It's here
Is he dead or alive?
He's so stiff, of course he's dead
he's a hero
what did you say?
Capture him
yes
you're an accomplice
chief tang... listen to me
this student is not a bad man
he's the son of a seafood shop owner
son of a shop owner?
Yes, exactly
these are his classmates
yes, we're his classmates
where are you studying?
They all study in Chong wen college
are you vouching for them, Mr. wang?
Yes. Apologize to lord tang
you're too young and gauche
always causing trouble
Do you know who I am?
I do... I do. Tang San-yao, lord tang
yes, yes. Let's go, quickly
uncle wang, we didn't do anything wrong
yes, I know
tang San-yao is notorious
for his craze after money, lives and women
you mustn't antagonize him
as the saying goes, "one must...
"Humble oneself under enemy's rule"
Mr. ho... please open the door
who is it?
Mr. ho
open the door, Mr. ho
Mr. ho...
What's the matter?
There's something we can't understand
so we've come here even at this hour
"humble oneself under enemy's rule"
do we and our children have to
humble ourselves forever?
I say, we'd be beheaded if we don't
if we fear not death, we don't have to
you're right. It's well said
one brave man alone is not enough
but unity is strength
mr, ho, the tartars are well-armed
we...
Men owes allegiance to his country
lord zheng is recruiting in Taiwan
he becomes tartar's biggest trouble
the manchu emperor has ordered
coastal residents to move away
and to be on their guard
Mr. ho
I wish lord zheng could use us
the day will come
don't you all want to help?
Yes
good. Come here
yes
secret documents will arrive by sea
I need a way to bypass customs
liu yu-te
your family is running a
seafood shop, don't you?
Yes
Open sesame...
Shut sesame...
Mr. ho sent us here
good
Little brother, you're a brave fellow
Lock it up...
Yes,
hurry...
Dad, has San li's abalone arrived?
The abalone... go, go now
but last time, the sea
cucumbers have been...
Ah te, what's going on?
A big order for abalone was placed
I am showing them some samples
so you're in business now?
Ah te, you don't need
to take the whole case
I'm in a hurry to deliver it
hurry? Do you know the market price?
The quality is high.
Remember to raise the price
open it
yes
Excellent kung fu
not really. You'll find the best
at Shaolin temple
Mr. ho, we could invite them to join us
yes
Shaolin monks don't involve
in worldly matters
if Shaolin could teach kung fu to laymen
people could fight the tartars
that would be great
South gate, mountain yue. Here... it's here
general tien
arise
come over
Lately, we've suppressed rebels
and found this on their leaders
zheng Cheng-gong's edict
look, what have you been doing?
There must be many of zheng's men
hiding in canton
we must capture the rebels
and kill them to scare them off
Who's that?
No idea. He's secretive, maybe a spy
I'm innocent. I'm a delivery boy
I've brought dried fish. Look!
Shut up
Lord zheng, notorious rebels...
Who told you to bring this here?
No... why ask?
Kid, we can make you talk.
We'll take you back
and torture you with manchu ways
we'll torture you all one after another
see if you'll talk or not
I'll talk... don't torture me
I... I say,
there is someone
Tang San-yao,
go on with the torture if you like
Mr. ho, I saw a squadron of manchu troops
there are over 100 and
are patrolling our alley
Mr. ho, what shall we do?
We must keep calm and be on the alert
yien-pin, let them hide in your home
Mr. ho, what about you...
Mr. ho, Mr. ho
go quickly, go
what about you?
Hurry up, quick
Master, look
please have mercy... please talk to them...
Please ask them not to...
Quiet! General's order:
No dried fishes can be kept
then...
What's your relationship to liu yu-te?
He... he's my son
bring him here
he's not home... why do you want him?
We've uncovered many spies recently
one's a teacher; Another's his pupil
liu yu-te's a pupil of that school
we'll capture him and torture him
sir, our young master won't do such thing
yes! Please have mercy
how do you know he wouldn't?
Let's talk it over...
Dad...
Yu-te, run quickly... yu-te
young master, run, run quickly...
Run quickly, young master
you want to rebel?
Yu-te, run quickly, run
He's innocent... my son
liu yu-te, come up quickly
my son is innocent! My son
Change your clothes at once
everyone in school uniform will be arrested
wonder what's happened to my home?
You two try to find a hiding place first
we can find out later
right, let's go now
What has happened to my home?
Your home... your...
Tell me
all the houses in the street next
to your home have been cordoned off
what about my father?
Dad...
Don't be sad. It's the same for mine
I wish I had learned kung fu
instead of studying
so I could fight them
studies teach us right from wrong
what's the use of that?
We can't talk sense with the tartars
We can't stay in this town anymore
I heard that the martial
arts headquarters is...
Shaolin temple
We're lucky that we made it
let's go straight on
Hey! Did you see a group of men riding by?
Why don't you answer me?
Go
Dismount and chase them
yes
these two must be traitors
one stay behind to watch
the horses, others chase
yes
Hurry up
Go
Liu yu-te, mount it
liu yu-te?
Liu yu-te, escape now. Go
don't let him get away
Liu yu-te, good luck
Please give me some water
Thank you, sir
how far is it to Shaolin temple?
It's not far, only up the mountain
but you look like you can't make it
I can... even if I have to crawl there
Sit down.
I don't think you can
Shaolin monks buy food here everyday
their cart is over there
Hurry up... do it orderly and quickly
get going, go
why is it so heavy?
Yes, I don't know why
go. You'll be punished if you're late
let's go, quick
push harder, harder, go
Hurry up, park the cart there
come and lend a hand, everybody
why are you standing there?
Come here to help, hurry
take this to the kitchen. Be quick
Why are you so slow? Hurry up, hurry