Quick
Move it quickly
Lets' say if one of
you had Twin swords and were...
...confronted by this technique
what would you do?
Then I would surely die with pierced guts
Master
Follow me
Master, we were lucky to accomplish your mission
Brother Wang gathered the darts and hid the money
Have you seen Lei Li who uses the Twin swords?
Yes. Excels at skills with
both the long & short sword
In less than a year...
he has already made a name for himself
But then, his arrogance and inexperience...
will lead him to a trap
You've carried out my instructions
Yes
We've killed Chieftain Ho's brothers and...
sent the bodies back to Yuan Sing Security bureau;
Along with a word that while dying they said...
Lei Li robbed and killed them
Cheiftain Ho had sent Lei Li a letter...
and asked him to meet at the Black Forest
Master, once you show yourself
...he'll never appear in the martial arts world again!
Master, you are number one in the martial arts world
No one can match your fame
I am here. Yet, why the hell be so pusillanimous!
What is it? Speak up
Friend Lei, your skills
have rocked the martial world
I little expected you to turn out a robber
...and stoop so low
If you have been robbed and desire to seek my help
I promise I'll get the goods back for you
Two friends brought back our dead brother's body
They said our brother told him before dying...
that the robber used twin swords
So who else could it be?
Nonsense... I'm not responsible for the robbery
I suggest you go look for Cheng Giu
Halt!
I'll teach you a lesson
You are such a pain in the neck
Attack
Lei Li, you robber and plunderer. You...
However reckless, you can't equal my twin swords
Master, some people are fighting over there
Hero Lung
Well well... Chieftain Ho, what's up?
He... he is a robber
You be the judge, Hero Lung
You are still young
Why use your martial art skills
...to commit such vile deeds!
Who are you?
Lung Er Zi
Oh, so it's chivalrous Hero Lung
Your fame precedes you
That's kind of you. And your good name?
Lei Li
Your name is not new to me either
But you haven't been righteous
Considering your age I'm prepared to spare you
...provided you repent your ways
That's sheer nonsense
Or do you refuse to heed my warning?
Let's see how good your skills are
Well... newborn calf not
scared of the tiger, huh!
I'm prepared to try out some moves with you
If I lose, I'll cut off my right arm and...
retire from the martial arts world
I'll do the same if I lose
Why come to such an extreme decision?
You are young
lt'd suffice if you just amend your ways
Bull shit
I'll let you attack first
Who are you to decide?
Well... I'll make the first move then
Son, the more experienced the better
I have lost!
Don't attach too much importance to
winning and losing
Here is your knife
You may forget what you have promised
A man ought to keep his word
I'll cut off my arm and retreat
The arm shall remain here
...and be a reminder to evil-doers
Don't chase, let him go
I'll make it my responsibility to get back
...your money pouch
Chivalrous Lung, you are a true hero
Today, if it weren't for you...
I'm afraid we'd all be dead
Go back please, everyone
I'll send forth the lost money once I find it
Our sincere gratitude
You're welcome
Please escort chieftain
...and his men back
You two remain here
and help me trace the lost goods
Yes
We take your leave
So where have you both...
hidden the money from Yuan Sing security bureau?
Master
Chieftain Ho must announce this matter...
then your fame will be even greater
Yes, it would add to your heroism...
to have rid of an arch enemy
This Lei Li fellow;
A few more years in the martial arts world...
and his fame would have soared higher than yours
Where is the money hidden?
Master, for our hard work
...can we please have it?
No one knows about this anyway
Teacher, we'll do whatever errand you give us
You both are actually trying to coerce me!
No, we don't dare
Master
You should know
Last year I took your two brothers...
to victory against the Bai Fa Swordsman
How come they have never returned, huh?
No idea
You're like them
Master...
We don't dare ask for money anymore
The money is hidden at the Tiger Mansion, we...
Because you have only one arm
I've taken you in out of pity
You must speed up your work
Don't think because
it rains there'll be no customer
Go to the kitchen and have the noodles...
ready for serving
I have never come across...
such a silent man!
Lei Li, we have customers
A bottle of wine and a plate of beef, quick
On the double
Boss Li, turn up the lights
When are we going to be served?
You've hired a cripple
A lot of money you'd have saved
Yes
What the heck!
It's been raining heavily these days
Hey, people say you won't speak unless it thunders
Is that true?
If it's like that...
then he should transform into a tortoise
Damn, the table is dirty
Do you take us for fools?
Do it quickly
Boss Li, look
A cripple is useless
He has to remove the plates to wipe the table
Just do it
Just ask your mother to grow you one more arm
Please order whatever you desire
Although he is handicapped
...he is quick and diligent
Brother Lei
I'll do it
Miss, we put it on
your father's tab as before, right?
Sure
It's raining heavily, I'll accompany you
Okay
Won't you have a drink with my dad?
Lei Li, you're always being bullied
Like those thugs you also should keep...
a sword at the waist
Maybe they'd lay off then
Dad often remarks that...
you must have known kung fu before
Is that right?
Is it true?
Ba Jiao, you go carefully. I'll head back
Hero Fung
Who are you?
Oh, it's really you, we're saved
Everyone knows that...
your twin swords are matchless
You've detained me just because of this?
Oh no, we're running for our lives
From a distance we saw your gait
...so we ran up to you
We've really met our saviour
Hero Fung, we have been robbed
Please help us
Right
Where?
Just over there at the slope
We fought for our lives and escaped
This is a dangerous road
Yesterday too someone was robbed
It must be done by the men at Tiger Mansion
Yes, Tiger Mansion
Our money has been robbed by Chieftain Chan
Okay, I'm headed towards Tiger Mansion anyway
I'll remember your request
Many thanks
Hey guys!
They didn't say which treasury house!
Never mind, for sure this fellow
...will go to Tiger Mansion anyway
The top guys of Tiger Mansion are at the tavern
Let's go and have a drink
No, teacher has forbidden us
...to consort with their folk
Why is that? Teacher himself...
Shut up and go
Hero Fung will be here soon
We'll be in trouble if he runs into us
Let's go
The wine is good here
Hey, get us another bottle
Be quick
This kid sure has some skills
Yes
You see, a cripple has to think of alternate ways
You needn't speak on his behalf
How long have you been here?
Almost 2 years
You studied martial arts?
Look at me when speaking
Lei Li
Miss Ba, you want to buy wine?
Yes
Let me help you
Miss, he can do it pretty fast
...you needn't show sympathy
You should pity us, we're drinking alone
Why don't you drink with us?
Look, the lad objects to it
Where is she from?
She... she's the daughter of blacksmith Ba
So I see
Pretty girl, we need to have a lot of work done
Please ask your father to come up with you
...to our place
Good food and wine; it'd be real fun with us
What else would you both like?
Damn kid, mind your own business
Gentleman
Please ask the good sir to let him be
Shut up or you'll have a hard time too
Damn, the lady has run away
Now you get her back for me
Do you hear me?
Bastard, you want to be a hero
Be careful, he knows kung fu
You know kung fu? Very well
That's too cautious... here, watch me
Hear that, bastard?
Get the girl back
Didn't you hear?
Hey
I'm here
Please don't bully him anymore
Come, drink with us
You...
Let her go
Let go of her
Who are you?
Just a passer-by
You're the twin-swords hero Fung?
That's right
Listen, brother...
Hurry, let's go
Why didn't you fight back just now?
I don't know what you're talking about
Come out
Who were those two thugs a while back?
They're the top guys at Tiger Mansion
Your swordsmanship is great
Those two fellows...
could also take on many at a time
Who is that one-armed youth?
He is the helper here at Boss Li's eatery
Don't pretend to be a hero
Why don't you just let them have their way?
Look at you now, all beaten up!
I run a small place. Rather not have any trouble
Miss Ba, your dad awaits the wine
You go back
Brother Lei
Please go
I'll come again...
to give you something
My friend, you...
If there's something you need...
please let us know and I'll make it
People say real fighters don't show their strength;
But I don't understand...
I don't know what you're talking about!
Chief
Before Fung comes to Tiger Mansion
...why did you fight with him?
Chief, we didn't want to
He unexpectedly turned up, we had no choice
Look at you nincompoops!
Hero Fung's swordsmanship is exceptional
If he came charging in, I'm afraid...
Give the order to tighten security
Yes
Master Chan, please come in
Your men had a fight with Fung?
Yes
The two leaders of the Mansion have been wounded
How are their skills?
Reasonably good
According to them Fung's skills are excellent
...and out of this world
Alright, have invitations sent out...
to martial artists within a few hundred miles
Have them all meet at this place
Brother Lung, we must lure Fung here
...to get rid of him
It isn't advisable to leak this out
Oh, come on. I have my own ideas
Have our names on the invitation
Yes
And send one to Fung too
Set the date at five days from now
Those who serve the invitation must be highly skilled
Brother Lung, I still miss the point
Tiger Mansion is mysterious to the outside world
Nobody knows what we have done
I want Fung to come in...
and defeat him in front of everyone;
Thus forcing him out of the martial arts world
A superb plan indeed!
Dad
Yes dear, what is it?
I think you have something on your mind
You approached me so many times
...yet you won't speak up
Dad, don't you have a good sword hidden away?
You said, unless it is a great swordsman...
the sword's power cannot be brought forth
And also that it has a peerless edge
Yes. Why have you brought this up?
I want to give it to Lei Li
Give it to him for what?
He is a good man, but bullied by many
If he had a sword
...it'd perhaps be better
Nonsense
The poor fellow has lost his right arm
Naturally he'd be bullied
Know this, presently he is only pushed around
Say if, how good a sword he may have...
he will surely die by another's sword
He can practice swordplay though; it's better...
he died in a fight than be trampled upon like this
That's utter rubbish
Do you know how I came by that sword?
It was 20 years ago; even before you were born
On an evening just like this
A young hero barged into our place
He had this sword...
and a sword stuck in his guts, bleeding profusely
I hid the sword
Not until much later I found out that...
he was a famous swordsman of the time
Alas... what good did the sword do!
However strong one is,
there'd always be one better!
Keep the wind bellows going
Jiao dear, have you gone to bed?
Yes, father
I suggest you go...
to the town and find suitable lodging
What, are you turning me away?
No, it's just that our place
is not very appropriate
Mr. Boss
You're wrong there
One's body isn't even 7 ft.
Could settle down anywhere
Am I right?
Friends, they say wine makes the heart sadder
But better bend one's conduct
than to keep kowtowing
Come, drink with me
Sir, you are drunk
Only a real hero, a brave man
can transcend above everything else, like you
Whyever...
You...
Lei Li, don't offend customers
Lei Li? You are Lei Li?
Lei, my friend
Please don't follow me
Boss Li
Where's that chap...
who wounded some people here?
Is someone looking for me?
What do you want with me?
Fighters within 500 miles...
will meet at the Tiger Mansion in five days
Here is the invitation from Hero Lung
Hero Lung?
Yes, Hero Lung Er Zi
Why would he consort with the folks...
at the Tiger Mansion?
Tiger Mansion is famous
What's so strange about Hero Lung...
having a relationship with Chieftain Chan?
Right, I'm going up there anyway
Let's have the invitation
Come on, what's to fear?
There's a little something I want to know
Yes, please ask
Tiger Mansion is known for heroism & justice;
Yet discreetly indulges in unlawful activity
The 2 recent robberies... who all were involved?
There has been no such incident
Hero Fung, we're here to deliver the invitation
...with good intent. Please don't hurt us
Go tell Chan Chun Nam
I'll be there in 5 days
Ask him to be prepared to greet me
And yes, my regards to Hero Lung
Let's go
Lei Li, Lei Li
Brother Lei
See what I've got for you!
What is it?
A blade... a good sword
Tuck that sword in your waist cloth
Whoever wanting to bully you...
will have second thoughts
Thank you, but I won't use it
I... I can't, please take it back
You are willing to be bullied?
Ba Jiao, you don't understand
It's useless even if I carry it
I did have a sword once, I...
Kindly take it back, I don't want
No, once I've brought it I won't take it back
I'll leave it here. It's up to you if you want it
Ba Jiao!
Truly rare... wonder if I can ever be like him!
Abandoned his twin swords!
This girl is a tender sweetie pie
We both can enjoy her
You're injured more. Naturally I'd go first
Oh, that doesn't matter
Sure
Ba Jiao!
Lei Li, whom are you chasing?
Men from Tiger Mansion
They... they took Ba Jiao
Please don't cry
If Lei Li had not come after you...
you would have ended up at Tiger Mansion
Lei Li?
Yes
I think he wanted to return you the sword
...and saw you were abducted
Why doesn't he want the sword?
You may not understand
Tell me. Perhaps I would
He had great skills before
Maybe even greater than mine
But he was defeated...
and lost an arm
Now he just wishes...
that he'd forget he ever knew Kung Fu
Unknowingly you might have made him suffer more
...by giving him the sword
I see!
Brother Fung
Brother Lei
I am a helper at the tavern
I'd rather not talk about the past
You still treat me as your friend
I treat you as my brother
Brother Fung, come along
I'll cook something delicious for you
Sure
Yes, go ahead, you two... just forget about me!
Come, grab my sleeve
Lei Li, I have never seen you smile
Until noon, there won't be customers
I'll keep you company
Don't mind me, carry on with your work
Lei, the customers are waiting
Brother Lei, I admire you can do that
I simply envy you
Come on, quit kidding
Think I'd joke with someone of your experience?
You had better not go to this meeting...
at Tiger Mansion
I must, I think Hero Lung, too...
has been tricked by those men
I have to reveal their treachery
Hero Lung? Lung Er Zi
I shouldn't have mentioned him
That's fine
I lost to...
his three-sectioned staff
Hero Fung, there is one technique...
specially designed against twin swords
I lost because of this technique. This...
It's okay.
You've long stopped thinking about kung fu
I won't fight with him either
So why talk about such things?
Brother Lei, I have decided
I'll retire after this meeting
We'll take up farming at Tai Wu lake
What are you laughing about?
I don't know for sure if Ba Jiao...
will leave her father to go along with you
Don't give up, not everyone knows kung fu
Those who do might not be that much happier
Brother Fung
I haven't been happy this past year
I torture myself daily
Only until now I can realise in my heart...
that I have no more pain
Thank you for coming, we're honoured
- Please
- Thanks
Brother Lung
Do you think Fung will come?
He certainly will
I have seen too many of such young heroes
Yes, many of them...
have been defeated by you...
over the years
But brother Lung...
why do you never kill them?
That's why I'm known as Chivalrous hero Lung
Our Jin died at the hands of Fung;
You think that would make him change his mind?
Don't worry
He'll think I'm on his side and that I'm here...
to uphold the justice
Right there and then I'll decide what to do
I'll be back before the sun sets
Brother Fung, if you fight with Lung
...you must guard against that special technique
He is a famous swordsman
Why would I fight with him?
If he is a famous swordsman...
why would he be with the gang of Tiger Mansion?
Most likely he has been deceived
I'll sort it out
Well, I hope so too
Brother Fung, I'll await your return
Right on
That sword is still with me. Please take it back
To take it back in broad daylight...
would get me a good scolding from dad
It's better to leave it with you
Most welcome, Hero Fung
Please
Hero Fung has arrived
Your fame precedes you
It's an honour to meet you in person
You are Chan Chun Nan?
Yes
Where's Hero Lung?
Hero Lung and other heroes...
are waiting in the grand hall
Good. Don't try any moves. Let's proceed there
And you'll receive a fair hearing. Come on
Hero Lung
What is the matter, Chief?
Who is this young man?
This is twin swordsman, our friend Fung
Hero Lung
You flatter me
Why do you have a conflict with Chieftain Chan?
Hero Lung, Folks
I am afraid you've been deceived
Tiger Mansion looks innocent enough
But it is an evil place
Chief, is it like that?
You allege that hero Fung
injured or killed your men
What actually happened?
There is no such thing
But it is a fact Fung is the culprit
Fung, my friend
What have they done?
Robbing
Nonsense. What treasury house did I rob?
Exactly
Who did they rob?
One of them is Lin Shing.
About the other I'm checking
What? Lin Shing!
Is that the one in Chun Kong county?
Most probably
What a joke!
I'm the chieftain of Lin Shing Security Bureau
Wouldn't I know about robbery at my place?
Hero Lung, you'll be the judge
Fung, what about the other security bureau?
Hero Fung, I'm afraid you're grossly mistaken
You've injured men of Tiger Mansion...
slaughtered them and lied about the incident
If everyone with some martial art skills
...were as outrageous;
What will this world come to?
Oh!
So inviting me here was to teach me a lesson!
No, I was passing by...
and heard of the incident
And since we are all martial artists
I just hope to be an intermediary
You've just arrived and drew a sword at the host
Isn't it out of line?
Goodbye everyone
Hold it!
The so-called leader of Tiger Mansion, Jin Yi
abducted the daughter of...
blacksmith Ba in Ma Chao town
Hero Lung
About this why don't we
clarify with Chieftain Chan?
As per our information
two of them were going by...
when you suddenly appeared and killed one
You believe him?
Actually speaking I can't believe you
You mentioned two bureaus were robbed
but actually there has been no such case
I understand now. I totally understand, Hero Lung
So you are up to that
Fung, you've recklessly
harmed people with your swords
Today, in front of all of us...
You must right this wrong
All along it's me you wanted to pick a fight with
Why bother with this nonsense?
Hand me the weapon
Let's witness the power of your twin swords
...that has made you so reckless
Please make way, everyone
If you promise to amend your ways...
I wouldn't necessarily want to fight you
Save this for after you win the duel
Watch this
This is your special technique
And you can't thwart it
If I had three swords, I could have defeated you
But with just two hands how can you handle three?
Look at you, barging in like this
I almost dropped the egg
Says who? Even with a number of eggs in mid-air
...I'm sure you can still catch them
Let me help you
Hero Fung should have returned by now
There you go again... you're so anxious!
The sun hasn't gone down yet
If you cut your arm
and retire from the martial world...
I'll let you out of this place
How many were there before me?
Hero Lung is so merciful, just do it
I... I'll kill him
Chieftain Chan, the matter is out of my hands
The quarrel between you both...
shall be dealt with by yourselves
Sure
Relax, he's been seriously wounded
Everyone, little did we expect this to happen
...and disturb you all
This is not Hero Lung's responsibility
He had already let him go
It was his own fault
He sought his own death
But it could be said he died at my hands
Chieftain Chan, give him a proper burial
Yes
Please go back, gentlemen
My mood is spoilt. I just want to rest a few days
Yes
Lei Li, that twin-swords lad is great
In case if he had a mishap...
what's the use of worrying for him
Go and do your work
Teacher is great
Not only he had the kid buried appropriately
...but also wept at his grave
They all say our Master is such a hero
...and stands tall among men
This is real kung fu
Hey, bring the wine
C'mon, be quick. Stop dreaming
Who are you talking about?
What rubbish! That's none of your concern
I ask who are you talking about?
Speak
It's... about twin-sword Hero Fung
What about him?
He's dead and buried behind Tiger Mansion
This chap has gone nuts
That Fung is a good friend of his
Lei, you are here
Boss Li told me... he said Fung is dead
Why do good men die easily?
Lei Li, speak something
I'll avenge him
How can you...
I have to avenge him
Don't go, please
I must avenge him
Hurry, run!
Where is hero Fung buried?
Take me there
Over there
Attack
Quick... come on, move
Chieftain
What's happening out there?
Someone has stormed the place
...and killed three leaders
Who is it?
Don't know
Who are you?
You go and check what's happening!
Yes
Such swift swordsmanship!
It's him
Lung Er Zi
Lei Li
You've lost your arm, know your place
After that incident I've been humble & law-abiding
But you killed hero Fung; I'm here for revenge
Revenge?
What capability do you have?
Even when you were famous for your twin swords
...you lost to me
How will you avenge him today?
You are rather here to die with him
...and not avenge him
I... I'm here to accompany him in death
Meet your death now
If I had 3 swords I could defeat you
Fung wielded twin swords with both hands
But you could manage three with just one arm!
It's your turn to retire from
the martial arts world
Lei Lis