THE JOURNEY OF THE HYENA
Oh, shit.
Don't forget your change.
- Remember me to your mother.
- Yes.
- Peace be with you.
- And you.
- How are you?
- Good. And you?
Good.
My tomatoes are all over the place.
Help yourself, neighbor.
The postman's hiding something.
No letters from France.
My son doesn't write to me.
If you'd listened to me,
you'd never have let him go.
Nothing good comes of France.
You'll have to go to a marabout
to make him come back.
Kids like him
never come back from France,
or they bring back white women
with their diseases.
My son wouldn't do that.
I'll pay you
when my husband comes back.
Like hell! You'll pay now.
When will you pay us?
We're sick and tired of this.
- Let her go.
- Wait. I'll pay now.
- You're a disrespectful girl.
- You have to pay!
Your mom and I are good friends.
This never happened before.
Tell Mory to meet me at the university.
- Is he riding a motorcycle or an ox today?
- Get out of here!
- Beat it, you and your worn-out shoes!
- Beat it!
You say you're a student,
but you don't study!
You'll never make it in those weird pants.
You want me to tell Mory!
I don't like him.
He's got no class, no shame,
no job, nothing.
You ride around on that motorbike
with a cow's skull on it.
Go on, go to your university.
That place is like a freak show.
If you want water,
you'd better listen up.
Everyone, wait your turn.
Help her.
Okay, here we go.
Kids, if you've got nothing to do,
get out of here.
Stop it!
Hey, comrade, will the revolution
wait much longer for you?
So much for the sacred revolution.
All these chicks think about
is screwing.
- They're wasting their time.
- She's impure.
- Look at this fool.
- You think this is a circus?
Please, I just came to pick up Anta.
I get it.
It's your fault that she's always late
for our meetings.
Just wait.
I get it. He dressed up as a cowboy
so he could spy on us.
Kill him.
Pull. Come on.
- Hey, cutie.
- Leave me alone.
Leave those flat-assed
student chicks alone.
Where's Mory, Aunt Oumy?
Probably throwing up the rice
he still hasn't paid me for.
- That's your problem.
- Haven't you heard?
Mory threw himself over the cliff.
Now kill the goat!
There's a boat leaving tomorrow.
- Let's take it.
- Got the dough?
You can't even pay off all your debts.
That's no big deal.
We'll split and go to Europe illegally.
Then what?
No hassle. We'll get lucky.
We just need some ready cash.
Then we can tip the right guys.
We've got to dress up,
act like we're loaded.
We'll hand out francs
to all the kids we meet.
No one will catch on.
When we come back,
I'll be a big shot around here.
They'll have to call me Mr. Mory.
You can join the Red Cross.
You've heard of them, right?
They're a bunch of crooks,
absolutely loaded.
Seduce one,
they'll make you their president.
I've never seen anything like it!
You owe me!
Want to kill me?
If you want to stay out of jail,
pay your debt!
Whoreson! Son of a bitch! Bastard!
You've no dignity or shame!
I hope you die and go straight to hell!
Paris, Paris, Paris
A little piece of heaven on earth
- Look there.
- What?
Some Gris-Gris.
You mustn't touch them.
- Says who?
- My grandma.
Who told her?
Look.
There's all sorts here.
One for broken hearts.
One for syphilis.
And here's another one,
a good luck charm.
This card wins. This one loses.
Can I see?
This one loses.
- You think you can pick the winner?
- Just checking.
Okay, let's go.
You really think he can do it?
Black wins. Red loses!
Try your luck.
This one wins. This one loses.
Turn it over.
Black. You win.
You haven't played yet. Turn it over.
The ace wins.
The queen loses.
- I'm in for ten.
- Ten.
You have to chose the ace.
- What?
- The ace.
I'm putting in 100.
Come on. Let's play for 100 francs.
If you don't want to make money,
don't play.
The ace wins.
The queen loses.
I shuffle, and that's it.
Want to play? Come on. The ace wins.
Just like I said, the queen loses.
I shuffle, and that's it. Pick one.
1,000 francs. 1,000.
Small bets only.
- 1,000.
- What? You found a wallet?
Have a seat.
Let's see what I earned yesterday.
Here you go. 1,000.
Pick this one, you win.
Pick this one, you lose.
I shuffle, and that's it.
Pick one.
You lost, pal.
You lost.
Where's your 1,000?
Stop him!
Thief!
Give me a cigarette, kid.
Those assholes think
I ripped off 1,000 francs.
They haven't seen anything yet.
Just wait and see.
Have you realized
we're sitting on a gold mine?
What?
This wrestling arena makes
loads of money on Sundays.
- Get it?
- Yes.
I wonder where they keep the cash.
This is a great day for Senegal.
Long-standing ties
bind France and Senegal.
The Lebou tribe organized today's
event at the Iba Mar Diop stadium
to make a generous contribution
to the construction
of General de Gaulle's memorial.
It's a great event.
Elders, women, men and children
are gathered here today.
Ousmane Ngom faces
Robert Diouf in today's match.
Isn't that the same cop as before?
Yeah, it's him.
He won't bother anyone today.
He's got a full pack of cigarettes.
There's just one problem.
Which trunk do you think
the money is in?
- The green one on top.
- The green one?
No, the blue one.
That's why the other's on top.
- I bet it's in the green one.
- Don't contradict me.
I'm the boss man here.
It's in the blue one.
Let's grab it and go.
The Lebou tribe organized today's
event at the Iba Mar Diop stadium
to make a generous contribution
to the construction
of General de Gaulle's memorial.
All this cash
for General de Gaulle's memorial?
They should build more of them.
Boeing, Concorde or Caravelle -
Paris, here I come.
Anyone who treads on my toes
will be sorry.
The Eiffel Tower, Notre-Dame,
the Champs-Élysėes, the Arc de Triomphe,
the big one.
I'll move in the right circles,
hit on all the mulatto girls.
You can only be black or white here.
I'm sick of it.
What a surprise, brother.
You're a cop?
The other night, right after you left,
the place was raided by the police.
I only got away because
I'd gone to get cigarettes.
Beat it. We've never met.
Don't mess up my career.
Smart-ass.
Miss, much as I enjoy your company,
which one of these fine houses
is yours?
Drive on. I'm going to my second home,
my Maison de campagne.
This doesn't look so good,
all those cats.
Is this the right place? I'm scared.
How can you stand it here, miss?
All these windblown trees.
I'll drop you off and be on my way.
It gives me the creeps here.
Have you got a husband?
You must be brave to live here.
God help us.
God save us from places like this.
This is a bad place.
It's really scary.
You must not be Wolof.
Only white people could live out here.
What's that boat doing there?
If I had the tools, I'd fix it up
and we'd split for Paris.
Stop dreaming.
Even an angel couldn't move it.
Think of something else.
I got it!
See all the way down there?
Turn right, and you get
to that fat guy's place.
He's got a nice house.
I met him at Mapenda's.
It's really nice.
Let's go pay him a visit.
But before we go,
I've got to take a dump.
Go ahead.
It's Mory.
Scram.
Have a seat, Mory.
You go join the women. Go on.
The joy of love
Is only fleeting
But heartbreak
Lasts a lifetime
I left everything
For that ungrateful Sylvie
But she left me
For someone else
Make yourself at home, Mory.
Relax, this is a house of joy
and pleasant company.
This is my place.
You can have whatever you want.
I'm going to take a shower.
I'm covered in salt.
I'm salty enough
without adding any extra.
Mory, who's that short-haired chick?
Listen to me.
I'm not jealous,
but there's a big difference
between hens and goats.
Strip. I'll rub your back.
The water's just right.
Mory, I'm Charlie.
Charlie, the mother hen.
I make everyone happy.
That boy you just saw,
he's my number-four boy.
When he arrived,
he was as skinny as a rat.
Now he looks great.
I took care of him.
I massaged him,
cooked for him, made him happy.
So you want to go to France?
Honey, France isn't what it used to be.
When I lived there,
France was really great.
The Champs-Élysėes,
Pigalle, Montparnasse.
Mory, come on. The water's great.
Mory, I'll scrub your back for you.
Let me wash you.
I'll show you what I can do.
The water's just right.
Come on, let me show you what I can do.
The water's perfect.
Come on.
The master says you're to take us.
Hurry up.
I thank the griot, the percussionist.
Today we'll see if you can play
and I can dance.
Love me, I'm a wrestler anyway.
Hate me, I'm a wrestler anyway.
Allah decides who is a wrestler.
Allah has decided
no one can oppose him.
See my ass?
Birane Thione attacked me,
and I shoved him with it.
I sent Sa Niambour flying
with a shoulder shove.
I did the same thing
to Doudou Backa too.
I thank the griot, the percussionist.
I laid out Diop Dione.
I gave Ibou Faye his big break.
Griot, your drum is pure gold.
Your drumstick is pure silver.
A boy as tall as me should be king,
but I'm not.
So when I fight, I have to win.
My father's strength is in me.
My father's rage is in me.
My father's moves are in me.
My father's talent is in me.
I want kids who'll play for me.
At least they'll wake me up.
Let's go.
Here's Mory The prodigal son is back
Mory, the good, the egghead
The well-educated
Mory, the great
Stop.
You will never bring shame
Vultures and hyenas
Will never get the better of you
A feast for the prodigal son
I am here before you
I will be with you till the end
Let the drums beat
Mory, you are our chosen one
Our favorite friend
Mory, you are in our hearts
Mory, answer me
Talk to me, Mory
Say yes to me, Mory
The prince said yes to me
The sky is clear now
Mory said yes to me
Hello?
Central Police Headquarters?
Is Sergeant Blanchet there?
He isn't?
What about Mr. Thioye?
He's out too?
Is there anyone available?
Give me the division commander
Djibril Diop, please.
Ah, he's there.
Tell him it's Charlie, please.
Is that you, Mambety?
Hello.
How are you?
Inspector Mambety, you're an ingrate.
You promised to come to my house,
but then you vanished.
We'll discuss it at home.
Anyway, I'm not calling about that.
It's business.
I'm calling
because somebody ripped me off.
He wanted to go to Europe.
He needed cash and came to me.
I wanted to help him.
You know what I'm like, a real Pygmalion.
You know, I always help the kids.
He came in. I was taking a shower.
He stole all my clothes.
Then he ran off.
Anyway, he's easy to recognize.
He's tall with messy hair,
looks like a hippy.
He's with a girl
who's got a dreadful hairdo.
They stole one of my cars,
the all-American classic
with stars and stripes.
I don't remember the license number.
No.
But they're hungry.
You'll find them at a restaurant
or a travel agency.
They love money.
Don't look - Yes.
They want to leave the country.
I'm counting on you.
Okay, I'll make a statement.
Why don't you come over
and take it down, honey?
I've got some first-class whiskey.
You will? Fine.
See you tonight.
VACATION AND LEISURE
Here you are, miss.
Have a nice trip.
Miss, haven't I seen you somewhere?
Must have been New York.
PORT OF DAKAR
NO ENTRY WITHOUT AUTHORIZATION
This city's rough.
No entry on the right.
No entry on the left.
Men with clubs everywhere.
All because there are too many debts.
But we've got to keep going.
Debts never killed anyone.
Right, debts don't kill. Let's go.
Take me to the port, please.
That guy's been waiting for me all day
because I owe him.
Look, it's Margot.
You're always running some scam.
Driver, let's go.
The joy of love
Is only fleeting
But heartbreak
Lasts a lifetime
The Ancerville will set sail
from Dakar at 4..00 p.m.
Mao Tse-tung is a wimp.
What China needs is -
I told my pupils on the first day,
"Your job is to kick out
the neocolonialists whom I represent."
We've taught in Dakar for seven years now.
The Italian Communist Party
is too extreme.
We never left Dakar.
There's nothing to see in Senegal.
Barren intellectually as well.
Our salary is three times
that of the Senegalese teachers,
but they don't eat like we do.
They're not as refined.
And what would we buy here? Masks?
African art is a joke made up
by journalists in need of copy.
We set half our annual salary aside.
Not that we stint ourselves.
America needs austerity
to improve its economy.
I invested two million francs
in a bona fide business in Nice.
When we left this morning,
our houseboy threatened to quit
unless he got a 1,500-franc raise.
After all we've done for him.
They're just big kids.
Heartless.
I left everything
For that ungrateful Sylvie
And she left me
For someone else
Mr. Diop is requested
to see the captain at once.
I repeat, the Ancerville will set sail
from Dakar at 4..00 p.m.
PORT OF DAKAR
PIER 1 ENTRY
I repeat, the Ancerville will set sail
from Dakar at 4..00 p.m.
Is he still alive?
- He's losing blood.
- It looks really bad.
The ambulance is here.
Recognize it?
It was a handsome beast.
I'm trying to catch a glimpse
of the ambulance.
- Be careful.
- Watch out.
THE END