Roll again. Roll again.
Eleven?
Nine.
What?
Four and five is nine,
not eleven.
It's good, it's good!
Four and five is nine,
not eleven.
- Throw again, brother.
- That's enough.
Hey, Tsotsi,
what we doing tonight?
Yeah, what we doing tonight?
Aha, the little gangster.
You learn to drive yet?
So I got sick.
So what?
- Come sit, Teacher Boy.
- Fuck off! I'm not your Teacher Boy!
You know you went too far tonight.
What's your name, Tsotsi?
Your real name?
Tsotsi? Thug?
That's not a real name.
- Boston, don't ask him questions.
- Why not?
I've been with you for six months.
I want to know his name.
Every man has a name.
A real name from his mother.
Hey, Soekie. Come on.
We're dry here.
Hey, you. Relax!
I'll come when I'm ready, okay?
Decency, Tsotsi.
You know the word?
- Decency?
- Soekie!
I got sick because there's
some decency left in me.
And that big man with the tie
had a lot of decency. And now?
- He's dead.
- Soekie!
Jesus, Butcher, fetch it yourself.
I'm trying to have a serious discussion.
Come sit, sonny.
Chill out.
Just remember,
I'll have no trouble in my place.
- Jesus!
- What?
Sick again?
Jesus!
Tonight, Tsotsi,
when we dropped that big man,
it was like that inside me.
Does anything do that to you?
A woman, Tsotsi?
Maybe you had a woman,
and when she left you,
it hurt.
And you bled.
Your father-Your father, Tsotsi.
Your father, where is he?
Your father and mother.
Where are they?
Jesus, Tsotsi! A dog?
What about a dog?
Tell that bastard
never to come here again.
John? John?
Open the gate!
The remote isn't working.
Stop!
Pumla!
Yeah, that's the registration.
Just tell them the car's been stripped.
No baby.
Oh, fuck.
Jesus. You stink.
Quiet, baby.
Quiet.
Tsotsi!
- Hey, Tsotsi!
- Yeah, what?
It's us.
- Who?
- Aap and Butcher.
- We need to talk.
- About what?
About Boston.
- Where is he?
- Over at Soekie's.
He can't work with us anymore.
Says who? You or him?
What's that, man?
- What?
- That smell.
- It's me.
- What's wrong?
I'm sick.
Shit. You need a doctor.
No, I'm fine.
Hey, sister!
Feed it, man!
Come feed him here.
If you got no milk,
let him suck me.
So, what are we doing tonight, Tsotsi?
Let's meet later.
At Park Station.
Later's good.
We'll meet later.
Okay.
Hey, man. Did you smell that?
Stinks like shit.
You said there were fingerprints?
This bastard's a nobody.
But you said
he went into the township?
There's a million people in there.
- It's chaos.
- Sir, we can't even track stolen cars-
Stop telling me what you can't do!
I want my child found.
When my wife wakes up,
I want our son right here beside her.
Is that clear?
Where's Tsotsi, man?
- Fuck him, really.
- Sure. Fuck him.
Hey! Fucking look
where you're going!
Dog!
And now?
You want me to say sorry?
Watch where you put your feet.
Move!
Late edition, Daily Sun.
What's up, Bheki?
How you doing?
Tell me, who won?
Irish Fancy, brother.
By a length. Seven to two.
- Lame donkey.
- You see?
- Did you win anything?
- Win what? Fuck off.
Put a hundred on Red Bullet tomorrow.
You'll see.
Red Bullet has no legs.
Silver Lightning.
Don't take too much!
Where is that guy?
Hey, where'd you buy that license?
Did your mother teach you to drive?
What you want, boy?
Do you want my money?
- Stand up.
- What?
Get up and walk.
And who are you?
Jesus Christ?
- I'm a cripple.
- You're lying. Stand up.
Go to hell.
Fine.
Here's all the money I have.
What do you want from me?
Take the money
and leave me alone.
Fuck, man.
Fuck you!
Fuck! You fuck-
You fucking bastard!
Fuck you! Fuck you!
Fuck you, man!
Are you happy now?
You've made an old man
piss in his pants.
Why are you following me?
Why?
I saw a dog once.
Two kicks-
And its back was broken.
It crawled just like you.
What kind of man kicks a dog?
What happened to your legs?
I worked in the mines-
Digging for gold.
A beam fell on me
and it broke me.
Why do you go on
when you live like a dog?
I.
I like to feel the sun on the street.
Even with these hands,
I can still feel the heat.
Go pick up your money.
Okay, sir.
Enjoy your tea.
- Be well.
- Thank you.
What do you want?
Put them down.
Fuck you! Put them down!
Sit.
Sit!
Please don't hurt my baby.
I won't hurt him.
Put him down.
In the bag.
What?
Look in the bag.
Hey, look in the bag!
Feed it.
I'm not leaving until you feed it.
Feed it!
Okay.
You made this?
Yes.
Why is it rusted?
I was sad.
And this one?
You were happy?
Yes.
Better?
You have something now, right?
You can do something?
Yes, this will help.
You find him.
And you tell him,
if he has hurt my child in anyway,
I will kill him with my own hands.
He's full.
Put him back.
Where is his mother?
He's mine.
Put him back.
Can I wash him first?
There you are, little one.
You want me to wash you?
You do, don't you?
Tell anyone, and I'll kill you.
Come on, brother!
Seven!
Bullshit! Seven, what?
Three and five is eight, you moron.
Eight is close!
Lend me 50, Fela!
Fifty bucks. Shit!
But I feel your pain.
You're rich, man.
- What's 50 to you?
- Fifty, to me?
End of the day, 50 lets me buy beer
for losers like you.
- Sure, win then.
- Fuck off.
Throw again.
Who does this look like?
- Tsotsi, no?
- No, man.
- What's it say'?
- Says he shot a woman.
Stole her car,
with her child inside.
What kind of man
does shit like that?
No, it's not Tsotsi.
It's not Tsotsi.
He can't drive.
Fela, remember?
You tried to teach him?
He drove your 320 smack into a bus,
down Koma road,
in front of the police station.
Remember?
It's not Tsotsi.
Yes, I remember!
Don't be angry, Soekie.
Hey, that Tsotsi-
You know what?
You should all be working for me.
Stop this messing around.
You too, Teacher Boy.
Or are you gonna take that beating
and go crawling back like a woman?
Tsotsi never went to school.
Doesn't understand decency.
You know about that, Fela?
Decency?
Hey, man.
Don't start with
your fucking big words.
Can't even spell the word,
can you?
Decency? Let's see.
D-E-C-E-N-C-Y. Decency.
- How's that?
- What's it mean?
Decency means making
a fucking decent living, sonny.
Respect, man.
For yourself.
It's got fucking nothing to do
with your standard of living.
You want respect?
You'll get respect
the day you give up the bottle
and get a driver's license.
I need drivers, not drinkers.
So, fuck your decency.
Yeah.
Fuck my decency.
Hey, fuck off, you.
Play.
Anytime,
if you need help,
just ask.
Quick and silent.
Old style.
Play.
David.
Come here.
Come and hold my hand.
Don't be afraid.
What are you doing?
I want him near me, Mandla.
My son, go outside.
Now!
- Please, Mandla.
- Quiet, woman.
You know you are sick.
What if he gets sick like you?
It's all right, my baby.
- It's all right.
- You.
Stay away from your mother.
I said out.
Get out, damn it!
Fucking dog!
Out! Fucking dog!
Leave it.
My son.
Don't look at me like that.
David!
- David!
- Tsotsi!
Hey, Tsotsi!
- Who's it?
- It's me, Aap.
Open up!
What you want?
- Hey, man, I'm just dropping by.
- For what?
I always drop by.
I'm just dropping by.
Hi.
- Where's Butcher'?
- He won't come.
He's angry.
Says you done a job on your own.
Maybe I did. So what?
Yeah, that's what I told him,
“Maybe you did, so what?”
But now he says,
“Let's go join Fela.”
So, what you doing here?
Years, man.
You and me, we've been together.
The two of us,
since we were kids.
And all those years
you've just been following me.
“Hey, Tsotsi, what we doing tonight?”
“Hey, it's good, it's good.”
Fuck! Why can't you
decide things for yourself?
Okay, fine.
But we can start over again.
Like when Vusi and Peter were shot.
It felt like this.
But we started over again.
We found Boston and Butcher.
And we started over again.
- What?
- Yeah, what?
You know what, brother?
This time, it's finished.
Finished and done.
Go join Fela's gang.
I can't help you anymore.
Sorry.
Tsotsi.
What?
You want to go back
to your big fancy house?
What?
You want to go home?
I'll show you a home.
What you want?
What's in the bag?
Let me see.
- What you doing with that?
- Why? You want it?
Here.
Fuck off.
We can't feed it.
Did his mother die?
You see that pipe.
Top row. Left corner.
Yes. It's theirs.
Used to be mine.
Where you staying now?
I have my own place.
So, why bring your baby to us?
He wants him to see his old house.
Where've you been?
Quiet. Quiet, baby.
Hurry up.
Hurry, please!
Quiet.
Feed him.
Drink, baby.
Drink, you hear?
Drink, so you can grow big.
What's your name, little one?
What's your name?
What shall I call you?
David.
Yes.
His name is David.
Yes, David.
Now you are drinking.
Are you his father?
No.
What happened to his mother?
Is she dead?
Where is your baby's father?
Last winter,
he went to work one day,
and he never came back.
It was dark. After five.
It's a long walk home
from the factory.
You don't always see
who is walking behind you.
What was his name?
Zachariah.
How do you get money?
- Do you sew?
- Yes, I sew.
And I mend clothes.
What about these things?
Can you sell them?
I've sold some.
Not many.
How much for that one?
Fifty.
Fifty! For broken glass?
- You see only broken glass.
- What do you see?
Color. Light. On you.
Can't you see'?
Give him to me.
Give me the baby.
I'll take care of him.
You can come see him anytime.
My Jabu and David will play together.
I know about babies.
I'll look after him.
Give him to me.
I'll be back in the morning.
He better be here.
Where are you going?
To get money.
So I can pay for your milk.
- I don't want your money.
- Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
Don't forget.
He's mine.
Keep still!
You must keep it clean.
You never had a child, did you?
Hey, don't be rude,
I'm helping you.
You are clever, Boston.
You should go back to school.
School costs money.
We should go work for Fela.
We'll make plenty of money.
He can work here with me.
He'll drink all your profit, sister!
Leave him alone, please.
Get out!
I don't want you here.
- He can come stay with me.
- What?
You think he wants to be with you?
Look at his face.
Look at the mess you've made.
And now it's infected.
Say what you want to say and leave.
I remember when he first came here-
to the shacks-
I remember he had a lot of money.
You gave him as much beer as he wanted.
- He came here to forget.
- Yes.
And when he fell down in the street,
sick from the beer you sold him,
I found him.
Not you.
Brother.
Who took care of you
when you were lying there in the street?
Lying in your own vomit.
Who cleaned you up when you
couldn't even remember your name?
Who picked you up then,
brother, huh?
Me or her?
Help him back to my place.
Why did you bring me here?
You were a teacher, right?
I was never a teacher.
I never took the exam.
Don't laugh.
You still can.
I can't go back.
You need money.
We will help you.
We will get money,
and you will take the exam.
- Yes.
- You see?
We need to do a job.
Where are we going?
We're going. That's all.
It's good.
Tell me, why are we here?
Stop asking him questions.
Why this house?
Drop it.
We're working together, right?
Why are we sitting here?
We're sitting.
It's good.
- Shut the alarm off.
- It's over there.
Don't make any mistakes.
- Who else is here?
- Nobody.
Move!
Sit.
Where's your wife?
In the hospital.
She was shot three days ago.
Please, guys.
Take everything,
but my wife needs me.
Our child is missing.
- Let me kill this guy now!
- No. Later.
- Why later?
- We might need him.
What for?
Do you have a safe here?
There's no safe.
We'll see.
He's seen our faces.
I said later, okay?
Just do what I say.
You Okay?
What's going on with you?
Hey, buddy.
They say each wine is different.
Is that true?
Sure.
You get used to the taste.
I prefer beer, Zamalek.
Hey, buddy.
I'm hungry.
Do you want something?
Sure.
Hey, buddy, what do you have?
Cheese, cold meats, sausages?
- Chicken livers?
- Sure. In the fridge.
Shit!
What you doing? They haven't finished!
Are you stupid?
Look what you've done!
- It wasn't me, man! Look in his hands.
- What were you doing, huh?
I didn't see!
What you doing?
You know you can't drive!
- Get in!
- Open the gate!
Get in the car!
- What have you done?
- He was shit!
He's dead. He's dead!
Yes, he's dead.
With him it was always kill, kill, kill!
You never stopped him before!
Okay, let's do it.
Buddy, if you had learned
to drive properly, I'd give you more.
Move!
Let's go.
Come on, brother!
You want to stay with Fela?
When is it my turn?
- For what?
- You fucked up Boston, real bad.
Now Butcher.
When is it my turn?
You're right.
We're finished.
It's over.
Like Butcher.
Finished and done, boy.
- Who is it'?
- It's me.
What happened?
Can I come in?
Please.
Thank you.
It's for you.
I don't want it.
I won at craps.
I know where you got him.
I saw the newspaper.
They say his mother
may never walk again.
You can't give back her legs,
but you must give back her son.
What's this?
Milk.
For mothers without milk.
You put it in here, right?
Yes!
But it won't make you his mother.
Please, give him to me.
I'll take him back for you.
If I take him back,
can I still come here?
Boston.
I'm sorry, my brother.
Hello? Yes, I told you,
Western Section.
Just behind the bar.
I see you.
- Where is he?
- That shack. With the small window.
Watch the car.
- Hey, you! Where's the baby?
- What baby?
- Get the gun!
- Talk! Talk fast, boy!
- I don't know anything.
- Don't bullshit us!
No. Stop!
That's not him!
What are you saying, Ma'am?
Talk, Boston!
Where'd he go?
I don't know.
Take it easy, Zuma.
Hey, tell me the truth.
I'm not stupid.
I'm not lying!
It's true, man!
You!
What do you want?
Take it.
You need anything,
help yourself.
No, sir. This is fine.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Come on, people.
A child was stolen by someone
who lives on this street
and nobody's seen anything?
Hello. Yes?
- Pumla, eat, please.
- John, I can't.
Hello.
I'll leave it here.
Who is this?
Your baby- I'll leave it here.
Don't do anything stupid, guys.
We're coming.
- Please, sir. Wait.
- Out of my way!
Put the child down and step away!
Please stay inside, sir!
Please, I beg you.
Just stay where you are.
- Put the child down!
- Hey, please, take it easy.
That's my child he's holding.
John, what's going on?
Pumla, go back inside, please.
Hey, back away, Ma'am!
Steyn, pull her back!
Don't you touch me!
Boy.
Bring me my child.
Bring my child to me!
Hey, put the child down
and back away!
Quiet, man!
Let us deal with this, please!
Tell your men
to lower their weapons.
This boy is going nowhere.
All right, everybody.
Don't do anything stupid. Relax.
You too.
Lower your gun, please.
Brother.
We don't want anyone to get hurt.
I promise.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
I'm going to open
the gate now, okay?
You stay there.
I'll come to you.
I'm opening it now.
Is that okay?
All right?
I'm opening it.
I'm coming now.
Put your hands above your head.
I said, put your hands
above your head.