DISTRIBUTED BY PRODIS
RAYMOND DANON PRESENTS
THE
WOMAN
Yes?
Ah, Marianne!
It's nice to hear from you.
Yes.
Yes, I'm working.
Yeah.
No, I have to work. Listen...
listen, I'll call you back.
Love you.
I'll call you back later.
Goodbye.
"All my life...
I've had two passions,
women
and liter--"
Yes?
An,  Hélène!
It's nice to hear from you.
No, I'm working.
Yes, I'm working.
No, I told you I'm working.
Listen, I'll call you later.
That's right. Goodbye.
Talk to you later. Love you.
Shit.
Dammit.
Hello?
Yes.
Put him through.
Yes, put him through.
Hello, listen, old boy,
I've helped you for the past 15 years.
We're nearly friends.
You're in a crisis.
I don't want you to crumble.
Listen to me,
I have here in front of me
the details of your situation
and the results.
-Do you want the details?
-No.
Fine, here are the results.
I manage seven of your books.
For the latest one,
the royalties come to 7,100 new francs.
That's perfect. Send it to me.
The advances I gave you come to three...
330,000 new francs.
The difference is
231,000 new francs.
In other words,
you owe me 23,100,000 old francs.
Not only that,
but you suppose I'll pay your taxes.
And not only that,
you suppose I'll send more money.
There are limits, my friend.
What do you want exactly?
Jérôme, for three years
you haven't delivered a book.
That's the problem.
The problem results from another problem.
My books are about women.
I can't write because
I can no longer stand women.
They've become an abomination,
a mistake of nature.
That's it.
That's it! That's great.
Write that for me.
Go to hell.
Yes?
Jerome...
I have an idea.
What if I found you a woman...
who doesn't weigh on you?
Who isn't a burden?
Who inspires you
without tying you down?
You just have to trust me.
-Let me do it.
-Really?
I'll take care of finding her,
and you get to work if I do find her.
So what do you say?
"Urgently seeking secretary.
Perfect shorthand, highly competent.
Pretty.
Open to all points of view.
For short-term travel with famous author.
High salary.
Apply at Rene Garanciére Publishing,
11 Servendoni Street."
Hello, miss.
You fit the criteria we're looking for.
Please take a seat.
You read the ad carefully?
Yes, I have to travel
as the secretary of a famous writer.
High salary.
Yes, um...
There is a clause
that may surprise you.
It's not routine
for the publishing house to recruit
secretaries for our authors.
But Jerome Hervé
is the most famous.
We want to help him.
He's looking for a secretary
who is competent, which you are.
But there's an additional...
An artist...
needs inspiration...
understanding...
encouragement.
And that is why we're asking you...
Excuse me, miss.
Read clause number five for yourself.
"Said secretary agrees
to collaborate at all times,
both day and night,
with collaboration not limited
to a professional context."
"She agrees to grant Jérôme Hervé
immediately upon his request
everything a woman can grant a man."
"Everything a woman can grant a man."
What does that mean?
I know full well what that means.
-It means you take me for a whore.
-Not at all, miss.
Understand that, like you,
I consider this clause--
It's despicable.
It's ridiculous.
I'll be a slave to a man
I've never seen before.
Do you think I'd be
a dirty old man's plaything?
I'm not that kind of girl.
So you decline the offer.
No, I accept.
JEROME HERVE
AVAILABILISM
On Track A, the Trans Europe Express
Mistral express train,
departing at 1:20 p.m. in first class.
Hello, Marianne?
I'm calling from the train station.
You know leaving for work
was the only solution, darling.
But you know I can only work
when I'm on the move.
Traveling inspires me.
What?
No, of course I'm going alone.
I can't wait for us to be married, either.
That's why I have to finish my book,
you see?
Yes.
Yes!
Listen, darling, my train is leaving.
Hugs and kisses.
Yes.
Listen, I'll call you back
as soon as possible.
Love you, bye.
On Track A, the Trans Europe Express
Mistral is about to depart.
Please board the train.
Hello, Hélène?
Darling,
I'm calling from the train station.
Yes.
No, not for long.
No.
I have to do some writing,
and I wanted to finish my book
before our wedding.
But you know I can only work
when I'm on the move.
Traveling inspires me.
Well, me, too, darling,
I can't wait to be married either.
Listen,
I'll call you back
because my train is leaving.
Love you.
See you-- goodbye.
Clara,
that's a pretty name.
Actually, maybe pretty
isn't the right word,
but it's a name that's--
Clear!
Yes.
It's funny how big the countryside is.
It's even too big, if you think about it.
I wonder why the countryside is so big.
That's a question I've never asked myself.
It's funny, I always ask
questions no one else does.
Why?
I wonder why.
-Because you're curious.
-Oh no.
-No?
For a woman, I'm not curious at all.
-Oh really?
-But I'm interested in everything.
I always want to know
how things will turn out.
Would you like a cigarette?
No thanks, I don't smoke.
But I'll still have one.
Usually, you can only smoke one.
That's true.
I wonder why.
I like to put two or three chocolates
in my mouth at the same time.
Luckily, I never eat them.
-Why?
-Because I hate it.
I hate anything sweet.
Except for cake, of course.
Forgive me for intruding.
Sir, if you could sign this menu for me,
I'll paste it in your book.
My pleasure.
-Here you are.
-I've read all your books.
Really?
Why do you write books?
Why shouldn't I write them?
Because there are
so many other things to do.
I knew a writer once.
Which one?
I forgot his name.
He was a great chess player.
Do you play chess?
Do I look like I play chess?
What's your sign?
Aries.
I should have known.
I'm a Libra.
Alcohol, liqueur?
No, thank you.
We'll have a drink while working.
I hope you don't mind getting to work.
Did a woman give you that tie?
Yes.
Why?
Because it doesn't suit you.
Put The Women as the title.
Very good.
Start a new paragraph.
"How I got here."
Type!
It's the title of the first chapter.
"How I got here."
"Next week, I'm marrying
Marianne in St. Moritz
and Hélène in Venice."
Period, new line.
You or your character?
Me.
Is that true?
Yes.
How funny.
"For 15 years, I've written
only about women,
and I'm interested in only them."
I've always dreamed of seeing up close
a man who never loved.
Right.
It's precisely because I loved
that I was loved...
and that I wrote my first book.
My first book was inspired
by a broken heart,
a break-up
that I didn't intend.
The first woman who mattered in my life
was named Anne.
We liked the same things,
including freedom,
which is so rare.
We were happy...
because we had the same tastes,
the same education,
the same desires.
In short,
we got along swimmingly.
We never left each other.
And yet, we were as free as the first day.
Everything was perfect between us.
Never a moment of boredom.
We also loved to talk,
to make love,
and to be silent.
It was--
Happiness?
"At any rate, it looked like happiness.”
Period, new line.
How long did it last?
It lasted...
Five years.
What's five years?
Us.
Listen...
you're leaving to Cuba for your report.
I'm going to San Francisco for my exhibit.
The Azores are on the way.
It'd be fun to get married there,
while we're at it.
You want to get married?
You?
Do you want...
do you really want to get married?
To you,
on an island
for kicks.
Well, we can go to an island
without getting married.
If you don't want
to get married on an island,
we can do it somewhere else.
In our neighborhood.
I told her yes,
and I went to hide in a bistro.
I spent my life in the bistro...
writing like a madman
the things I didn't dare say.
I wrote that thanks to her,
I discovered something about myself.
I love you, we're happy,
but I just discovered what I prefer.
And I prefer pleasure
and adventure to happiness.
I prefer freedom to happiness,
spontaneity, you see?
The closer the marriage date got,
the more unsent letters I wrote.
I decided to write her a new letter.
It turned out very well.
I wrote that we would ruin everything,
that we should absolutely not marry.
That letter also stayed in my pocket.
Jérôme Hervé,
do you take Anne de Monfort
to be your lawfully wedded wife?
It's...
it's very difficult
to answer such a question
with a yes or no, at least for me.
No, you have to answer "yes."
That's it, that's the law.
Jerome Hervé, do you take
as your lawfully wedded wife
Miss Anne de Montfort?
No.
It isn't...
I'm really not marriage material.
You understand?
No, you don't understand.
You understand, right?
Here, you need to understand.
Read these letters.
You'll understand everything.
I didn't think we had split up.
I thought she would reply.
I anxiously awaited
her answer to my letters.
She sent them back to me
with just two words,
"Publish them."
She was perfect until the very end.
I would never have thought of it alone.
Those letters made me famous.
And it was your first essay,
Availabilism.
You've read it?
"In love,
only beginnings are enjoyable."
"And that's why we must start over often."
"Availabilism" is the desire
to keep one's future intact
by never forming bonds.
-A singular being.
-That's right, a singular being.
I just bought it. I haven't read it.
Oh really?
I flipped through.
This isn't bad.
"We must always prefer the unknown
to what we've already experienced,
even if what we have is enjoyable."
"Man's greatest misfortune
is his ability to imagine
thousands of lives
while imprisoned in one body."
"It amplifies this misfortune
if we become prisoner to another being."
"In contrast, alleviating it
means preserving
the greatest number of possible choices."”
Yes. Do you like it?
I think if I were a man,
I would reason like that.
If I were a woman, too.
What are you?
I wish I knew.
I never talk about myself.
I am me.
Are you done questioning me?
You're the one
writing your memoirs, not me.
Next chapter.
Quote, "One Lost, Ten Found."
"Ten found."
Well, was it fun?
What was amazing
was that they were all different.
Otherwise, I would have stopped.
I was reborn with each one.
Life began again, everything began again
because no two were alike.
The lives I led were
all the more delightful
since I knew
I didn't have to stay until the end.
Few women could resist
my fascination for them.
I was fascinated
every time.
I always used the same words to attack.
"There are two women in you."
It always did the trick.
"Miss, there are two women in you."
"There are two women in you."
But you had a lot more than ten.
-Of course.
-How many?
I don't know.
Do you know your number?
How many?
Three.
You think I believe that?
Only three?
Those are the only ones that mattered.
I forgot about the others.
It's as if nothing ever happened.
Well, as for me...
that number is zero.
One day, something
extraordinary happened, an event.
A smile.
It was Bastille Day.
I was very happy, I liked her.
I liked her from the back
and from the front.
And she smiled at me.
I was... a happy man.
It's funny.
I feel like there are two women in you.
She smiled.
She smiled her dreadful smile.
I wondered if she smiled
because she had heard it before.
Yes, she had heard it before.
I asked her from whom. She said me.
Oh my God, I remembered.
Six months earlier in Florence,
I was crazy for this girl,
and I had forgotten.
How...
how could I tolerate a life
where no memory left its mark
because there were too many?
How could I have forgotten Florence?
If I couldn't recognize
a woman I had loved,
with whom I was infatuated,
my life was absurd...
and I had to change fast.
Come in.
Good evening, may I turn down your beds?
Yes, please.
Come.
Come into the hall
while he makes the beds.
The train is about to depart.
Thank you, Clara. I needed you.
No, you needed a secretary.
I needed to be with a woman
who didn't captivate me.
It's refreshing.
Thanks to our contract,
we've avoided whatever ruins love.
No, we're done for tonight.
Go get undressed.
Just like that?
Of course.
I'm getting undressed, too.
Which do you prefer?
Which what?
Which bed.
The one on the right or left?
We're going to sleep?
Yes.
Men are funny.
Who was the guy with you at the station?
Are you in love with him?
Madly.
Is he?
We'll have to see.
Is he jealous?
It's not that I'm tired,
but I like smoking in the dark.
In the dark, I can't taste the tobacco.
I hate the taste of tobacco.
So why do you smoke?
Because I can't live without it.
Clara?
Yes?
Come.
Where?
To my bed.
To do what?
Make love.
No, we said we were sleeping.
I changed my mind.
Why?
For God's sake, Clara!
You signed a contract.
Hey!
My contract
doesn't require me to want you,
only to put up with you.
Let's go.
Go to bed.
I'm better off on my own.
So now,
the contract isn't enough.
I have to be in love with you too.
Go to sleep.
We'll both be better off.
Oh, pardon me.
What are you doing here?
Forgive me, I have the wrong room.
That's quite all right.
See you later.
Okay, I'm ready.
To type.
Being a secretary is also in my contract.
Where were we?
You're not happy.
You're disappointed?
I'll make up for it
by being a good little secretary.
Do you want to know where we were?
Yes.
"I'm suspicious of too great a success
because it risks tying one down,
especially a man of my nature
who practices Don Juanism
without being a true Don Juan.”
Type.
"I was vulnerable...
because it pained me
to deny myself certain deep pleasures,
namely the limits
of knowing another being...
and the depths of tenderness."
"As a result of my conquests,
I desired love."
"This desire terrified me."
What was left?
Bodies.
Nothing but bodies.
I met this one
in the studio of a photographer
for whom she was posing.
It was perfect.
I was immediately reassured.
Our relationship
would be entirely physical.
The only problem was knowing
if I would tire of her.
if my desire would outweigh my boredom.
I had to find out right away,
so I invited the body to lunch.
Take your fork like this,
then you insert it like a knife.
Like this.
Like that.
And you eat it.
It's delicious.
I didn't know oysters had feet.
Yes, they do.
Give it a try.
Good job.
What would you say
to a weekend trip to the countryside?
Just you and me.
-It's a great idea.
-Yes.
Yes.
"Beautiful women..."
Yes?
"Beautiful women are easier than others."
Easier than others?
Why?
As a result of constant solicitation,
their resistance has weakened.
It's true.
Yes, it's true.
"Marianne...
Marianne was a creature...
seduced by her own character."
And I was seduced only by her body,
which was absolutely reassuring.
A body is like an Old Master's painting.
Its value is certain.
I wanted her...
and she seemed to want me.
Basically,
it happened naturally,
like all important things.
I wanted to exhaust all the pleasure
this woman could give me.
And since the pleasure didn't run dry,
we left.
I thought we would leave for a few days,
but after a week,
we were in no hurry to end our trip.
All of France was ours.
Every landscape became a bedroom.
We made love every three miles,
80 times on average.
That's not bad.
It was fascinating
because every day
we prepared to leave.
Every day, we said that's enough.
Let's go back to Paris.
Then we didn't go back.
Summer passed by imperceptibly,
from farewell to farewell,
reunion to reunion.
Without knowing it,
whereas we had only left for a weekend,
we were spending
the whole summer together.
We thought every day
was our last together...
that we would leave each other.
It was over
and hadn't mattered at all,
but I was crazy about her.
What did you like about her?
I thought I had figured her out
and deep down there was nothing there
but an abyss of femininity.
She was an expert
in the art of silent thought.
Who was she thinking about?
We hid everything from one another.
Starting with me,
who carefully hid my happiness.
That day,
I was enraged...
because it was impossible
to get a word out of her.
She was merely a woman
whose excesses captivated me
and who should be treated as a woman.
Like that.
I had loved solitude.
I could no longer stand it.
Marianne reduced me to thinking
any pleasure without her was incomplete.
I wondered if it was mutual,
if she was dreaming of someone else...
the bullfighter in the arena, for example,
which she never admitted.
On that day specifically,
she chose the moment
the bull was about to die
to tell me...
"You know, ever since I met you,
it's the first time I've liked a man."
It was both a declaration
and a threat.
The sea
with her.
And the fear of it ending.
We're good, very good.
Yes, good.
It was the first time we said it.
There's a difference
between being happy and knowing it.
We knew it.
And my fear changed...
became clear.
My fear was,
"She's going to leave.”
I asked her, "You won't leave?"
If you want, I'll stay with you...
forever.
I remained silent, then I refused.
I had to refuse.
She was offering total happiness.
I refused because I wanted
to split up at the peak of happiness.
We were at the height of passion.
Yes, I let her go to Sweden.
Did she know I was leaving
out of an excess of love?
That I wanted to save our love
by protecting it from the slow decline
that awaits all couples?
I don't know.
I knew by splitting up,
we were saving one another.
It had to be done.
I did it.
There you go.
I got a novel out of it...
The Summer.
It was the summer with Marianne,
and it was also what had been.
It's very lovely.
I'm very sensitive to beauty.
Too sensitive.
I can't look at it for long
because it bores me.
Does he interest you?
He's cute with his moustache.
It's not that I fancy
men with moustaches, but...
I like them.
And last night you showed me
you don't like me.
-Are we working right away?
-No.
-Fine, I'll walk around.
-Go ahead.
Do you have The Summer by Jérôme Hervé?
The Summerby Jerome Hervé...
Here you go.
You're not going to read that?
It will bore you to tears.
Do you really feel like reading?
Wouldn't you rather talk?
The bill, please.
That's enough! I'll break your--
You little--
Bastard!
Be a dear and give this back
to the hairdresser.
Get undressed right now.
Do you only want me
because other men do?
-Be quiet!
-I have to be quiet?
-Yes!
-I'm sorry, I didn't know.
Do you want me... with or without shoes?
Trying to deter me is a waste of time.
Is it for me or the contract?
Do you want to rip it up?
You can't speak to me that way.
Okay, let's get to work.
Remember you're my secretary.
Here.
I'll try to be a good secretary,
for want of being a good...
a good...
How should I put it?
You tried to ruin everything.
I stuck to the contract.
-You spoiled your pleasure, not mine.
-Good.
I'm ready.
Fine.
Type, it's all you're good for.
If you want me to type,
you have to dictate.
Right.
Where were we?
We finished with Marianne.
You avoided the danger
of a woman who was good enough.
"And who I never forgot," period.
The sight of all women disgusted me
as long as they weren't Marianne.
And if I looked at Hélène, seen here,
it's because she was unlike a woman.
She was a parachute and ski champion.
She was the fastest, tallest,
most underground woman in the world.
She had done it all
and wanted to do it all.
She excelled in everything,
she loved danger.
She wanted to conquer, not please.
Her rule of thumb was self-defense.
Modesty was her passion.
There was no doubt regarding her ability
to avoid the male gaze.
I didn't forget Marianne,
but I thought of Hélène as sport.
Conquering the victor, subduing her...
became my goal,
a serious goal.
I loved waging war against her.
I wanted to win.
This war of patience,
which I had never fought before,
gave me a reason for living,
for getting up in the morning...
and shaving.
I followed her everywhere,
even to the most boring places.
Helene was charmed
by my interest in her passions.
But I started growing impatient.
It was the first time
I had devoted months to a woman
without making a single move.
It was the first time
I needed so much effort,
cunning and patience to seduce a girl.
And she refused.
I always deny you everything.
Maybe because you ask me for everything.
Maybe.
Now you're not asking me anything.
I'm asking for it to continue.
Let's go to my place.
Take the first left, please.
Ask me anything.
Anything.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll arrive in Rome in a few minutes.
Thank you.
So Hélène...
An, Hélène.
I kept on with Hélène
because of her modesty.
She kindly lent herself to me
but never fully gave herself.
She found a way to stay...
more virginal than life.
It was unbearable.
I wanted to know
how far I could go with her.
Oh no, be quiet, please.
Sometimes I don't like you.
Really.
I would have given up
if I hadn't felt her
hesitating, trembling...
her love for me.
I asked her
for resounding proof of her love.
That's what I wanted, resounding proof.
What better proof than acting
against your own nature?
Accepting the unacceptable?
I told her my demands.
Impulsively, she said yes.
I demanded the worst thing
she could think of.
It's this way.
No!
Don't start again!
Shut your mouth and come on!
Come, you'll see, it's very easy.
No, not that!
You promised me.
You said yes.
You gave your word.
You're not a little girl
who goes back on her word.
-No! Listen--
-Do it for me.
I'm asking you to do it for me.
We're here.
Come on.
Let me go, I don't want to.
It's an order.
Go on.
Come, we're here.
Are you the new girl?
What are you waiting for?
That's it, you're obeying.
You are tolerating
what is contrary to your nature.
You couldn't even stand
my gaze without rebelling...
the gaze of the man you love.
You are under everyone's gaze.
I was overwhelmed with emotion...
with pleasure in Hélène's defeat.
I wondered if
she withstood it out of love.
I wondered if she took
as much pleasure as I did in her shame.
In other words, I thought only of her.
It was perhaps the first time
that I thought only of her.
I was crazy.
I was crazy with pleasure.
Helene, marry me.
You're irritating me with your women.
I wish you were unhappy.
-I am unhappy.
-No, you're not.
You're annoyed.
I want you to be sick.
In the jungle...
covered with flies.
I'd shoo them away.
But it's not possible.
I can't stand the heat,
except for in winter, of course.
You fascinate me, Clara.
Shut up.
So are you going to marry
Marianne or Hélène?
Tell me how you found Marianne again.
Once Hélène submitted, did she bore you?
On the contrary, she inflamed me.
The next day, we left on a trip together.
And you found Marianne again.
Yes.
What does it mean that
we found each other here?
Surely, it means something.
It means we shouldn't leave
each other again.
Really,
it's extraordinary
that you're not married at your age.
Oh...
at my age.
I'm not the only one.
I'm not marriage material.
Yes, you said so yourself.
Does marriage disgust you?
No, I--
You think the best relationships
are the most casual.
Yes.
Yeah.
You're probably right.
Do you know why they're casual?
No.
Because they're open.
Yes.
I think it's Panther Two.
What's Panther Two?
His boat is named Panther Two.
Whose boat?
Bob's boat.
He loves me.
He's been waiting for me for a week.
Poor thing.
What?
Go on, goodbye.
See you soon.
We'll talk on the phone.
Come on, don't be dumb.
I'm not dumb.
I'm free.
Like you, like him.
You don't want to marry me.
Neither does he.
He's like you.
He wants to love me.
What a good idea.
-I forbid you--
-You have no right.
Ow!
Be sensible.
Don't just stand there, you look foolish.
And I don't like you to look foolish.
My love.
You have suffered.
I like that.
What about Marianne?
How did you end up
wanting to marry her after that?
First, I had my fill
of Hélène and her wedding,
so I managed to postpone it.
I was resigned.
But I managed to postpone the date
and move the location.
I was like a prisoner in his cell
who is no longer tormented
and says, "That's the way it is."
Put yourself in a prisoner's shoes.
He's used to a certain routine,
then suddenly...
something happens, an unexpected event.
Not necessarily something
that sets him free
or leads to his pardon or escape.
Something...
a noise...
a smell...
an event.
For a prisoner, that event
gives him hope.
And that event for me
was Marianne's phone call.
It jolted me awake.
She was in Megéve.
She wanted to see me.
She had to see me.
Naturally, she didn't say why.
Marianne never says why.
I imagined her.
I saw her.
I heard her voice and saw her body.
No other woman could inflame
my imagination like her.
I wanted to be near her.
I was as impatient as she was.
I imagined her hanging up the phone,
and I leapt towards her body...
her body that I could never forget
because her soul...
was a mystery to me.
The mere memory of Marianne's body...
was enough to drive me insane.
I felt elation in her presence.
The idea of seeing her made me feel...
the promise of happiness,
which I hadn't known before meeting her.
She made me more intense.
I was beside myself.
-You're ridiculous.
-Not at all.
He's the first man
who makes me want to be faithful.
Really? Well...
Perfect.
It was that good
on the boat in St. Tropez?
Tell me.
-No, I don't want to.
-Yes, tell me.
No.
Leave me alone.
I questioned her.
The guy was a pleasure boat king.
He sailed from one marina to another.
He was currently in America.
He phoned three times a day.
He sent 10 telegrams and long letters.
He took lessons to perfect
his French and Swedish.
He was crazy.
And so was I.
Tell me!
I don't want to.
-Tell me.
Leave me alone.
Tell me!
Tell me what it was like.
No.
Slut.
He'd go crazy if he saw you here.
But he doesn't see me.
-Luckily.
-No, not luckily.
When I left you in St. Tropez, I knew it.
He must know too.
You're crazy.
Maybe you want me to call him.
Yes.
I had an idea.
I became obsessed with it.
I would tell her what I wanted...
to bring him back.
He was in the Bahamas or somewhere.
She should have him come back urgently...
the following day.
Under what pretext?
A good pretext.
The truth but slightly altered.
I wanted her to tell him
she met a man in Megéve
who held her very close
and whom she felt
she could no longer resist.
And if he didn't come the next day,
she feared what would happen.
She was asking for help.
Did she refuse?
Yes, she refused.
It was time for his morning call
from wherever he was.
Hello?
Is it you?
It snowed all last night.
You can't imagine how cold it is.
What?
Your chest is bare?
You're making me fantasize.
-Your bare chest.
-Marianne, please.
Darling, my skiing
is improving thanks to you.
You said you wanted me
to be a great skier.
Marianne.
If you don't do it, I'll leave right now.
I didn't read the letters the day before.
I read both yesterday afternoon.
I read both of them.
They were delightful.
If you do it, I'll marry you.
If you do it...
I'll marry you.
Bob...
I have something to tell you.
It all went the way you wanted.
He came the next day.
There's always a gap
between a dream and its fulfillment.
But it was small,
and he came two days later.
I prepared everything.
I booked a room in a new hotel.
He came in and saw us...
Making love?
Yes.
Who will you marry in the end?
Neither.
They're interconnected.
I loved one because
of the other and vice-versa.
It would be a crime to choose.
You need a third.
I have her.
Why not?
Because I don't love you.
I don't love you either.
I have a taste for you.
It's delicious.
What you want is my help.
That's how men are today.
You have to help them without listening.
I hate being useful.
I don't want to.
Forgive me, I forgot about the contract.
I don't care about the contract,
I'll rip it up.
-Rip it up?
-Yes, I want you to want me.
But I don't want you.
Hello?
Yes.
A female journalist?
Oh really?
Is she-- well, is she...
is she young and pretty?
Okay, well...
Tell her to come up.
My dear Clara, I...
You want me to take a walk?
You understand.
-Some water?
-What? No... yes.
No, thank you.
The Algerian War, the Vietnam War,
the Nigerian Civil War...
-Do you want ice?
-No.
Suez... Budapest--
Yes, that's right,
Suez, Budapest, Prague.
Famine in Africa and Asia.
You know I'm not really to blame.
The Israeli problem, the Black problem...
You think due to 15 years of writing,
these disasters--
None of these problems matter to you.
The conflict between neo-capitalism
and neo-Marxism,
decolonization, protest, youth,
overpopulation,
which will become horrible in 20 years
since the global population will double
and automation will have relegated
half of humankind to unemployment.
Where did you get your glasses?
Rather than taking on
the issues of your time,
you've wasted your time on women.
Today's woman is a monumental problem.
She claims to be both free and oppressed,
capricious and conventional,
man's equal and his dependent.
It's safer to take an interest in politics
rather than modern women.
Tell me...
what's your name?
Louise.
Tell me, Louise, your glasses...
Some glasses make eyes bigger.
I'm sure yours make them smaller.
How do you know that?
May 1?
Oh yes.
I was right.
Of course, I knew it.
I liked you from the start.
I don't even know why.
There are two women in you.
First of all, I don't love him.
Secondly, if I love him,
that's precisely why I shouldn't go back.
Third of all, he's a bastard.
Fourth of all, if I love him,
and I go back, I'll be unhappy.
Fifth of all, I shouldn't go back
if I don't love him,
and I shouldn't go back if I do.
It's the same thing.
Sixth of all, if I don't go back,
will that idiot leave me alone?
Seventh of all,
if I don't go back, I'll be unhappy.
I'll be unhappy no matter what.
Eighth of all, I'm prepared to be unhappy
whether or not I stay with him.
Ninth of all, I'll be unhappy
for longer if I stay with him
because I love him.
It's very simple.
First of all, I'll tell her
I was ridiculous with the girl
because I couldn't stop thinking of you
and couldn't do anything with her.
Second of all,
why couldn't I do anything with her?
Because her only flaw was she wasn't you.
That's where we are.
I love you.
Are you mad at me?
I don't care.
I tried to forget you.
I failed.
What?
I tried to forget you and failed.
That girl had only one flaw.
She wasn't you.
Bastard.
I told her...
I love Clara.
You don't love Clara.
You love women.
Help!
You're here.
You're here for real.
I'm saved.
I love you.
How?
You knew, Marianne?
You knew about Hélène?
No.
No, you're mistaken.
If I get married,
it won't be to either of you.
Yes, I know to whom.
But I don't know if she wants to.
No, Marianne, I'm not a bastard.
You can't control
if you no longer love someone.
Obviously, it's...
As you wish.
Hugs and kisses.
Listen-- hello?
Hello?
She hung up.
Good for her.
And Hélène?
I called her first.
I went in alphabetical order.
You know what we'll do?
We'll go to the seashore!
I'll never forget you.
"She loved me and left me."
"Why?"
"She was certain...
that I couldn't bring her...
happiness."
"She condemned me mercilessly."
"She knew too much about me."
"That's why she left."
"After she left...
I understood...
there was only one thing to do,
give up women...
which I did."
"I am done with women."
Are you sure?
Yes.
Really sure?
Yes, at least I...
I think so.
It's my impression.
Anyway, you can type "The End."
THE END
THE WOMEN
A FILM BY JEAN AUREL