Mount Zu:
The collective name of a mountain range
found in the west of China in Pa-Shu,
otherwise known today as Sichuan.
Pa-Shu played an extremely significant
role in ancient military strategy.
Thus, the ancient proverb states:
'For there to be chaos under heaven,
there must first be chaos in Shu.
'When all has been conquered under heaven,
Shu will remain unconquered.'
Within both mythology and folklore,
another face to Pa-Shu is revealed,
one full of mystery and wonder,
derived from its mountain's many
strange peaks and ancient temples.
Therefore, tales abound of
celestial swordsmen and heroic divinities,
culminating in the legends of the
heroic swordsman of Zu Mountain.
ZU
MOUNTAIN
MOUNT ZU:
NEW HEROIC SWORDSMEN OF MOUNT ZU
Planning:
LEONARD HO
Producer:
RAYMOND CHOW
Director:
TSUI HARK
It is the twilight of the
Uprising of the Five Barbarians.
Therewhile exists eleven kingdoms.
Disparate factions vie for supremacy.
The world is plunged into chaos.
Summon the scout here immediately!
Scout Ti Ming-Chi greets
the left and right commanders.
- Where are the Yellow Banner remnants now?
- Report, Left Commander.
The Yellow Banner has fallen,
the Eastern Shu army fled for their lives.
Your subordinate observed them fleeing
to San-Chang Brook in the foothills.
As it should be.
When we take them on the water,
their corpses will line the riverbed!
Report, Left Commander.
The Yellow Banner is already routed.
There are many civilians
along San-Chang Brook.
A direct attack will harm innocents.
If that is so, we shall take them on land.
Find a path immediately.
I want to end their nation and bloodlines!
- This soldier understands!
- It is long and winding by land.
The risks are too great.
Ti Ming-Chi, lead the way now!
I want to pursue them on water.
We go by water!
No!
Going by water is too slow,
allowing the enemy time to escape.
We shall pursue them on land.
We go by land!
Nonsense!
- We go by water!
- We go by land!
We go by water!
Ti Ming-Chi, who will you obey?
This soldier obeys both.
Obeying both is insubordination!
I'll have your head!
Then I won't obey either!
Your head, then!
Kill!
My two commanders,
that's not what I meant!
Stand down.
We're on the same side!
A boat...
Boatman, take me across the river.
I... can't...
Why not?
- The blade at my back says I can't.
- Boatman, get down!
- Western Shu?
- Eastern Shu?
Western Shu, this here's the
middle o' nowhere, not a battlefield.
- Right! Put away yer blade, then.
- You first!
- Me last!
My good fellers,
do you have to be so cranky?
I'll count backwards from three.
You jump aside, sheath your blades,
and we're all good! Alright, ready!
Thr...
Ya said you weren't gonna fight!
Of the five generations of my clan,
Eastern Shu killed four. I'll avenge them!
So what? Six generations of my clan
were wiped out by Western Shu.
- How d'ya repay that debt?
- How? With a blade!
Me life's tougher than any blade.
We'll do it yer way, then!
I chop! I chop! I chop!
I block! I block! I block!
- I chop, chop, chop!
- I block, block, block!
Chop, block, chop, block,
chop, chop, block!
You're in for a treat...
My reinforcements are here.
How d'ya know they're yers?
Why can't they be mine?
Easy, we just take a look at
the colour of the arrows.
Grab an arrow, then.
[BON VOYAGE]
They really are my reinforcements!
Ya didn't even take one,
how d'ya know what colour it is?
You have to take one?
You can tell just by touching it!
Don't believe me?
Take a look, then.
Alright... but you first!
It's neither.
- It's yellow!
- Dang, yellow!
- Bow or stern?
- The back!
- Seize them and bring them here!
- Aye!
Steady on!
All these years of fightin'
have made me numb.
I don't wanna fight ya anymore.
I'm goin' now.
Hey!
I'm done fightin'!
- Hey!
- 'Hey' what?
I said I'm done! I'm done! I'm done!
'Done' your stupid fat head!
Your water flask!
It really is my water flask!
Hey, you alright?
Why are you so big
but your guts so small?
Ye're one to talk. With that grim face
o' yers, I can't tell if ye're good or bad!
Hey!
So, where 'bouts ya from?
I'm from the village left of San-Li-Pu
on the eastern border of Nan-An.
That right? I'm from those parts too.
But I'm from the village on the right.
No wonder you looked so familiar!
You're actually pretty good company.
O' course I'm good company.
Apart from the colour of me clothes,
I'm just the same as you.
The world's such a mess now
all 'cause the country's not fer people,
and the people not fer country.
Here and now, we're good company,
but it ain't so dandy on the battlefield.
Kill!
It's happenin' again!
Charge!
Kill!
A rainbow flurry means a rainbow melee!
Forget the colours!
We'll put on an act fer now,
give 'em somethin' to gawk at!
Why're ya fer real?
I said put on an act!
Why're ya tryin' so hard?
- Hey, should we keep fighting?
- You watch the front, me the back.
- Wait fer a chance to get outta here.
- Let's go, then!
Ya stupid-head, is this any time
to show off? Let's go!
Yer being too hard, stupid-head!
Hey—
That was effective.
Hey, fatty!
I'm over here!
Don't ya worry! I'm a-coming!
It's the three of us against one of him!
Hey, what's this? We're on the same side!
Get 'im! Get 'im! Get 'im!
It's six of us against the three of them!
Why're ya just standin' there?
It's nine of us against the six of them!
It's all of us against one of him!
Kill!
Hey, let's go!
Hey, let's play dead.
Don't move. They'll sort 'emselves out.
Hey, how long do you think they'll go for?
I think they're almost done.
Yer all playin' dead?
Yellow again! Let's get outta here!
There's still one in red and one in blue!
Don't let them get away!
After them!
Brother, go on ahead.
I'll take it from here.
No way! This is life and death.
How can I ditch you?
- What kind of brother is that?
- Come on! One death is better than two!
- Just go!
- I'm staying!
Go already!
Who pushed ya down there?
Mother!
Save me!
Hey, my saviour!
My saviour, don't rush off.
You wish to say something to me?
Great Hero, you must know that
the world is sinking as it burns.
The chaos of war,
existence is misery.
Great Hero, with your peerless
martial arts you must save mankind!
This tumultuous world of man,
therewhile exist eleven kingdoms.
Mankind live out lives plagued by turmoil.
However, they only have
themselves to blame.
They kill one another,
treating human lives
like grass beneath their feet.
What utter nonsense!
Neither you or I have the ability
to bring about change.
The hearts of man are so corrupt.
While you still have a conscience,
seek refuge in the mountains
and leave behind the world of man.
Great Hero, why say such things?
As long as everyone puts in the effort,
peace can be restored under heaven.
Youth is truly formidable.
Even lecturing me...
Alas, time is not on your side.
If you don't leave this place,
you will become just like them.
Great Hero? Great Hero?
Great Hero?
Great Hero...?
These great heroes usually
move in mysterious ways.
He must be testing me.
Alright, then! I won't stop waiting
till he shows up!
You're finally here!
You were waiting for me?
Don't be stupid!
In such a dangerous place,
only the King of Hell is waiting!
The King of Hell?
Right! No wonder there's
so many skulls here!
There must've been a battle here once!
Not a battle. All these skulls bear the
mark of the Demon Cult.
In order to practise their evil sorcery,
they sacrifice so many children.
These are all virgin bones.
- Virgin bones...?
- Now you know why I told you to leave.
Is it because I'm a virgin?
How lucky...
You're wrong.
Whether you're a virgin or not,
these demonic sorcerers won't spare you.
And though you claim to be a virgin,
nobody will believe that.
So?
Why did you wait for me?
I want you to take me as your disciple.
I have always walked alone.
As of today,
let's change your bad habit!
Master!
Master? Master?
- Master...?
- I am not your master!
Teach me martial arts,
and once I've mastered it
I can fight oppression, help the weak,
and save the masses!
I will not take you as a disciple!
Master...? Master...? Ma—
Call me again and I will disappear!
I— I'll shut up! I'll shut up!
You can come out now!
A blood crow! Take that!
Above the Ninth Heaven,
the stars appear!
The wheel of the bright moon
shrouds the cosmos!
De... De... De... De... De... De...
You can stop with the 'De'.
They're with us.
Hsiao-Yu of Tibetan-Kun-Lun.
Ting Yin of the South Sea.
Ting Yin.
Zen Master Hsiao-Yu.
- So your surname's Ting!
- What's it to you?
Scholar, our ten year engagement has come.
Are you also here to meet Long Brows?
Monk...
He was afraid this would be too much
for you and asked me to lend you a hand.
Just two crows and
you're jumping at shadows.
How can you defeat the
Blood Demon's guardians like this?
Dammit! I Amitā your Buddha!
The Blood Demon grows more aggressive
each day, so we need to join forces.
What say you?
A monastic displays compassion,
delivering all from hardship.
The Demon Cult spread their wickedness
from the Stone Forest Temple.
This fills Buddha with burning rage,
let alone I, Hsiao-Yu?
These past three years,
my idiot disciple and I come and go
from Ching-Tsang to trace their movements.
To think that I would run into you today.
The demonic qi here is strong.
It seems it's nothing as simple
as just a few sorcerers.
Hey, what's the plan?
You ask too much!
My philosophy has always been:
Share a table at dinner, meditate alone!
- Walk your own path!
- You never change!
- I walk to my own beat, you walk to yours!
- I-Chen?
- Master!
- Virgin?
- Great hero!
- We enter the temple!
- Aye!
Enter the temple.
What kind of person is this monk?
He is a most impulsive person.
Hey, friend?
Virgin?
You calling me?
- Do you want to take a look inside?
- Sure!
- I-Chen, over here!
- Yes, Master!
Damn scholar, stand aside!
I can't keep an eye on you!
Short-haired monk,
keep an eye on yourself!
Eating vegetarian gives you weak arms!
Amitābha. Dammit!
Master?
Watch out!
Let's go!
Guardians of the Demon Cult,
welcome their distinguished guests!
Hey, how'd you get up there?
Kid's stuff. Just watch the show.
Monk, it's so dangerous here,
why'd you come down?
Even if you didn't rile me up,
I'd still come help you!
Who are you, distinguished guests,
that dare trespass
the altar of the Demon Cult?
We're the type who knowingly
walk into a tiger's den!
We're obviously not common people.
We come in heaven's name
to mete out righteousness!
Who are these people?
They're bad, we're good. Get it?
The doctrine of our Demon Cult:
- Those who come in heaven's name: Kill!
- Kill!
- Those who smite evil for justice: Kill!
- Those who protect all life: Kill!
- Kill!
- Those who oppose our Demon Cult: Kill!
Who don't you kill, then?
Those who believe in me: Do not kill.
Monk, you think you can
win them over with words
and spare ourselves a fight tonight?
Save your breath
so you can still put up a fight at least!
That's right.
Damn scholar, I'll let you leave here
in one piece—a corpse!
Put it out with water!
It's really strong!
I can't take it!
Monk, do you need a hand?
Return!
Hey? What are you waiting for?
Take this!
I never would've thought our years
of hard work would fall short of success.
Great Master, it's all my fault.
If it wasn't for—
Young brother, don't be hard on yourself.
That's right, young benefactor.
It was a heavenly blessing that you
managed to escape calamity today!
Monk? When will we receive
a heavenly blessing and meet again, then?
You don't get a heavenly blessing!
Let us never meet again.
If it wasn't for you, would those
demon monsters have gotten away today?
You really don't make any sense,
what complete nonsense.
Fine! If that's how it is...
Heaven, earth, north, south:
Take your pick.
The moon is in alignment tonight.
I'll head up north.
Then I'll head down south.
Very well. From this moment onwards,
- may our paths never cross!
I Amitā your Buddha!
- I-Chen?
- Yes?
We're leaving!
Soldier Boy?
You take care now.
May our paths cross again!
Great Hero?
Great Hero...?
Great Hero? Great Hero...?
He's disappeared again...
He doesn't take me seriously at all!
I ask you to save mankind,
and you all leave without saying a word!
Why did you even learn kung fu, then?
Like turtles hiding in their shells!
No wonder the world is in absolute chaos
and devilry runs rampant.
'They only have themselves to blame'?
You're responsible too!
The heavens are great, the earth is great—
But I'm the greatest!
I don't need any of you!
I'll take care of it myself!
You lot... Don't ever come back again!
You're all back?
We said our paths would never cross.
Why do we meet again?
We said you'd head north
and I'd head south.
You switched directions without saying
a word. What's the point telling me now?
Why are you still talking?
He's already sucked up our weapons!
Hurry up with a plan!
- What's happening?
- Don't know.
But in all my years following my master,
I've never seen him so nervous.
Hey, what's happening out there?
Unsheathe!
- Great Master.
- Master!
Return!
Let's go!
Monk?
We've never worked together before.
I never imagined our first meeting
would be a catastrophe.
Quiet now.
- What are you doing?
- I'm transferring true qi to you!
- You're making jokes at a time like this?
- Making jokes?
I can't even joke if you want me to!
I-Chen! Your martial uncle's gone insane!
Don't let him do it!
- I-Chen!
- Master?
- Tell him to stop!
- Martial Uncle?
If we don't heal your master now,
he'll be in grave danger!
- Master?
- You're not listening to your own master?
- Martial Uncle?
- Silly boy, you're still kneeling about?
Keep watch outside
with this young brother here.
- Holler if anything happens!
- Ting Yin!
The Blood Demon will use this chance
to attack us, you fool! I-Chen?
Get out!
Come back!
Hey, where'd that monk I-Chen go?
You better not show yourself!
A hero came to my rescue again?
That can't be right...
I've always been so unlucky.
Hey!
Why am I stuck?
What is this stuff...?
Hey! Who the hell are you?
I am the founding ancestor of Mount O-Mei:
Long Brows!
The founding ancestor of Mount O-Mei?
What the hell are you doing here?
How could I not make an appearance
at a time like this?
Are you good or evil?
I'm good, of course!
Would a bad guy wear white?
Take a closer look!
Don't touch my beard—
How come it's on me now?
Don't touch my beard!
- What now?
- You're still touching...?
Don't touch it!
- Kid?
- You calling me?
It's not like I'm calling myself.
Grab two rocks for me.
- Here.
- Bigger ones!
Follow me!
Throw them when I tell you to.
You better not throw them
before I tell you to!
You so-called righteous people.
Your foundations have yet to take root.
Thus, you are at the mercy of me,
the Blood Demon!
This monk has been tainted by
my Blood Demon venom.
Within ten days,
as the poisoned blood pollutes his heart,
he will lose his mind as I enter into him.
At which point, he will become
the new vessel for the Blood Demon!
When righteousness advances,
evil is already ten moves ahead.
What is that?
The Blood Demon's
primordial essence manifest!
Primordial essence manifest,
what's that mean?
The Blood Demon's physical body may
be obliterated, but its essence remains.
Using the virgin bones to protect itself,
it will bide its time,
eventually attempting to
resurrect once more.
Grab a hold of my leg!
Even my Grand Sky Mirror
cannot completely eradicate it.
We're in a real mess this time.
A real mess?
Then who's gonna clean it up?
I can keep it from getting worse
in the meantime.
My Grand Sky Mirror is able to
subdue it for now.
But after 7 times 7 is 49 days,
the Big Dipper in the heavens
will change alignment.
And then, as per every ten years,
my Grand Sky Mirror's brilliance
will fade,
its magnificence will vanish.
- Then what?
- You'll have to clean up the mess!
- I'll have to clean it up?
- Of course! If not you, who? Me?
Haven't you heard the saying?
Aged waves push young waves forward.
There were two swords
at the founding of Mount O-Mei.
One was the Tzu-Ying,
the other was the Ching-So.
They were known as the
Purple & Green Dual Swords.
18 years ago, the girl prodigy Li I-Chi
took these swords and entered asceticism
in the Sky Beyond the Sky,
the Cave Within the Cave.
Now, it is only with these swords
can we destroy the Blood Demon!
How do I get to this place?
The entrance is at Heaven's Blade Peak.
You must set out immediately.
If you do not return in time,
once it is free,
not even the combined powers
of the Three Immortals, the Two Elders,
the Lone Youth, and the Seven Monks
can stop it!
- You hear me?
- What about you, then?
Don't be daft! If I leave,
who else can put up with it?
Leave now!
What are you waiting for?
18th generation disciple of Kun-Lun,
I-Ching, kneel and receive your orders!
From this moment forth, you are
the 18th chief of the Kun-Lun Sect!
Receive your orders!
These are the Dharma beads
of the Kun-Lun chief.
I-Ching!
You must never forget, as the chief,
you are responsible for the entire sect.
You inherit its past, usher in its future.
Glory to Kun-Lun!
Master, you're not really
giving up, are you?
Leave me alone!
How can someone like me be chief...?
What happened to the rock?
Master!
You think you can just seal your meridians
and take your own life?
- I'll find someone to heal you!
- I won't let you heal me!
- I'll heal you no matter what!
Be quiet!
Who do you think...
you were talking to just now...?
I'm the chief! I can't—
Master...
I didn't do it on purpose.
I'll restring it at the very least.
To think, the world is in even
greater turmoil than I imagined.
At first, I wanted to implore you
to come save us, the ordinary people.
But I don't know who's
saving whom anymore.
Today is the first of
the 7 times 7 is 49 days.
Once I've taken this monk to be healed,
I'll immediately go in search of
the Purple & Green Dual Swords.
I only hope I won't be too late.
[SPRING TERRACE OF HEARING]
What is it?
There's fish.
- There's so many down there!
- Really?
Still running? Still running?
Still running?
The fish tricked me!
You damn fish!
Electric eel!
Soldier Boy, this fish is
still real lively!
Little Master?
- What is it?
- Have you had this before?
I was once a monk for a few days too!
The great masters mentioned that eating
cooked fish isn't considered killing.
Have a taste!
- It really isn't killing, right?
- Of course not!
Martial Uncle!
That's not my master!
It's the Blood Demon's double!
- Hey, where's the sword?
- It's behind you!
Which one's real and which one's fake?
What? Why'd he turn into a woman?
Return!
Evil and devilry know no bounds.
- You have to be careful, understood?
- Understood.
I-Ching, what is that?
It's a fish. I just caught it!
I'm thinking of setting it free,
earn some karma.
If there's nothing else, we'll head for
the Celestial Fort of the Jade Pool.
Good thing martial uncle
didn't realise the fish was cooked.
Hey, hey, right on cue.
You can have all this back.
You may kindly leave now.
The poisoning from which
this great master suffers...
I have no means of curing it.
Look, listen, ask, and feel
are the four essentials of diagnosing.
You've done nothing,
so how do you know he can't be healed?
Perhaps if the fort mistress
ends her seclusion.
- Fort mistress?
- So there's also a fort mistress?
Our mistress has been in seclusion
for many a year.
She will not end her seclusion for you,
unless...
Unless what?
Unless it is meant to be.
The Celestial Fort's Ice Flame
burns only once a month.
The length of time for which it burns
is sometimes long, sometimes short.
If one suffering a malady beholds the
fort mistress before the flame burns out,
the mistress will spare no effort
to heal them of their ailment.
As of now, the flame is nearing its end.
Our mistress has yet to appear.
It seems...
it is not meant to be.
T-t-then, then what will happen
to my master?
Households are bound by rules,
nations are governed by laws.
Since we remain within the Celestial Fort,
we must abide by the fort's ways.
I, Ting Yin, will keep the Ice Flame
burning with my very life's qi.
Even if I am completely drained
of my life's qi,
I, Ting Yin, will not yield!
I made it clear beforehand.
Whatever will be is at the mercy of that
which transcends heaven and earth: Fate.
Right... and what I'm doing now is
preventing the fate that you have created!
Hey, that's the demoness!
We've been had!
Soldier Boy! Soldier Boy! Soldier Boy!
Martial Uncle!
You can't go around calling
women demonesses.
- Martial Uncle, that's not it at all.
- Not what?
That fort mistress looked just
like a demoness, though!
You're the demoness!
The sorcerer at the spring terrace used
Shapeshifting Light Magic to trick you.
You've been fooled.
Now, I need you to be on full alert.
I'm going to open up his
Conception and Governor Vessels.
Open up his Conception and
Governor Vessels?
You're gonna transfer martial arts
to him out of the blue?
He really should be thanking you.
Master?
Great Hero?
Quiet now.
Our qi is currently linked.
Even the slightest lapse in concentration,
and both our meridians will be destroyed.
What should I do now, then?
Combine all your senses,
be like flowing water.
You tread on my master like that,
how can he stay a vegetarian?
When did I get that good?
What is... the meaning of this?
Could it be, you don't want
this monk to be healed?
- Hey? Are you cold?
- It's freezing...
With all those girls hanging out front...
How can we get inside
and see what's going on?
Hey! What are you looking at?
Hey, she's so damn bossy,
we'd be hard-pressed to talk our way in.
I wonder if there's another entrance.
It's so big in here, there must be!
Hey, let's go look for it!
Hey!
- Hey, where are you off to?
- Nowhere...
Sister, we're just looking for somewhere
to relieve ourselves. Right?
- Is that alright?
- No, it's not!
While inside the Celestial Fort,
outsiders can't just do as they please!
Whatever, then. When you gotta go,
the world is your latrine!
- How dare you?
- I don't?
Go ahead and try it!
Try it? I'll try it, then. So what?
You think that'll scare me?
Why are you so feisty?
Don't tell my master no matter what!
Hsiao-Yu!
Having been in seclusion for so long,
and now expending so much true qi,
the mistress needs to rest.
Now the monk's poisoning
has been relieved,
the two of you should leave
the Cavern of Mists.
Please.
- Hey, Soldier Boy! There's a hole!
- They might've entered the tunnel!
- Let's get 'em!
- If there's a hole, then get in!
What kind of hole is this?
Help!
I'm underwater!
Soldier Boy, hurry up and save me!
Hey! Wake up now!
Hey! Are you dead yet?
Wh... Where am I?
- You don't know how to swim?
- I don't know how to swim.
- Flying swords!
You damn bitches!
You love peeping, huh? There!
That pair's gone too!
I'm going to take you to see your masters.
Let them know just exactly how
you offend public decency!
Don't do it!
Big Miss, I'm begging you. Don't—
You win some, you lose some.
Why should I be scared to see 'em?
If master finds out
I pulled her waistband off,
he'll accuse me of offending
public decency!
Pulling off a waistband's nothing!
What's that?
- What?
- Don't make her angry...
Big Miss, I'll do whatever you want.
Just don't make a big deal out of this.
Then we'll be even.
In that case...
Alright, then! You slap him.
He slaps you.
You keep slapping each other until
Big Miss isn't mad anymore.
When you've stopped being mad,
it'll be my turn, then!
Haven't you heard the saying,
killing is fine, humiliating is not?
I'm not slapping him!
Your neck's so stiff you won't slap him?
You have to face your masters otherwise.
They're not my masters.
I'll face 'em, so what?
Don't do it! Don't do it...
- Soldier Boy, slap me. C'mon, slap me!
- I don't slap brothers.
Don't treat me as a brother.
C'mon, slap me.
- I won't, I won't, I won't.
- Slap me.
If you won't slap me,
I'll slap myself, then.
How can you be the chief
if you don't have any dignity?
I'm thinking of stepping down.
I hold out!
Luckily, I've still got some tricks left.
Don't think I'm some kind of pushover!
The Ice Flame has burned out,
thereby marking the end
of our fate together.
Fort Mistress, may our paths cross again.
Since our fate together has ended,
how can our paths cross again?
When the Ice Flame burns, as does fate,
so why have you come out to see me?
I didn't come out to see you.
If not to see me,
then perhaps to fight me?
The one named Ting, you speak the truth.
That day I healed the monk,
you were ill-mannered towards me.
I wish to wash away the disgrace!
Ill-mannered?
Are you so exhausted
you can't think straight?
When you fainted that day,
all I did was help you up.
If that is considered ill-mannered,
then I, Ting Yin, am a degenerate.
Or so you tell me.
I...
You, you, you, you speak up, then.
The one named Ting,
your arrogance runs wild!
I must discipline you!
Just two moves isn't enough
to discipline me, is it?
I know you have matters to attend to.
Is that so?
I'll save three moves for when
we resume our fight upon your return.
If you're brave enough to wait,
I'll be brave enough to return.
Very well. We'll slap palms
to mark our promise.
I-Chen? I-Chen...?
That's fine. You stay behind
and take care of your master, then.
You can come out now!
I knew you would definitely follow me.
Not an edge of steel on you.
What will you do if anything happens?
You have two swords.
Gift me one so I can defend myself.
This sword is one I have been
hanging on to to give to my disciple.
Master!
Don't get the wrong impression.
I don't want to
take on a disciple just yet.
This sword...
I'm lending it to you in the meantime.
Take it.
It's alright, I guess.
Better than nothing.
Great Hero?
Oh, no... Someone's in trouble.
Great Hero? Great Hero?
My complexion's hideous, isn't it?
It's not...
I wouldn't say it's too hideous.
I've already sealed off
my Nine Great Meridians.
But it's not like paper can cover up fire.
Don't worry! I'll take you to
the Celestial Fort right away!
Ti Ming-Chi... Do you really
want to be my disciple?
Kowtow to me three times,
and you'll be my disciple.
This sword will be yours forever!
- Will you heed the words of your master?
- Yes!
I want you to promise me one thing.
If we can't reach
the Celestial Fort in three days...
You have to kill me!
You hear me?
Kill me!
Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill!
- Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill!
Kill!
He's...
You've been poisoned too?
Hurry up and get the fort mistress
to come out and save him!
Great Master... Whether the mistress
comes out to save him or not
depends on whether he
and the mistress are meant to be.
The Ice Flame burns, as does fate
is the rule of the Celestial Fort.
- Rule?
- That's right, Master!
- It was the same when we saved you!
- Shut up!
You're a traitor to the Kun-Lun Sect!
When is it your place to talk?
Ice Flame?
Correct.
Hurry up, then! Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry up! Hurry up! Hurry up!
Fort Mistress!
You are a follower of Buddha,
and yet you lack self-cultivation!
This is the Celestial Fort
of the Jade Pool!
You think this is Mount Kun-Lun?
If you don't summon the fort mistress now,
I won't hold back!
If you won't hold back, I won't either!
You women... You got nothing better to do,
always hiding in a place like this,
coming up with weird rules!
I only became a monk because of you women!
I'm wasting my breath!
You! Come out if you have any gall!
Otherwise, hide in there for the
rest of your life, you damn spinster!
Hsiao-Yu!
We are only passing guests...
Should you be strong-arming them?
The fort mistress and I have
a prior understanding.
I said I would definitely return here.
To think, those words would
turn out to be an omen.
- Master.
- Disciple...
Master.
You are now one of the South Sea Clan.
I want you to abide by South Sea
clan's creed:
To annihilate evil and vanquish devilry,
righteousness surpasses all bonds.
Do it now...
Now!
'Righteousness surpasses all bonds'?
'When the Ice Flame burns, as does fate'?
How moronic!
Your existence is governed by a flame!
You'll heal the dead but not the living!
What Ice Flame? What rules?
It's all lies! You're all just
scattered like sand!
I wont kill! I won't kill...
Get out of my way!
Let go already!
You're coming out now?
- Chi Wu-Shuang?
- Fort Mistress.
Spare no effort,
and heed fate's command.
Do you understand?
Fort Mistress, you—
If something is meant to be,
then let it be.
What's wrong?
The mistress damaged her true qi
when she healed you.
Now to heal your friend,
I'm afraid she has put herself in danger.
Ting Yin...
When healing your friend,
I exhausted my true qi.
Now...
I lack the true qi to heal you.
Life lies in the hand of the healer.
If this is how it is...
Fort Mistress... Kill me.
This has already crossed my mind.
I understand.
Cherish a smile in your sacrifice.
In a single moment...
affection and animosity end.
I injured the fort mistress.
Hurry up and help her...
- Master!
- Martial Uncle! Are you alright?
- Martial Uncle!
Ting Yin!
Master? Master?
Look what you've done!
You almost killed him!
Alright, alright.
Which one of you is in charge, then?
- I...
- Alright, alright.
No one's in charge?
I'm in charge, then!
Alright, then... from now on,
anything to do with him,
I'll be the one responsible!
Let go of me!
Let go of me—
- Let go of me!
- What are you doing?
You really want to kill him?
I told you, he's my responsibility!
Let go of me... Let go of me!
You let go of me!
Come back down first!
Let me think of a plan. Come down now!
Let go of me!
Let go of me! Let go of me!
- Let go of me!
Do you want to kill him?
Damn monk, stand aside!
If you want to kill him,
kill me first!
Fort Mistress...
All of you, leave now!
I must break the Bronze Mirror
and seal this place in ice.
Fort Mistress, then how will you leave?
Don't let Ting Yin leave!
Don't worry about me!
Why do you spare him?
- Leave the Celestial Fort now!
- Why?
Fort Mistress!
It's too late!
Master?
Master...?
It's always you!
If you didn't bring your master here,
would my master be in this mess?
Get my master out from there!
Go rescue my master! Go rescue my master!
The entire Celestial Fort's sealed in ice.
What are you two still doing here?
Leave me alone!
Blood!
You can't keep me in here!
What's happening?
If the ice keeps falling here,
this will be sealed in ice too! Let's go!
This is the only way out of the fort!
T-this hole?
I've tried it before.
I don't know how to swim!
Count me out. You two leave without me!
Don't overthink it.
We'll drag him into the water!
No! No! I'll drown! No!
Help me—
What are you doing?
I've never left the Celestial Fort before.
I don't even know...
where I should go now...
You're asking me where you should go?
I don't even know how to answer that.
Men can realise their ambitions anywhere.
You're a delicate little wench, though.
You're terrible with people,
and you're so damn shrill.
You cry easy too!
As for what you should do with your life,
I encourage you to become a nun.
Sure, it might be a bit bland,
but you're suited for it.
What's that? You better shut up now!
Did I say something wrong?
I just say whatever comes into my head.
15, 16, 17.
Hey, what are you doing here?
I-Chen, do you remember Long Brows told
us to go to Heaven's Blade Peak
to look for Li I-Chi and the
Purple & Green Dual Swords.
There's only half a month left.
If we don't go now, and the
demon's essence manifests,
all the good people under heaven
will be met with tragedy.
I couldn't save the people in the fort.
Now you want me to try and save others?
I used to be a soldier for Western Shu.
Because I could no longer bear
the chaos of war,
I hoped that one day,
heroes would come and save us all.
Eventually, I met our masters
and thought we were saved.
However, I never imagined that the
righteous would not only refuse to unite,
but also be incapable of action.
The Dual Swords still haven't been found.
Our masters torn away from us.
They were only concerned
with their clans and sects.
They claimed to be subduing demons,
upholding justice, smiting evil,
saving the masses under heaven.
Actually, they were nothing more
than scattered sand.
If we continue to follow
in their footsteps,
say nothing of saving them,
but our generation won't even
be able to save ourselves.
You're right. Master and Martial Uncle
lacked unity,
and that's why they lost to evil.
We shouldn't be like them!
Where are we going now, then?
The three of us set off immediately
and ascend the Heaven's Blade together.
Heaven's Blade Peak. Geez, it's so big.
There's only two days left.
Where do we start?
Oh, yeah...
Why are you two so stupid?
Use your mouths, of course!
Use our mouths?
Li I-Chi the heroine...?
How ridiculous... Look with our mouths?
Hey, look over there.
Hey! There's an entrance down there!
The rivers and the lakes laugh with pride,
for 'tis I, Heaven's Blade!
For what reason have you three
come to this place?
Could it be that he's Li I-Chi?
Don't be stupid. Li I-Chi's a woman.
You have yet to answer what I asked you!
Such disregard for rules.
Are you even aware that you almost
trespassed into the Demon Realm?
This here is the pinnacle
of heaven and earth.
The boundary between gods and demons.
This is the boundary between
gods and demons?
That's right, why have you
been chained up here, old man?
Nonsense!
I am not an old man.
I am Heaven's Blade.
None under heaven can keep
the Heaven's Blade chained up!
It was by my own hand
that I am chained here!
You well know this is the entrance
to the Demon Realm,
so why did you chain
yourself up here, then?
Old man!
Step aside! I will do it myself!
Heaven and earth were originally as one.
But gods and demons know not unity.
From when Pan-Ku opened up the sky,
since the primordial chaos,
the war between gods and demons
already endured without end.
Therefore, I, Heaven's Blade, have been
deep in thought here for a hundred years,
attempting to comprehend
the logic of all this.
Ultimately, I was overwhelmed by
the Dark Qi from the Demon Realm.
My strength fades with each passing day.
Thus, I had no alternative
but to chain myself here.
On heaven and earth, there is a Dark Qi
emanating from the centre of the universe.
However, the existence of the Virtuous Qi
makes it retreat deep into the underworld.
The Dark Qi is the magical root
of the world's self-destruction.
Although it is trapped
within the Demon Realm,
it still orchestrates the evil scourge
of war that plagues the world.
As long as the Dark Chi exists,
the world will never know peace.
It is most unfortunate that I,
Heaven's Blade, am as advanced in years.
With no successor,
I can only stay here and keep watch.
If evil were to pervade the Demon Realm,
its wicked reign of a thousand years
would commence in but a moment.
Is there no one under heaven
that can overcome the Dark Qi?
Currently under heaven, the edge
of the Virtuous Qi has been dulled.
That which may overcome it...
It may not necessarily be the
Purple & Green Dual Swords and Li I-Chi.
- Li I-Chi?
- Where is she now?
This being the boundary
between gods and demons,
the zenith of the Dark Qi
can be found here.
But by the same token, here also exists
the Residences of the Divine City.
She is there to your right,
in the Sky Beyond the Sky,
the Cave Within the Cave!
- We finally found her!
Alas, it is too late...
Too late?
She isn't dead, is she, old man?
Nonsense! When you die,
she will still live!
I speak of myself, how my own powers
have deteriorated to such an extent.
We have had an intruder for some time—
I only realise it now!
Master...?
Demons are born of the heart.
The heart is born of infinity.
Gods are born for demons.
Demons exist for gods.
Gods and demons were originally
of one lineage.
So why on heaven and earth,
are good and evil divided?
The Dark Qi, the ultimate sorcery!
He wants to enter the Demon Realm!
As long as I, Heaven's Blade, am here,
dispel all thoughts of even
stepping into the Demon Realm!
You smacked into my nose...
We'll block his way!
The Seventh Dusk Sword?
That's right. The Seventh Dusk Sword!
The Seventh Dusk Sword is
a blade of justice.
This is not our first encounter.
Not our first encounter,
but we are not the men we once were.
Unless you renounce evil
and return to righteousness!
Your naivety is astounding!
Even if I'm astoundingly naive,
I'll still upturn the cosmos!
The world is in enough turmoil.
I won't let you enter the Demon Realm!
A mantis cannot halt a chariot,
you overestimate your ability!
You insist on this stubbornness?
- Soldier Boy!
You have much potential, child.
Fear not, the old man is here!
Heaven's Blade...
Your powers are at an end!
I advise you to preserve what's left
of your feeble and aged body.
Retire to the countryside
and live out the rest of your days.
My feeble and aged body?
This battle of good and evil
is a battle of determination!
Determination?
One is as the high noon sun!
The other is as the dwindling twilight!
There is no contest!
Are you alright?
The pull here is too strong!
Don't come any closer!
Get out of here now!
Or it'll be too late!
Soldier Boy!
- Soldier Boy, don't let go!
- Hold on tight!
- Soldier Boy!
- Soldier Boy! Don't give up!
- Soldier Boy, are you alright?
- Soldier Boy! Sol—
- Soldier Boy!
Watch out!
I-Chen?
I-Chen, what are you doing?
I'm always so gutless...
I don't think I can be the chief.
I'm turning these beads over to you.
Take them back to Mount Kun-Lun for me.
But you...
Soldier Boy's trapped inside.
- There's still a chance to save him!
- I-Chen, I'm coming with you!
Don't be stupid!
If we don't make it back out,
who'll look for the Dual Swords?
I can stay here and wait for you!
Wait for me? If I make it back out,
I'll definitely come look for you!
If I don't come back,
what's the point of you waiting, then?
Time to part ways. We can't hesitate.
It's just you and me left.
If we don't leave now,
then no one'll be saved!
Time to part ways!
Go!
Why are you still here?
Soldier Boy...?
Hurry up and save Soldier Boy...
Or he'll be sucked into
the Demon Realm!
I-Chen!
Soldier Boy!
Grab onto this!
Hold on tight!
Hey—
Soldier Boy, don't worry.
We're safe now.
But... I don't know how
to get out of here.
Boy, I'll use my final breath
to send you outside!
Hold onto the chain next to you.
Elder Heaven's Blade died
in order to save us.
Soldier Boy!
Soldier Boy? Soldier Boy...?
Soldier Boy...?
Come up now!
I don't how to swim.
I won't be able to save you!
Soldier Boy?
Solider... Boy...?
Soldier Boy...?
Soldier Boy, we escaped from
the Demon Realm. We're safe!
Soldier Boy? Don't be like this!
Soldier Boy? Answer me!
How are you feeling? Soldier Boy?
The Purple Sword?
The Green Sword?
Soldier Boy, did you see it?
Did you see it?
It's the Purple & Green Dual Swords!
Look! There's someone over there!
Li I-Chi?
That is I.
Hooray! We—
Soldier Boy, we found Li I-Chi!
Hey... why are you dressed like that?
You too!
- Matriarch Li I-Chi.
I am already aware of Long Brow's plight.
You have come from so far away...
Did you know?
Heroes abound like
a thousand crashing waves.
From the rivers and the mountains,
the gifted emerge.
You are this generation's masters of
the Purple & Green Dual swords!
Thank you for the swords, Matriarch.
The qi of heaven and earth
controls the entire cosmos.
The Dual Swords are forged from
the earth's precious stones.
Swords are wielded by man.
Man is wielded by their hearts.
Once the trinity of heaven, earth, man
unite as one,
their might will be endless and infinite!
However, while heaven and earth,
and yin and yang coalesce,
they also contradict.
Therefore, the Dual Swords
must never cross.
Otherwise, there will be endless
and infinite calamity.
At best, the swordsmen will die.
At worst, heaven and earth
will be wounded.
All living things will perish—
a mutual destruction,
And yet...
these two swords of heaven and earth
are at their most powerful
when they as two unite as one.
They can't cross but also can't not cross?
What do we do?
Even I am unable to understand this.
I will transmit my voice a thousand miles
and consult Ancestor Long Brows.
Long Brows?
They've found the
Purple & Green Dual Swords!
If this keeps up—
How come Li I-Chi and I
are of one in heart and mind?
Long Brows, why is it the
two swords cannot cross?
For the two swords to cross,
the wielders must be
one in heart and mind.
The seven stars are about to shift.
At which time, my Grand Sky Mirror
will be rendered useless.
What does it mean to be
one in heart and mind?
One in heart and mind
is when two people speak,
their voices ring out as one.
Swords are wielded by man.
Man is wielded by their hearts.
If the two of them are
one in heart and mind,
the two swords will unite as one.
- Thus, the cosmos is upturned,
- heaven and earth unite as one!
Heaven and earth unite as one...
and the two must be of one heart?
The Purple Sword is heaven.
The Green Sword is earth.
The Purple & Green Dual Swords.
Heaven and earth unite as one.
Matriarch Li?
- Matriarch Li?
- Master.
You need not be sad.
- Are you playing tricks? No!
It is I.
My primordial essence has
united the two of you as one.
- Are we still men?
Of course, you are.
Look how worried you are...
For heaven and earth to unite as one,
the two of you must be in harmony.
With my primordial essence, the two of you
can be one in heart and mind.
Consider it aged waves push
the young waves forward.
A new generation is replacing the old.
The seven stars will soon
change alignment.
Hurry to Mount O-Mei.
Kill the primordial child
and save Long Brows!
- Aye, Master!
Eastern Shu remnants, listen up!
We let you escape last time,
but today you meet your end!
Western Shu remnants, we feigned defeat
to lure you to San-Chang Brook!
To think, we waited for such a long time,
and yet you cowards never showed!
Oh, no... The seven stars are
changing alignment.
Stop fighting! Look above you!
Charge!
Can you hear me...?
Western Shu, only one of us
can exist in this world!
- Where's our commander?
- How do we fight without a commander?
I've hung your commanders up here!
How strange! How did our commander
get up there?
The primordial child on the mountain
is about to manifest!
If you don't leave now,
you'll be in great danger!
- What's that damn girl on about?
- Right! What are you on about?
Look over there!
Hey! Careful not to get sucked in!
I-Chen, what devilry is this...?
Hurry up and follow me!
Hey! Hurry up and follow the commander!
They're flying so fast,
how can we possibly keep up...?
What? It's Ting Yin!
- He's stopping us from saving Long Brows!
- That's right! Yeah!
Damn... He's locked up the swords!
- I-Chen, watch out!
- Soldier Boy!
The ultimate sorcery is
the nemesis of the righteous!
- Hey!
- I-Ching!
Why did the sky turn dark?
The Blood Demon devours the sun?
Keep your balance!
How can I possibly let you manifest?
I won't let you devour the sun!
I can't stand anymore!
Brother, get off me!
I'm being crushed too!
Why aren't the Purple & Green
Dual Swords here yet?
Stop pushing me! Hey!
I'm not pushing you,
the ground's gone slanted!
Then why are you still pushing me?
It's a cliff down there!
Hold on tight! Don't fall down!
I can't even stand straight,
how can I hold on?
Stop pushing me!
Don't push me!
If you grab onto each other in a line,
you won't all fall down there!
- Grab onto me!
- Grab on now!
Hey! Hold on tight or you'll fall!
Hey! You're pulling too hard down there!
I can't hold on!
My neck! My neck!
Don't let him lock up our swords!
I know! We'll transform
the swords into shields!
My magic is boundless!
You cannot block it!
Soldier Boy, where are you?
Solider Boy! Where are you?
I-Chen! I'm over here!
I-Chen, are you alright?
I'm fine!
I'm fine too!
I can't see Ting Yin right now.
But he should be somewhere
between the two of us.
To break through his magic,
we have to get him in a pincer,
attack from either side!
I don't know where you are!
How can we fight him, then?
Our hearts and minds are connected,
we'll be able to find each other!
Really?
We're running out of time!
We have to unite the
Purple & Green Dual Swords!
They're trying to unite?
I-Chen, he's trying to exhaust
our life's qi!
Tzu-Ying, Ching-So. As you are
beginning to unite,
your minds must be connected,
or once the Dual Swords meet,
both man and sword will be undone!
At this critical stage,
your mind mustn't lose concentration!
You must focus!
You still haven't united?
I can't take it anymore!
I-Chen, did you lose concentration
just now,
almost destroying the Dual Swords...?
Soldier Boy! I get it now!
Let's unite now!
Alright!
Damn! He's in the way!
You wish to unite?
The end has come for the righteous!
I'm not powerful enough,
my historical mission is almost over!
The Blood Demon manifests!
Oh, no... I can't look...
Ting Yin, the venom runs too deep.
I think... you and I are both powerless.
As long as the green mountains stand.
In a single moment,
affection and animosity end.
A fine line separates good and evil.
By sacrificing herself, the fort mistress
fulfilled a great act of subduing demons.
Truly worthy of respect and admiration.
Unite now!
Let's see you survive that!
Up there, what is that?
There's something flying down!
Yeah! It's three people!
The descendant bows
to greet Long Brows.
Truly Heroes abound like
a thousand crashing waves.
From the rivers and the mountains,
a new generation rises victorious!
I'm goin'!
Fatty?
Fatty, our bodies may stand as two,
but our hearts are as one.
Hopefully, when this gourd returns to you,
all the people of the world will be
one in heart and mind,
wars will cease to be,
there is peace under heaven.
Then it will truly be a bright new day!