Here's your ID card.
And your wallet.
Three hundred and twenty-eight.
Sign here.
A lot has changed
in the last 14 years.
Don't lose your temper.
Always keep your cool.
Stay out of trouble.
Or you'll be blamed
because of your past.
Be very careful.
Repeat after me.
- Everything's beautiful in Allah's world.
- Everything's beautiful.
- The trees and leaves.
- The light and the air.
- The seas and the oceans.
- The seas and oceans.
- Everything's magical in Allah's world.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Take care.
You too.
DAAGI
- Ride available?
- Yes.
- Nazir Road.
- Nazir Road?
Where's that?
It's next to Mizan Road.
That's Alia Madrasa Road.
Want to go there?
Alia Madrasa Road...
- Take me there.
- Okay, come.
Stop here.
Fifty bucks.
Speak up!
No!
Everything's beautiful in Allah's world.
Everything's beautiful in Allah's world...
Nishan?
They released you?
Yes.
Nishan!
Nishan, my son!
My Nishan...
My Nishan is back.
Sit, my dear.
Come on, sit.
Please.
They let you go.
No one informed me about it.
My son.
Will you have some juice?
Lime juice?
I'll make some for you.
Got an early release?
On the occasion of Victory Day.
What has that got to do with it?
You still have
eight months to serve.
Did they really let you go?
Yes, Dad.
I didn't escape.
They let me go.
This room will be locked
from now on.
"We rant and rage
but no one pays heed.
Why speak of God...
when none feels the need?"
- Excellent!
- Beautiful!
Hey, Nishan.
Do you want to learn
the whole poem?
Or just a few lines?
Boss, a few lines will do.
Recite the lines to your girlfriend.
She'll hug you and say...
"Come, let's make love".
She doesn't want to make love.
Only wants to get married.
Careful.
Make it fast.
My girlfriend is waiting
in Saidpur.
Okay, thanks.
Bye.
- Let me go!
- No.
- What the--
Getting all romantic
after being away for 10 days.
Not 10.
Seven days.
- Where were you?
- I told you.
Had to go to the border
for some work.
You could've called me.
How would I?
What if your dad answered?
And calls don't get through
from India.
You could've told me
you wouldn't be here.
Let's continue the fight
at Babu's place.
No!
I'm not going anywhere.
We'll stay right here today.
I don't like it here.
Such a boring place.
Only trees and animals.
I know what you like.
You've really taken me for granted.
We're not going to Babu's house.
- We'll be here today.
- What?
"If the heart hurts...
If the heart hurts, we seek a cure.
But what if the heart
is the cause of pain?"
Stop it.
Had enough of Ghalib's poetry.
"A hundred moons may shine..."
Nishan, my family is looking
for a groom.
"A hundred moons may shine
yet none can match your light.
A hundred moons may shine
For only in your presence
does the night feel bright."
A thousand moons may shine
but the night is still dark
if you don't grace it
with your presence.
The night is meaningless without you.
Come on.
Let's go to Babu's house.
You men have only one thing
on your mind.
Please let's go to Babu's place.
Come on.
Hang on!
- Hurry up.
- Get in.
- Dad has gone out.
- Quick.
- Close the door.
- Oh!
I'll be back in an hour.
It's just us!
Babu!
Open the door.
I've left my office keys behind.
- I told you!
- Quiet.
I have to take my keys.
Open up fast.
Hey, Babu!
What?
Hey!
- What did you break? Open--
- Dad.
When did you come?
You're here?
- Who's inside?
- What?
- I heard a glass break.
- It's a thief.
- No.
- Yes!
- Hey, come out!
- Dad, quiet.
I'll go catch the thief.
Stay right here.
Don't move.
- I'll check.
- Okay.
- Why is he here?
- Use the back door. This way.
Dad, hold on.
- Caught the thief?
- There's no one.
I'm sure it was a cat.
There's no one.
Hey, wait!
Let me go!
I'm not going anywhere with you.
Not until we're married.
Either marry me or break up!
Damn it!
If you choose me by mistake
If you stay with me by chance
I'll still smile gazing into your eyes
If dusk falls
when I'm lost in your thoughts
If my eyes well up
like a quiet, flowing river
I'll forget all my pride
and come back to you
How will you go leaving me behind?
Who will love you the way I do?
Let me feel your touch
Give me a piece of your heart
For the world knows
in this birth
My life is empty without you
Let me feel your touch
Give me a piece of your heart
For the world knows
in this birth
My life is empty without you
FRESHERS' WELCOME 2008
Now the pride of Saidpur
to present the awards.
Please welcome gold medallist,
Nasiruzzaman Sohag.
Only jobless fools become toppers.
Go.
As I keep waiting for you
My heart feels like a barren sky
I forget all my pain
and drift into a world of dreams
Nishan, wait!
Where were you
for the last seven days?
Not seven.
Four days.
- Where were you?
- India.
India?
Stop lying.
Who will love you the way I do?
Let me feel your touch
Give me a piece of your heart
For the world knows
in this birth
My life is empty without you
Let me feel your touch
Give me a piece of your heart
For the world knows
in this birth
My life is empty without you
For the world knows
in this birth
My life is empty without you
It's quite late.
Lunch is ready.
Where's the chutney?
When do your exams start?
What exams?
College finals.
You don't even know.
What's your aim in life?
What are you going to do?
What else?
I'll do export-import business.
I'll import items from India
and sell them here.
Huge profit!
Is that so easy?
Everyone in Saidpur
would've done the same.
But they don't have contacts
like I do.
I'm not made for desk jobs.
Why would you be?
Jobs are meant for idiots.
Like me.
- "Like me."
- Let him eat.
What's wrong in doing business?
Your dad was businessman too.
But he's right.
He's an idiot.
- Mom, I'm hungry.
- Hey!
Why are you shouting?
- Mom!
- "Mom!"
Hey, Zarine.
How are you?
- How's your mom?
- Hello.
Mom is fine.
I was nearby for some work.
I know, I know.
You're here to see your idiot.
Carry on.
Come with me.
- Dad's here--
- They've found me a groom.
A doctor or an engineer?
The most eligible bachelor
in Saidpur.
They're going to fix my wedding
in two weeks.
Dad has approved of him.
I won't be able to stop it.
- Hello, uncle.
- Hello.
- Nishan.
- Yes?
Come over on the 15th.
I'll speak to Dad.
You don't have to do anything.
Please just come over.
I'll handle the rest.
Who's the most eligible bachelor
in Saidpur?
He needs everything right now.
So annoying!
- Carry on.
- I'll get married to him.
Go ahead.
How dare you?
- Huh?
- It's...
It's hurting.
Nadia!
I'll beat you up!
What?
See you on the 15th.
Don't miss it.
Please!
Stop.
- Who is it?
- Babu, it's me.
- What happened, Zarine?
- Where's Nishan?
He's in India.
Can't get through to him.
He didn't even call me once.
He's in Agartala.
Must be having network issues.
When will he return?
I don't know.
- You don't know?
- No.
Zarine, what's wrong?
Zarine!
A hundred moons may shine
but it means nothing
if you don't grace it.
The night means nothing
without you.
- Hello, uncle.
- Hello.
- You're...
- Zarine.
Right, Zarine.
How can I help you?
- Want to send a money order?
- Where's Nishan, uncle?
Sit.
You can't build a home with him.
I know him very well.
He doesn't know
what he wants from life.
He's not serious about anything.
You were classmates.
You completed your graduation.
But Nishan dropped out.
He wants to do business.
Make easy money and become rich.
Maybe he'll forget the difference
between right and wrong some day.
Don't wait for Nishan.
Find a nice guy and get married.
Zarine is going meet her groom today.
Go empty-handed this time.
She's her dad's only child.
Her dad will kick me out
if I go empty-handed.
I have to take something for him.
You remind me of my younger self.
Boss.
Did you think about my proposal?
If you work with Ranjit Singh...
you can't defy my orders.
You'll always be under my control.
"In sorrow's clenched fist...
- In sorrow's clenched fist--"
- "My life is but sand.
The tighter the grip...
the more it slips from my hand."
This is why...
I like you so much.
Get up.
Make up your mind.
This is not grocery shopping.
It's a fancy deal.
You'll go in for 14 years
if you get caught.
I need money.
I've made up my mind.
Okay.
There's unrest at the border.
Get on with it when the dust settles.
Rabi.
- Rabi.
- Coming!
Yes, boss.
This is Nishan.
- Hi.
- He'll deliver the item.
You'll go with him
after two weeks.
He's a fresher.
A newcomer.
If he screws up...
Don't worry.
I'm a seasoned guy.
Stop, stop, stop.
Get down.
Relax.
Do you see the light there?
It will be back here in two minutes.
You have two minutes to run.
If you fail,
we'll have to abort the task.
Keep the flashlight.
But don't turn it on.
Or you'll be done for.
Be careful.
Run! Run! Run!
Come on.
Watch out!
Run!
Hurry up.
Tuhin!
Nishan!
Hello.
Come downstairs, Babu.
Why?
Come fast.
Okay.
What happened?
What's wrong?
- Give me a shirt.
- Where were you?
Didn't I warn you?
Didn't I tell you it was too risky?
What if you got shot?
- Why do you have to do this?
- I'm fine!
My dad...
won't invest in my business.
I will crack a big deal.
Then use the money
to start an import-export business.
- Do you get it?
- I do.
What will you do then?
Zarine's dad won't accept me
if I don't earn well.
- I'll save money--
- Zarine got married.
What?
Zarine got married.
To whom?
Sohag.
Last Friday.
They're moving to Canada
so they rushed the wedding.
Nishan!
- Zarine! Zarine!
- No, Nishan... Please...
- What's wrong?  Who are you?
- Zarine!
- Zarine, come out.
- What's going on?
- Let go of me!
- Everyone's watching.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Zarine.
- How could you?
- Nishan...
- How?
- Let's go.
- How could you?
- Let's talk inside.
- Answer me.
- Come on!
- How could you do this to me?
- She'll be disgraced.
Let's sit and talk.
- How could you?
- Stop it--
Don't you dare touch me!
How could you do this to me?
How?
Stop it, Nishan.
- Cheater!
- Please let's go.
Bloody cheater!
Traitor!
Come on.
Nishan, don't do this.
- How could you do this?
- Nishan, quiet.
- Come on!
- Let me go!
- How could she?
- Come on.
Is he the guy you told me about?
You said he isn't serious
about you.
But didn't seem like it.
You think I lied to you?
Why would you lie to me?
- I didn't hide anything from you.
- Zarine.
- I told you I'm not a virgin.
- No, I--
Called him right in front of you.
- You know everything.
- Zarine--
Why are you getting mad at me?
It has hurt his ego.
He thinks he's lost.
He'll forget it all by tomorrow.
You need to end this.
You both need closure.
We don't need anything.
Believe me.
He'll forget everything tomorrow.
Zarine, I feel...
I've come between you guys.
I've ruined your relationship.
Come.
Careful.
This way.
Nishan.
I didn't get to introduce myself.
I'm Sohag.
Let me talk.
He knows who you are.
My husband and I are here
to clear something up.
He knows we were in a relationship.
I didn't hide anything from him.
But he thinks he's breaking us up.
I told him he's wrong.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Can you give me five minutes
with her?
No.
We'll talk in front of him.
We have nothing to talk about
in private.
Four minutes?
You need my permission
to talk to me.
Three minutes?
Zarine, talk it out.
Please.
End it.
Babu, come with me.
Let's go.
I won't let you go.
Let me go.
Let me go, Nishan.
Why...
Why did you leave me?
- How could you dump me?
- Let me go.
Nishan, let me go!
You're drunk?
Huh?
Let me go.
"A hundred moons may shine
yet none can match your light.
For only in your presence
does the night feel bright."
Beautiful!
Wow!
I won't let you go.
Move.
- I have to go.
- Hey, listen.
Nishan, I'll scream!
Let me go.
He, why are you closing the door?
Keep the door open.
Don't force me to shout!
See.
Look.
I survived a shootout
just to come back to you.
Don't dump me.
How could you just leave me?
- Let me go.
- Please don't leave me.
I don't accept this marriage.
I'll marry you today.
I'm begging you.
Please don't kill me.
- Please, Zarine.
- Let go of me.
I waited for you.
But you didn't come.
Now let me go.
Now I'm a married woman.
My husband is waiting for me.
Let me go.
He...
Sohag has tainted you.
I...
- I'll make you pure again.
- Nishan, no...
Zarine?
- Zarine!
- Nishan!
- Nishan, open the door.
- Open up, Zarine!
Open the door.
Zarine!
Open the--
What happened?
Zarine?
Bloody scoundrel!
Son of a b---h!
What did you do to her?
Why did you close the door?
Speak up!
Bloody rascal!
Why did you close the door?
Get lost!
Nishan!
This monster...
...killed my son!
You'll rot in hell!
Give back my son!
Nishan must be hanged!
- Nishan must be hanged!
He pushed Sohag off the terrace.
Your Honour, Zarine called him.
Sohag and Nishan were talking.
It was just an accident.
- Nishan must be hanged!
Nishan...
- Hello, uncle.
- Hello.
You here?
- When did you get out of jail?
- Uncle...
Babu.
Nishan?
Nishan!
How are you?
How have you been?
I did my time right...
so they reduced my sentence.
Oh, I see.
I'm very sorry, buddy.
I didn't check in on you
for a long time.
You did visit me a few times.
My dad...
didn't show up even once.
Hey.
You took the final exams, right?
Yes, twice.
But couldn't continue my studies
in jail.
Prison is...
a hellhole.
Everyone wants to
have an upper hand over you.
They sniff out your weakness
from a mile away.
Then gradually...
your soul dies.
Ranjit sent me.
Prison changes you.
A good person becomes bad.
And a bad person becomes evil.
Guilt feels like a heavy rock
sitting on your chest.
I've prayed for only one thing
these 14 years.
That I don't die there.
Not like a criminal.
I've ruined so many lives.
Zarine.
Sohag's mom.
My grandma.
My dad.
I hope they forgive me.
Until I've atoned for my sins...
I won't be free.
I have only one wish.
I want...
things to be as they were.
Buddy.
Where does Zarine live now?
Her dad got a transfer to Cox's Bazar
soon after.
We haven't been in touch since then.
Sohag's mom lives with her daughter
in Dhaka.
She comes here sometimes.
I don't keep track of them.
Hello, Commissioner.
Hello.
Has Nishan been released?
Yes, today.
Did he come back home?
Yes.
Why?
Why is he back home?
I don't understand...
Where else would he go?
Somewhere else.
He should be in Dhaka.
He's not an ordinary criminal.
Everyone knows what he did.
And they're talking already.
Commissioner.
He's been punished for his crime.
He's served his time.
He was punished by the law.
But society is yet to forgive him.
Ask him to leave for Dhaka.
The world is cruel.
People will say a lot of things.
Don't pay heed to them.
Don't run after easy money.
Work hard.
Try to find a purpose in life.
Life is like riding a cycle.
You have to keep going
if you don't want to fall.
I hope you’ve learnt that by now.
You haven't met Nadia's husband.
Go over for a few days.
Get a haircut and shave before you go.
Be like the Nishan we knew.
Here you go.
Keep my phone.
Till you buy a new one.
Here.
And keep the money.
You'll need it.
Get going.
Turn left, please.
But we're headed this way.
Do as I say.
Pull over.
- Make sure we get the tender.
- I'll take care of it.
How's the sweet?
- Great!
- Delicious.
Nadia.
Brother!
It's been so long.
I told Mom so many times.
I wanted to go meet you.
But she didn't let me.
Now I'm here.
Russel, this is my brother.
Hello.
Come here.
How are you?
I'm good.
- Sit, I'll get you some juice.
- Sure.
He is the exigence officer
at Water Development Board.
- And his wife.
- Hello.
I do the contractual work
in his office.
- Please sit.
- Sure.
Seems like you met your sister
after a long time.
Yes.
He was settled abroad
for many years.
- Just returned a few days ago.
- Where were you?
Saudi Arabia.
I was there for a long time.
Where did you live?
Jeddah.
I see.
I was in Riyadh.
I'm Rahim.
And you?
Have some more sweets.
Why don't you freshen up inside?
Please come.
Here.
Have a seat.
I'll send Nadia.
Hey.
Are you Rafeez?
Come here.
I'm your uncle.
I've got chocolates for you.
You said he wouldn't come.
Why the hell is he here?
I have guests over.
I can't even introduce him
to anyone.
I have to lie over and over.
Now you want them all
in the same place.
If they find out who he is,
I will be out of a job.
- Can't my brother meet me?
- Why not?
But go to your house.
He's just here with bag and baggage.
He's here to see me.
Nadia.
Don't cross your limits.
Don't ruin our family for him.
What's wrong with you?
Why would it ruin my family?
It will!
I don't want any nuisance.
Hope I made myself clear.
Brother!
Everything is beautiful in this world!
The light and the air.
The trees and leaves.
Dad.
Nishan, you're here.
This is my son, Nishan.
Nishan.
This is Feroz.
My former colleague.
We retired together.
He lives in Ukilpara.
- Sit.
- Hello.
Come on.
And this is Likhon.
She's Feroz's niece.
She lives in Rajshahi.
Her dad runs a silk business.
And this is Likhon's friend.
I see.
Feroz wants you and Likhon
to get married.
You'll have to move to Rajshahi
after marriage.
You'll have to look after
their business.
I think it's a good proposal.
You'll have a family.
You'll find a purpose in life.
The rest is up to you.
Listen.
I think they should talk in private.
Let's go outside.
Right, let's leave them to it.
Let's go. Come on.
"Sit here."
"Sit face to face."
- "Say something."
- What do I say?
"Anything.
Ask her something."
Will you still interpret for her
after we get married?
Why would I?
You'll learn sign language.
I thought "buy one get one free".
Package deal.
Hello, Babu.
Really?
Okay, I'll be right there.
Yes, I'm on my way.
Bye.
Sorry, I'll have to leave.
I think you don't know something.
I should let you know.
I got out of jail
a few days ago.
I was in for murder.
Got a 14-year sentence.
Not death penalty.
Everyone knows about it.
Maybe your uncle does too
but he didn't tell you.
I'm broken glass.
You'll end up getting hurt
if you're near me.
Bye.
And I don't want to
live off my in-laws.
This is Nishan.
Hello.
How are you?
Babu has recommended you
so there won't be any problem.
- Okay, Babu?
- Thank you.
Under the vast sky by the river
I look for the warmth of a home
Wandering through the lanes of memory
I find solace in its quiet embrace
I miss the good old days
The dreams that once touched me soft
Have now drifted away with the wind
Will you give me my world of dreams?
WILL WE TALK HERE
OR GO SOMEWHERE ELSE?
FIVE MINUTES?
Will you give me my world of dreams?
Will our love story
have a new beginning?
UNCLE TOLD ME EVERYTHING
ABOUT YOU
I LIKE YOU
I LIKE YOUR HONESTY
AND YOU'RE SO BLOODY HANDSOME
I'M SCARED YOU WOULDN'T LIKE
A DEAF-MUTE LIKE ME
I WAS MARRIED BEFORE
MY HUSBAND TOOK ALL THE MONEY
AND ELOPED ABROAD WITH MY COUSIN
WE'RE BOTH BIRDS WITH BROKEN WINGS
DEFEATED IN LIFE'S BATTLE
IF YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY PLANS FOR MURDER
WILL YOU GIVE ME YOUR EVENINGS
FOR THE NEXT FEW DAYS?
I'M NOT AFRAID OF BROKEN GLASS
I'll let you know.
I look for a light in the darkness
Will you give me my world of dreams?
Will our love story
have a new beginning?
We're the only friends you have.
Will our love story
have a new beginning?
WILL YOU DROP ME HOME?
Brother.
Please come over tomorrow.
I've spoken to Russel.
Come over once.
We'll sort it out.
Please, Brother.
Okay, sure.
I'll be there.
Bye.
Nishan.
Hang on.
Here, take your lunchbox.
- Thanks.
- Bye.
Bye, Dad.
"You've forgotten me.
But I haven't.
Let's reminisce some moments
from the past.
You know everything
I've been through.
I know.
You're doing a job.
You're living a simple, ordinary life.
I know everything.
But...
The world is very cruel, Nishan.
No, boss.
Everything is alright.
Everything.
I'm very happy.
Really happy.
This is the life I want.
Look, boss.
You helped me a lot
when I was in jail.
I'll always be grateful to you...
But I...
don't want to get back to that work.
Okay.
Bless you.
Thanks.
Bye.
Boss.
Should we use Nishan?
No.
Let him be.
Make sure you clear them all today.
Nishan.
Come here.
I'll keep this.
No need.
Come here.
Get to work.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
You don't have to come anymore.
What...
I mean... Why...
What did I do?
You didn't do anything.
Don't you know?
Don't you check social media?
Social media...
They let that criminal out?
My dear son is lying in the grave.
And his killer will live happily?
He should've been hanged.
I want him to be hanged.
Everyone's trending
#BoycottShilpiStore.
I'll have to shut up shop
if the video goes viral.
I'm sorry.
No...
Bye.
Take care.
No!
Get lost!
Go away!
Excuse me.
You're Nishan, aren't you?
You look like a normal person.
Why are you here, bugger?
Want to kill me?
- Killing my son wasn't enough?
- Ma'am, please...
I'll kill you!
- I'll kill you!
- Please forgive me.
How dare you come here again?
What the hell are you doing here?
- Please leave.
- I'm going to kill you!
- You bloody scoundrel!
- Please forgive me!
- Please go!
- You're dead!
- Get lost!
- Please leave.
- Go!
- He killed my son!
- Please go.
- Leave!
- It's okay. Calm down.
- He killed my boy...
Everything is beautiful
in Allah's world...
- Hello.
- Where's Nadia?
- Who are you?
I'm her brother.
She called me over.
And you just came?
Don't you have any sense?
They're a family.
But they're fighting over you.
Jashim, go inside.
I called you to say
you don't have to come.
Who is he?
Russel's cousin brother.
Hey.
- What's this?
- It's nothing.
- Show me.
- Not...
Did he hit you?
Is it because of me?
It's common in married couples.
Hey, Russel.
How could you hit my sister?
My parents raised her
with a lot of care.
We've never raised a hand on her.
How could you?
- Hey, it's all your fault.
- Hey!
- Hey! Hey!
- Brother!
- I'll kill you!
- Let him go!
Brother, no...
Please...
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
I won't come here again.
I'll never come here.
Everything is beautiful
in Allah's world.
The trees and the leaves.
The sky...
The air and water...
Nishan!
You'll rot in hell!
Bloody monster!
Everything is beautiful
in this world.
- Nishan must be hanged!
- Hang him now!
- Our brother's blood!
- Won't go to waste!
- Won't be spilled in vain!
- Our brother's blood!
- Won't go to waste!
- Nishan must be hanged!
- We want him hanged!
- Our brother's blood!
- Won't go to waste!
- Won't be spilled in vain!
Nishan must be hanged!
Nishan must be hanged--
What else is left?
What else will you do?
Why did you go to Sohag's house?
Why?
What do you want?
You want them to set us on fire?
Rahim.
Excuse me.
Please.
Why did you go there?
I went to apologise.
You killed her son.
And you want her to forgive you?
Then what should I do?
Should I kill myself?
Tell me.
Should I hang myself?
Tell me what I should do.
People think you were there
to threaten her.
You wanted revenge from her
for sending you to jail.
That murderer went
to Sohag's house.
Threatened his mom
because she got him arrested.
We want revenge!
We want justice!
I will leave this place.
When?
Whenever you say.
The sooner the better.
Okay.
I know what happened...
so I'm not filing the case.
One more thing.
Don't step out of the house
until you leave.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
Problem solved.
Forgive me, Dad.
You never look me in the eye.
Because it reminds you...
that your mom died because of me.
Forgive me.
Please don't hate me.
Did you really go there to apologise?
Yes.
It takes courage to apologise.
Even the mighty have fallen
because they didn't apologise.
Go to Rajshashi.
Get married to Likhon.
Find a purpose in life.
You'll be at peace.
My biggest mistake in life was...
not being strong
when I needed to be.
Your life would've been different
otherwise.
Uncle.
Excuse me, uncle.
Please move.
Smile!
Look here.
Dad said...
I'll be happy if I marry you.
IS THAT WHY YOU'RE HERE?
No, it's a major reason but...
What's the matter, Kushali?
Yes, Nishan?
Does Zarine live in Rajshahi?
Zarine?
Zarine doesn't stay in Rajshahi.
Likhon lives there.
I just saw Zarine.
You're mistaken.
Zarine doesn't live in Rajshahi.
I'm very sure I saw Zarine.
There was a little girl with her.
I think it's her daughter.
Zarine doesn't live in Rajshahi.
You made a mistake.
How does it matter if she lives there?
You're there for Likhon.
Why are you thinking of Zarine?
Hang up.
"This is the guest room."
"Uncle is in Dhaka."
"He'll be back tomorrow."
"You can stay here
for the next few days."
You can move in after the wedding.
What the hell!
I didn't say anything wrong.
I have to go out.
"Should I come?"
No, I'll go alone.
"Okay."
A great girl...
A peaceful life...
...is awaiting you.
And you're chasing a mirage.
Why?
You're inviting trouble.
Please don't do this.
Forget Zarine.
Hey, stop!
Shoaib wants to see you.
Who's that?
He wants to see you.
Hey!
Don't you get it?
Come with us.
I'm in a bad mood today.
To hell with your mood.
Hey!
Why do you get in to fights
on the road?
Naughty boy!
He's a fresher.
A newcomer.
You'll be in big trouble.
Shoaib works for me.
Saw you entering the shopping mall
so sent for you.
They could've told me about you.
Then there'd be no twist in the film.
Hey! Up, up, up!
Come up.
Bulletproof glass.
Can't risk rolling it down.
Where are we going?
My farmhouse.
We're almost there.
Whose car is this?
Mine.
Come.
Don't worry.
I'm here.
I know what everyone is up to.
Don't worry.
I'll handle it.
Trust me.
My daughter.
Kushali.
Where's Radid?
He's gone out with Mom.
What the hell!
Ma'am said it's important.
Don't worry.
Ashraf is with them.
Damn her important work!
Is Radid okay?
I've told you so many times.
Don't go out without the red car.
Don't care about you.
Why have you taken my son?
Say hello to your new uncle.
Come here.
Sit with me.
Come on.
Come closer.
I have some work.
What work?
More important than me?
Come to me.
Sit with me.
- I have really important stuff to do.
- Come on!
Look at her.
Stepdaughter.
Doesn't look like me at all.
She looks more like you.
Just joking.
I'll make you pure again.
Nishan.
Dad!
Dad.
Nishan.
Sit.
Want to play the drums?
I'll play it with you.
My son.
Look.
Looks exactly like me.
Smells like me too.
Go and play.
My son.
My blood.
You left me at the hospital.
Then I was in prison for three years.
After I got it,
I started my business.
It's all legal.
Nothing shady.
All white.
I'm involved in politics now.
Going to contest in the MP elections.
Then, go on to become a minister.
After that...
the game will begin!
You're going to work with me.
I need people like you.
I don't want to work
in the border area.
You know nothing about the border.
It's not just smuggling cows.
There are more things to do.
Networking, distribution,
accounting, security.
Forget your worries.
Stay here.
You'll learn the ropes soon.
Just be loyal.
That's all I need.
I'll teach you the rest.
You don't have to decide right now.
Sleep over it.
- Shoaib!
- Yes, boss?
Drop him off.
Come on.
She looks more like you.
Ranjit sends his regards.
Why didn't you tell me
Zarine married Rabi?
Ranjit asked me not to.
He is very fond of you.
So didn't want to cause any trouble.
Nishan.
Yes, Ranjit.
You wanted to stay out
of the business.
I didn't force you to stay.
But...
If you get back in the business
then it has to be with me.
My Nishan will work with me.
Not with some traitor.
What say, Nishan?
Yes, Ranjit.
Anyway...
Join that dumbf--k's gang.
But share...
...all his plans with me.
The day Ranjit Singh loses it
Traitor!
he'll destroy Rabi's entire family.
Keep this.
I'm not meant to be a family man.
Couldn't do it before.
Can't do it now.
And if you marry me...
people won't let you live in peace.
This world is very cruel.
They'll keep reminding you,
you married a murderer.
I've found a job.
Found some old friends.
At the end of the tunnel...
I've found some light.
Please let me go.
I have to leave.
Or else all hell will break loose.
- Bye.
- "No worries.
It's your life, your decision.
I'm perfectly okay with it.
See, I'm smiling."
Can I hug you?
"Take care of yourself.
Travel safe.
I'll be waiting for you."
I have to go now.
"I'll be waiting."
Bye.
"A hundred moons may shine.
Yet none can match your light.
For only in your presence..."
"For only in your presence..."
"...does the night feel bright.
Such great wealth cannot
through charity be earned.
Love is a fragrance
that lingers on forever.
Even at his most lonesome...
he is never alone."
Want to say something?
This is my wife, Zarine.
I did a lot of contractual work
for her father.
Earned a lot of money.
A single mother.
She couldn't find a husband.
All kinds of old geezers
were lining up.
She was so gorgeous.
So sweet.
Her father asked me
and I readily got married.
Zarine, this is Nishan.
He'll be working with me.
He'll stay at the guest house.
Want to say something?
She doesn't say anything.
Come on.
Continue.
Bloody monster!
Murderer!
Why have you come here?
What do you want?
Answer me!
How are you, Zarine?
Nishan, please go away.
You can't stay here.
Leave right now.
Whose daughter is Kushali?
She is my daughter.
Sohag's daughter.
- Kushali is my daughter.
- No.
She is Sohag's daughter.
Don't lie.
She looks exactly like my grandma.
My dad and grandma
were thick glasses too.
- Sohag had glasses too.
- Thousands of people wear glasses.
Are you sure she is Sohag's daughter?
There it is.
You have doubts.
- I know she is Sohag's daughter.
- No, you don't.
Kushali is my daughter.
I can feel it in my heart.
I'll tell Radid's father everything.
Radid's father?
I've lived with criminals for 14 years.
Rabi knows everything.
He brought me here
despite knowing it all.
He is planning something big.
I'll tell Kushali
how you killed her father.
I didn't kill Sohag!
It was an accident.
I made a mistake.
Please consider that, at least.
I can still see it
like it happened yesterday.
My life would have been so different.
My daughter grew up
without a father.
Her life would have been so different.
And you're asking me to consider?
I don't want to see you
ever again.
If you don't leave,
I'll kill you.
Sit.
Did Ranjit call you?
No.
You'd last met him in India.
Haven't you met him
or talked to him since?
No.
Ranjit Singh is a dangerous guy.
He wants to control everything.
He must have
the last word on everything.
One has to partner up with him
in business and no one else.
Strange rules!
Junaid Khan.
India's biggest gold smuggler.
Picked up a consignment
from Junaid Khan.
Ranjit has destroyed all the documents
and killed my men.
A few days back, the cops
got hold of Ranjit's consignment.
And he accused me
of informing the cops.
Can you imagine?
I offered to parlay with him.
But he's insisting I pay him
the full amount of the lost cargo.
I suggested we talk face to face.
Let's resolve the matter.
He wants money first
then he'll talk.
He's not even answering my calls.
Nishan.
Ranjit Singh is really fond of you.
Put in a good word for me.
What will I say?
Tell him Rabi wants to
resolve the matter.
In person.
Face to face.
He won't listen to me.
Ranjit is...
only going to listen to money.
Talk to him about money then.
No problem.
It's a video call.
Talk to him.
Hello.
Who's this?
Sir, this is Nishan.
Rabi is here with me.
Hey!
What are you doing
with that scoundrel?
Sir.
He wants to discuss money.
He will return what he owes you.
Just talk to him for a minute.
Hey, take it away.
I just need to talk to you.
Want to sit face to face
with you.
And resolve the matter.
Come.
Come to India.
Right.
You want me to go to India
so that you can kill me?
Do you want me to come
to Bangladesh?
Why?
What will happen?
Do I look like a scary ghost to you?
I'm not going to hurt you.
You pretty much
run the government here.
You run the entire syndicate.
And they won't spare me.
Just come to Bangladesh.
I'll return all your money.
Just come and meet me.
You'll return all the money?
I'll pay you hard cash in dollars.
Nishan is here, right?
He'll keep you updated
about everything.
Sir, please.
Please don't harm
my family and my kids.
Okay.
I'll let you know.
Keep the phone.
If Ranjit calls...
Let me know.
Okay?
I need to talk to you.
You know who Nishan is
and what he's done.
You haven't told me anything.
Will you still let him stay here?
There's still a lot I don't know
that's why I'm keeping him here.
Is he Kushali's father?
I don't know.
I must find out.
I don't think even you know
who her father is.
Do you know?
Nishan is doing something important
for me.
He'll stay here.
Then I'll take the kids to the city.
There's no security
in the city residence.
If you want to go,
take Kushali with you.
Radid will stay here.
My kid's safety matters the most.
You would've known
if you had a kid.
It's tough to be a parent.
Pass it to me.
I'll slap you!
She fell again!
Let's play.
I'll help you.
Look ahead while riding.
Kushali!
Come inside.
No need to learn to bike.
Let her learn from him.
What's the issue?
It's okay.
I'll teach you.
You'll learn in a jiffy.
I'll teach you in a second.
Don't worry, my baby.
Don't worry.
Raise your leg.
Right here.
Come on.
Get on.
Don't worry.
Come on, paddle.
Right, paddle.
You have to hold the bike
from behind to support.
You don't have to touch her.
Let it be.
I have to go.
I have classes.
Who's going to drop you off now?
No one's around.
Who will take you?
He'll take me.
It's too risky to go to the city now.
You can't go.
There's no risk.
For him.
He's Ranjit Singh's guy.
Go ahead.
Take her.
I can take care of myself.
Is your name Nishan?
Yes.
What does it mean?
A mark.
A sign.
Is that even a name?
Mr. Sign.
Do you live in Saidpur?
Yes.
My grandparents used to live there too.
But not anymore.
They live in Dhaka now.
My dad died before I was born.
In an accident.
I've never seen him.
How dare you?
Nishan!
Wait, Mr. Sign.
That's my school.
Stop here.
Wait here.
My God!
Eight missed calls?
This woman is crazy.
Anyway.
Are you on social media?
No.
It's nonsense.
I deactivated my account too.
We use a new app.
Do you know...
what Rabi does?
Yes, he's in politics.
The way he behaves with you...
Did you tell your mom about it?
He will deny it.
And call it my mistake.
Then he'll fight with Mom.
Mom has already been through enough.
I don't want more for her.
Promise me you won't tell anyone.
Promise me.
I promise.
Here, keep this.
Blow it and I'll be there for you.
I could've taken you to coaching class.
No problem.
Mr. Sign is nice. I like him.
The staff don't enter the house.
It's out of bounds for them.
I told you to leave, Nishan.
I won't leave, Zarine.
What?
I won't go away.
They threw me out of Saidpur.
I didn't say anything.
I left home.
But I won't go from here.
I don't care what you want.
I'm taking Kushali away from you.
She's always be your daughter.
I don't want her
to be known as a criminal’s daughter.
I don't want that.
I know society all too well.
It's very cruel.
It never forgives you.
Want to be forgiven just like that?
Is that so easy?
Mom, I'm going out to play.
I don't have anyone.
I'm all alone.
You...
know everything.
Dad always told me
to find a purpose in life.
I didn't listen to him.
Always thought it was nonsense.
But now I know what he meant.
I've finally found a purpose.
Please try to understand.
I had a lot of hopes
when I came out of jail.
Thought I would get back my old life.
But society destroyed all my hopes.
I've found a flicker in the dark.
Don't take that away from me.
Please have mercy on me.
Mr. Sign!
There, she's calling me.
She is so pretty.
So smart.
I'll keep her safe.
I'll protect her.
Kushali is my daughter, isn't she?
Downloaded the tracker app.
You can track my location.
- What is it?
- It's an app.
What's an app?
You don't know what's an app?
LOL!
You don't know what LOL stands for?
LOL.
Laughing Out Loud.
Laugh Out Loud.
No.
Laughing Out Loud.
LMAO.
Laughing My A-- Off!
No, Babu.
She's my daughter.
I know it.
I can just feel it.
She's my blood.
Damn it!
Now everything will change.
Nothing will change.
She'll live with her mom.
I'll just be around.
She is my own.
That's all that matters.
I'm happy with this.
I'm very happy.
LOL.
Laughing Out Loud.
Please!
OMG!
Oh my god, you're so mad at me.
BTW.
By the way, listen to me...
Hello, Granny.
How are you?
I've made a new friend.
Nishan.
What?
Nishan?
Kushali!
Go inside.
Come on.
Go inside, Radid.
Okay, Mom.
No poetry in my house.
I'll only inform Nishan
where we'll have the meeting.
Only two people.
You and Nishan.
Tuhin and me.
Why didn't you come on the 15th?
I waited for you all day.
That day.
The next day.
The day after.
And the day after...
But you didn't come.
Why didn't you come, Nishan?
I thought I'll earn some money
and then...
Did I ask you to bring money?
I told you I'll manage everything.
Still, you didn't come.
Why didn't you come?
Zarine.
Why didn't you love me
the way I did?
Why didn't you hold on to me?
You don't know how to love.
You don't know what love is.
Why don't you...
I know...
I know now.
Listen.
Hope you don't have
any more work with Nishan.
Why do you ask?
Nishan won't stay here anymore.
He'll have to leave.
Hello, Ranjit.
Boss.
Why are they here?
It's game over for Rabi today.
Come on.
Kushali!
Kushali.
- Granny!
- Where is he?
Where's that murderer?
- Who?
- Nishan.
- He's nice.
- Nice?
Kushali?
Back with your old flame?
Is that why you brought him over?
- Come inside, Mother.
- Let me go.
Is that why
you didn't tell her anything?
So that you can get back together?
Rabi brought him over for his business.
That's why you got married
to a criminal.
- It's do or die today.
- Mother...
Mother.
- Keep quiet.
- Your dad didn't die in an accident.
Please don't tell her anything.
Nishan killed him!
Mother!
Ask your mom.
Ask her.
My dear son...
They killed him.
They killed him...
They killed my Sohag...
Kushali?
Kushali!
Nishan!
Ranjit.
Boss.
Greetings.
I love you.
Got the location?
I'll send you the exact location.
Hello, Deputy Inspector General.
There's been a disaster!
Nishan shot Ranjit Singh
and ran away with the money.
Talk to you later.
Don't worry.
Peekaboo!
Nishan!
Where are you?
What did you think?
I bumped into you by chance?
It was all just a coincidence?
You came to Rajshahi by choice?
I made sure you ended up here.
I f--king planned it all.
Used a thorn to remove another.
Nishan.
Where are you?
Time to settle our scores.
Let's settle our scores.
Come out.
I told you
I'd shoot Ranjit Singh first.
But you wanted to kill him.
I took the shot.
I'm sure I got him.
- We didn't find the dead body.
- We will soon.
Don't worry.
Khan is calling.
Khan.
Nishan blew it.
He blew it.
He f--king screwed us.
The underground business
has its rules.
You shouldn't have broken them.
You messed up the system
by killing Ranjit.
You'll pay for it.
No, no, no.
I didn't do anything.
Hello--
Bloody hell!
How did he find out from India?
Who leaked the news?
It's the f--king DIG now.
What the hell did you do?
Why did you kill Ranjit Singh?
Nishan did--
Shut up, scoundrel!
You think I'm a f--king fool?
It's gone up to the authorities.
I'm in trouble now.
Please listen to me--
You're finished!
You're a goner.
F--king s--t!
Radid!
Hey, why are you here?
I'm here to meet my granddaughter.
Bloody hag!
Zarine!
Ma'am has gone out with Radid
to look for Kushali.
Bloody b---h!
You all killed my son.
Now you're after my granddaughter.
I'll kill you too.
- Wait and watch!
- Go ahead.
I'll kill you.
You're so dead.
Kill me.
Come on.
I anyway died the day my son died.
- Kill me!
- Take her away!
Why aren't you answering my calls?
I put it my phone on silent.
I don't want to go back home.
Kushali!
Move it.
Hurry up.
Kushali!
Kushali, wait!
Let me go!
Where are you?
I don't want to know.
Get home with Radid in two minutes.
Ranjit Singh is still alive.
You wanted to do business with Khan...
...so you betrayed me.
Now I'll teach you how to kill people.
I have got your daughter.
I'll destroy your family.
Boss.
Give back Ranjit's money!
What?
Damn it!
F--king hell!
Bloody swine!
F--king traitor!
Sir.
For God's sake, save me.
You have six hours
to leave the country.
I better not see you or Ranjit
here again.
Alhamdulillah!
- Thank you, sir--
- Kushali!
Where is Kushali?
- Bloody whore!
- Mom!
F--king b---h!
It took you half an hour
to come home?
Come, Radid.
We'll leave.
- Where are you going?
- It's not safe here.
They'll kill us any moment.
I'm running away with Radid.
- Will you come?
- I can't leave Kushali behind.
Then die, b---h!
- Don't take my son away.
- Let go of my son!
- How dare you stop me?
- I won't let you--
Mom!
Give back Ranjit's money!
Dad!
- Come on, give it to me.
- Nishan!
- Dad!
- I want the money!
- Nishan!
To hell with Nishan!
Ranjit has kidnapped Kushali!
He'll Kushali
if he doesn't get his money back.
Give back the money!
Dad!
Don't kill my dad.
Please don't kill...
Radid.
I'm fine.
My son.
Mine.
Your daughter is everything to you.
My son is everything to me too.
My own blood.
Ranjit asked me to...
go to Bilonia Station
with the money.
That scoundrel runs the place.
He'll kill my whole family
if I go there.
I'll give you all the money.
I promise, Nishan.
Just let me save my son.
I've lost everything anyway.
Please let me save my son.
My son, my son...
Please...
Forgive me, Nishan.
Please forgive me for his sake, Nishan.
Forgive me...
Please forgive me...
Dad!
I've begged for forgiveness all my life.
But I've never been forgiven.
I forgive you for your son's sake.
I forgive you, Rabi.
Let's go.
You here?
I'm going with you.
I won't change my mind.
We only have a few hours.
We won't be able to get her back
if they cross the border.
Take me to my granddaughter.
- Kushali is not your--
- Nishan.
Fine!
Nishan.
What did he say?
He gave me the phone.
Nishan.
Ranjit.
I'll give back your money.
I trusted you, Nishan.
I didn't betray you.
Rabi planned to kill you.
And pin the blame on me.
But I didn't betray you.
Someone else did.
Send Rabi with the money.
I'll let his daughter go.
Rabi won't come.
Kushali is not his daughter.
She is my daughter.
I'm her father.
And Zarine is her mother.
She is my ex girlfriend,
the engineer's daughter.
Oh! I see.
I know about Zarine.
But is she really your daughter?
Mom!
Mom, don't come!
He won't keep his word.
Don't come!
Of course, she is your daughter.
Ranjit.
I'll get your money.
Tell me the place.
Cross the railway line.
Close to the border...
there's a village called Matikata.
Come to Majumdar's house there.
Meet me with the money.
But Nishan...
I never forgive traitors.
Bring my money.
I'll let your daughter go.
But I won't let you go.
Tuhin is dead because of you.
Blood for blood.
Come alone.
Alone!
Okay, done.
I've finally found the purpose
in my life.
I'm not hurt at all.
I'm rather relieved.
I feel like...
I'm leaving a piece of me behind.
A part of my soul.
A sign.
Mr. Sign.
Zarine.
Raise Kushali with a lot of care.
I know she'll become a scientist.
Don't tell her about me.
- Tell her--
- Kushali is not your daughter.
She's not your daughter, Nishan.
How many times
will you say the same thing?
I'm not lying.
Remember I took a strand of your hair.
I had a DNA test done.
Got the report.
You're not his father.
Here, take a look.
Even I thought she's your daughter.
That's why I got the test done.
Zarine...
a DNA report...
can be wrong.
But this is not wrong.
Her DNA matches with her grandmother's.
Not yours.
Don't sacrifice your life for her.
Start afresh.
Live your life.
I'll take the money.
I'll plead with them.
They might let her go--
Bloody monster!
Sohag's mom.
Zarine.
My grandma.
Guilt feels like a heavy rock
sitting on your chest.
Nishan.
Dad, please forgive me.
I wanted to tell you but I couldn't.
I don't hate you, my son.
My mother forgave you.
Why wouldn't I?
Mother kept thinking of you
until her last breath.
Hating you...
would hurt her.
So I forgive you, my son.
Don't be sad.
Goodbye, Dad.
Take care.
My daughter grew up without a father.
Her life would have been so different.
Is your name Nishan?
What does it mean?
A mark.
OMG!
Oh my god,
you're so mad at me!
Ranjit!
I've got your money.
Let Kushali go.
Come out of hiding.
Did you kill my dad?
Yes.
Your dad died because of you.
They said, "Your dad is coming".
Why?
Are you--
You know what's your real punishment?
Ranjit, you gave me your word.
She'll watch her father die
right before her eyes.
That's your punishment.
Hey!
No firing close to the border, idiot.
- I won't kill you today.
- Nishan...
You'll regret all your life
that you couldn't save your daughter.
Your daughter will end up
in some brothel in India.
And every day, a new jerk...
a monster will take his turn with her.
Nishan!
No, no, no...
Nishan...
Let me go.
Hurry up.
Move it.
Split and move.
Come on.
Move it.
Keep quiet or I'll shoot you.
Walk!
Keep quiet.
Nishan wants the Security Force
to take us out.
Keep quiet!
Quiet!
Mom!
- Kushali!
- Mom...
My girl...
My dear granddaughter...
Nishan!
- Nishan!
- Nishan.
- Nishan?
Get up, Nishan.
We have to save him.
Get something.
- Hey, there's a cart.
- Come on.
Nishan, where does it hurt?
Nishan...
Zarine.
I forgive you.
I forgive you, Nishan.
All my life...
I've tried to force my will on you.
I've only brought you pain.
Nothing but pain.
Break it fast.
He'll die. Quick!
We have to take him
to the hospital.
"When the heart hurts...
we seek a cure.
But what if..."
Nishan...
"But what if the heart
is the cause of pain?"
- Mom!
- Nishan...
Found a cart.
But no driver.
- You have to save him.
- Help him up.
Come on.
We'll have to get medical help.
Be careful.
Everything is beautiful
in Allah's world.
Everything is magical
The air, the water, the light...
Kushali!
Nishan! No, no, no.
Nishan.
Nishan, please no...
Nishan...
She's stubborn just like me.
- Nishan!