A Shochiku Production
Japan Art Festival Entry
37th Year of Showa Era (1962)
"In the year 1630,
"13th day of May.
"Fair skies.
"Extremely hot
from early on in the day."
Iyi Clan Journal
"At 10 in the morning,
Master Bennosuke...
"...pays a visit to the Kandabashi
mansion of the Honourable Lord Doi,
"to present fresh river trout
from the Shirakawa River,
"which arrived from our domain.
"No other official business to record.
"However,
at about four in the afternoon,
"a samurai claiming
to be a former retainer
"of the Fukushima Clan in Hiroshima
"appeared at our gate."
HARAKIRl
Produced by HOSOYA Tatsuo
Original Story by TAKIGUCHl Yasuhiko
Screenplay by HASHIMOTO Shinobu
Cinematography by MIYAJIMA Yoshio
Music by TAKEMITSU Toru
Cast:
NAKADAl Tatsuya
ISHIHAMA Akira, lWASHITA Shima
TAMBA Tetsuro
MISHIMA Masao, NAKATANl Ichiro
SATO Kei, INABA Yoshio, AOKl Yoshiro
MIKUNl Rentaro
Directed by KOBAYASHl Masaki
Soto Sakurada-machi, Edo
Official Residence of the lyi Clan
You were a retainer of the former
Fukushima Clan in Hiroshima?
Correct.
My name is Tsugumo Hanshiro.
Written with the character "Tsu"
for "harbour"
and "Gumo" for "cloud".
What is the nature of your visit?
The house of my master fell in 1619.
Subsequently, I left the domain
and moved here to Edo,
where I found shelter
in a back-alley tenement.
While eking out a meagre living,
I sought connections
for employment with a new master.
But try as I might,
we live now in times of peace,
and my every effort has been in vain.
Failing to find employment
and with little to do,
he finds himself in dire straits
and believes that
he can endure it no further.
Rather than live on
in such poverty and disgrace,
he wishes to die honourably
by committing harakiri
and asks for permission
to use our forecourt.
Such is his request, sire.
Not again?
Will it never stop?
How shall I respond, sire?
Fine. Show him in, then.
This way.
Please enter.
Thank you.
I am a former retainer
of Lord Fukushima Masanori
of Hiroshima.
Tsugumo Hanshiro by name.
I respectfully beg your favour.
I am senior counsellor
of the House of lyi, Saito Kageyu.
I am much obliged
for this immediate interview.
The purpose of my visit...
I've already been told of your request.
Rather than live on in endless poverty,
idly waiting for death,
you wish to end your life
in a manner befitting a samurai.
I believe that was the gist of it.
Indeed.
In these times,
your resolve is truly admirable.
I can only express the highest esteem.
You mentioned that you served
the former Lord Fukushima.
Did you happen to know a man
named Chijiiwa Motome?
Chijiiwa?
Yes.
Well...
You don't recognise the name?
I'm quite certain he said he'd served
the former Lord Fukushima.
In its prosperous days,
the clan's retainers
numbered some 12,000 men.
One could hardly know them all.
I see.
But never mind that.
Earlier this year,
perhaps around the end of January,
this ronin named Chijiiwa Motome
came calling.
The purpose of his visit
was the same as yours.
He requested the use of our forecourt
to dispatch himself with honour.
Is that so?
Would you like me to tell you
what happened in that case?
I would indeed.
You say you were a retainer
of the former Fukushima Clan
in Hiroshima?
Correct.
I served the former
Lord Fukushima Masanori of Hiroshima.
My name is Chijiiwa Motome.
And what is the nature of your visit?
After the fall of my master's house,
I moved here to Edo and found
shelter in a back-alley tenement.
While eking out a meagre living,
I sought connections
for employment with a new master.
But try as I might,
we live in times of peace,
and my every effort has been in vain.
So now it seems it's our turn.
How shall we respond?
Let me think.
It's amazing how such foolishness
can take hold.
Blame it on what the Sengoku Clan did.
- Say what you will, that was a mistake.
- No, Yazaki.
- That's not necessarily true.
- Why not?
The fellow who went
to the Sengoku house
was serious about committing harakiri.
There was nothing dishonourable
about his intent.
It was precisely because
they were touched by his sincerity
that the Sengoku house decided
to take him in as a back-room retainer.
That was good.
They made the right decision.
The problem is the shameless
imitators who have followed.
They have no intention whatsoever
of performing harakiri,
and just because they're hurting
a little for food and clothing,
they show up at our gate
to practise their pathetic extortion.
We can't very well allow him
to disembowel himself in our gateway.
Our only choice is to follow
the example of other clans,
and give him a little something
and ask him to leave.
No. That will not do.
If we give him money and send him away,
he'll soon be followed by others.
One after the other,
like ants drawn to a mound of sugar.
Ever since the Battle of Sekigahara,
Edo has been teeming
with masterless samurai.
They're like wild dogs
roving about in search of prey.
Think what people will say...
"Everybody thought that
the House of lyi had backbone,
"so up until now,
the ronin avoided their gate.
"But look what they've done now.
"They boast of their martial valour,
"but this is a time of peace,
"so they're just living
through yesterday's dreams."
Would you have such derisive chatter
spreading all over Edo?
Especially when our lord
is away in his domain.
Under no circumstances
can we allow a stain
on our lord's name while he's away.
Giving him money
and asking him to leave,
such lily-livered nonsense
is out of the question.
He hasn't the slightest intention
of killing himself,
yet he speaks of honourable harakiri.
Counsellor!
If I may...
My apologies for keeping you waiting.
I am Kawabe Umenosuke,
a member of Lord lyi's mounted guard.
My name is Chijiiwa Motome,
a ronin from Hiroshima.
Kindly come with me.
- Excuse me?
- I am to show you to the bath.
Since Lord lyi is at present
away in his domain,
Counsellor Saito conveyed your request
to His Lordship's son, Bennosuke.
He finds your resolve most admirable
and wishes to grant you
an immediate audience.
So... I am to have an audience
with Master Bennosuke?
Correct.
I must beg your pardon,
but your present attire will not do.
While you refresh yourself in the bath,
we'll arrange for some new robes
for you.
I place myself in your hands.
Your kindness overwhelms me.
I must be dreaming.
This is so...
...completely unexpected.
Almost...
Pardon me.
My apologies
for keeping you waiting so long.
I must ask you to change again.
Your robes.
Is something wrong?
What about my audience
with Master Bennosuke?
I was told I'd be granted an audience.
I don't believe so.
- You must have misunderstood.
- No, I'm quite certain.
That was the word I received
from Kawabe of the mounted guard.
Kawabe?
Now that you mention it...
That must be it.
So I'm not mistaken?
I believe I understand.
When Counsellor Saito conveyed
your desire to Master Bennosuke,
he noted how rare it was these days
to find men with such a sense of honour.
"I would like to add this man
to the ranks of our retainers", he said.
"But when a man declares that
he wishes to cut his belly open,
"it can only come
from a most profound resolve.
"I am sure it would be no use
trying to dissuade him.
"Grant him his final wish.
"I would like to meet this man
of uncommon valour
"and tell him how much
I admire his purpose.
"Unfortunately I am scheduled to go
to Lord Dot's residence at this hour.
"Extend to him every courtesy
of this house,
"and have all our retainers
witness his final act,
"that they may remember it
as a proud example."
Such were Master Bennosuke's words,
I was told.
Tell me, what do you think
of this story?
A most interesting tale,
worthy of the famous red armour
that symbolises the House of lyi
and its reputation
for great martial valour.
May I ask what your intentions are?
You mean...
...about this?
Exactly.
You may set your mind at ease.
I came here
with every intention of dying.
Well, well.
A most admirable resolve.
In that case, Master Tsugumo...
...perhaps I should recount for you
a little more of Chijiiwa Motome's story.
By all means.
Now then, we must be aware of the time.
Please change into those robes.
All other arrangements
are already in place
for a harakiri ceremony
with all the proper formalities.
I have a request.
I must beg a brief respite.
Respite?
I will not run or hide.
I will return to this house.
But I beg you for a day or two respite.
I'm afraid it's too late for that.
- But this is absurd!
- Absurd?
We made the harakiri arrangements
at your own request.
My most abject apologies!
Just a day or two respite.
I will return without fail.
A samurai's word is his bond.
There can be no delay!
Master swordsman Yazaki Hayato.
Fit and eager,
his skills honed to perfection.
One false step
and he'll cut you in two.
The others will descend on you as well.
Rather than being chopped up
like a dead fish,
perform harakiri
and die like a samurai.
Now, change into those robes.
O, ancestors of the House of lyi,
I must beg your forgiveness
for defiling the mansion courtyard
with unworthy ronin blood.
I do this to preserve
the honour of this house,
as well as that of the Tokugawa family
and of the samurai code itself.
I beg you to be witness to my decision.
His short blade is the same.
Look at it.
It wouldn't cut tofu.
He sells off his soul as a samurai,
replacing his blades with bamboo,
and then says he wants
to perform harakiri?
The nerve of the man!
Everything is in place
for the ceremony to begin.
Master Chijiiwa Motome...
Rather than wait for death
in dire poverty,
you've declared your wish
to die honourably by harakiri.
It is a commendable decision.
You are an example for all samurai.
I am ashamed to admit it,
but even in this house
known for martial valour
since our ancestor Naomasa's day,
the resolve you've shown
is seen but rarely.
So they may witness
the noble demise of a true warrior
and engrave its lasting impression
upon their minds,
I've ordered all retainers
of this household to attend.
May your heart be at peace.
I beg of you!
What is it?
I beg for a brief respite,
a day or two's grace!
I swear I will not run or hide.
I'll return to this spot without fail!
Please! I implore you!
This is most unexpected.
I've heard lately of incidents
all across Edo
in which ronin, who don't deserve
to call themselves samurai,
demand the use of a clan's forecourt
to commit harakiri,
but are happy to walk away
in exchange for a few coins.
Surely you're not...
Absolutely not, sir.
No, no.
Of course not.
I'd never believe that a man
of your noble character and mien
could be such
a despicable extortionist.
Now then.
You may proceed.
Unworthy as I am,
I shall be your second.
I am an exponent
of the Shindo-Munen-lchi school.
I imagine you are aware,
but let me note just to be sure.
The rite of harakiri
has changed over time.
In recent years,
it is often harakiri in name only.
The subject reaches for the blade
on the wooden stand,
and his second immediately
strikes off his head.
In other words,
there is no disembowelment at all,
and in fact sometimes
the stand holds not a short sword
but only a folding fan.
However,
our proceedings today will not sink
to such debased and empty forms.
We shall adhere strictly
to the traditional ways.
Is that understood?
You will rip your bowels open
crosswise, like this.
Once I see you have done so,
I will strike off your head.
Until I'm satisfied
you've fully torn open your bowels,
I will not bring down my sword.
Is that understood? Now then.
It is your own sword.
That is the blade you will use.
A samurai's sword is his soul.
No blade could be more fitting
for this purpose than your own.
Come. What keeps you?
Proceed!
Strike me!
No, not yet!
Pull your blade across!
Why do you delay?
Draw your blade across!
Pull it to the right!
I suppose he had no other recourse,
but even so, to bite off his tongue?
Would you say he was being
resourceful or just unseemly?
Then again,
who in his right mind attempts
harakiri with just a bamboo sword?
Now then...
What are your intentions?
You mean...
...about this?
The account I've just given you
of Chijiiwa Motome's fate
is true in every detail.
Take my advice, Master Tsugumo.
Quietly take your leave.
You need have no such concerns with me.
Unlike this Chijiiwa fellow...
...the sword in my belt
is not made of bamboo.
I will not bite off my tongue,
I will disembowel myself in grand form.
Very well.
Master Tsugumo,
since you are unswerving in
your resolve, I shall grant your wish.
- Attendant!
- Sire?
This ronin from Hiroshima,
Master Tsugumo Hanshiro,
is to be granted use of the courtyard
to perform harakiri.
His present dress will not do.
Give him fresh robes befitting one
who journeys to the next world...
If I may.
What is it?
Please do not trouble yourselves
over such things.
For the final moments
of a down-and-out ronin like myself...
...surely nothing is more fitting
than the clothes I now wear.
I am deeply grateful for the courteous
and considerate treatment
that you have accorded me today.
I can find no adequate words
to thank you.
Thus, I shall begin.
Might I ask, Counsellor,
who will be serving as my second?
I have assigned Shinmen Ichiro.
Master Shinmen?
Did you wish for someone else?
Yes, sir.
I would like to request
Master Omodaka Hikokuro.
You request Hikokuro?
I believe he's a retainer in this house.
I've heard he's trained
in the Shindo-Munen-lchi school.
Indeed.
Hikokuro is a fine choice.
Hikokuro?
I'm afraid he's not
in attendance today.
He sent a note saying he's ill
and requesting a few days' rest.
I see. That's too bad.
Master Tsugumo,
as you heard,
Omodaka is not present today.
You will need to make another choice.
That is most disappointing.
I had my heart set on Master Omodaka
performing the service.
I wonder if I might not beg
his special consideration.
Well, he says he's ill,
but he seemed fine yesterday.
Surely it can't be anything serious.
Messenger!
Make all due haste
to Omodaka's residence.
Tell him to come immediately,
if his illness permits. Now hurry.
I'm putting you
to a great deal of trouble.
Please accept my apologies.
Now then,
do you wish to wait here?
Or would you like
to come inside and relax?
No.
The comfort of your residence
might cause my resolve to waver.
My journey into eternity mustn't
grow distasteful. I shall remain here.
You display remarkable discipline.
I can but express my admiration.
If I may, Counsellor,
it could be quite tedious for us both
to sit here and wait in silence.
To pass the time,
perhaps you'll allow me
to tell you a little about myself.
About yourself?
Yes.
The hardscrabble tales of a half-starved
ronin don't amount to much,
but what befalls others today
may be your own fate tomorrow.
Perhaps your retainers
will find some small point or two
worth remembering
among my otherwise useless ramblings.
"What befalls others today
may be your own fate tomorrow"?
Well, this could be amusing.
I want everyone here
to listen carefully.
The words of one
staring death in the face...
...are unlikely to be
useless ramblings.
I'm sure we'll all learn something.
Counsellor.
That tale you related earlier...
...may I be assured
it was true in every detail?
Indeed.
The ronin from Hiroshima
named Chijiiwa Motome
was a man of some acquaintance to me.
Chijiiwa Motome...
...was a man
of some acquaintance to me.
Motome was a lad of 15,
and my daughter Miho
was an angelic child of 11.
That was 11 years ago.
But when I close my eyes,
their images come back to me vividly,
as if it were only yesterday.
- My turn again.
- Never mind.
All we do is count stones all day
to repair the castle walls.
We won't need bows and arrows
for a long while.
"The world is at peace.
The four seas are calm."
Incidentally, this coming 22nd
is the seventh anniversary
of Nut's passing.
I knew it was soon,
but is it seven years already?
Yes, and I'm planning
a modest ceremony at my residence.
- But don't bring any offerings.
- Very well.
I can hardly believe it.
Seven years already.
What never ceases to amaze me
is how a rough warrior like you
has managed to raise Miho all these
years without taking a second wife.
Jinnai... look who's talking!
When your Yuki died, I wondered
how you would ever manage.
But look at you.
You're a perfect example
of the kite begetting a hawk.
Kite begetting a hawk?
You were the widower kite,
doting on your child
in every aspect of his upbringing.
And lo and behold,
the child grew not into a kite
but a magnificent young hawk.
Nonsense!
He certainly keeps growing,
but he's got a long way to go
before you can compare him
to a hawk soaring overhead.
I never figured either of us would be
good for anything but battlefield laurels,
but we haven't done too badly
at raising our children.
Had life gone on like that,
all would have been well.
But it was not to be.
When all is said and done,
our lives are like houses
built on foundations of sand.
One strong wind and all is gone.
How my master's house
with its 498,000-koku domain
was brought to ruin...
I'm sure you already know
even better than I do myself.
Due to an unreasonable judgement
by the Tokugawa shogunate
regarding the repairs being performed
on Hiroshima Castle,
in June 1619,
my master, Fukushima Masanori,
was ordered into exile at Kawanakajima,
leaving his 12,000 retainers
without any means of livelihood...
...through no fault of their own.
Jinnai!
To Tsugumo Hanshiro
"In view of our long-standing friendship,
I ask your indulgence in the following.
"The castle repairs commissioner,
"the Honourable Fukushima Masakatsu,
"will be electing death at any moment.
"Therefore, I will precede him
on his journey.
"My company alone will suffice,
"I beg you not to follow.
"Regarding my only child, Motome,
"he has grown tall,
but he is still only 15.
"Please look after him
as he finds his way in life."
Why was he so hasty?
Committing harakiri
even before I have done so.
Hanshiro, I forbid you to follow.
If the house could still be saved,
I would allow it.
But with the house abolished,
it would be pointless.
- Jinnai's company will suffice.
- But, sire...
Don't be foolish, Hanshiro.
Jinnai died because he knew
you would if he didn't.
He died to accompany me
on your behalf as well.
Which means, Hanshiro,
that you must now live on.
Both for you and for Jinnai.
Also for his son, Motome.
Who will look after him if not you?
I go now to meet Jinnai.
Hanshiro, is there anything
you'd like me to tell Jinnai?
Do you have nothing for me
to say to him?
Tell Jinnai...
Tell Jinnai this.
Have no fears about Motome.
I will watch over his path to manhood.
I will not fail him.
I swear this on my life.
Go on, Master Tsugumo.
What did you find out?
It seems his illness
is indeed most serious.
What is the nature of his ailment?
According to his family,
a high fever and excruciating pains
in all his joints.
Go on.
I asked if I might visit him
at his bedside,
but he sent word back
that his pain was so great
that he did not wish to be seen
in his present state.
All I could do was convey
the message you sent and return.
It seems there's nothing we can do.
Perhaps he was overcome
by the relentless heat of recent days.
Master Tsugumo, you heard what he said.
I must ask you to select
someone else as your second.
I am sorely disappointed,
but it appears I have no choice.
In that case...
I would ask for Master Yazaki Hayato.
Hayato?
Inaba, am I to believe he too has
been absent these four or five days?
Correct, sire.
He requested leave
because he wasn't feeling well.
Master Tsugumo,
I'm afraid Yazaki Hayato
is also absent due to illness.
Master Yazaki is also ill?
I'm sorry to hear that.
Again, it seems I have no choice.
Then I request Master Kawabe Umenosuke.
Counsellor,
surely it's not possible
that Master Kawabe is also
under the weather?
Well, well.
It seems he is indeed indisposed.
All three of them unavailable
on this particular day,
what a very odd coincidence.
Most curious.
- He's up to something.
- Clearly so.
Hikokuro was the one who first insisted
that Chijiiwa Motome be forced
to go through with harakiri.
Yazaki was the one
who discovered his blades were
bamboo and insisted he use them,
and Kawabe was quick to agree.
That's why I urged that he at least
be spared the bamboo blade...
- Of what good is that now?
- Indeed, sire.
But how shall we deal with him?
I doubt he intends
to meekly disembowel himself.
He obviously has something
up his sleeve.
Whatever it is...
...he won't get away with it.
We'll force his hand
and make him commit harakiri.
In fact, if he refuses,
we'll fall upon him and cut him down.
What happens within the walls
of this compound...
...is as secret as what happens
behind the walls of our own castle.
One signal from me
and everyone will know what to do.
But I'm bothered about Hikokuro
and the other two.
I need to send someone
to find out more.
Under the circumstances,
I'd like you personally
to find out the real story.
Master Tsugumo...
Summer days are long,
but the hour advances.
I must ask you to proceed
without further delay.
But, Counsellor,
the ritual cannot take place
without a second.
I understand your concern,
but I've discussed the matter
with my senior colleagues.
With all three men of your choice ailing,
we cannot accommodate your wishes.
You will have to accept our selection.
Shinmen Ichiro!
I command you to serve
as second for Master Tsugumo.
Perform your duty with care.
I must protest!
To act as my second,
I have named three
specially selected men.
I must have one of these three.
Are you perhaps deaf?
All three you name are ill
and are not present today.
I explained this very clearly.
Did you not hear?
Then in that case, I have no choice.
I must call off my harakiri for now.
Enough, Tsugumo Hanshiro!
Your scheme for extortion
has gone too far.
It's bad enough to march in here
demanding a place to perform harakiri.
But then you quibble endlessly
over naming your second.
You never intended to commit harakiri.
All you really want is money...
Counsellor!
If I were the extortionist you say,
would I be calmly sitting here
on this platform?
- Then why do you not quietly proceed?
- I am fully prepared to die.
But cutting my belly open
does not in itself
ensure a smooth passage
to the netherworld.
I need someone to expeditiously
strike off my head,
a swordsman of reliable skill.
I do not commit harakiri
to atone for a crime.
The least I can expect
is to choose my own second!
Further debate on the matter...
...is clearly a waste of time.
You are a fraud,
a disgrace to our class.
You never intended to commit harakiri!
Insolent dog!
Wait!
Hold back! Wait, I say!
I beg of all those present
a moment, a brief moment.
You can't possibly have
anything more to say.
But I do. I do have more to say.
I haven't finished my story.
I have no ears
for your endless ramblings.
Counsellor!
If you force me to,
I will fight desperately to the death,
no matter the odds against me.
Some of your men
will be wounded undeservedly.
Some may even lose their lives!
Would it not be better
to simply hear me out?
Once I have finished my story,
I will disembowel myself
without further ado.
Or if you feel harakiri
is too good for me,
you may turn your men on me
to do what they will.
In any event,
I would first like you to hear
what I have to say.
As to these conditions you stipulate,
do I have your word?
You have my word.
And as a samurai,
you will hold true to it?
Very well, but make it short.
I will not listen
to your useless mutterings for long.
Men, fall back.
Now, where was I?
Oh, yes...
My master's house fell
and Chijiiwa Jinnai died.
But before doing so,
he asked me to look after Motome.
When my master's house fell,
we immediately left the domain
and moved to Edo.
The streets of Edo
were crowded with ronin,
flotsam from the Battle of Sekigahara.
In former times, other clans would
have gladly taken in any ronin
who'd earned a name for himself.
But in an era no longer in need
of warriors or horses,
so peaceful that no wind even
rustled the leaves on the trees,
it was a constant struggle
simply to find a meal.
Indeed, it shames me to recall
our miserable lives
over these last eight or nine years.
But amidst all our hardships,
my daughter Miho was rapidly
becoming a woman,
and soon it was the spring
of her 18th year.
Father.
I've set out your lunch
in case I'm not back in time.
The greatest delicacies
taste of nothing when eaten alone.
If you're not back, I'll wait.
I'll collect the money for these
and then stop by Yoshizakicho
for some dried fish.
Good day!
Welcome, sir.
Busy as usual, eh? On your way out?
Yes, to the wholesaler in Kyobashi.
The Mikawaya, I suppose. Take care.
Practice makes perfect.
You've become very deft at that.
Forgive me.
I hate asking you
for advances all the time,
but my earnings refuse to catch up.
You disarm me by beating me to it.
I came intending
to lodge a complaint or two,
but now that you've made
the first move...
...what can I say?
By the way,
what are your thoughts on that matter
I raised the other day?
Have you come to a decision?
Yes, I have decided.
Glad to hear it.
That takes a load off my mind.
No...
I appreciate your proposal
regarding Miho,
but I've decided to decline.
In the end, her adoption
by the Joshuya family
would be a mere pretext
lasting perhaps six months.
Once established
as a member of their family,
she'd be sent to Lord Sakakibara
as his concubine.
Master Tsugumo,
the Sakakibara are a noble family
with a domain of 110,000 koku.
It may seem odd to seek benefit
from your daughter's connections,
but you need do nothing
and doors will open to you.
I understand that.
But, Master Seibei, no matter
how much I've fallen on hard times,
I cannot profit from making
my daughter a concubine.
It's fine to uphold your pride.
But as a parent, you must consider
your daughter's feelings too.
What?
She's young and beautiful,
yet she doesn't have
a single fancy kimono to wear.
She can only look forward to endless
days of slaving at her father's side.
Master Tsugumo,
you can't fight the world you live in
nor go against the tide of the times.
It's a good proposal
for both Miho and for you,
no matter which way you look at it.
In fact, to be honest,
is it not precisely because Miho
was blessed with such beauty
that an avenue like this
remains open to you?
Confucius said:
"He who knows not the will of heaven
is not a superior man."
"He who knows not proper decorum
must not rise to his feet."
"He who knows not the heart of words
cannot know the heart of man."
That will be all for today.
Thank you, sir. Goodbye.
Hey, Katsuzo,
let's go sparrow-hunting today!
Hello, Uncle Hanshiro.
It's good to see you.
Some tea?
- Much obliged.
- Not at all.
I know this house well enough
at least to put water on to boil.
As it happens, Motome,
I came today to discuss
a matter of some weight.
You sound so formal, Uncle.
What could it be?
How quickly the days and months fly by.
Miho is now 18.
She looks more
like her mother every day.
In fact, it's hard to see...
how she could possibly be of my blood.
If she'd taken after me,
she'd never have grown so beautiful.
Uncle... what are you trying to say?
Well... Motome...
I'd like you to take Miho as your wife.
I realise this is all very sudden,
but what do you think?
Motome?
Uncle, you know as well as I
the state of my livelihood at present.
I offer classes in the Chinese classics
to a handful of children
and live from hand to mouth.
How could I possibly take a wife?
Do you dislike Miho?
All I'm asking is
how you feel about her.
It's not only because of the promise
I made to your father
that I hope you'll marry Miho.
Boorish and dull as I am,
I'm not entirely insensitive
to your feelings for each other.
It was more difficult than I expected
to persuade Motome.
I didn't realise he had such
a stubborn and wilful streak.
But I knew he loved Miho,
and I knew Miho would have
no objections to the match.
The crane that lives a thousand years
A symbol of myriad joys
The tortoise that lives 10,000 years
Bears on its back the three worlds
of heaven, earth and man
The sands upon the beach
Numberless and smooth
May they ever reflect the morning sun
After two years, a child was born.
It was a boy, and they named him Kingo.
Of course, I was the one
who chose the name.
Good day.
What's this? Asleep again?
Father, you're too generous.
Nonsense.
Even after I married you off,
you still cook for me.
And besides,
I now have only myself to support.
I save more money
than I know what to do with,
and I can't take it with me!
Well, well.
Did you wake up?
Now, none of that, you little rascal.
A warrior's son should not
be flashing his dimples.
What did I tell you now?
Really? Even the Matsudaira Clan
of Dewa province?
That's right.
I can understand abolishing
the domains of newer vassals,
but to treat vassals who've supported
the Tokugawa for years so harshly?
The shogunate's policy towards
the daimyo is completely beyond me.
We'll see an increase
in the number of ronin.
Did you hear?
One of them tried to commit harakiri
at the Sengoku Clan's gate.
A ronin named Oi Shume,
formerly of the Kurume Clan.
I heard the Sengoku were so impressed
that they offered him employment.
That much was fine.
It's what happened next.
Yes, I heard.
Other ronin who got wind of the story
began presenting themselves at the
gates of daimyo houses all over Edo,
insisting on committing harakiri
and refusing to budge.
In order to get rid of them,
the houses offered them money to leave.
It's a shameful turn of events.
It certainly is.
No matter how hard-pressed they may be,
it's a despicable thing to do.
In these difficult times,
it's no help growing desperate.
Becoming too impatient
to seek employment
is a danger we must all
take care to avoid.
You are absolutely right.
If you stop worrying
about finding employment,
you can sit here like this
without answering to a superior,
at no one's beck and call.
What's the matter, little one?
It's time for his milk. I'll nurse him.
Don't give him your breast
every time he cries,
or he'll develop bad habits.
Lookee here, Kingo. Ready?
All right?
Upsy-daisy. Here we go, Kingo.
In Kanda
At the Myojin Shrine
There's a festival
This very night
Kingo was the centre of our existence,
and the three of us lived happily
with the constant sound
of warm laughter
raising peaceful ripples around us.
It truly was a time
of greater happiness
than I'd ever known in the domain.
However, good things
never last for long.
"We've been granted to live thus far...
"But it won't last forever...
"We're destined to leave this world...
"And there's nothing untoward
about it."
One day, Miho suddenly coughed up
profuse quantities of blood.
She had always been
of weak constitution,
and with the endless burden
of our piecework labour...
...she'd driven her frail body
too hard for too long.
Motome panicked.
The poor fellow.
Date Clan construction site,
fifty labourers at 40 mon.
Fifty labourers at 40 mon.
Just a minute, samurai, sir!
Are you trying to get me in trouble?
There isn't enough work
even for the townsmen.
If the authorities spotted
a two-sworded labourer,
I'd be in for a real dressing-down.
Hosokawa Clan construction site,
twenty labourers at 45 mon.
Pawn Shop
Poor Motome,
he tried everything but to no avail.
Miho was gradually wasting away.
And the worst was yet to come.
It's seared forever in my memory.
We' d just barely made it
through the end of the year,
and the plum blossoms
had begun to bloom
shortly after the beginning
of the new year.
What's wrong?
Is it Miho?
It's Kingo.
What? Kingo?
A fever.
Like he's on fire.
Why, Miho?
Why did you just sit by
until it came to this?
I thought it was an ordinary cold.
What did the doctor say?
You did have a doctor see him,
didn't you?
You haven't had a doctor see him?
Why haven't you had a doctor
look at him?
Kingo, fight it off.
Your grandpa,
like your mother and father,
has already sold off
everything of value.
There's not a thing,
not a thing we can do for you.
There's nothing...
...nothing we can do, Kingo.
But you're the son of a samurai.
You can't let a little illness
get the better of you.
Don't let it beat you.
Don't let it... Don't let it...
Father.
I have an idea.
What?
I need to go out.
Please look after Kingo.
What do you have in mind?
A former retainer of the Kato Clan
now lives in Nihonbashi
and makes his living as a moneylender.
His rates are so high
I didn't dare go to him before,
but I can't worry about that anymore.
You're right. If you know such a man,
hurry and go!
I'm on my way.
I'll be back by evening at the latest.
As you can see, Miho is too weak,
so please take care of Kingo.
Of course. I know what to do.
But, Motome,
you can see he's barely hanging on.
You must be quick,
and you mustn't fail.
I'll return by evening without fail.
Until then.
We're depending on you, Motome!
No, no, I'll do that.
It won't be long now, Kingo.
What's taking him so long?
He's getting worse.
What could Motome be doing?
No, no. Your getting up
won't do Kingo's fever any good.
Where can Motome be?
He swore he'd be back by evening.
What could he be doing?
I waited.
Every moment felt like an eternity.
But Motome did not return.
We never saw him again.
"I'll be back by evening,
so please look after Kingo."
Those were his final words
as he went out the door,
and that was the last I saw
of Chijiiwa Motome.
But then,
around nine that night,
he did return home.
Only not on his own.
He was borne home by a party
of retainers from the House of lyi...
...most courteously.
This was the request with which
Chijiiwa Motome came to us.
But our forecourt is a busy place
and would have been inconvenient,
so we offered him our courtyard and
saw to his needs with all due propriety,
thus allowing him to fulfil his wish
to commit harakiri.
We understand there have been
incidents all across Edo lately
in which ronin present themselves
at the gates of daimyo houses
and threaten to commit harakiri
unless given money.
This disgraceful practice has put
many houses at a loss as to what to do.
But now we have Chijiiwa Motome,
a samurai of true valour,
who carried out his resolve
to die honourably.
And we the members of the lyi Clan
responded appropriately
to facilitate his wishes.
In contrast to many disgraceful ronin
and the spineless timidity
of other daimyo households,
both parties in this instance
acted in an exemplary manner
that will open eyes and clear the air.
It is truly an occasion
for mutual congratulations.
- We bid you...
- Wait.
To avoid any misunderstanding,
show the blades.
That's right.
For the record, we wish you to examine
the swords Chijiiwa was carrying.
You will note that
both blades are of bamboo.
Bamboo?
As you can see,
both are made of bamboo.
No one must accuse us later
of having switched blades.
So take a good look.
Is it clear?
In that case,
Motome must have borrowed
a blade from your household?
No, he did not.
He died magnificently
using his own blade.
Motome... killed himself
with that bamboo blade?
Exactly.
The entire household
witnessed the spectacle
of harakiri performed
with a bamboo blade.
As you may imagine,
an unsightly affair.
It would have been more fitting
for a samurai
to end his life with a true blade,
which is a warrior's soul.
- So long.
- We bid you good night.
Miho wept.
She wept...
...and wept.
Motome!
Forgive me!
I had...
I had no idea.
You had even sold your blades.
For Miho's sake,
you even sold your blades.
But I...
...I would never let this go.
It never entered my mind.
The stupid thing was too dear to me...
...and I clung to it.
To this stupid...
With his fever still raging
and in a coma,
Kingo died two days later.
Three days after that,
as if chasing after him,
Miho died as well.
Thus did Tsugumo Hanshiro find
himself utterly alone in the world,
having lost every last person
he had ever cared about.
Master Tsugumo,
does that conclude your story?
I suppose it does.
No...
...there's one more thing.
May all those here listen carefully
to what I'm about to say.
No matter how grinding
his poverty and hunger,
for a samurai to present himself
in someone else's entryway
and declare that he wishes
to commit harakiri there
is an unspeakable act that
can in no way be excused.
Having said that...
...the manner in which
the House of lyi handled the matter...
...surely left a great deal to be desired.
If a samurai risks shame and ridicule
to beg for a day or two's grace,
he must surely have good reason.
A simple inquiry
as to the reason for the request
would have told so much.
Yet with this many witnesses present...
...not a single one among you
had the consideration to ask.
His wife lay on the very verge of death,
while his beloved son burned with fever,
in dire need of a doctor.
Motome no doubt wished
to explain the situation to me,
make whatever last effort
he could for his son,
before turning all further care
over to me,
and then return here
to the House of lyi.
Tsugumo Hanshiro!
Enough of your self-serving excuses!
What?
As to Chijiiwa Motome,
the circumstances that drove him here
were no doubt complex.
But it was he who declared
his wish to commit harakiri.
What followed upon that request
may not have been what he intended,
but he reaped what he himself sowed.
He was in no position to complain,
or to blame or condemn anyone.
At that point,
all he had to do was cast all else
aside and die a magnificent death.
To face death without wavering,
that is the true way of the samurai.
But what did this man do?
He cravenly asked
for a day or two's grace.
One might well accuse him
of having gone mad!
True enough.
Motome had indeed gone mad.
But I say good for him!
I praise him for it.
He may have been a samurai,
but he was also
a man of flesh and blood.
He could not live on air alone.
When a man has reached
the point of no return,
even one as strong as Motome will
go mad trying to protect his family,
and I would praise him for it!
They'll call him the "Bamboo Ronin".
Not only samurai, but townspeople, too,
will scoff at his wavering.
But let them laugh all they want.
Who can fathom the depths
of another man's heart?
Thanks to the shogunate's ruthless
policy of wiping out the provincial lords,
countless samurai lost their masters
and were cast out
to wander the depths of hell.
How can those who never want for food
or clothing understand their misery?
To those who find Motome loathsome
for his pleading, I ask you,
what if you found yourself
in the same position?
Would you do any differently?
After all,
this thing we call samurai honour
is ultimately nothing but a faade.
Is that your grievance?
- Grievance?
- Is that what you're trying to tell us?
That samurai honour
is nothing but a faade?
Exactly.
"Even if I say I want
to commit harakiri,
"they surely won't make me do it."
Such wishful thinking
is where these ronin go wrong.
If a man says he wants
to commit harakiri, we will let him.
In fact, since he has proposed it
himself, we'll make sure he does.
That is the policy of the House of lyi.
For us, samurai honour
is no mere faade!
And so Tsugumo Hanshiro too
has come here with no intention
of committing harakiri,
but rather out of deep bitterness
over the manner in which the lyi Clan
treated his son-in-law Chijiiwa Motome,
and the desire to vent
his many grudges.
Is that what you think?
That's not for me to say.
You can only look into your own heart.
But all the same,
you have no intention
of letting me leave here alive?
That is my decision to make.
I need make no excuses to you.
Counsellor,
there is a proverb, "The suspicious
mind conjures its own demons."
Do you know it?
When I say I will disembowel myself,
I truly mean it.
Yet, even after all I have said,
you still refuse to...
Suppose I were to go on living,
what could I possibly have
to look forward to?
The fact is, I can hardly wait
to join Motome and Miho and Kingo
in that world to which
they have preceded me.
But I would never be able
to look them in the face
were I to go empty-handed.
I think you can understand that.
I thought perhaps once I had explained,
even members of the lyi Clan would
surely say, "So that's how it was?
"Perhaps we were overzealous that day
in pressing towards that end.
"Anyone can see that our handling
of the situation was less than ideal.
"In some ways,
perhaps we carried things too far.
"No doubt both parties could have
conducted themselves to better effect."
If I could take with me
even a single word in this vein,
it would be a comfort to Motome.
Was this not the most fitting gift
I could hope to offer him?
Such were my thoughts!
But I see now it was nothing
but wishful thinking.
If you can see that,
then it makes the rest easy.
This world does not bend
to sentimental tales.
If you really think that samurai honour
is ultimately nothing more
than a faade,
then you never had a chance
of swaying us.
So in the end,
these have been nothing but
the useless grumblings of an old man.
But it does no good to lament that now.
Well, then, forgive me
for my long-winded recitation.
I will now proceed with the ritual.
Tarry a moment.
Before that,
I must return some items
that belong to this house.
For identification,
I have placed name tags on each.
Please examine them carefully.
Master Yazaki Hayato
and Master Kawabe Umenosuke...
I understand they're both among
the best swordsmen of the lyi Clan,
held in high esteem
for their courage and honour.
But, Counsellor,
gentlemen,
let me set your minds at ease.
I took only their topknots.
Not their lives.
In the case of Yazaki Hayato,
it was six days ago.
Hold it!
In the case of Kawabe Umenosuke,
it was five days ago, on May 8th.
However,
when it came to that master swordsman
of the Shindo-Munen-lchi school,
Master Omodaka Hikokuro,
I had a little more difficulty.
Perhaps aware of what had befallen
Yazaki and Kawabe,
I could not catch him off guard.
In fact, to be honest,
I found myself at quite a loss
as to how to deal with Master Omodaka.
May I enter?
If you reach for your sword,
I'll slice you in one motion
from shoulder to waist.
However...
...I fear the lintel will catch
the tip of my blade.
If you lunge to the side,
then this pillar will get in the way.
It took a few days to locate your home.
My apologies for the delay.
I ask you to make ready.
This is obviously no place
for a sword duel.
It's a bit far, but I must ask you
to accompany me to Gojiin-gawara.
As miserable a hovel as this is,
your landlord will be inconvenienced
if you do not return.
And without someone to retrieve your
remains, your soul will wander aimlessly.
I suggest you leave a note.
It should indicate
you're going to Gojiin-gawara
for a duel with Omodaka Hikokuro
of the lyi Clan.
Taking advantage of the wind
was brilliant,
but a blade can do more than cut.
It can also stab,
or even snap another blade in two.
Swordsmanship untested in battle
is like the art of swimming
on tatami mats.
On the other hand,
I had not seen battle either
since the siege of Osaka Castle
16 years ago.
Taking his head
would have been difficult enough,
but taking only his topknot
proved more difficult still.
Whatever the differences in our skill,
for a samurai to have his topknot taken
is the same as having
his head stricken off.
It is an ineptitude, a disgrace,
that can scarcely be atoned for
even by death.
Yet these men claim illness
and shirk their duties
while waiting for their topknots
to grow back. Counsellor!
This house boasts of its red armour
and its martial valour,
but it seems that even
in the great House of lyi,
samurai honour is nothing more
than a faade.
Madman!
Cut him down!
Fall back!
Tsugumo Hanshiro has been killed, sire.
And our casualties?
What were the casualties among our men?
Sugita Masakatsu, Uemura Sobei.
Shinmen Ichiro, Yoshioka Uemon.
Four dead.
Eight more seriously wounded.
The ronin from Hiroshima,
Tsugumo Hanshiro, committed harakiri.
All our own men died of illness.
The House of lyi has no retainers
who could be felled or wounded
by some half-starved ronin.
Former retainer of the Fukushima Clan,
Tsugumo Hanshiro,
committed harakiri honourably,
according to his wish.
All our men died of illness.
Their deaths have nothing to do
with Tsugumo's.
Furthermore, we cannot allow
any more to die of illness.
See that the wounded
are treated immediately.
I have just returned, Counsellor.
Omodaka Hikokuro...
...last night at his home...
Kawabe and Yazaki both claim illness.
- But in fact...
- Fool!
Why did you not order them
to commit harakiri on the spot?
Go back at once
and order them to do so!
And take some skilled swordsmen
with you.
If they fail to willingly disembowel
themselves, make them do it by force.
Of course, these two men
and Omodaka too,
did not officially commit harakiri.
They died of illness.
Imbecile!
You weren't born yesterday,
you know the ways of the world!
Do you not realise the implications?
Idiot!
I am on my way, sire.
The former retainer of the Fukushima
Clan, Tsugumo Hanshiro,
died by harakiri at six in the evening.
His speech and behaviour
had been erratic.
Many of those present felt
he showed signs of derangement.
Furthermore, it has become clear
when another former retainer
of the Fukushima Clan,
one Chijiiwa Motome, asked to commit
harakiri in January of this year,
we did not err in our chosen response.
Word of the martial rigour
of this house echoed throughout Edo.
In the present case too,
word of our resolute handling
spread across the city
before two days were out.
As a result,
on the third day,
in a formal session at Edo Castle,
Lord Doi took the occasion
to confer words of praise
upon our young master Bennosuke
as follows...
"At peace, yet ever vigilant.
"Let the House of lyi continue
to embrace this principle,
"and your fortunes are sure
to prosper forages to come."
The 16th day of May,
1630.
HARAKIRl